# Transcript
ID: e03e7743-8428-430a-a428-033ed90c0ae6
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-1866450124987257775/7581251673948174220/s93290-US-6258s-1751022302.mp3
Description: It's already the heat of summer, and the news keeps coming. Nilay, David, and Jake start the show with a bunch of tech news, including the latest on Tesla's robotaxi launch, some updates on the Trump Phone, new devices from Fairphone and Unihertz, and Meta's shifting strategy for face computers. After that, The Verge's Adi Roberston joins the show to talk about two important AI lawsuits that were both decided this week — one involving Anthropic and the other involving Meta — and what this particular battle means for who will win the AI war. Finally, in the lightning round, it's time for another round of Brendan Carr is a Dummy, some huge news in the HDMI world, and the end of the Blue Screen of Death.
Speaker 5:  Hello and welcome to GR Cast,
Speaker 1:  The flagship podcast
Speaker 5:  Of being the new editor in chief of Vogue.
Speaker 5:  I just put my name in the ring. I don't, I don't think that would be
Speaker 5:  a good idea And I, I love my current job, but it
Speaker 5:  is true that Anna Wintour is stepping down as editor-in-chief of Vogue, the
Speaker 5:  most legendary editor-in-chief of all time. And
Speaker 5:  hey, you know, hey,
Speaker 6:  NELI, 30 more years of this.
Speaker 5:  Hi, I am your friend, NELI. That's Jay Kakis. Hello. Hello. David Pierce
Speaker 5:  is here.
Speaker 6:  I like imagining Vogue as just like
Speaker 6:  everyone is wearing black on every page of every issue of the magazine
Speaker 6:  and, and there's like Packer's logos in the background. Yeah, that'd
Speaker 5:  Great. That vo that that's my vogue. And, and only iPhone fours are
Speaker 5:  allowed the most beautiful phone of all time.
Speaker 6:  You would last two issues, but they would be glorious.
Speaker 5:  I've only met Anna once or twice, and
Speaker 5:  both times she was utterly charming. I, I have to say.
Speaker 5:  But the second time was at the American
Speaker 5:  Society of Magazine Editors Awards, the ASME awards. And we had a table right
Speaker 5:  next to like a Conde Nast table that Anna was at, and they were terrified
Speaker 5:  of her. Like she was sitting there and all of the Conde Nast people
Speaker 5:  were sitting there just in terror. And then our table was just like drunk
Speaker 5:  and cheering like we were having the most fun. And they, they
Speaker 5:  kept staring. And I was like, don't you know? And I was like, I do know.
Speaker 5:  This is our vibe. It's our time now. You're the legacy media.
Speaker 6:  I, I always like thinking about how she must feel about Devil always
Speaker 6:  wears Prada in the way that Mark Zuckerberg feels about the social network
Speaker 6:  because like, he's a been very upfront about how
Speaker 6:  he did not like the way he was portrayed in that movie. I would say history
Speaker 6:  has proven that movie more right over time than I expected. No,
Speaker 5:  Jesse Isenberg was vastly cooler than Mark Zuckerberg in that movie.
Speaker 6:  I mean, yes,
Speaker 5:  Like history, what history has proven is Mark Zuckerberg is a huge nerd who
Speaker 5:  can't outrun his own essential nature. Yes.
Speaker 6:  Fair. Which I think was a, a large part of what that movie is going for.
Speaker 6:  But like, yeah, I, I think that thing where somebody like very
Speaker 6:  famously portrays you and it changes the way everyone thinks about you has
Speaker 6:  gotta be such a weird phenomenon that like most people think when they close
Speaker 6:  their eyes and think of Anna Winter, they think of Meryl Streep. And that's
Speaker 6:  just weird. That's gotta be so strange.
Speaker 5:  It does. And and you know, I watch several product whenever it's on television.
Speaker 5:  I, it's like, it's a great movie. You should watch it. It
Speaker 6:  Is.
Speaker 5:  And Becky has always reminding me that I think I'm Anne Hathaway, but
Speaker 5:  in fact I,
Speaker 5:  I'm now the Meryl Streep character. Interesting. It's over. But anyway, look,
Speaker 5:  if you know anyone over there and
Speaker 5:  you want to see Vogue get super weird. I I'm open to a
Speaker 5:  conversation. I'm not, you know, just
Speaker 6:  The vogue was a series of feeds, you
Speaker 5:  Know what I mean? Yeah. Like, have you thought about going all in on activity
Speaker 5:  pub in the world's most important fashion magazine? There's a lot
Speaker 5:  there. You can unpack a lot there. The world's most important fashion magazine
Speaker 5:  and the age of Instagram and TikTok is a weird thing to be.
Speaker 5:  They, they have a monopoly on taste. Right. It's the cover of Vogue
Speaker 5:  that's important. The contents of Vogue almost are not. And so like that's
Speaker 5:  the dynamic there. And it's super interesting if you're not Anna
Speaker 5:  Wintour and you don't have that monopoly, whether or not Vogue can
Speaker 5:  be the thing that it is in the age of Instagram, TikTok in the age of all
Speaker 5:  the celebrities just being able to publish their own pictures of themselves.
Speaker 5:  It's a thing. I'm just, I'm just saying it's a thing. All right. We, we can
Speaker 5:  set that aside. But if you know anyone and if you know anyone at Kanye ask
Speaker 5:  has, or wanna have a really weird conversation about the future of Vogue,
Speaker 5:  you know, again, I love this job. Either there's not another job, other job
Speaker 5:  really for me. But
Speaker 6:  I'm trying to decide if it would be more fun to like point the verges
Speaker 6:  resources at getting you elected president in 2028 or getting you the job
Speaker 6:  as editor in chief of Vogue.
Speaker 5:  It's like, it's, they're
Speaker 6:  Very different futures, but I find the project of both of
Speaker 6:  them very fun.
Speaker 5:  I do think I can shape the, the direction of the country in either role.
Speaker 5:  It just in very different way.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Which is more effective.
Speaker 5:  All right. There's a lot of news this week. A lot of updates. We,
Speaker 5:  we got a, there's a big set of AI copyright decisions that
Speaker 5:  Addie is gonna join us to talk about and unpack. I would say earlier today,
Speaker 5:  Addie And I had a conversation and can only be described as we got into our
Speaker 5:  feelings about copyright law because of these AI decisions. So we gotta talk
Speaker 5:  about that. There's updates on the Trump phone.
Speaker 5:  Brendan's got a new commissioner at the FCC, so he just
Speaker 5:  immediately started doing some of the dumbest stuff in the world. There's
Speaker 5:  a, a side note, like there's some FTC dumbness, it's involving
Speaker 5:  just straightforward Bribery, which is pretty good. A lot, just a
Speaker 5:  lot going on in the world. But we should start with a little update
Speaker 5:  on the Robotaxis, the Tesla Robotaxis in Austin. I think
Speaker 5:  David on the Tuesday show, Andy was on, we were like a day in. Now we're
Speaker 5:  several days in. I would say the obvious has occurred.
Speaker 6:  It was very funny. So we, Andy And I talked about it a bunch and he kept
Speaker 6:  being like, look, we, we should be cautious. Tesla should be cautious,
Speaker 6:  but it's only been a day. We'll, we'll see what happens, you know, hope for
Speaker 6:  the best, expect the worst. And like, boy did it just kind of go sideways
Speaker 6:  from like minute one.
Speaker 5:  So there's a bunch of videos now there's like a media component to
Speaker 5:  this where the only people who seem to have access are Tesla
Speaker 5:  influencers and like hardcore Elon Musk ex
Speaker 5:  posters.
Speaker 5:  And they're all like, we're the media now. And it's like, are are you?
Speaker 5:  But then they're all just doing this like incredible live streaming. Like
Speaker 5:  everything is being posted. And so even through the filter
Speaker 5:  of a bunch of people who's, who hold themselves up as being
Speaker 5:  Tesla boosters, there's just like endless videos of these,
Speaker 5:  these cars just like making mistakes. And the net result of it, just
Speaker 5:  from my perspective as a person watching these videos is that it's just full
Speaker 5:  self-driving, right? There're yes, there's safety
Speaker 5:  monitors in the cars and there's that one
Speaker 5:  picture of one steering wheel in the background of one photo. You know,
Speaker 5:  like maybe they're all being remote controlled, you know, there's all these
Speaker 5:  rumors about this stuff, but you kind of watch it and you're like, oh, this
Speaker 5:  is just like watching any other full self-driving video. Only
Speaker 5:  like the cars are making mistakes without a driver
Speaker 5:  so that it all feels way more dangerous.
Speaker 6:  Right? They're all, only they're sitting in the backseat. Right. Is like
Speaker 6:  a pretty meaningful change in how Right. We're actually applying this
Speaker 6:  technology
Speaker 5:  When FSD messes up and the person's in the driver's seat. They're like, I'm
Speaker 5:  taking control. And they're like, oh, that was scary right Now. It's like,
Speaker 5:  whoops.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. What are these safety monitors actually supposed to do?
Speaker 7:  Just like, like comfort you when when like you rear end somebody. Like it's
Speaker 7:  all right, we, we, we, this, this happens from time to time.
Speaker 6:  There have been a bunch of these And I think when the safety
Speaker 6:  monitor does and doesn't get involved has been sort of fascinating. Like,
Speaker 6:  there, there were, there was the one I think that has been kind of all over
Speaker 6:  the place and Andy And I talked about this on Tuesday where the car
Speaker 6:  just veers into the wrong lane for a second. And the, the safety
Speaker 6:  monitor doesn't seem to flinch that this is just like, it's fine,
Speaker 6:  we're just gonna go in the wrong lane because we thought the turn lane started
Speaker 6:  before it did. But then there are a couple of other ones where like
Speaker 6:  something actually goes where and the car just like
Speaker 6:  stops in the middle of the road and then the safety monitor does get involved.
Speaker 6:  So it seems very much like the safety monitors instructed to
Speaker 6:  basically not do anything no matter what, unless
Speaker 6:  it has like officially broken, which is kind of a
Speaker 6:  wild set of instructions to give to a safety monitor in a car like this
Speaker 6:  in a project as early as this. But I just, I don't know how to
Speaker 6:  read it any other way. Like they, they should have been getting involved
Speaker 6:  more if they were allowed to be getting involved more.
Speaker 5:  There's definitely one where the car gets stuck kinda like between two cars.
Speaker 5:  It's a tight and the safety monitor drives it out.
Speaker 6:  Okay. I didn't see that one. That's something, I
Speaker 5:  Get it right. It's a very limited beta slash pilot of this
Speaker 5:  stuff. There's not a lot of these cars,
Speaker 5:  it's a trial. Sure. They're on public roads with other people and other cars.
Speaker 5:  Right. It does seem to me like the safety monitor should just be in the driver's
Speaker 5:  seat. Especially if it, again, as it appears
Speaker 5:  it's just full self-driving. Like it's not more,
Speaker 5:  if they were faking it and there was a warehouse full of people remote
Speaker 5:  driving cars, I'd be like, yeah, safety monitor in the RC, you know, but
Speaker 5:  like you, you watch these videos and
Speaker 5:  it, it feels anyway from my perspective, like it's just full self-driving
Speaker 5:  and then you get to the fact that most people can't access the cars,
Speaker 5:  right? It is just this limited group at least posting content
Speaker 5:  that is very apt to supporting Tesla.
Speaker 5:  And you have this like war against the media narrative, right? And I'm just
Speaker 5:  gonna say this as many times I can access is poison.
Speaker 5:  And if you hit capture where the companies are covered, you're gonna make
Speaker 5:  bad shit over time and you're gonna lose your audience. And that's just the
Speaker 5:  way it goes. And all of these folks who are like,
Speaker 5:  the media doesn't just gonna have the wrong narrative about Tesla. If Tesla
Speaker 5:  was confident in the product, they would just let reporters
Speaker 5:  into it and let them drive around and say, this is amazing. You could just
Speaker 5:  take Waymo. 'cause Waymo's confident in its product. It think it thinks
Speaker 5:  the products expanding the markets, it operates in this,
Speaker 5:  this thing where you think Tesla has rewarded these influencers
Speaker 5:  is actually a sign of deep insecurity. Like the most
Speaker 5:  insecurity And I, you can see it. I mean we, this is, this is our world,
Speaker 5:  right? You see it with every company when they're not proud of their products,
Speaker 5:  they close the distribution, they limit the access. You know, we play
Speaker 5:  these games, but we, our rules are clear. I if you're listening to this,
Speaker 5:  you know, our rules is clear. You can't buy us, you can't buy our branded
Speaker 5:  content. We're unsponsored for flight, all this stuff. Because that's how
Speaker 5:  we manage the access games. We just draw the
Speaker 5:  lines as clear as we can. We say, look, we won't play the games. If we don't
Speaker 5:  get the access, we'll go and do the next thing. And I like, there's the
Speaker 5:  video, there's the, there's the one video of the woman in the backseat that
Speaker 5:  the car breaks so hard, it throws the phone out of her hand and then she
Speaker 5:  starts apologizing for the car and it's like, oh, this is bad.
Speaker 5:  Like this is a really bad media ecosystem. If you think that the
Speaker 5:  reward is the, the car breaks so hard while you're not wearing a
Speaker 5:  seatbelt, the phone flies. Sorry, we we have it. Do you wanna just play it
Speaker 5:  David?
Speaker 6:  I do.
Speaker 8:  Let's find out. You guys know we're not lying because we have that stopwatch
Speaker 8:  going, whoa. Alright, so we just slammed
Speaker 8:  on the brake. I'm not exactly sure what just happened,
Speaker 8:  but the car thought it saw something and this
Speaker 8:  happens in full self-driving. This is something that does happen. That's
Speaker 8:  something that people have talked about being one of the limitations
Speaker 8:  of full self-driving with Robax is that occasionally it SLAM's
Speaker 8:  on the brakes side of nowhere. You guys kind of saw me react.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I
Speaker 5:  Mean you get the idea. What are we doing?
Speaker 7:  It happens sometimes guys, sometimes your car just
Speaker 7:  slams the brakes on you and you just sit there
Speaker 5:  With no, the safety, presumably a safety monitor just saying nothing while
Speaker 5:  this video is happening.
Speaker 6:  It is sort of fascinating that this is what Tesla has conditioned
Speaker 6:  its fans to believe is
Speaker 5:  Just how this works. No, I'm saying it's more sinister than that. I'm saying
Speaker 5:  it has conditioned access on that behavior. Oh sure. And
Speaker 5:  that feedback loop is actually bad for the comp. It's bad for people,
Speaker 5:  right? It's bad for people like great products. It's also bad for the company
Speaker 5:  'cause they're not actually getting the negative feedback they need, right?
Speaker 5:  The market is not actually providing any information. They have a bunch of
Speaker 5:  influencers who are afraid of their access being taken away and not getting
Speaker 5:  invited to the next cyber rodeo or whatever. And then they're yelling at
Speaker 5:  reporters who are just trying to do their jobs, but they're
Speaker 5:  like, you can literally hear the lack of objectivity there. And look, e everyone
Speaker 5:  can yell at us. You somehow, in my career, I've gone from being reliably
Speaker 5:  called an Apple shield to being called an Apple hater. Great, I
Speaker 5:  sure whatever you can yell at us about our perceived biases,
Speaker 5:  but we have our rules. Like you can just read the policy. Like those, those
Speaker 5:  rules exist to, to at least like
Speaker 5:  provide a set of guidelines for what you expect from our behavior and how
Speaker 5:  we think about access and all these other things that we, you know,
Speaker 5:  that are part of our job and our careers and the, the media that we make.
Speaker 5:  I but you can hear literally in these videos, the influencers thinking
Speaker 5:  if my access will get taken away And I I
Speaker 5:  need to apologize for this car fucking up. And it's like, no, a real person,
Speaker 5:  a real customer does not stop and say this happens.
Speaker 5:  They just get the fuck out the car and like, that's your problem.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The video did make me think about like the terrible Uber rides that
Speaker 6:  I've had in the past and like, they happen occasionally and you have them,
Speaker 6:  but like there's a person in the front seat you can tell to like one year
Speaker 6:  at CESI had an Uber driver who drove me at
Speaker 6:  i i 45 miles an hour through parking lots of
Speaker 6:  casinos in Las Vegas to get me to the airport. And we
Speaker 6:  were just like launching ourselves over speed bumps. And for the first time
Speaker 6:  ever I had to be like, guy, you, you gotta stop dude. Like I'm not in a
Speaker 6:  hurry. Please stop driving like this. And he did and it was fine.
Speaker 6:  And I was like, I went from being like, I'm going to die in the back of this
Speaker 6:  like dodge charger.
Speaker 5:  Of course it was a Dodge Charger
Speaker 6:  To, it was okay 'cause there was a person I could tell and it was just like,
Speaker 6:  it's, it's not that these things are
Speaker 6:  uniquely bad drivers. It's it's that like we have a chain of understanding
Speaker 6:  how this stuff works that we just, none of this has made any sense. Again,
Speaker 6:  it goes back to like put the safety monitor in front of the steering wheel.
Speaker 6:  Like Yeah,
Speaker 5:  But he can't. Right. I know why he should And I know why Elon should put
Speaker 5:  the safety monitor behind the wheel. I know why he can't because the future
Speaker 5:  of Tesla's valuation depends on robo taxis working not on
Speaker 5:  selling new or better cars.
Speaker 6:  That's why this whole thing exists. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Anyhow. Well the more time will pass, presumably more people will get access
Speaker 5:  to this thing. I'm just, I I've been bemused it,
Speaker 5:  it feels like a bunch of people are entering
Speaker 5:  a kind of journalism where the compromises of access will be made
Speaker 5:  clear and some people will learn the lesson and some people won't. And it
Speaker 5:  all kind of feels like speed running to me. Like you're
Speaker 5:  about to have a whole bunch of experiences here. But I'm, I'm watching these
Speaker 5:  videos and I'm like, oh, the thing doesn't work as well as it should. Right?
Speaker 5:  And if you actually wanna compete with Waymo, if you actually wanna build
Speaker 5:  those stuff, it needs to work a lot better than this. A lot faster. And like
Speaker 5:  everything with Tesla, maybe it'll just take a long time. But I don know
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna continue watching this list of Reddit video updates.
Speaker 6:  They're very good. I really, it's Reddit has done an admirable job
Speaker 6:  of putting together timestamped versions of hilariously bad things happening
Speaker 6:  to these people. Yeah. I highly recommend it.
Speaker 5:  By the way, if you wanna be a a auto journalists and you think Tesla is much,
Speaker 5:  by all means, I'm just, I will just say it again. Access is poison.
Speaker 5:  It will it, if you chase access, it will kill you. And
Speaker 5:  I say this to our staff all the time, the less access you need, the more
Speaker 5:  you get. And that, that's a, that's a dynamic that's very hard. Again, I
Speaker 5:  think they're just speed running media in like a very particular way. We'll
Speaker 5:  see how it goes. Alright. Speaking of access, poison
Speaker 5:  and speed runs. There's an update on a Trump phone.
Speaker 6:  Jake, you helped me investigate this. Do you want to take us through what
Speaker 6:  happened with the Trump phone this week? Yeah, well if you guys will recall
Speaker 7:  About a week ago
Speaker 7:  Trump organization announced Trump Mobile. The Trump mobile announced
Speaker 7:  the T one phone 8,002
Speaker 7:  Gold Edition, believe the name is. And I think we came on here and we said,
Speaker 7:  we don't believe that a lot of this is, is accurate.
Speaker 7:  One of the biggest things was that they said it was going to be made in the
Speaker 7:  United States.
Speaker 7:  Eli went on TV and shouted that that was a lie.
Speaker 5:  That's true. I will say I, I was not on the show last week And I listened
Speaker 5:  to it And I had the, I had what I believe is the very common experience of
Speaker 5:  yelling at The Vergecast. So I feel a lot of empathy for the
Speaker 5:  audience. But CC invited me on, I was like, this is fake.
Speaker 7:  And lo and behold,
Speaker 7:  David, earlier this week, scrolling through their website
Speaker 7:  sees that they've changed the website used to say made in the U
Speaker 7:  United States. Now it says what, what's the exact phrase, David? Oh
Speaker 6:  My god, I'm so excited to read this website to you. First of all,
Speaker 6:  shouts to Simon who saw this before I did and sent it to me.
Speaker 6:  Can I just, can I just like read you a bunch of copy please. This is the,
Speaker 6:  the phone page of the T one on the
Speaker 6:  Trump mobile website says at the very top, meet the T one
Speaker 6:  premium performance proudly American. This is the new
Speaker 6:  tagline of this phone, the T one trademark. They put trademark everywhere,
Speaker 6:  which I really respect isn't just another smartphone, it's a bold step towards
Speaker 6:  wireless independence. That doesn't mean anything designed with American
Speaker 6:  values in mind. The T one trademark delivers top tier performance, sleek
Speaker 6:  design and powerful features. All without the inflated price tag designed
Speaker 6:  with American values in mind is what is replacing made in the
Speaker 6:  USA. We also have with American hands behind every
Speaker 6:  device, we bring care precision and trusted quality to every detail. Are
Speaker 6:  those
Speaker 5:  Just Don Jr's hands? Like he's just, he's just collecting his checks.
Speaker 6:  There's just some, some American has put hands
Speaker 6:  near
Speaker 7:  A phone. An American, yeah, that's all we know for an American hand has put
Speaker 7:  their, has has clicked the Ali Express order button.
Speaker 7:  That is what happened to you. I am telling you, you go to Olly
Speaker 7:  Express, you type in big Android phone and you will find what is something
Speaker 7:  that is very close to the T one phone. And I, the
Speaker 7:  other thing that David noticed I is that they've, they've changed the specs
Speaker 7:  as well. The, the phone is not going to ship a as the exact phone
Speaker 7:  that they announced a week ago, which means that like
Speaker 7:  they clearly were not confident in what they announced. I think we all said
Speaker 7:  that would be the case and we were already starting to see it morph in front
Speaker 7:  of our eyes as they realized that it was, it was not correct. David, what
Speaker 7:  is the updated spec? They, I believe they changed the RAM and they changed
Speaker 7:  it screen size. So the
Speaker 6:  Ram is now gone from the website straight. Okay.
Speaker 6:  It normally, there was a, there was, if I remember right, there was a section
Speaker 6:  on the site that said like processor and RAM and it had no processor listed
Speaker 6:  but it said 12 gigs of ram. Now that whole section is gone. So we still don't
Speaker 6:  know the processor and now there is no ram apparently. The other one, which
Speaker 6:  I think is maybe the bigger signal that
Speaker 6:  something big has shifted here is it has gone from a
Speaker 6:  6.78 inch screen to a 6.25 inch screen,
Speaker 6:  which I would just point out is a very different phone. Yeah. If you lop
Speaker 6:  off a half inch of the screen, you've gone from an iPhone plus to an iPhone.
Speaker 6:  Like that's just a different thing. And
Speaker 6:  like the, they fixed a couple of things like now it
Speaker 6:  says battery as battery instead of camera, which is very exciting.
Speaker 5:  It's very good. Although I was always excited for a 5,000 milliamp hour camera.
Speaker 5:  Camera. It was gonna be, it was gonna be
Speaker 6:  A sick camera.
Speaker 5:  That
Speaker 6:  Camera will power your house somehow. We don't know yet. It also,
Speaker 6:  instead of saying it's gonna ship in September, it just says coming later
Speaker 6:  this year, even the coming soon is gone. Which is very funny.
Speaker 6:  So I like, the only thing I can think of is that they got
Speaker 6:  in some kind of legal hot water over the phrase made in the USA,
Speaker 6:  which is a thing that you have to follow certain rules to be able to say
Speaker 6:  about a device or any product. And
Speaker 6:  also that they went from having one
Speaker 6:  supplier to having another supplier. It's the only thing I can think of is
Speaker 6:  that whatever they bought on or thought they were gonna buy on Ali Express,
Speaker 6:  now they're buying something else with a half inch smaller screen. There's
Speaker 6:  just no reason that happens in a week other than that.
Speaker 5:  Especially at 4 99. Right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The render is still the same, the price is still the same. I'm still
Speaker 6:  convinced this phone does not exist and will never exist. But even the
Speaker 6:  thing that doesn't exist makes less sense every
Speaker 5:  Day.
Speaker 7:  The made in the US thing was just particularly egregious, right? Like i I
Speaker 7:  from the start, it was wildly obvious that that could not be true.
Speaker 7:  And I guess after enough people asked about it, they realized maybe we
Speaker 7:  shouldn't lie about this one. Which I guess I, I don't wanna say kudos on
Speaker 7:  that, but you know, good, good for stopping lying that that is
Speaker 7:  a positive.
Speaker 6:  It's not, not lying,
Speaker 5:  You know what I mean? The phone doesn't exist. I'll give them credit for
Speaker 5:  for not lying when they ship us a phone. I believe, Jake you
Speaker 5:  ordered one, right? The
Speaker 7:  Verge has ordered two, two of them. Two sh
Speaker 5:  We're a thousand dollars deeper than the Trump phones.
Speaker 7:  Well, yes. Well so Sarah Smithers are
Speaker 5:  Who are, it's take one day off the show, Jake's like blow a grand on Trump
Speaker 5:  phones. We
Speaker 7:  Listen, somebody needs to find out if these phones are real.
Speaker 7:  Sarah Smithers, our wonderful editorial operations director
Speaker 7:  has spent a week trying to order these things. It turns out
Speaker 7:  for the first week they did not have an option to order them if you lived
Speaker 7:  in Washington DC
Speaker 5:  Oh, good.
Speaker 7:  And so we had to keep emailing them saying, Hey, this is part of the
Speaker 7:  United States. Could you please accept our
Speaker 5:  Order? Because our corporate headquarters is in DC Yes,
Speaker 6:  I understand.
Speaker 7:  So we will find out for all of you if this phone exists,
Speaker 7:  if it is any good. And if they, as the website
Speaker 7:  promises randomly start billing you recurring charges at
Speaker 7:  some point.
Speaker 5:  So many, many people have asked us to review the phone
Speaker 5:  and I'm, I'm confident we will. I just, I wanna set some
Speaker 5:  expectations that it's not like the, a review
Speaker 5:  of a mid-range Android phone is often a banger. Do you know what I mean?
Speaker 5:  Like it's a mid-range Andrew. Yeah. You know, you already know what it is.
Speaker 5:  The thing that you want from us is to point out the obvious lies. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Which is like, you almost don't need the phone to do it, but
Speaker 5:  at best, like the best thing this can be is a
Speaker 5:  competently executed mid-range Android phone.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That's literally the, the 100th percentile outcome for
Speaker 6:  this thing. Yeah. Is a, it exists and B it's fine. That is the best
Speaker 6:  possible outcome for the Trump phone.
Speaker 5:  I suspect there will be a yawning chasm between the device
Speaker 5:  shipped to us the two devices apparently that will be shipped to us and that
Speaker 5:  outcome and that, you know, that's the point of a review. But I'm just trying
Speaker 5:  to I don't think you're gonna open it. So like light on fire, I think it's
Speaker 5:  gonna be a mid range Android phone with some shit bundled software.
Speaker 6:  All right. Neli Trump mobile project Gen five SISs.
Speaker 6:  You have to bet on one as a grand success in the
Speaker 6:  future.
Speaker 5:  Oh it's, it's Project Gen five sis. Wow. EAs easily big,
Speaker 5:  easily Project Gen five sis. And I'm only saying this
Speaker 5:  because it, to the extent that it exists,
Speaker 6:  You were about to say it exists and they were, there was about to be a party
Speaker 6:  in that office. Yes. You almost said it.
Speaker 5:  To just set this up for the audience again, because I'm often reminded that
Speaker 5:  I, we speak in code and inside jokes like a bunch of high school seniors.
Speaker 5:  Project Genis is the result of T-Mobile
Speaker 5:  being allowed to merge with Sprint in the first Trump administration. And
Speaker 5:  what they did was they told T-Mobile it had to divest a bunch of assets
Speaker 5:  in Spectrum to Dish Network, a satellite television
Speaker 5:  operator, which would then create a new from the ground up 5G network so
Speaker 5:  that we would've five national carriers and there would be competition and
Speaker 5:  look around, does it exist? And then they launched a network,
Speaker 5:  they called it Project on Fivey. They're now rolling it in a Boost mobile
Speaker 5:  whatever. Most of those phones still roam onto at t and T-Mobile 'cause the
Speaker 5:  network doesn't exist. But in some pockets of America the network apparently
Speaker 5:  exists. That's what it got for you. And so just because they built
Speaker 5:  some cell towers and put some radios on, some polls,
Speaker 5:  someone will try to turn that into money because they've spent the money.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's true. Here what they've done is they asked Chat GT to make a
Speaker 5:  midrange Android phone, the word Trump on it, and no one has to collect on
Speaker 5:  that investment. And so project Gen five says, just 'cause there's hardware
Speaker 5:  in the world, like a little bit has a, you know, on, on our
Speaker 5:  Go 90 scale where zero is alive and 90
Speaker 5:  is dead is Quibi. I I would put
Speaker 5:  trumpet 90
Speaker 5:  just lives at 90 and, and Gen five sis at like a 75.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  That seems fair.
Speaker 5:  I don't think I've ever applied the, the Go 90 scale gym streaming services
Speaker 5:  to to to telecom providers. But it works.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, there's like three of them that are at 10 and everybody else is hovering
Speaker 6:  in the mid eighties at all times. That's a lot. That's just what we do.
Speaker 5:  There's more phones. There's a new fairphone that's
Speaker 5:  modular. Is this, is this what this is? It's a modular phone. I love a modular
Speaker 5:  phone.
Speaker 6:  I find Fairphone totally fascinating. This company has just been like sort
Speaker 6:  of chugging along in the background doing great work on making like
Speaker 6:  upgradable repairable more well
Speaker 6:  made and thoughtfully designed smartphones than almost anybody.
Speaker 6:  And it's not like a huge hit. And their phones have been not like amazing
Speaker 6:  because they're trying to like do the right thing more than they're trying
Speaker 6:  to build great phones. And those two things are hard to do together. But
Speaker 6:  the zoo one's really interesting. It's, it's the Fairphone six. It is
Speaker 6:  smaller and lighter but has more battery. It's more powerful. They've just
Speaker 6:  like made a bunch of the trade-offs you want them to make for the first time.
Speaker 6:  But they're also doing the, the like modular accessories thing. Like, do
Speaker 6:  you guys remember the, the nothing phone that came out and it had the little
Speaker 6:  loop on the side that you could like stick a lanyard or like change the case
Speaker 6:  and screw that stuff off That's coming to the fairphone. They're starting
Speaker 6:  to do stuff like that. But the thing I think is really cool is they're shipping
Speaker 6:  this phone in basically two different ways.
Speaker 6:  One is with Android, like normal Android and
Speaker 6:  Fairphone has a pretty like refined take on Android, but they're also shipping
Speaker 6:  it with a button that essentially lets you switch to like a minimalist mode
Speaker 6:  of Android. Which is kind of like as we haven't learned a ton about it,
Speaker 6:  but it seems like basically a, a power do not disturb feature, which I think
Speaker 6:  is super clever.
Speaker 6:  And then the other one is it's shipping with a, a
Speaker 6:  de Googled version of Android, which is called EOS made by this company,
Speaker 6:  I believe it's called Morena. And essentially they've
Speaker 6:  spent several years now building out a version of Android
Speaker 6:  that is totally like bereft of Google services. Huh. And
Speaker 6:  that's one you like really have to make a moral choice.
Speaker 6:  It's like, it's like being a vegan, you know what I mean? It's like you have
Speaker 6:  to do it on purpose and live with the consequences, but you're doing it because
Speaker 6:  you believe it's the right thing to do for the world.
Speaker 7:  It's interesting, I I suspect there probably is a lot of overlap between
Speaker 7:  those two markets. Like there're gonna be a bunch
Speaker 6:  Of vegans who hate that. I just made that
Speaker 7:  Comparison. Oh, I was not, I didn't mean vegans and people who are against
Speaker 7:  Google. I I thought I meant people who want to repair their
Speaker 7:  phone endlessly and who want to get away from Google. Oh for sure. But it,
Speaker 7:  it is, I think the bummer about this, you know, I I think there's a, a
Speaker 7:  very exciting device, right? Like this is I think the best looking fair phone
Speaker 7:  yet it looks like a normal phone. It's like an upper mid range Android
Speaker 7:  device. It looks great. The colors are fun.
Speaker 7:  I like that it's opinionated with the, the, you know, the button that does
Speaker 7:  the, the minimal launcher. But if you wanna get it in the US
Speaker 7:  you have to get that D GoogleFi version. Oh,
Speaker 6:  That's the only one in the us Yes. Oh, that
Speaker 7:  Sucks. And that is a problem, right? Yeah. Because
Speaker 7:  choosing to go without Google Services means missing out on a
Speaker 7:  lot of the phone experience. Right. Just like everything's in the play store.
Speaker 7:  Just good, good luck. Right? Like most people that
Speaker 7:  I know use Gmail. Yeah. Where,
Speaker 5:  Where do you get apps for this thing? I'm, I'm like clicking on this website.
Speaker 5:  Where do you get apps for it if you don't have the Play Store
Speaker 7:  Side load? 'em, they
Speaker 6:  Have a proprietary app store and they have some stuff. But it is, I mean
Speaker 6:  it is like vanishingly small number of apps compared to the Play store.
Speaker 5:  Yes. They're side loading and there's, you know, Android is Android, there's
Speaker 5:  other app stores, but the play store and then play services provide
Speaker 5:  a whole lot of capabilities to Android apps.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Well, And I think increasingly so does Gemini.
Speaker 6:  And So I think we're, we're now hitting this place. Like there was also some
Speaker 6:  news this week about Gemini getting more and more
Speaker 6:  integrated with the system and starting to do some like cross app
Speaker 6:  stuff like we've been talking about with like, the future of Siri. And so
Speaker 6:  the, the non Google version of Android and the Google version of Android
Speaker 6:  are getting like much further apart over time and not
Speaker 6:  closer together. So I think the case here for something like Morena
Speaker 6:  is gonna get harder I think because it's like you, you're,
Speaker 6:  you're just gonna have to make a broader set of sacrifices. 'cause I think
Speaker 6:  like if I don't wanna have a Google account, it's not that hard
Speaker 6:  to get like a proton email account and use
Speaker 6:  DuckDuckGo and like you, you can relatively successfully replace most
Speaker 6:  Google services with something else without trying all that hard.
Speaker 6:  But if you believe in all this AI stuff and especially like the way it might
Speaker 6:  change the way that you use your devices, taking that out is gonna make all
Speaker 6:  kinds of other stuff just break. Yeah. It's like, it's like, oh, I don't
Speaker 6:  use HTTP on my web browser. It's like, well then you can't use the internet.
Speaker 6:  Like, and it, it does feel like a lot of the AI stuff is heading that way.
Speaker 5:  Oh, David, you explained this in your piece about Marina it, they just downloading
Speaker 5:  the apps through Google, they're just, they're just piping you to the play
Speaker 5:  store and then they have a clone of play services that runs. Yeah, I mean
Speaker 6:  I knew they had, they had their own clone of play services that doesn't feed
Speaker 6:  any stuff back to Google. I had forgotten that. They just take apps from
Speaker 6:  the play store.
Speaker 5:  Fair enough. Yeah. I mean you wrote this three years ago, so you're,
Speaker 5:  I'm you're forgiven for not remembering about the weird open
Speaker 5:  source Android clone.
Speaker 6:  I have thought this company is interesting for a long time.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I'm fascinated by this and I'm fasted by the, the button that turns
Speaker 5:  it into minimal mode on the phone. Like it's a switch. Love that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But yeah, I mean the, this whole the fact that you have to commit to an entirely
Speaker 5:  secondary operating system, that's a, that's
Speaker 5:  a rough, that's a rough ask.
Speaker 6:  Totally. But I think the, the, there's also like something
Speaker 6:  in this combination of like more repairable, you can swap
Speaker 6:  out some parts and this like tiny but
Speaker 6:  growing accessory ecosystem that like, there's something there
Speaker 6:  if you're a person who wants to sort of muck around with your phone from
Speaker 6:  time to time. That I just think is very cool. And to Jake's point, this is
Speaker 6:  the first one that is like on its own, a pretty compelling phone, which is
Speaker 6:  awesome.
Speaker 7:  This is the thing I, I feel like in the past the Fairphone have always looked
Speaker 7:  a little bit lesser than, And I think this one obviously we'll still have
Speaker 7:  to review it, see if it all holds up. This is the first one that you look
Speaker 7:  at And I, it it looks like a modern phone. It does not look like you're going
Speaker 7:  to dramatically miss out on things with the exception of those living in
Speaker 7:  the United States. So that's a bummer. But I'm really
Speaker 7:  excited to see how this pans out.
Speaker 5:  All right. There's one more phone that I'm desperate to talk about this week.
Speaker 5:  It's The Titan two, which the only way you can describe this is that it's
Speaker 5:  a, it's a Blackberry that runs Android. That's what it is. And it looks exactly
Speaker 5:  like an old Blackberry. It has a screen and it physical keyboard
Speaker 5:  And I don't know who this is for.
Speaker 6:  It has already raised a million dollars on Kickstarter.
Speaker 6:  Like, so this is the thing I I I keep and it's, it's done
Speaker 6:  big traffic on the site. Like people are into this thing. And I think my
Speaker 6:  overwhelming theory about devices like this for years has been
Speaker 6:  that people have real nostalgia for this stuff but
Speaker 6:  not actual desire for it. Right? It's the same thing as small iPhones,
Speaker 6:  right? Everyone on earth is like, oh God, remember when
Speaker 6:  like the iPhone five just like fit perfectly in your hand. Wasn't that so
Speaker 6:  great? And then you present them with a phone that small and they're like,
Speaker 6:  why is this so small? I don't want this. The battery sucks. What are we doing
Speaker 6:  here? I've always assumed that that is the same
Speaker 6:  thing with physical keyboards. People remember their Blackberry 'cause it
Speaker 6:  was their first smartphone and it was really exciting and it was like a,
Speaker 6:  a simpler time in the tech world and that was all very cool. But then things
Speaker 6:  like the, the Clicks keyboard come out and they're like sort of a compelling
Speaker 6:  novelty in their, their fun and exciting to have and play with. But it's
Speaker 6:  not a thing that is like a mainstream viable
Speaker 6:  product. But then this thing comes out and raises a million dollars on Kickstarter.
Speaker 6:  And so I'm like, there's clearly some people out there who want a giant
Speaker 6:  ass slab of an Android phone with a big keyboard on it. It looks
Speaker 7:  Delightful. There's two things about this that I think are special that we
Speaker 7:  need to talk about. One is that on the backside of it,
Speaker 7:  there's a second screen that shows notifications and a
Speaker 7:  clock. It, it sort of just looks like an ambient Apple watch. It's it's pretty
Speaker 7:  cool. It's interesting like normally, you know, you're like, I wanna have
Speaker 7:  my phone out but not have it out. So I like flip it over and this way you
Speaker 7:  flip it over but you still have your phone out. So it's actually, you're,
Speaker 7:  you're just not, not being rude. You're still being rude. Which I think is
Speaker 7:  delightful. And then they also advertise multiple times
Speaker 7:  that they have an infrared port and they do not explain what that means or
Speaker 7:  what you do with it.
Speaker 5:  You obviously you turn off motion smoothing at the bar, Jake.
Speaker 7:  I but but does it, does it, is it an outward infrared port or is it an
Speaker 7:  accepting infrared port? Can I control my phone with a remote?
Speaker 5:  Oh I see. Is it an iron blast or an IR window? Know
Speaker 6:  They do
Speaker 7:  Not clarify. They
Speaker 6:  Make phone calls with my TV remote is is what you're talking about. Because
Speaker 7:  That would be pretty innovative. I don't know if it would be useful but
Speaker 7:  it,
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna go ahead and say it's an IR blaster.
Speaker 7:  I mean that's why this thing has raised a million dollars. Yeah
Speaker 5:  People, people just want to go to the bar and like click around
Speaker 6:  Menus. This is officially the most 2013 phone we've seen since
Speaker 6:  2013. It's
Speaker 5:  The, the standard was called erda, IRDA and you could very,
Speaker 5:  very slowly beam contact information between phone like dumb phones
Speaker 5:  back in the day. It's a real thing.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It wasn't great and no one used it but it was, it was called erda and there
Speaker 5:  was a time in gadget blogging where like if a phone didn't have erda,
Speaker 5:  like the commenters would be like No Erda.
Speaker 6:  I'll say to this thing's credit. I think one very
Speaker 6:  compelling thing about it is that you can buy it right now on Kickstarter
Speaker 6:  for $269 And I think that for like a
Speaker 6:  a half novelty of a phone is a perfect price
Speaker 6:  and we're like starting,
Speaker 5:  Alright two. Two Trump phones or four Titans.
Speaker 6:  Oh four Titans. It's not close. Gimme The Titan and a fairphone over the
Speaker 6:  two Trump phones. I'm a happy guy. There's also
Speaker 7:  Actual motion footage of this phone existing
Speaker 7:  which cannot be said. There's not a single frame of the Trump phone existing.
Speaker 5:  Alright. Some more gadgets to round out our first segment, which is very
Speaker 5:  gadget heavy. I point out we're all over the place. Gadgets
Speaker 5:  Microsoft and Meta announced an Xbox VR headset that is
Speaker 5:  just a Quest three s that's green and comes with a controller.
Speaker 6:  One of my favorite things to do this week has been to troll
Speaker 6:  Reddit. Watching people be confused about what this thing is.
Speaker 6:  It's so funny. So two things are true, right? One,
Speaker 6:  this is the best looking quest there has ever been. The black and green color
Speaker 6:  like works for the quest in a way the like white beige thing kind of doesn't.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The combo of Xbox stuff and
Speaker 6:  Quest makes sense. Shipping it with a controller that's already paired makes
Speaker 6:  sense. Like this thing is a gaming machine, they're treating it like a gaming
Speaker 6:  machine. It's stream Xbox Games makes perfect sense. There are
Speaker 6:  so many people who just think this is an Xbox that will play Xbox games
Speaker 6:  and it turns out it doesn't. And we, this is
Speaker 6:  what we've talked about before. Like the list of Xboxes that don't play all
Speaker 6:  Xbox games is vast and this is one of them.
Speaker 6:  It will, it will stream some games. If you have
Speaker 6:  Xbox Game Pass Ultimate, which requires jumping through a series of hoops
Speaker 6:  I cannot even begin to describe to you And like
Speaker 6:  this thing is it both is and is not an Xbox in a way that is driving a lot
Speaker 6:  of people on the internet. Absolutely up the wall. Wait,
Speaker 5:  Everything at this point is and is not an Xbox. The state of being an Xbox
Speaker 5:  is probabilistic. This
Speaker 6:  Is what I mean. Yes. But this one's called Xbox.
Speaker 5:  Like every morning I wake up and think to myself, am I an Xbox? And I go
Speaker 5:  through the list of what games I support and yeah. And many days the answer
Speaker 5:  is yes. That's
Speaker 6:  It's beautiful for you. Is is your Samsung frame TV an Xbox?
Speaker 5:  It could be. 'cause you can run Game Pass on it, right? So wait, I have
Speaker 5:  not paid a lot of attention to Game Pass. So this is just a VR headset and
Speaker 5:  it's got the one app in it that runs in 2D. Right? So you're in the VR
Speaker 5:  environment and it puts up a big fake tv, A big virtual tv
Speaker 5:  and then it just runs Game Pass on it. That's right. It's not even running
Speaker 5:  VR games. No,
Speaker 6:  The Quest does that Anyway, this is just
Speaker 6:  Pure like a branding exercise. And again I think the branding exercise makes
Speaker 6:  a lot of sense but it is just, it is just a
Speaker 6:  branding exercise. This is, this is a like, I don't know,
Speaker 6:  imagine some celebrity picked a color scheme for a
Speaker 6:  quest and it did that. This is that it's just called an
Speaker 6:  Xbox. So people assume it's gonna be an Xbox.
Speaker 5:  Well it's an Xbox in the sense that Xbox Game Pass Ultimate is
Speaker 5:  Xbox.
Speaker 6:  If that's an Xbox, we're all Xboxes.
Speaker 5:  That's just what I'm saying. Every morning I wake you're Xbox. Yeah. Alright.
Speaker 5:  It's very confusing. I'm trying to figure out who is making money here.
Speaker 7:  Microsoft seems to have some very long-term plan here to
Speaker 7:  redefine what the Xbox is and they are really
Speaker 7:  overshooting for what they can actually deliver on today that that seems
Speaker 7:  to be like I, I do not see how Xbox is benefiting from this
Speaker 7:  right now when they're just confusing everybody.
Speaker 5:  So my understanding is that Xbox is, it came in second place the last two
Speaker 5:  generations, right? Yes. The PS four and the PS five blew the Xbox away and
Speaker 5:  then the switch and presumably the switch to is they're all gonna be great
Speaker 5:  and that's gonna be a total other thing over there. And I, it
Speaker 5:  feels like Microsoft is reacting to coming in second place as though they
Speaker 5:  have failed so completely they need to burn it all down. Right? And
Speaker 5:  they're like, we will reconceptualize the very concept of Xbox and turn it
Speaker 5:  into like a PC console gaming situation on handheld
Speaker 5:  cloud streaming service on, on VR headsets and then
Speaker 5:  the actual console is like of little value to them.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think that's right,
Speaker 5:  Right? That that's kind of what this all feels like. But I'm just saying
Speaker 5:  the Quest three s is not a huge hit for Meta. Right?
Speaker 5:  There's been reporting that they've kind of lost interest in Quest
Speaker 5:  'cause their glasses are the success which we'll talk about in a second.
Speaker 5:  The, the Ray bands and now the Oakley Smart Glasses feel like their future.
Speaker 5:  And so it's like, okay, a an an unsuccessful VR headset
Speaker 5:  is being paired with an unsuccessful gaming brand to
Speaker 5:  accomplish
Speaker 6:  What the thing about it is, I actually think in
Speaker 6:  a certain way calling this thing an Xbox makes it make more sense
Speaker 6:  because it is a gaming machine. Like everybody who works
Speaker 6:  on VR stuff will tell you this is not true. But VR is a gaming platform.
Speaker 6:  It just is. But
Speaker 5:  This isn't play VR games. This is, this is the same as one of those
Speaker 5:  X reel glasses that just picks, puts up a fake tv.
Speaker 6:  Yeah those, that's also an Xbox, apple Vision Pro also an Xbox. Do you know
Speaker 6:  what I mean? Like what isn't an Xbox help?
Speaker 6:  But I think like the, to the extent that this just screams, this is a large
Speaker 6:  screen on which to play games, I'm not bothered by it. Sure. But the thing
Speaker 6:  you're describing is why people are getting tripped up because it's like,
Speaker 6:  oh this should now play my Xbox games and it
Speaker 6:  isn't that simple. And so we're in this position of like
Speaker 6:  nobody, many more people know what to make of Xbox
Speaker 6:  than know what to make of Quest. So I can actually see why
Speaker 6:  bringing Quest and Xbox together makes sense for shipping
Speaker 6:  this headset. Except
Speaker 6:  it's, it's not fully an Xbox, I just, I get turned in circles.
Speaker 6:  But you know, ultimately this thing is like a limited edition and looks very
Speaker 6:  cool and not that many people get it. So it's like
Speaker 6:  whatever. But I do find it sort of fascinating that they're like leaning
Speaker 6:  into this thing is for games and Microsoft is like, games are for everything
Speaker 6:  and they're like, oh I see why you're friends. Like sure,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. Just on the one hand, you know, Microsoft spent last week or
Speaker 5:  I guess two weeks ago talking about the, you know, the wrong ally and being
Speaker 5:  like the future of Xbox is Windows games on the go. We also support
Speaker 5:  Steam and one turn later they're like, it's a limited cloud
Speaker 5:  gaming library on the quest it does
Speaker 5:  feel, it just feels like they, they've they've lost sight of what they want
Speaker 5:  Xbox to be. So it's everything and yeah, who knows.
Speaker 5:  Agreed. The Meta Smart glasses, they are a success
Speaker 5:  at least according to the metrics. Meta Keeps saying and they've expanded
Speaker 5:  them this week and now they've got Oakly smart glasses, same basic
Speaker 5:  concept as the Raybans. Only they look like Oakley's
Speaker 5:  and they shoot three K video slightly higher resolution video 'cause they're
Speaker 5:  slightly bigger. Is is basically my understanding of the product.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Pretty much the, the thing I thought was really interesting, Alex Heath
Speaker 6:  talked to one of the folks on the team building this stuff and they confirmed
Speaker 6:  what we have always suspected, which is that people use these glasses for
Speaker 6:  two things. One is audio and one is camera and they call them
Speaker 6:  AI glasses. Which is very funny because it's like, well we're gonna call
Speaker 6:  this thing a thing no one uses them for but
Speaker 6:  like this, this positioning makes sense. Doing it with
Speaker 6:  Oakley makes sense. I don't think these glasses are particularly good looking,
Speaker 6:  but I also can't pull off Oakley's in general. So I'm not like a great
Speaker 6:  person to judge this. When you
Speaker 5:  Went on the eighth grade trip to dc did everybody buy fake Oakleys?
Speaker 6:  Oh, a hundred percent. Yeah. I've owned so many fake Oakleys joke in my life.
Speaker 6:  We,
Speaker 5:  We called them,
Speaker 6:  What'd you call them? Oakleys. Oh we were, we were Oh very good. Yeah
Speaker 6:  it was, they were good. But yeah, I think like this, this thing Meta is doing
Speaker 6:  continues to make perfect sense to me. It's, it's still
Speaker 6:  not clear how you bridge the gap between this
Speaker 6:  and the Orion glasses that we talked about before because there like the
Speaker 6:  technical breakthroughs required to get from one to the other are vast and
Speaker 6:  unsolved.
Speaker 6:  But just this thing where like Meta has a hit at relative
Speaker 6:  scale doing this basic kind of stuff and they've just decided to lean into
Speaker 6:  this is the thing that everybody wants. We will figure out how to stack capabilities
Speaker 6:  on top of it over time feels like the right move to me
Speaker 7:  It also feels really clear that their partnership with Luxottica has just
Speaker 7:  continued to pay dividends here. Right? Like you need
Speaker 7:  glasses that are naturally chunky enough to fit this hardware.
Speaker 7:  Totally. And they have managed to find multiple styles here
Speaker 7:  that
Speaker 7:  adapt well to this additional hardware that are already
Speaker 7:  formats that people know and love. Right? These are very popular glasses,
Speaker 7:  they're very popular brand names. Expanding to Oakley was a really smart
Speaker 7:  next move after RayBan. And So I Right like this is
Speaker 7:  a, a challenge that every other company getting into the glass space is gonna
Speaker 7:  have. If you put out knockoff pair of Raybans or Oakleys, people will be
Speaker 7:  able to tell that they're a knockoff pair. Right. Meta's biggest
Speaker 7:  advantage here is it is just selling Oakley's with some headphones in them.
Speaker 7:  Right? That's not a bad product at a bare minimum, right? Nobody has to use
Speaker 7:  the ai
Speaker 5:  Well I think Meta is desperate for
Speaker 7:  A platform. Well they would like
Speaker 5:  That where their AI assistant is the first party
Speaker 5:  assistant not an app on the iPhone. And they've settled in these
Speaker 5:  glasses. I will say they, they transition lenses are available, but
Speaker 5:  all the cool photos are, they're reflective orange lenses and Meta has
Speaker 5:  continued attempts to make transitions. Very cool.
Speaker 5:  Continues to amuse. That's all I'm just saying. Especially 'cause if you're
Speaker 5:  wearing transition Oakleys, many decisions have been made along the way.
Speaker 6:  Vindication is coming for my dad who's been wearing transitions for like
Speaker 6:  a decade, the world is coming around to Joey.
Speaker 5:  I don know if you saw Joanna Stern's video with Craig Federighi and Craig
Speaker 5:  Jaws react, but Jaws was wearing transitions in the video
Speaker 5:  in about halfway through. They tinted 'cause they were in the sun. And I
Speaker 5:  was like, well this is, I mean it's fine. Like dude do you whatever you want
Speaker 5:  do, but the fact that they, you can't control them actually sometimes causes
Speaker 5:  problems.
Speaker 6:  Maybe it's a defense mechanism where he's like, these questions are too hard
Speaker 6:  and just,
Speaker 5:  Just black them out. Like I can't see you just like you
Speaker 5:  can't see Siri.
Speaker 5:  I don know I look the fact that it's camera and, and and headphones.
Speaker 5:  Exactly the same problem as Alexa had for years. Sure. It's timers and music
Speaker 5:  and it's great. I think people like having cameras on their face. I got a
Speaker 5:  TikTok ad today for like what can only be described as a necklace with a
Speaker 5:  mag safe mount. Huh? Because people mount their phones here when they like
Speaker 5:  drive their cars and do stuff and they want the like first person view.
Speaker 5:  I get it. I get why people want cameras in their glasses. I
Speaker 5:  don't think Meta has actually trans, I would love to know the rate at which
Speaker 5:  people who buy these glasses also use the AI stuff
Speaker 5:  has is Meta convincing 2% of those people to be like, I love the
Speaker 5:  Meta AI assistant. How many people are looking at stuff and Andre like,
Speaker 5:  what is that? 'cause that's the use case they keep coming up with. Right?
Speaker 5:  Again, I I think the real thing people want to build is Orion the
Speaker 5:  augmented reality glasses. And even Orion doesn't actually do augmented reality
Speaker 5:  yet. Like we're, we're, we're, we're long, long away. But if you
Speaker 5:  love in Oakley and you like glasses, I joined a Stern speaking of Joanna
Speaker 5:  loves her, met Ray Bands, loves him. Can't get enough of them.
Speaker 6:  I wear mine all the time just as sunglasses that happen to do other things.
Speaker 6:  Like that's that's great.
Speaker 5:  Do you have the transition lenses?
Speaker 6:  No. Mine are just sunglasses. So I just get to be the cool guy who like wears
Speaker 6:  sunglasses inside the coffee shop for a while.
Speaker 5:  Does the Meta app support multiple glasses?
Speaker 6:  The last time I tried I could only, I could only be paired to one at a time.
Speaker 5:  I mean these are just like, right, these are, these are problems with the
Speaker 5:  form factor that you're gonna have to overcome. You nobody wears the same
Speaker 5:  pair of glasses all the time, right? Like even people who wear glasses,
Speaker 5:  like prescription glasses. I have two pairs of glasses because when you go
Speaker 5:  to the store with my glasses, they're always like, do you want two pairs
Speaker 5:  of glasses?
Speaker 5:  And then people with sunglasses have lots of different kinds of sunglasses.
Speaker 5:  Like being locked into one pair of one style sunglasses forever is not great.
Speaker 5:  And now they have multiple sauces. I don dunno, I'm just saying the, on
Speaker 5:  the chart of wearable bullshit, you still have to put the thing on your face
Speaker 5:  man. It's the utility has to be much higher than it's right now. But you
Speaker 5:  love them,
Speaker 6:  They're great and they're like, they've solved the face problem because they
Speaker 6:  just look like sunglasses. Like that's the thing that's, that's to, to Jake's
Speaker 6:  point, like the, the hardest thing about this is just
Speaker 6:  provided to Meta by another company that is fabulously good at making glasses.
Speaker 6:  People like and rather than do what
Speaker 6:  Meta tried to do and what Apple is trying to do and what traditionally
Speaker 6:  tech companies have always done, which is like build the hardest, most
Speaker 6:  expensive thing and then try to like trickle the tech down to cheaper
Speaker 6:  prices. Meta was just like, we're gonna do the least and then
Speaker 6:  try to build up from there. And I actually think in this particular case
Speaker 6:  in part because of, you know, the, the problems that come with Eli's chart
Speaker 6:  of wearable bullshit, that's the right move. Like make a thing
Speaker 6:  people like and then figure out how to get it to do more stuff strikes
Speaker 6:  me as way more compelling. Yeah. Than I'm going to build a helmet for your
Speaker 6:  face and then figure out how to make you like wearing it.
Speaker 5:  The Apple Vision Pro everybody. Yeah. Alright, we gotta take a break. We'll
Speaker 5:  be back. Speaking of Meta, we gotta talk about their big AI win Philanthropics
Speaker 5:  big AI win but they're also losses. We'll, we'll be right back. We'll explain.
Speaker 5:  All right, we're back. Addie Robertson's here. Hey Addie. Hey, I'm excited.
Speaker 5:  Usually when you And I talk something very dark has happened
Speaker 5:  like a lot of times you're under coder and we're like, well Addie's here.
Speaker 5:  And you, we both had the same reaction. I'm excited to talk to you about
Speaker 5:  AI and copyright 'cause this is just chaos. Like it is delightful
Speaker 5:  chaos in our nation's courts as the AI copyright cases begin to
Speaker 5:  wind their way to some decisions.
Speaker 11:  Oh yeah, these are fun.
Speaker 6:  Can I back us up here a little bit and just like build from the ground up
Speaker 6:  a little bit because yeah, I confess I have had trouble keeping
Speaker 6:  these two cases this week separate in my head and then also
Speaker 6:  trying to figure out what they have to do with each other because it seems
Speaker 6:  to be a lot. So Addie, can you just like walk us through these
Speaker 6:  trials a little bit? First, let's do anthropic first. 'cause that that decision
Speaker 6:  hit first this week. Just remind us quickly like what that case
Speaker 6:  was about and what was decided this week. This
Speaker 5:  Is David saying Neli can't immediately get in his feelings. That's just what
Speaker 5:  happened. Yeah, NELI
Speaker 6:  Neli was so fast to like, let's talk about the the whatever the
Speaker 6:  fourth factor of copyright law and I'm like, can I remember what books are
Speaker 6:  first?
Speaker 11:  Yeah. So there are two groups of authors here and both of them found out
Speaker 11:  their work is almost certainly ingested into the training data set of
Speaker 11:  a chatbot company. In one case, Meta in one case, anthropic and they both
Speaker 11:  sued. And there are kind of two arguments. One argument is these things
Speaker 11:  were pirated in the first place and then in some ways the bigger
Speaker 11:  argument is well even if you get these things
Speaker 11:  legally, you are putting these into a training set that is then using
Speaker 11:  them to power a very lucrative product. And that's unauthorized,
Speaker 11:  that's copyright infringement. You need to get permission from us and Payos.
Speaker 6:  Okay, so this became Neli a fair use
Speaker 6:  thing. Yep. Kind of all the way down, right?
Speaker 5:  It's very important to separate what specifically is fair use
Speaker 5:  and the courts here don't agree there.
Speaker 5:  There's a lot going on in these, but it's important to just think
Speaker 5:  about AI from the technical perspective. There's training the model
Speaker 5:  and then there's inference where you get outputs from the model. And in these
Speaker 5:  cases it's all about training. The model is
Speaker 5:  in the anthropic case, literally buying a bunch of used books,
Speaker 5:  ripping off the covers, scanning them into a database and then using
Speaker 5:  that database to train a model. Is all of that fair use?
Speaker 5:  Not, if you ask the model to produce some copyrighted
Speaker 5:  book, is that copyright infringement? Right. And that's a big distinction.
Speaker 5:  And the reason people hate lawyers just 'cause lawyers are constantly making
Speaker 5:  extremely pedantic distinctions between things. But
Speaker 5:  in these cases those distinctions are wildly important because the judges
Speaker 5:  react to those distinctions between training and inference between inputs
Speaker 5:  and outputs. Very, very different. So
Speaker 6:  Both of these cases work fundamentally about training, right?
Speaker 11:  Both of these cases are sort of fundamentally about training with a
Speaker 11:  side which is actually also very important of you
Speaker 11:  pirated these books in the first place. Oh, it's kind of the difference
Speaker 11:  between, again, in both cases at first they were
Speaker 11:  like alright, we're going to download all these books and we're gonna train
Speaker 11:  on them. And then Meta kind of kept it there and anthropic went,
Speaker 11:  wait, we need to fix this. We're not comfortable with this. So then as Neela
Speaker 11:  mentioned, they got a bunch of books and they destroyed
Speaker 11:  the books after scanning them. So then there was a copy in the clout
Speaker 11:  and this turned out to be a really hugely important
Speaker 11:  distinction for reasons besides the training.
Speaker 6:  If I told you to just go buy a million books, would you know how to do it?
Speaker 6:  I've been thinking about this all
Speaker 5:  Week. Anthropic hired one of the people who ran Google books. Like they found
Speaker 5:  the one person who knew how to do it. So the philanthropic case is really
Speaker 5:  interesting. For that reason they started by saying we're just going to
Speaker 5:  steal stuff. And they pirated books and they referred to the problem they
Speaker 5:  had as like legal business slog. That's in the opinion.
Speaker 5:  And the legal business slog is like, should we pay money and acquire things
Speaker 5:  legally? And they're like, no, we'll just steal it. And then they came back
Speaker 5:  around and we're like, we're gonna scan a bunch of books. And the judge in
Speaker 5:  that case adding my read was that he cared a lot about
Speaker 5:  acquisition.
Speaker 11:  He was so mad.
Speaker 5:  Well he's very focused on did you acquire these books legally or not? He
Speaker 5:  makes a distinction between the legally acquired books and the the
Speaker 5:  pirated books. And then he spends a lot of time being like, okay, once you
Speaker 5:  have the stuff, what can you do with it that's fair or not?
Speaker 5:  And the first thing, and this is really just again, pedantic steps
Speaker 5:  down the line. The first thing that did was they made a
Speaker 5:  big database of books
Speaker 6:  In.
Speaker 5:  And that is, you don't think about that in the, in the context of
Speaker 5:  you're training a model, but the judge spends a lot of time being like,
Speaker 5:  okay, the first thing you did was make a database of books and then you use
Speaker 5:  that database, you can use that database to do all kinds of stuff. You can
Speaker 5:  just search the database to see what books you have. And he,
Speaker 5:  you know, there's a lot of like consumer rights history
Speaker 5:  here, a lot of Google history here ripping the covers off of books
Speaker 5:  and scanning 'em into a big database. If if you wanted
Speaker 5:  to do that to all the books you owned, you would be like, I can do that.
Speaker 5:  Right? Like if the judge here had found that buying a million books
Speaker 5:  ripping the covers off and scanning 'em into a database was illegal, like
Speaker 5:  a lot of things would break. I think like
Speaker 5:  I I, there's some part of this where copyright has such
Speaker 5:  a maximalist control over what you can do with the things you can buy
Speaker 5:  that the only answer you can get to is you're allowed to buy a million books,
Speaker 5:  strip the covers off of them and scan the in new database as long as you
Speaker 5:  don't let other people access the database. Yeah,
Speaker 11:  It's pretty notable here that they went from, okay, yeah, obviously it's
Speaker 11:  illegal to acquire these digital books but there are many legal ways
Speaker 11:  to acquire digital books and it is notable they didn't do that because you
Speaker 11:  have the most maximalist freedom as a consumer with a
Speaker 11:  physical copy.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it gets it. Like you, if you wanted to buy a bunch of Kindle books
Speaker 5:  like they come with DRM, they come with license restrictions. You can, as
Speaker 5:  I was saying, you can buy a bunch of eBooks without that but you still end
Speaker 5:  up with like terms of service agreements. But you just go buy a book, you
Speaker 5:  can kind of do a physical booking, gotta do whatever you want. So the judge
Speaker 5:  says, okay, you made this database that was fair use
Speaker 5:  ripping the covers off the physical books and scanning the database. That's
Speaker 5:  fair use. You're allowed to do that.
Speaker 5:  Stealing books and making a database. That's not fair use
Speaker 5:  where stop there the end, you're in trouble for that.
Speaker 6:  Is that even a fair use thing or is it the stealing the books?
Speaker 5:  Well he's made the distinction between is it fair use to buy a bunch
Speaker 5:  of physical books, rip the covers off and scan them? Okay, that's fair use.
Speaker 5:  Is it fair use to steal a bunch of books? No,
Speaker 11:  There's sort of a bunch of separate charges here. There are the charges
Speaker 11:  of, all right, is it copyright infringement to do this or is it also separately
Speaker 11:  copyright infringement to pirate all these books,
Speaker 5:  Right? So and then philanthropic tried to fix it by
Speaker 5:  saying the database is not important, training the model's important.
Speaker 5:  And the judge said, okay, training the model from your legal database. That's
Speaker 5:  fair use, that's very transformative. It especially because
Speaker 5:  the authors one conceded that trading the model was just like reading
Speaker 5:  a book, which is a big thing to concede, right?
Speaker 6:  Which has been an argument of the AI industry for years, right? That it's
Speaker 6:  like, it's the equivalent of reading a webpage and talking about it.
Speaker 5:  And this is gonna come up over and over again. And I think this is why Addie
Speaker 5:  And I both think these are fun. The the lawyers blew it for the authors like
Speaker 5:  left and right and the judges are kind of like, you know, you guys are blowing
Speaker 5:  it like try again but don't blow it. So the lawyers conceded
Speaker 5:  that it was just like reading a book and then they did not argue the
Speaker 5:  outputs of the model would affect the market for their work,
Speaker 5:  right? So they stopped, and this is why it made the big distinction between
Speaker 5:  inputs, snap outputs, they stopped at training, they did not get to,
Speaker 5:  if you ask anthropic, if you ask Claude to make our book, it'll just make
Speaker 5:  our book. Or if you ask Claude to summarize our book, it'll just like spit
Speaker 5:  out the answer to our book and that will ruin the market for a book. They
Speaker 5:  just didn't go there.
Speaker 6:  And the judge is like, like this is where you need to explain the different
Speaker 6:  tenets of of copyright and fair use stuff. Okay,
Speaker 5:  So David, the four actors of fair use, here we are, we it, we got here. So
Speaker 5:  inevitably you've
Speaker 6:  Told me this so many times and it just, it just goes fully. My eyes glaze
Speaker 6:  over every time you say this to me. So I'm gonna try and listen this time
Speaker 5:  It's 17 United States code section 1 0 7 4 factors of
Speaker 5:  phrase. So this is when when someone accuses you of
Speaker 5:  stealing their work, you say no, no it's fair use. And so it's what's called
Speaker 5:  an affirmative defense. You say, yep, I did, I did sample your song.
Speaker 5:  This is fair use. I, I'm I'm, yep, you're
Speaker 5:  right. I made a copy but it's fair use. And then the judges are supposed
Speaker 5:  to evaluate this on a case by case basis. They have four factors, the purpose
Speaker 5:  and character of the use, the nature of the copyrighted work, the amount
Speaker 5:  and substantiality of the portion used and the effect on the use of the market
Speaker 5:  and how important each of these factors are just
Speaker 5:  goes up and down over the years. The Supreme Court issues fair
Speaker 5:  use copyright decisions, you get law review articles being like the third
Speaker 5:  factor is no longer in vogue. Like it's, everyone's always arguing this,
Speaker 5:  But here what everyone should be arguing about is the
Speaker 5:  fourth factor, the effect of the use on the market.
Speaker 5:  If you train a chatbot on all the books in the world and then you can just
Speaker 5:  ask the chat bott about those books and it will tell you the answer. The
Speaker 5:  market for those books will inevitably dry up.
Speaker 6:  And this, if I'm remembering correctly, is like the New York Times whole
Speaker 6:  argument in its case against open ai, right? That if you can get open AI
Speaker 6:  to regurgitate New York Times articles, you can, why would anyone
Speaker 6:  go to the New York Times?
Speaker 11:  I mean I would be careful with that because in that case it is specifically
Speaker 11:  output. They are saying that you could get them to regurgitate exact text
Speaker 11:  and here it's kind of more a, you can generate a bunch of stuff that imitates
Speaker 11:  us and that infringes on our ability to sell
Speaker 11:  things or also that it can summarize and it can give answers and that can
Speaker 11:  even if it's not really direct clear your copying our stuff
Speaker 11:  that's still diminishing the market.
Speaker 5:  And then in the anthropic case, the authors didn't allege the
Speaker 5:  outputs,
Speaker 6:  Right? They just didn't argue about it at all. They
Speaker 5:  Were totally focused on training and they didn't get to outputs. And the
Speaker 5:  judges even sort of saying throughout the opinion, you didn't talk about
Speaker 5:  the outputs. So your argument is merely training the
Speaker 5:  model will have some effect on the market for your work.
Speaker 5:  But like what is it? You didn't argue it's not here.
Speaker 5:  Like we don't have a record for it so I'm just not gonna talk about it. So
Speaker 5:  we're totally focused on training and not on inference, right? We're totally
Speaker 5:  focused on the inputs to train the model and not on the outputs of the model
Speaker 5:  itself. And so the authors lose, he says training
Speaker 5:  is fair use. This is totally transformative. You can take, you can legally
Speaker 5:  acquire books, you can put them into a database, you can use that database
Speaker 5:  to train a model. Making the database is fair use, making the
Speaker 5:  model from what's in the database is fair use and then stop,
Speaker 5:  right? And like there's a big yawning gap there of well now you have a model
Speaker 5:  what's going, what's, what do you think is gonna happen? And the answer is
Speaker 5:  like, oh, you're gonna make a bunch of stuff that competes with the author's
Speaker 5:  original works. And so that's a real puzzle. Like I, who
Speaker 5:  knows what happens next. And he even leaves it open like
Speaker 5:  if you wanna ledge the next thing, you can ledge the next thing. And then
Speaker 5:  on top of it he says, you what you are not allowed to do is
Speaker 5:  pirate a bunch of books and make a database he doesn't even get to.
Speaker 5:  And then you can train the model he just says, doing that first
Speaker 5:  step where you stole a bunch of books and put them in a database, that's
Speaker 5:  not fair use. You can't do that. And that is a nightmare. Like
Speaker 5:  you might read this as training the model as fair use for your legally acquired
Speaker 5:  physical books that you've ripped the covers off and scanning your database.
Speaker 5:  What it does not say is it's fair game for anything, right? And so if you,
Speaker 5:  for example, have opened YouTube
Speaker 5:  and downloaded a bunch of YouTube videos, I'm looking at you open ai,
Speaker 5:  well you violated YouTube's terms of service, the copyright and all those
Speaker 5:  videos is owned by the YouTubers. You have a, you
Speaker 5:  have a database of content that you're training SOA on that
Speaker 5:  you don't have the rights to. And so this anthropic decision has
Speaker 5:  opened the door to being like, we're not even gonna get to training as fair
Speaker 5:  use, we're gonna get to your illegal database of YouTube videos
Speaker 5:  and you can't, you're not allowed to clean up that problem by saying training
Speaker 5:  is fair use. So this first decision, very complicated,
Speaker 5:  like very technical, very readable. We've profiled judge sup before Sarah
Speaker 5:  has profiled him. He writes code, he's, he's in the weeds of the the,
Speaker 5:  the technical details here. But what you have is training
Speaker 5:  is fair use if you have a legally acquired set of content to train from.
Speaker 11:  There's also kind of a backwards looking and a forward-looking issue here.
Speaker 11:  Which is say in the future, if you're kind of just starting from scratch,
Speaker 11:  then the upshot of this is well okay you gotta buy a million books
Speaker 11:  that costs a lot. It's a finite number and
Speaker 11:  backwards looking. If you've already done all this stuff, the potential
Speaker 11:  damages for each work are just like ruinous if you add them up
Speaker 11:  to a large enough number. And so anybody who's starting from scratch
Speaker 11:  with a model that is starting acquiring all this stuff legally, like that's
Speaker 11:  one economic model. Any of the big players, that's a whole different one.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. 'cause they've already done all this.
Speaker 5:  And again, open ai, open AI has a lot of money, but every
Speaker 5:  YouTuber in the world can read this decision and say, well you, you stole
Speaker 5:  our videos. And it wasn't, you can't buy physical YouTube
Speaker 5:  videos and rip the covers off of them. And in the database you access 'em
Speaker 5:  on YouTube, which has terms of service that says you cannot do this.
Speaker 5:  So this is a, this is already like puzzle one, this decision.
Speaker 5:  You read it and you're like, okay, there's a way forward if you pay a bunch
Speaker 5:  of authors and maybe it doesn't even work, right? Used books don't pay the
Speaker 5:  authors, but there's, there's parts of copyright law that say you're allowed
Speaker 5:  to buy used books and do whatever you want with them. And this ruling reaffirms
Speaker 5:  that. It does not say you can just pirate a bunch of stuff and train it and
Speaker 5:  call that fair use. Okay, so, okay, so here's a bunch of liability for the
Speaker 5:  industry. Then literally the next day a decision
Speaker 5:  in the Meta case comes down, which Addie I'm reading
Speaker 5:  is basically being like, no, actually Judge Alsup got this wrong. Like this
Speaker 5:  is all theft left and right.
Speaker 11:  It's basically Judge Allsup got all the fundamentals of this right? But
Speaker 11:  he weighted the transformative factor, overarching factor and the fourth
Speaker 11:  economic market value factor totally wrong. And that makes him
Speaker 11:  completely wrong on all of it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Go through this case. So this case is slightly different but it's a
Speaker 5:  bunch of authors suing Meta and if I'm correct,
Speaker 5:  Meta got caught using Torrented books like Straightforwardly. They just torned
Speaker 5:  the books
Speaker 11:  From Library Genesis I believe. Yeah. That collection of
Speaker 11:  books that was just this very large corpus of pirated books. They
Speaker 11:  torrented them. There's debate about whether that included them
Speaker 11:  uploading things, which one typically does when you torrent things.
Speaker 5:  The classic seaters versus Leers debate hits their nation's copyright law.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. They have to define seating and leaching in there. There's
Speaker 11:  a whole section about that. But they're specifically not dealing with the
Speaker 11:  copyright. Like was this direct copyright infringement
Speaker 11:  right now? Except to say, yeah look, it basically was.
Speaker 11:  So there's that. And then After that these authors
Speaker 11:  sued in a pretty similar way except that they
Speaker 11:  also specifically said the issue here is
Speaker 11:  partly that it is recreating our works. So they did focus on output
Speaker 11:  and then also that there's this market potentially for us
Speaker 11:  licensing our work to you and that that's a market that you're
Speaker 11:  taking from us. The judge called both of these clear
Speaker 11:  losers. He basically thinks everyone here is wrong. So
Speaker 11:  the Meta won the case, Meta won the case just handily. And it's
Speaker 11:  because the judge says, look, those are the only things you focused on.
Speaker 11:  And both of those are bad arguments, partly because they couldn't get
Speaker 11:  llama to actually spit out more than 50 words of the direct text.
Speaker 11:  So they were trying to say, look, you're verbatim
Speaker 11:  producing stuff and it just didn't work out. And then the second
Speaker 11:  one, because you just can't necessarily say,
Speaker 11:  yeah, if I were allowed to license this, I would make a lot of money. That
Speaker 11:  doesn't necessarily mean you should be able to exploit
Speaker 11:  that.
Speaker 11:  And so then after saying, look, concluding just
Speaker 11:  this argument is terrible, these lawyers are bad, please don't do this.
Speaker 11:  They said there's this other argument that would've been way
Speaker 11:  stronger. And it's that the fundamental use of these things
Speaker 11:  is to flood the market in a way that destroys the ability of
Speaker 11:  authors to make a living and completely diminishes the thing that copyright
Speaker 11:  is meant to do. Which is encourage human creativity.
Speaker 11:  Basically ais are creativity killing machines and
Speaker 11:  that should mean that it outweighs any potential transformative value.
Speaker 5:  So I wanna just quote from the opinion because it is brutal.
Speaker 5:  This ruling does not stand for the proposition that meta's use of copy
Speaker 5:  materials to train its language models is lawful. It stands only for the
Speaker 5:  proposition that these plaintiffs made the wrong arguments and
Speaker 5:  failed to develop a record in support of the right one.
Speaker 5:  He's just saying, you screwed this up. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  You did it wrong,
Speaker 5:  You did it wrong.
Speaker 11:  And then mentions, by the way, these guys only, they only represent 13 artists.
Speaker 11:  13 authors. So you know, there are a lot of other authors and maybe Meta
Speaker 11:  scan them. It probably did. Just saying that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. Wait, okay, so let, let's talk about this here. 'cause the, the
Speaker 6:  reaction to this this week has been fascinating because I think it's been
Speaker 6:  sort of a Rorschach test depending on how
Speaker 6:  who you are promoting here. All of the AI folks are like, this is
Speaker 6:  a landmark victory for ai. This puts us on the path
Speaker 6:  to do all the stuff that we needed to do. But then it also sounds like
Speaker 6:  there's a, there's an easy read of this that this is like a small victory
Speaker 6:  for these companies who won this case on a technicality
Speaker 6:  but have just had the door thrown wide open for everyone else on earth to
Speaker 6:  sue them better and win. Yeah. Which of those things is it?
Speaker 6:  Or is it both of those things?
Speaker 5:  It's the second one. Okay. It's, it's, so by far the second one, I think
Speaker 5:  you know, Addie, and when Sarah's on And I, whenever we're talking about
Speaker 5:  the legal system on the show, we are constantly reminding people
Speaker 5:  that the courts are not computers, they're not deterministic systems
Speaker 5:  that you cannot predict what will happen, right? And So I, I think the
Speaker 5:  AI companies are like, this is fair use and then they got an outcome that
Speaker 5:  kind of looks like this is fair use. And they're like, see, we predicted
Speaker 5:  this correctly. We were right all along. And what you actually have is the
Speaker 5:  court saying, these lawyers sucked. And if you had better lawyers and
Speaker 5:  you argued these things differently, we would have reached different outcomes.
Speaker 5:  But we can't reach those outcomes in the absence of your better lawyers.
Speaker 5:  And that is a maddening to people. I know it's bating to people because I
Speaker 5:  have the blue sky app on my phone And I open it from time to time and it's
Speaker 5:  just people being mad that these lawyers blew it and it, they blew
Speaker 5:  it. And the judge is saying flatly, they blew it. I don't know
Speaker 5:  why in the anthropic case, the lawyers happily conceded that
Speaker 5:  training an AM model is like letting school children read books to learn
Speaker 5:  things. I wouldn't have conceded that. I do know that it
Speaker 5:  costs a lot of money to build an expert record about how
Speaker 5:  AI systems versus work versus the brains of six year olds or whatever.
Speaker 5:  And they may not have had that money, but you can't know. And that's why
Speaker 5:  it's not deterministic. Like a lot of decisions got made along the way
Speaker 5:  and then we have these rulings. But there are more cases to come
Speaker 5:  as Addie's saying that the court and the Meta case is basically inviting
Speaker 5:  other authors to try to make the better argument that they have laid out.
Speaker 5:  You have the New York Times, which is over a million dollars deep into its
Speaker 5:  open AI litigation that's watching these outcomes and will change its
Speaker 5:  arguments. Then you have Disney, which is a very late entrant into all these
Speaker 5:  copyright lawsuits. They're partnered up with Universal and together they're
Speaker 5:  suing Midjourney about outputs.
Speaker 5:  They, they like they're, they're watching these cases develop, they're watching
Speaker 5:  these arguments and they're like, oh, we need to focus on outputs. By the
Speaker 5:  way, I need to disclose that Universals home by Comcast. NBC Universal is
Speaker 5:  a part of Comcast is an investor in our parent company. Our parent company
Speaker 5:  has a deal with OpenAI. One of the reasons these companies have deals with
Speaker 5:  OpenAI is because they wanna set markets for licensing, they wanna set rates.
Speaker 5:  So these lawsuits can proceed whatever way they're gonna proceed.
Speaker 5:  You can see it's not settled. These are just the first little
Speaker 5:  skirmishes. And a lot of times what's happening is that
Speaker 5:  the first plaintiffs are authors are
Speaker 5:  creatives who don't have the money for the most lawyering who need to get
Speaker 5:  to outcomes quickly. And they're getting outgunned by the lawyers
Speaker 5:  for the huge technology firms. That's not always gonna be the case.
Speaker 11:  Record labels are also in on this, oh, the record labels have sued
Speaker 11:  Suno and, and uio,
Speaker 5:  Although they're starting to settle some of those on the side.
Speaker 5:  I'm just saying like the legal system is not istic, it is also reactive to
Speaker 5:  what happens before. Like necessarily it's precedential, it's reactive to
Speaker 5:  these cases. And the arguments in the future cases will shift around these
Speaker 5:  decisions to attack their weak points. Or in the case of the Meta
Speaker 5:  decision to take the open invitation to get it right.
Speaker 11:  I would also say we're at the point where basically this is kind of every
Speaker 11:  judge for themselves at the point where you appeal and then you start getting
Speaker 11:  appeals court cases and then circuit courts start saying, alright,
Speaker 11:  here's roughly how we think about it. Then judges have
Speaker 11:  kind of precedents that they're trying to draw from. And of course if the
Speaker 11:  Supreme Court says something, then that's something that you have to weight
Speaker 11:  pretty heavily. But at this point they can kind of just stay stuff to each
Speaker 11:  other. So it's also not like this one ruling that say
Speaker 11:  Allsup hands down is a law that everyone else has to follow.
Speaker 11:  Somebody else can come up with their own theory of fair use, which is pretty
Speaker 11:  much exactly what we've seen.
Speaker 5:  Right. And fair use in the law is supposed to be case
Speaker 5:  by case, right? So one fairies decision is not supposed
Speaker 5:  to affect all the other ones in reality because of the money and time
Speaker 5:  and risk involved, they, they get treated as precedent.
Speaker 5:  But here everybody has incentives to reopen those doors again and again and
Speaker 5:  again. So I I I I don dunno. Addie what do you think? I think this
Speaker 5:  is a bunch of small narrow rulings that open the door to much more caste
Speaker 5:  to come. Not definitive reckoning, but I maybe you feel differently.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 11:  Don't know in part because I feel like sometimes court cases
Speaker 11:  are a little bit just they're reflective of a larger vibe
Speaker 11:  and culture that it, like I think we've seen with section two 30 cases
Speaker 11:  that it's not necessarily that judges all impact each other, but
Speaker 11:  that if you start seeing a bunch of rulings around one kind of particular
Speaker 11:  interpretation of the law or one kind of like weighting of something,
Speaker 11:  that sometimes means you are seeing a pattern that's gonna continue. It's,
Speaker 11:  it's correlation, not causation. And also, I don't know,
Speaker 11:  I'm actually wondering what would happen if all Hepa case that was more
Speaker 11:  specifically output based. Because on one hand, yeah, it opens up a
Speaker 11:  bunch of whole new cans of worms on the other, some of his comments
Speaker 11:  did seem like they kind of indicated it doesn't matter if somebody's say
Speaker 11:  writing a book with an AI system that
Speaker 11:  competes with yours, that doesn't inherently mean that
Speaker 11:  they're, that is unfair.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. He's got a line that's like, copyright law does not protect you from
Speaker 5:  competition. It's supposed to inspire more people to create. And there's
Speaker 5:  a, you know, there's a very deep meaningful tension in there
Speaker 5:  because the, the mechanism by which copyright law is supposed to inspire
Speaker 5:  you to create is by letting you sell your stuff,
Speaker 5:  right? You create stuff, you get rights to it, other people can't take it
Speaker 5:  for free. They have to pay you money. But at the same time, if
Speaker 5:  they take your stuff for free and then make stuff that competes with you,
Speaker 5:  like that's competition. Like there's something really weird in there. But
Speaker 11:  There are also a lot of pre AI cases where I think people would be a lot
Speaker 11:  more sympathetic to the idea that you should be able to say copy
Speaker 11:  things without having to get permission. Like the
Speaker 11:  fact that you can report on facts that somebody says in a news
Speaker 11:  story without getting permission from the original writer of that story.
Speaker 11:  Like the fact that you can do a pastiche of
Speaker 11:  an artist and that artist's style is not necessarily a thing that's automatically
Speaker 11:  copyrightable. I think these are all things that when humans are involved,
Speaker 11:  we actually are pretty okay with the idea that creativity is cumulative
Speaker 11:  and people build on each other. I think the thing that's really interesting
Speaker 11:  about the Meta ruling is that it specifically makes the argument that scale
Speaker 11:  is different, which is something I see a bunch of people make
Speaker 11:  pragmatically, but I don't think I've seen in the court system as much that
Speaker 11:  the argument isn't actually, well these things are fundamentally
Speaker 11:  different and not competitive because the writing is somehow different or
Speaker 11:  because something's not necessarily learning. It's because
Speaker 11:  you can create all of them so quickly that they will flood the market and
Speaker 11:  they will destroy the market for books specifically thinks romance
Speaker 11:  novels and spy thrillers, romance novels come up a bunch in this,
Speaker 5:  The whole, the entire like romance novel like Fanfic community right now
Speaker 5:  is like deeply insulted, right? They're at war seriously with AI
Speaker 11:  Every day serious. Yeah. Romance authors are starting to use AI and romance
Speaker 11:  readers are just furious about it.
Speaker 5:  Well, it's funny 'cause you, you, we've talked about this many times. So
Speaker 5:  if you go on those forums, like now people just say tropes all in a row and
Speaker 5:  request stories and like, oh, that's what AI is for. Like, I, I just want
Speaker 5:  this to happen.
Speaker 5:  Wild interactions in that community. The scale problem is really interesting
Speaker 5:  because if, you know, we just play this game right now on the show,
Speaker 5:  the moral dilemmas of copyright law become plain. So if I say to you,
Speaker 5:  David, can you rip a CD onto your computer without paying extra money to
Speaker 5:  a record label, what would you say? Yes. Can you rip 10 CDs?
Speaker 5:  Yes. Can you David Pierce rip 1000 CDs to your computer without paying record
Speaker 5:  labels additional money, I guess in theory, yeah. If you had to hard drive
Speaker 5:  space, could you rip a million CDs to your computer without paying record
Speaker 5:  labels? You David Pierce? Yeah, I think so. Can Meta do that?
Speaker 5:  No.
Speaker 5:  Like why? Like this is the problem, right? Right. You write the rule
Speaker 5:  that says it's okay to like rip CDs or we,
Speaker 5:  we got a lot of plexus on the
Speaker 11:  Show. Wait, fair use can account for this right there. Part of the consideration
Speaker 11:  of fair use is whether something is commercial or not.
Speaker 5:  Part of the consideration is whether it's commercial, but in, in the
Speaker 5:  anthropic case, judge s says, you're allowed to just make a database, right?
Speaker 5:  If what you wanna do is make it easier to search, make it easier to run different
Speaker 5:  applications on, it's totally fine for you to buy a million books, rip the
Speaker 5:  covers off and scan 'em into a database. It's the next use
Speaker 5:  that gets you into trouble, right? It's okay, is it training
Speaker 5:  the AI model? Is that fair use if you have the database? He says yes.
Speaker 5:  If you were to say, I've now made this database publicly available for
Speaker 5:  anyone to read all the books or listen to all the music in my database, you
Speaker 5:  would go to jail, right? Like that's, the internet archive
Speaker 5:  is in trouble for their database of books that they acquired. They scanned
Speaker 5:  it and they let everybody have access to. So the questions
Speaker 5:  get really difficult the second you start not just adding scale,
Speaker 5:  but adding different uses of what they're gonna do. And some of those uses
Speaker 5:  at commercial change the equation. And this is the problem. This is why
Speaker 5:  everybody hates copyright law. This is why everybody hates lawyers. You start
Speaker 5:  to get incredibly pedantic about what happened, when to whom,
Speaker 5:  who made the copy, when, where does the copy live? And everyone's like, it's
Speaker 5:  just a computer, right? I can just like open it up and get whatever I want.
Speaker 5:  And then underneath that, all of those questions determine who gets paid.
Speaker 5:  And I think here, you know, the big problem with the the,
Speaker 5:  the anthropic fair use ruling is one, if you buy
Speaker 5:  a million used books and train a model that generates billions of dollars
Speaker 5:  in value, the authors who wrote those books get nothing. That,
Speaker 5:  that's just the way it works in our society. If they pay a one-time fee to
Speaker 5:  buy a million brand new books and then train a model that
Speaker 5:  generates billions of dollars in revenue, the authors essentially on that
Speaker 5:  curve get nothing. They get paid one time. Is that fair?
Speaker 5:  Like I don't, I I truly don't know the answers to those questions. And these
Speaker 5:  really kind of don't get you there.
Speaker 11:  I don't know. I think that the Meta ruling is interesting because it does
Speaker 11:  actually kind of cut through all this because everything in copyright is
Speaker 11:  very angels dancing on a head of a pin. Like is putting something in ram
Speaker 11:  a copy.
Speaker 11:  But the overall argument is the whole reason copyright
Speaker 11:  exists is to encourage human creativity. And so the ultimate bar should
Speaker 11:  not be is this fair or is this hitting this
Speaker 11:  particular place where it starts being uncomfortable?
Speaker 11:  Or is the company that's doing this making it commercial? It
Speaker 11:  is, when you look at this thing holistically, does it serve the purpose
Speaker 11:  that the law is meant to serve? And that's not mostly how courts
Speaker 11:  work, but I think if you are considering this from a larger kind of philosophical
Speaker 11:  sense, that is interesting and worth considering.
Speaker 5:  Sarah and I have often crashed out because we both started as
Speaker 5:  like copyright minimalist warriors, you know, like
Speaker 5:  in our legal careers. And we've now like horseshoe theory around to like
Speaker 5:  copyright law is good actually, which is crazy. So the argument that you
Speaker 5:  would make from the other side, and it's a good argument, is that
Speaker 5:  human beings do not need copyright law to be creative. This, this legal
Speaker 5:  system that we've invented is there to create scarcity and economic
Speaker 5:  value for creativity, which certainly incentivizes some people to create.
Speaker 5:  But if actually, if you look around, our instinct is literal
Speaker 5:  human beings. Every day is to create, we will do it for free. People
Speaker 5:  wake up every morning and they have access to creative tools on their computers
Speaker 5:  and they cannot help themselves. Like it is just the, our
Speaker 5:  most essential human nature is to make stuff. And that's in real
Speaker 5:  tension here, right? Like it, it's hard to square the
Speaker 5:  courts saying we have to preserve the essential nature of copyright law
Speaker 5:  so that there will be creativity. And then literally those judges go home
Speaker 5:  and they open the Instagram app on their phone and it's just like the most
Speaker 5:  free creativity that has ever existed in the history of humanity.
Speaker 6:  I mean, somebody at Andreesen Horowitz is gonna play that clip that you just
Speaker 6:  said for everyone who works there. That's that's the crash. That's the, I
Speaker 6:  mean that is the argument that these companies make in favor of all of this
Speaker 6:  is that no, we're not diminishing anything because everybody would do it
Speaker 6:  for free.
Speaker 5:  Right? And then they, they make that argument from their yachts.
Speaker 11:  I'll link the counter argument to this, which is that while
Speaker 11:  people will create a lot of the purpose of creativity is to
Speaker 11:  share that thing with other people, other people. And if AI
Speaker 11:  creates a situation in which it is virtually impossible to distribute
Speaker 11:  your work or to get anyone to see your human made work, I think that you
Speaker 11:  can say that is really meaningfully chilling creativity. The problem
Speaker 11:  is that I don't think copyright laws that stands can solve this. There's
Speaker 11:  this really bizarre tension in the Meta opinion where,
Speaker 11:  okay, if you take its premises true that this will completely destroy the
Speaker 11:  market for books, then the only thing copyright law can do is
Speaker 11:  say, okay, well some people have to get a few dollars a
Speaker 11:  month as residuals for this to create this entire
Speaker 11:  creativity killing database. Really the only way
Speaker 11:  that you can take this argument as true is to assume that also
Speaker 11:  copyright law is going to be powerless to change it.
Speaker 5:  It might be, I mean we, oh, one outcome of all these
Speaker 5:  cases is they hit the Supreme Court and the Supreme Court says fine training
Speaker 5:  is fair use. Maybe that's an outcome. I think it is much more likely
Speaker 5:  that as these cases carene towards that risk.
Speaker 5:  'cause no one knows how that will go.
Speaker 5:  That actually the incredibly well moneyed interest here
Speaker 5:  will go get a law, right? That, that Disney and OpenAI and Google,
Speaker 5:  all of these companies have to deal with each other. They will go that
Speaker 5:  Nashville is a powerful economic force in copyright law.
Speaker 11:  Where does that leave the next generation of artists though? Because the
Speaker 11:  way that I see that gaming out is yeah, all the record labels that currently
Speaker 11:  have artists sell a bunch of data to companies and then
Speaker 11:  companies create this database and they train on it and they train
Speaker 11:  a bunch of, I don't know, music apps and apps for writing romance
Speaker 11:  novels and all of that. And then they create training
Speaker 11:  data based on that, that then they sort of cycle into their system over
Speaker 11:  and over, which is what they're trying to do right now. And then at that
Speaker 11:  point, where does the next generation get paid? I I don't know that
Speaker 11:  there's actually a way that happens, especially if there is this situation
Speaker 11:  where say AI generated content floods everything.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I don't know. I that I, I think that will be the heart of the
Speaker 5:  negotiation fundamentally. Especially because
Speaker 5:  private equity is in the mix. Like the creative
Speaker 5:  industry is not clean, it's not pure. It's a lot of essentially banks now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And so, like, you know, private equity companies have bought Bruce
Speaker 5:  Springsteen's entire catalog for $500 million. They're not
Speaker 5:  gonna take a one time training payment for that. They bought that because
Speaker 5:  they think they can exploit that music for years to come in various ways.
Speaker 11:  I, I don't know, I just think that's not actually satisfying because that
Speaker 11:  means Bruce Springsteen has a sp a steady string of income, but that there
Speaker 11:  is no market for the next person.
Speaker 5:  No, Bruce Springsteen got his one-time payment. I mean this is why it's particularly
Speaker 5:  gross. Bruce Stein has a half billion. Yeah, okay. Yes, fair. It's the private
Speaker 5:  equity company that made the investment is gonna wanna return over time
Speaker 5:  and that return over time is the thing that ideally
Speaker 5:  makes any new work also valuable. And that's
Speaker 5:  tough. I don't know how any of that plays out, especially because I don't
Speaker 5:  think this gets litigated. I don't think it's solved the level of Supreme
Speaker 5:  Court. I think Congress has to write a law in that you can already
Speaker 5:  see how messy that will be. That and, and the battle lines of that law is
Speaker 5:  these court cases wind ever forward are literally
Speaker 5:  the huge entertainment companies that basically own
Speaker 5:  this kind of lobbying. This is what they do this and they, they're very,
Speaker 5:  very good at it. Going up against Disney to walk back. Copyright law is
Speaker 5:  not historically a successful effort going up against Nashville in the
Speaker 5:  music industry to walk back copyright law, not historically a successful
Speaker 5:  effort. And in fact some of the only AI related laws we
Speaker 5:  have are like the Elvis Act in Tennessee that prevents people from
Speaker 5:  making ai Elvis impersonators.
Speaker 6:  Well and things like the Disney one are, are seem more sort of viscerally
Speaker 6:  straightforward in that you can just go to Midjourney and be like, show me
Speaker 6:  Simpsons. And it'll just do the Simpsons for you in a way that I think
Speaker 6:  things like these cases are, are a little, just feel more abstract
Speaker 6:  because it's like something goes in black box, something else
Speaker 6:  comes out in that one, it's just something goes in and then that same, something
Speaker 6:  comes out for free and you can do whatever you want with it. And I feel like
Speaker 6:  that we're just gonna look at that differently, whether we should
Speaker 6:  or not. It feels different.
Speaker 5:  Oh, the pictures always win. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  Legally different media are also different. Like you can quote
Speaker 11:  a bunch of a book, but if you want to sample three seconds of a song,
Speaker 11:  you're on much shakier territory. So
Speaker 5:  I would actually chalk that up to the fact that the record labels in Hollywood
Speaker 5:  are better at this than the book publishing industry fair. The the news media
Speaker 5:  is not great at this historically. And, and those industries are really,
Speaker 5:  really good at it. And part of it is to David's point, you have
Speaker 5:  a more visceral emotional reaction to that picture is the same and that song
Speaker 5:  is the same. Yeah, they are good at fighting these fights. So my
Speaker 5:  suspicion here, Addie, it might not be satisfying, is
Speaker 5:  that you get to some solution where there's still value for the individual
Speaker 5:  song. There's still value for the individual video. It might be
Speaker 5:  less than before and there might be more supply which will crash that value
Speaker 5:  because there's only so many people and only so many events to consume songs
Speaker 5:  and videos in the day. But I don't think you get to a place where this set
Speaker 5:  of artists gets paid once and no future artists get paid because that will
Speaker 5:  kill these businesses. And they're not existentially stupid. They can be
Speaker 5:  stupid. They're not existentially stupid.
Speaker 11:  My really dark take is that the reason Disney is suing Midjourney is because
Speaker 11:  Disney is about to use all of its IP to generate infinite Star Wars forever.
Speaker 11:  So, I don't know, I think we're just shifting the people who are going to
Speaker 11:  be making these things and flooding the market
Speaker 5:  Disney learns wrong lesson from and or is a real headline. You can,
Speaker 5:  it's, it's right there for you. We
Speaker 5:  We're back the lightning round, which David says has to be two
Speaker 5:  minutes long, two minute lightning round 'cause we just spent an hour crashing
Speaker 5:  out about copyright law. So let's talk about Brendan Carr for 45 minutes.
Speaker 5:  America's favorite podcast for the podcast by the way, lightning round Unsponsored.
Speaker 5:  If you, if we're in a Tesla and it crashes, we'll point out that it crashes.
Speaker 5:  I'm just saying you can't buy us. I've noticed a lot of people have started
Speaker 5:  posting on, on, on various social platforms at me that you can't tell us
Speaker 5:  what to do. That's all I've ever wanted from the lightning round is Unsponsored
Speaker 5:  for Flavor,
Speaker 5:  is people reminding everyone that you can't actually tell us what to do when
Speaker 5:  you can't buy us. I think when you die, I am gonna write, you can't tell
Speaker 5:  me what to do on your tombstone and it's gonna feel, it's gonna feel right.
Speaker 5:  It is the animating thesis of The Verge talking
Speaker 5:  that and figuring out what's going on with the Frame tv. Okay,
Speaker 5:  Brandon Carr is a dummy America's favorite podcast. In the podcast. It's
Speaker 5:  time. This, oh this is a short one
Speaker 5:  'cause he did something dumb, but it's like predictably dumb.
Speaker 5:  Like he, he did the dumb thing that Republican commissioners always do at
Speaker 5:  the FCC. So a couple of things happened. One, everyone
Speaker 5:  left the FCC presumably. 'cause Brendan is so unpleasant
Speaker 5:  to work for. Does Anna Gomez still work there? I haven't checked on this
Speaker 5:  in a minute. She still works there. She is not yet fired by Donald Trump.
Speaker 5:  Okay. The only Democratic commissioner on the FCC. And she literally will
Speaker 5:  set tell you she does not know why she, she has not been fired. So, and
Speaker 5:  she's on tour saying Brandon is a bad guy who's violating the First Amendment
Speaker 5:  wild stuff over there. So there was just the two of them, which is not a
Speaker 5:  quorum for the FCC to do its business.
Speaker 5:  Nathan Simington, who left the FCC, wanted this guy Gavin
Speaker 5:  Wax to be appointed. He didn't get it. This woman named Olivia Trusty
Speaker 5:  is the new Republican commissioner of the SEC. She was confirmed by the Senate.
Speaker 5:  She's a long history with everyone. There were statements about her, like
Speaker 5:  we would confirm her in a normal time because that's, she's a Republican
Speaker 5:  commissioner. Republican presidents get Republican commissioners. But Brendan
Speaker 5:  is such a weird threat to free speech that we're opposing her nomination.
Speaker 5:  That's, that's where Brendan has taken this organization. This, this
Speaker 5:  woman who would've sailed through a normal times was opposed by various
Speaker 5:  Democrats and various free speech troops. And literally they're saying she's
Speaker 5:  fine, but Brendan sucks. So we're, we can't let Brendan do anything. You
Speaker 5:  can't, you can't let him have another vote, right? She got through party
Speaker 5:  on vote. So it goes immediately,
Speaker 5:  immediately Brendan moves to open comment on letting companies
Speaker 5:  own more broadcast stations. So we have this concept in the United States
Speaker 5:  called media Ownership rules that say big companies can't own
Speaker 5:  all the TV stations for a variety of reasons. First,
Speaker 5:  you just want your local media to have a relationship to you,
Speaker 5:  right? That the TV stations and newspapers and radio stations that
Speaker 5:  serve your area should have some skin in the game where you live. Right?
Speaker 5:  They should be responsive to their local communities. And this is like deep
Speaker 5:  in the law and the policy where you, you want the local media to be local.
Speaker 5:  You don't want national media to ignore your concerns and, and do all this
Speaker 5:  other stuff. This is waxed and waned over the years. But you
Speaker 5:  can kind of feel it, right? If you go on social media, they, they're not
Speaker 5:  local media ownership rules. They're not rules that your algorithm necess
Speaker 5:  necessarily what's happening in your community. Everything is just national
Speaker 5:  culture war all the time. 'cause that's what plays in social media. Weird.
Speaker 5:  It's a weird outcome. So we have these rules eight from ages ago that say,
Speaker 5:  you know, big companies can't just buy a TV stations and national program
Speaker 5:  and they actually locally owned. And then we have this other rule that says
Speaker 5:  you can't, there's a percentage, right? The same company can't own all the
Speaker 5:  stations in your town. The same company can't own all the stations and all
Speaker 5:  the radio stations, all these favored. So you have all these media ownership
Speaker 5:  rules.
Speaker 5:  Brendan, Brendan thinks they're dumb. He thinks we should open it up
Speaker 5:  and let everybody on everything. And his argument is
Speaker 5:  it's not smart that these companies have to compete with the internet.
Speaker 5:  So we should let them own everything so they can get big enough to compete
Speaker 5:  with Google and Facebook. And the problem there, of course, is when you open
Speaker 5:  the social media apps on your phone, you are not subjected to local news.
Speaker 5:  You're subject to the national culture war, which is the exact reason the
Speaker 5:  policy exists.
Speaker 5:  Brendan, everybody, he's just like, just walked into
Speaker 5:  the literal opposite of the reason for the rule we should make. We should
Speaker 5:  make everything national culture war so that local news can compete with
Speaker 5:  Google is not the right answer at all.
Speaker 6:  Make local news, do national culture wars is what we're after.
Speaker 6:  Now
Speaker 5:  That's, sorry, boy Brendan. So that's Brendan,
Speaker 5:  he's a dummy as always. Brendan, if you can defend any of this stuff, you're
Speaker 5:  welcome on the show. I'd love to have you. It's been a minute since I've
Speaker 5:  issued this threatening invitation to you And I amm wishing it again. You're
Speaker 5:  welcome. On Decoder on The Vergecast. We've only got weeks to go.
Speaker 5:  David, I believe this is your last show before baby.
Speaker 6:  This is my last Friday show. I I will be on Tuesday's
Speaker 6:  show, which due to the magic of technology, we have already
Speaker 6:  recorded
Speaker 5:  This cake has already baked.
Speaker 6:  Exactly. But yeah, this is, this is the, the the last one
Speaker 6:  I'll be on for a couple of months.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And then I, I I'm weeks away here as well, So I miss Brendan and children.
Speaker 5:  Our children are coming. And Brendan, we will let our children interview
Speaker 5:  you. I think they can take you, buddy.
Speaker 6:  That's a good idea.
Speaker 5:  I I mean Max can take me, so yeah, I think she can,
Speaker 5:  she can definitely take Brendan. But you're, you're, you're, you're invited
Speaker 5:  anytime you want. You got a couple weeks to go. I'll come back special just
Speaker 5:  for you, Brendan. I do have, by the way,
Speaker 6:  It's gonna be so great when Jake interviews Brendan while we're out.
Speaker 5:  I think Jake can pick Brendan too. I'm not worried about it in the slightest.
Speaker 5:  Just a little bonus round. Not the FCC, the Federal Trade Commission did
Speaker 5:  some dumb shit this week. They are a allowing
Speaker 5:  Omnicom, which is a big ad agency to buy another big ad agency, but
Speaker 5:  they're issuing a consent decree that says they're not allowed to,
Speaker 5:  to like, keep ads off of x basically.
Speaker 5:  So they, they're literally stepping into the free market and saying you have
Speaker 5:  to spend money on platforms where you disagree with the political views and
Speaker 5:  then we'll let your merger go. Which, what kind of free market
Speaker 5:  is that? Where the government is like, we will let you merge,
Speaker 5:  but you are not allowed to choose how you spend your money.
Speaker 6:  You are required to advertise on objectionable content is such a funny
Speaker 6:  thing for the government to require.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The advertisers by the way, the clients are allowed to still make their
Speaker 5:  decisions. But the ad agencies, which fundamentally what the ad agencies
Speaker 5:  do is help people spend their ad dollars. They're not allowed to make those
Speaker 5:  decisions perfect. I can't imagine how that will ever
Speaker 5:  get, how will anyone get around this, this incredible rule. So
Speaker 6:  They're like, here's, here's the people, here's the Nazis.
Speaker 5:  And then just another, another one just to throw it out there.
Speaker 5:  Paramount is being sued by Trump
Speaker 5:  for the CBS interview. You, you know about this where he says the Kamala
Speaker 5:  Harris interview was deceptively edited, blah blah, there's some mediator
Speaker 5:  that's proposed some settlement, $20 billion and it's held up because
Speaker 5:  Paramount executives and their lawyers cannot figure out how to
Speaker 5:  pay this money without being on the hook for Bribery charges
Speaker 5:  because it's just Bribery.
Speaker 5:  This is a real problem. If you don't believe me,
Speaker 5:  you can read the notoriously leftist Wall
Speaker 5:  Street Journal editorial board saying, don't do this
Speaker 5:  Paramount, just fight and win this lawsuit. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  When
Speaker 5:  Rupert Murdoch is like, don't be an idiot, like go win your first amendment
Speaker 5:  argument and he agrees with you. You, I'm just letting you know. All right.
Speaker 5:  That's politics for today. Don't do Bribery. Brendan's an idiot.
Speaker 5:  Got it all on my system. David, do you have a ballot cleanser?
Speaker 7:  Jake? Let's
Speaker 6:  Do, let's do one each before we get outta here. Let's, let's, what
Speaker 7:  Do you have?
Speaker 7:  I am super excited about this one. Have you guys ever
Speaker 7:  looked at your TV and thought not enough pixels here.
Speaker 6:  I can tell you for knee, like the answer is constantly, every day
Speaker 5:  The
Speaker 7:  Answer. The answer is always, every single time you think this isn't enough,
Speaker 7:  guys, we're going a 16 k, it's happening. The, The
Speaker 7:  HDMI 2.2 spec is out. Now there are
Speaker 7:  some drawbacks, And I know this is gonna be a hard one for the gamers out
Speaker 7:  there. It's only 60 hertz. So I, I know
Speaker 7:  nobody's gonna want this just yet, right?
Speaker 6:  How is this gonna look on Bravia core? That's all I wanna know
Speaker 7:  Until we can get 16 1 20. You
Speaker 7:  know, it's not for me, but the HDMI forum is on top of it.
Speaker 7:  They're weirdly ahead of the curve here. I do not know what the current demand
Speaker 7:  is for support for 16 K 60 Hertz video.
Speaker 7:  I'm not sure how much of that exists. I don't know where I would get it.
Speaker 7:  The YouTubers aren't yelling at us to filming it yet.
Speaker 5:  I love by the way, that they've only revved it to
Speaker 5:  2.2. Right? Because we're at The HDMI
Speaker 5:  2.1 right now. I I, right? Yes.
Speaker 5:  16 1 20 is only worth 0.1.
Speaker 5:  They've only revved it to HDMI 2.2 to get to
Speaker 5:  16 1 20 16 K one 20. Look, what is it gonna take you guys?
Speaker 6:  30 2K 360,
Speaker 6:  The HDMI three.
Speaker 5:  This is, this is the goal. We gotta go to the, The HDMI forum headquarters
Speaker 5:  and just yell numbers at them until they concede that it's time to rev the
Speaker 5:  main version.
Speaker 6:  I love this. This is, I'm, I'm all in. I'm really excited to buy a bunch
Speaker 6:  of expensive HDMI cables and connect them to my $300
Speaker 6:  42 inch TCL Roku dv.
Speaker 7:  This is what is most important. As soon as these cables are, are available,
Speaker 7:  I don't care if you're still running 10 80 p any HDMI cable you buy from
Speaker 7:  here on out has better be a 16 K cable. 'cause one day
Speaker 7:  you're gonna wanna change out your Xbox and it's gonna be
Speaker 7:  too hard to get to. You're gonna need to make sure you have that 16 K support
Speaker 7:  just
Speaker 6:  In case my $19 Roku Express is gonna look sick.
Speaker 7:  Now it's gonna rule.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Okay. So Andrew Osky wrote this story for us. Every paragraph for this
Speaker 5:  story is great because Andrew's a great gadget writer and he wrote it very
Speaker 5:  dryly. And if you just read it on its face, this is the work of
Speaker 5:  people who, who have no connection to reality. So those
Speaker 5:  cables that you're talking about are now officially called HDMI
Speaker 5:  2.2 Ultra 96 cables
Speaker 6:  Sick.
Speaker 5:  Sure. There's a new standard they support called the Latency Indication
Speaker 5:  Protocol or lip.
Speaker 6:  That's a sick band name by the way. The latency indication protocol is like
Speaker 6:  a swing band that needs to exist.
Speaker 5:  Why is it called lip? Because it matches up the audio in the video, so
Speaker 5:  the audio matches the lips. Oh, that's
Speaker 6:  Good.
Speaker 5:  It's good stuff. That's good stuff.
Speaker 7:  And some might even say somewhat more important than 16 K
Speaker 7:  and having your audio synced to your video
Speaker 7:  htm I 2.2 mostly
Speaker 6:  Here on The Vergecast. We love a good acronym, So I I will take it. I'm all
Speaker 6:  in. I'm
Speaker 5:  Just saying the, it's a new top end. Ultra 96
Speaker 5:  is the new top end. You get high speed, premium, high speed, and ultra high
Speaker 5:  speed. And now Ultra 96,
Speaker 5:  I'm, I'm happy. All right. What do you got, David?
Speaker 6:  Microsoft is killing the blue screen of death. Finally,
Speaker 6:  after 40 years when your computer explodes, it will no longer show the blue
Speaker 6:  screen of death. It will show the black screen of death.
Speaker 6:  Microsoft is, is redesigning it. A thing that I learned this week, thanks
Speaker 6:  to a story Tom Warren wrote for The Verge in 2014,
Speaker 6:  was that Steve Balmer wrote the text of the blue screen of death message.
Speaker 5:  No way.
Speaker 6:  Because he didn't like, he, he got the blue screen of death and he thought
Speaker 6:  the, the wording didn't seem right for when it was going wrong. So he, they,
Speaker 6:  the Windows team challenged him to go do a better job. And he did. He wrote
Speaker 6:  the blue screen of death meth message, which is wonderful, but
Speaker 6:  now they're changing it to something much less
Speaker 6:  fun and interesting. It just now says your device ran into a problem and
Speaker 6:  needs to restart, and then at the bottom it actually shows you
Speaker 6:  the code of what went wrong, which is vastly more useful than what
Speaker 6:  the blue screen of death did. But it's much less fun and the,
Speaker 6:  the black screen of death just doesn't, doesn't roll off the tongue the same
Speaker 6:  way. And I will be very sad to not have my computer just
Speaker 6:  randomly run up this thing.
Speaker 5:  You still got to use the acronym, right? It's still the BSOD. It's still
Speaker 6:  The BSOD, which I assume was intentional, but
Speaker 6:  like why? Just this is a tragedy. That's, I agree.
Speaker 6:  There's no other way of looking at this. This is like a canonical thing in
Speaker 6:  technology. Everybody knew what the blue screen of death was and now it's
Speaker 6:  gone.
Speaker 5:  Oh, they're getting rid of the sad face. Yeah. Yeah. Dude, I thought
Speaker 5:  they were just changing it from blue to black. No, this, the face has
Speaker 5:  gone,
Speaker 6:  This is what I'm saying. It's devastating.
Speaker 5:  It's very bad. I mean, it was supposed to be a power
Speaker 6:  Computer. Your used to feel bad for you. And now it's like, do either of
Speaker 6:  you ever watch the office? Yeah. Do you know the scene where, where it's
Speaker 6:  Kelly's birthday and Dwight just puts up a sign that says it is your birthday.
Speaker 6:  That's the black screen of death Now it just says your device ran into a
Speaker 6:  problem and needs to restart your computer used to feel bad for you. It was
Speaker 6:  like, I'm sorry, I blew, I blew it and I'm gonna fix it now. And now your
Speaker 6:  computer's just like, well, I'm dead.
Speaker 5:  In other great moments of sort of dead ahead tech writing that Reid is very
Speaker 5:  funny. Tom wrote this story and he wrote it. It's very, again, it's very
Speaker 5:  dead ahead. It's got some good quotes. The whole thing did great reporting
Speaker 5:  the last line dead ahead. The changes to the blue screen
Speaker 5:  of death are part of the broader effort by Microsoft to improve the resiliency
Speaker 5:  of Windows. In the wake of last year's CrowdStrike incident, which left millions
Speaker 5:  of Windows machines booting to the blue screen of death, and it's like, oh,
Speaker 5:  part of that effort was making the screens black.
Speaker 6:  Do you think it's so that if you see a lot of them all at once, it's not
Speaker 6:  as obvious that they've broken. That's
Speaker 5:  What I'm saying.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, right. You can like bunch of black screens a room full of them
Speaker 6:  and they don't all, it's not, it doesn't immediately scream, right? We're
Speaker 6:  all
Speaker 5:  Destroyed. It's like how Tiffany has the trademark on its Pantone blue, you
Speaker 5:  see the blue screen and Jare, that Window's PC has crashed and now it's just
Speaker 5:  a black screen. You're like, maybe that's Linux Like it's, it's the wrong
Speaker 5:  thing to have a trademark on.
Speaker 6:  Own your shame, Microsoft.
Speaker 5:  That's the broadcast. Everybody own your shame. We'll see you next week.
Speaker 5:  Rock and roll.
Speaker 15:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 15:  you. Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one.
Speaker 15:  The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network.
Speaker 15:  Our show is produced by Will Por, Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer. And
Speaker 15:  that's it. We'll see you next week.
Speaker 4:  Support for this show comes from Pure Leaf Iced Tea. When you find yourself
Speaker 4:  in the the afternoon slump, you need the right thing to make you bounce back.
Speaker 4:  You need Pure Leaf iced tea. It's real brewed tea, made in a variety
Speaker 4:  of bold flavors. With just the right amount of naturally occurring
Speaker 4:  caffeine, you're left feeling refreshed and revitalized so you can be ready
Speaker 4:  to take on what's next. The next time you need to hit the reset button,
Speaker 4:  grab a Pure Leaf iced tea Time for a tea break. Time for a
Speaker 4:  Pure Leaf.