# Transcript
ID: 008af2e4-0e1a-431b-b7b4-90cc8120ebef
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-6944099679344751962/-6447151128613202066/s93290-US-6867s-1747386890.mp3
Description: Names are hard — but they don't have to be this hard. Nilay, David, and The Verge's Jake Kastrenakes start the show with some personal news, before digging into the monumentally silly thinking behind Warner Bros. Discovery re-re-naming its streaming service HBO Max. After that, and some more streaming news, we turn our attention to the gadget news of the week, including the long-awaited release of CarPlay Ultra and the latest announcements from the Android team at Google. Finally, in the lightning round, it's time for Brendan Carr is a Dummy, some debate on the future of Airbnb, and a brief party speaker update. Because the mystery continues.
Speaker 5:  Hello and welcome to Cast the Flagship podcast. The pretending that everyone
Speaker 5:  has Aston Martins, you know, just all everybody who
Speaker 5:  does it.
Speaker 6:  One of the great flexes of all time is being able to say our product has
Speaker 6:  begun rolling out in one car. No one will ever buy.
Speaker 5:  Well, no, it's all newer. Aston Martins David.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. One car no one will ever buy. So
Speaker 7:  I have to buy a new Aston Martin for this. I can't get this on my
Speaker 7:  existing,
Speaker 5:  We're gonna get to it. But yes, it is new
Speaker 5:  Aston Martins as of today. And then if you, you
Speaker 5:  have a newer Aston Martin that has the next generation Aston
Speaker 5:  Martin infotainment system, you can go to your dealer and
Speaker 5:  get a software update because God knows Aston Martin owners
Speaker 5:  cannot insert a USB drive into their own car.
Speaker 6:  Okay, I have a question. There is one Aston Martin
Speaker 6:  in my neighborhood. Is it journalistically
Speaker 6:  problematic? If next time I see them, I track them to their house and
Speaker 6:  ask them questions in their driveway about their Aston Martin? There's
Speaker 6:  only one. Like I, I know I, I could recite the license plate, but I will
Speaker 6:  not, but it's like, it's an Aston Martin, like I see it a lot and
Speaker 6:  it's like, oh, that's the Aston Martin. And I have always wondered where
Speaker 6:  they live. Do I now have a good journalistic reason to find out,
Speaker 7:  Go slow, start with cookies,
Speaker 6:  You know, okay. At at just like ask about the neighborhood and
Speaker 6:  then a couple weeks later be like, I need to go for a drive.
Speaker 6:  I, I like this
Speaker 5:  As a, as a car person. This is, this breaks in two ways.
Speaker 5:  One, this guy has been dreaming of the day
Speaker 5:  someone shows up and is like, I see you have an Aston Martin.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. There's no reason to buy one otherwise, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like I, I drive the, the Mustang around and like the high school
Speaker 5:  kids are like, wherever the engine, I'm like, well this is why I bought this
Speaker 5:  car. Like, it's great. That's exactly what you want. And then
Speaker 5:  there's the car people who were like, I'm not here.
Speaker 5:  I was in Florida a couple years ago right when the Lucid Air came out and
Speaker 5:  this was like, we're on vacation in like a, my friend's ritzy part of Florida
Speaker 5:  and I saw his neighbor had a lucid air. And so we were walking up and I deployed
Speaker 5:  Max who was, you know, at the time, a toddler. So like extra cute. And
Speaker 5:  I, I tod her over to the Lucid Air and I was like, my
Speaker 5:  kid likes your car, what is it? And he is like, I don't know what you're
Speaker 5:  talking about. And you just don't, you just walk away. You just, you don't
Speaker 5:  wanna Right. That's a, that's a person with security. Yeah, he did not. I
Speaker 5:  was like, no, not a lot of people have these. How'd you get it? He is like,
Speaker 5:  I don dunno.
Speaker 6:  He's like, what? What are you talking about? I don't have a car. What's a
Speaker 6:  car? Who
Speaker 5:  Are you? Yeah, now it's like Lucid would like everyone to talk about Lucid
Speaker 5:  Arrow a little bit more than they have been. But that and that, there's only
Speaker 5:  two ways this goes.
Speaker 6:  Right, okay.
Speaker 5:  I either, I mean, and it's an Aston, I think I know which way, like no one's
Speaker 5:  secretive about their Aston Martin. No.
Speaker 6:  If you're secretive about an Aston, you don't, you have too much money.
Speaker 6:  I don't, I don't like it.
Speaker 5:  But there's not like it Yeah, it, it's not like a hard, you don't have to
Speaker 5:  get like an allocation to go a new asset Martin.
Speaker 6:  True.
Speaker 5:  Like there's like Ferrari that you can only buy if you've bought enough previous
Speaker 5:  Ferraris. This is why all the crypto bros have Lambos, by the way, this is
Speaker 5:  a real thing. Lambos are so, like, new money is
Speaker 5:  associated with Lamborghini. 'cause Lamborghini will just sell you a car.
Speaker 5:  You are like, oh my God, I did it. Meme coin, what do I do? Buy
Speaker 5:  Lambo. And the reason is, 'cause you can just show up at the Lamborghini
Speaker 5:  dealer and they will just be like, yeah, you give us money and here's this
Speaker 5:  car. You show up at the Ferrari dealership and like, have you bought our
Speaker 5:  shit Ferrari's for the past 10 years and kept them and not recently. Now
Speaker 5:  you may have our best Ferrari. And those guys do not talk about
Speaker 5:  where they're at. They're, they're also often,
Speaker 5:  you know, the rulers of Middle Eastern nations. So they, they often don't
Speaker 5:  talk about it again. Of course. Anyhow, we're gonna talk about Next Generation
Speaker 5:  car. I don Dunno how we got here. We're gonna talk about next generation
Speaker 5:  CarPlay. David is gonna get arrested, stalking his neighbor in Washington,
Speaker 5:  DC that's gonna make for amazing podcasts later in this episode.
Speaker 5:  We have to start though
Speaker 5:  with news about ourselves. This is a real thing. We're gonna start with news
Speaker 5:  about ourselves. It's not what we think. David, would you like to tell the
Speaker 5:  class what's going on in your life?
Speaker 6:  I am having a baby in soon.
Speaker 5:  But to be clear, you are not, I
Speaker 6:  Am not personally having a baby. My wife is having a baby and I will
Speaker 6:  be there. Yeah. At the time
Speaker 6:  we're, she's due July 6th.
Speaker 6:  So sometime between mid-June and mid-July I am just going to
Speaker 6:  disappear into the ether for a couple of months. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And Neli, you also have news.
Speaker 5:  My news is, congratulations David.
Speaker 6:  Thank you. That's great.
Speaker 5:  And now to add some complexity to this mix,
Speaker 5:  my wife is also having a baby one week after
Speaker 5:  David and his wife. So already day is July 14th.
Speaker 5:  Children will arrive and then we will disappear. Yep. We're gonna
Speaker 5:  we're we're, we're gonna go away. We're gonna, we're gonna try to take leave.
Speaker 5:  Fox meeting has actually really, really great parental leave. I didn't, it
Speaker 5:  didn't when I had my first baby and I, I only took
Speaker 5:  like eight weeks and now we have like a like really great like industry leading
Speaker 5:  leave. We're gonna try to take it and like model it for our team. Like the
Speaker 5:  whole thing that we do. I suspect I will fail in, in some ways
Speaker 5:  to, to take the whole thing. Yeah. Just given the nature of the job.
Speaker 5:  But I'm gonna try, I'm gonna try. And in the meantime on this show, Jake
Speaker 5:  is gonna take over hosting.
Speaker 7:  It's gonna be fun. Yeah. First off, congratulations to both of you. Thank
Speaker 7:  you. It was very exciting. They said this off camera, but they're both gonna
Speaker 7:  do live stream gender reveal parties. I think. I think it's probably gonna
Speaker 7:  be on Twitch. Stay tuned. That's
Speaker 6:  Fun. I like that idea. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  It's, it is definitely, definitely what we wanna do.
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna do mine in the woods and we're gonna fire a cannon of some kind.
Speaker 6:  Do you think that's a bad idea?
Speaker 5:  Our doctor in their office, in the waiting room, there's a sign, you know,
Speaker 5:  when there's a, there's a sign, you know, this has been a problem, like in
Speaker 5:  a corporate environment, the sign says we will not tell anyone the
Speaker 5:  gender of your baby. And it says like literally down the line. Oh my God.
Speaker 5:  It's like, we will not call the bakery. We will not call your grandparents.
Speaker 5:  Oh wow. And it's like a long list and it's like every one of those is something
Speaker 5:  that has happened. And we will not call the bakery as the first one.
Speaker 6:  There have been like siblings and cousins who are calling being like, tell
Speaker 6:  me So I can go do the gender reveal party. We
Speaker 5:  Were just like, tell us. We wanna know. But I, what appears to be happening
Speaker 5:  is people go in for the whatever, one reveals the sex of the
Speaker 5:  baby and then they don't want to know. And they ask
Speaker 5:  the doctor, will you call our bakery so we can get the cake
Speaker 5:  that reveals the gender? I get it. And they're like, we are not part of this.
Speaker 5:  If you would like a cake to be involved in this situation, the baker can
Speaker 5:  come with you.
Speaker 7:  See, I thought there was a, a hipaa carve out for bakers.
Speaker 5:  It's very good that like every one of those on the side is like, oh, this
Speaker 5:  has happened like down to like firework story. And it's like, we're just
Speaker 5:  like not doing it. You realize
Speaker 6:  You just described like an Uber Eats feature waiting to happen, right? Like
Speaker 6:  it's, someone will come with you, find out the sex of your baby
Speaker 6:  and then go acquire all the necessary things for your gender reveal party.
Speaker 5:  It's very
Speaker 6:  Good. It's like it's sitting there.
Speaker 5:  It is, it is truly good. But yeah, it's, we're we're going and, and,
Speaker 5:  and in July we're just gonna dip. Yeah. And you'll you'll ever gonna be fine.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's gonna be, it's gonna be a like delightfully chaotic vergecast summer.
Speaker 6:  Jake is gonna take over the Friday shows. We have some really fun plans for
Speaker 6:  the, the Tuesday shows. You're gonna hear a bunch of different voices from
Speaker 6:  the rich people. And the instruction that Nila and I have been giving to
Speaker 6:  everybody is just get real weird with it. So I,
Speaker 6:  we take no responsibility for what happens over the summer, but also I think
Speaker 6:  it's gonna be very fun and I'm, I'm excited to actually get to like, listen
Speaker 6:  to the show and not hear my own stupid voice.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It's gonna be a good time. I'll still be here. We're gonna bring,
Speaker 7:  bring people in from all across The Verge. So lots of faces that you
Speaker 7:  already know and are familiar with. Hopefully we'll get some more time for
Speaker 7:  folks who get on here a little less often. We're gonna have a good time.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And then out in decoder what we're gonna do is, Alex Heath is gonna host
Speaker 5:  the Thursday episode. So we'll explain our episodes. Here's what's going
Speaker 5:  on. And on Monday, the, the CEO interviews, we have a bunch of really cool
Speaker 5:  guest hosts. I'm very excited to announce some of these names as they come
Speaker 5:  up. That's gonna be really fun. I've told those folks,
Speaker 5:  don't try to make decoder interviews. Just go talk to people you think are
Speaker 5:  really interesting and like have a good time. And I think once you hear who
Speaker 5:  the guest host are, you will be equally excited about the idea of those people
Speaker 5:  just like playing in the sandbox. So that's the plan.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's, it is just gonna be a mess. Yeah. I think everyone will be happy
Speaker 5:  that I'm not around. Just be perfectly honest. It'll be everyone will finally
Speaker 5:  breathe. The tech industry will take a break. Brendan cars,
Speaker 5:  honestly, I'm just gonna call in once a week in and rail up Brendan, if you
Speaker 5:  thought that you would get one ounce of relief. I don't know how I turn an
Speaker 5:  announcement into us having babies and the threat about Brendan Barr, but
Speaker 5:  I did
Speaker 6:  It. Brendan Carr is a dummy is has always been just for Eli. So it, it stands
Speaker 6:  to reason that you'll keep making it even when
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna hold my new child to the light like Simba and be like, your
Speaker 5:  job is to torment this man. It's gonna be great. I'm really excited
Speaker 5:  about it. We have done a basically bad job of keeping the secret for
Speaker 5:  months.
Speaker 5:  So I'm glad we can finally tell all of you. But it's happening. We're weeks
Speaker 5:  away. And then David and I have to figure out how to be parents of infants
Speaker 5:  again, which will be a delight. Yeah. I will say baby monitor
Speaker 5:  technology has progressed exactly zero in the past seven years.
Speaker 7:  Quick question. Who is reviewing the snoo?
Speaker 5:  It's gonna be, it's, So I threatened to review this SNOO when Max was
Speaker 5:  born and Dr. Harvey Karp, the inventor of the Sno and I
Speaker 5:  had many, many, many conversations
Speaker 5:  there. There's a lot going on with that product. He is very charming.
Speaker 5:  I think Kristen Raki, our creative director has written about the SNOO in
Speaker 5:  the meantime. Right. We, we've had a lot of babies on The Verge team recently
Speaker 5:  and there's a lot of SNOO opinions.
Speaker 5:  Sure. Max hated this. Snoo hated it. I was
Speaker 5:  gonna review it and we stuck her in it. There's a hilarious picture on my
Speaker 5:  Instagram where she's just in it like she's a little
Speaker 5:  baby and she's all swaddled up. 'cause you put him in a straight jacket to
Speaker 5:  put him in this snoo and she's just like, what the fuck is this?
Speaker 5:  Like, it's just like every exposed part of her body is communicating
Speaker 5:  that message from her eyes down. She, so we never used it. She was just like,
Speaker 5:  I I hate you. I'm very upset with you. I don dunno. David, were you a
Speaker 5:  new person?
Speaker 6:  No, we, I spent an alarming amount of money on things
Speaker 6:  a baby might sleep in that ours decided not to sleep in. But we never got
Speaker 6:  all the way to the snoo in part because right before I left on leave,
Speaker 6:  you and I were in a car on in, in San
Speaker 6:  Francisco going somewhere and you spent like an hour in traffic
Speaker 6:  railing against the snoo. And I was just like, well, I guess I won't get
Speaker 6:  the snoo. So the SNOO is just not allowed After that.
Speaker 5:  Look, we have, we have some parents, j Peters on our team, like loves the
Speaker 5:  snoo. Like I I think they, his view of it is like they wouldn't have gotten
Speaker 5:  it through it without the snoo. Great. Like whatever, like the lesson you
Speaker 5:  learn when you have the first baby is no one knows anything at all. Correct.
Speaker 5:  The babies are very resilient and they will be fine and you just have to
Speaker 5:  get through it. Yep. And so like, whatever works, man, like I have no judgment,
Speaker 5:  but Max just hated this thing. And there's one
Speaker 5:  piece of information from my many conversations with Dr. Karp that just,
Speaker 5:  it just, it just undid it for me.
Speaker 5:  So the, the snoo you know, like rocks the baby, it like, it detects when
Speaker 5:  the baby wakes up and it starts rocking and then he,
Speaker 5:  you know, there's this, it makes noise. It makes like white noise. And he,
Speaker 5:  in his books, if you read Happiest Baby, which is his book or whatever, he's
Speaker 5:  like, we tried to make the sounds of
Speaker 5:  like mothers around the world. They all instinctively make this sh sound.
Speaker 5:  And in the book, and even when you talk to him, he always comes back to the
Speaker 5:  like the sound Indian mothers make, which is, and he's, he's like, and they
Speaker 5:  go Shoo Cho. And like he's like, and then he's got this idea that all these
Speaker 5:  cultures make this sound. So what you gotta do is like, pet the baby really
Speaker 5:  hard and goes sh And I'm like, dude, if you go up to an
Speaker 5:  like my mom and you're like, did you ever just say Jupe to me really loud?
Speaker 5:  She'd be like, no, because that means shut up.
Speaker 5:  Like that's what my mom would say when she was angry at me later in life
Speaker 5:  to shut up. And I was like, this is just a weird, there's a gap here.
Speaker 5:  I don't understand. And then later I was actually talking to him and I was
Speaker 5:  like, where these sounds like you have this big idea about these sounds and
Speaker 5:  this like cultural connection to the sound. Like how did you make
Speaker 5:  the sound that the steam makes? And I was just never forget it. He was like,
Speaker 5:  oh yeah, my like nephew and I sat around like made a garage band.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And I was like, all right dude. It always comes back to garage band.
Speaker 6:  Like,
Speaker 5:  Alright man. So I will say Dr. Karp is lovely. I
Speaker 5:  believe him. He's very sincere. He has all these ideas of what this new is
Speaker 5:  and what it should be and different ways for it to go to different people.
Speaker 5:  They, they got in trouble recently for pricing. I think Jay actually wrote
Speaker 5:  that story for us. Many many parents love this product. It was just, I,
Speaker 5:  my daughter and I were both like, I don't know man.
Speaker 5:  Anyway, we're gonna have more babies. We we while further Snu coverage is
Speaker 5:  coming. That's it Everybody. That's The Vergecast. There's
Speaker 5:  some destabilizing
Speaker 6:  Yeah. To big Good. And to be clear, we're not going anywhere for a while
Speaker 6:  here. So we got, we got time. We have, we do have time. Many things left
Speaker 6:  to talk about before
Speaker 5:  We get got lots of developer conferences coming up. There's lots of news.
Speaker 5:  Yes. And then we're gonna take a break for the summer. Yeah. Come back. Alright.
Speaker 5:  Let's talk about speaking of things named Max
Speaker 6:  Neli. This is the, this should be the greatest day in in
Speaker 6:  recent history in your household. Just the, our long
Speaker 6:  national nightmare of max streaming services is
Speaker 5:  Finally over. No, they didn't get rid of the word max.
Speaker 6:  That's fair.
Speaker 6:  Now it's a, now it's a qualifier. That's true. It's, it's an
Speaker 6:  adjective now. It's, and not, not the noun.
Speaker 5:  So the news is that Warner Bros Discovery had its upfronts this week. All
Speaker 5:  the streamers had their upfronts, that's where they present to advertisers.
Speaker 5:  All the new kinds of things they can buy the new content that will be out
Speaker 5:  on the services. And as part of the WBD
Speaker 5:  upfronts, they announced that the streaming service Max would now be
Speaker 5:  called HBO Max, which is what it was called to begin with.
Speaker 5:  And they changed it 50 times along the way. Landing on
Speaker 5:  Max Big campaign. They shoved it full of weird
Speaker 5:  discovery reality shows when we talk about all that history. And then they
Speaker 5:  realized that no one cared about that. What they wanted was HBO shows. So
Speaker 5:  they're taking the weird discovery reality shows out and renaming the whole
Speaker 5:  thing. HBO Max, which again is what it was called
Speaker 6:  And what everybody continued to call it. Like they just could not break that.
Speaker 5:  It's funny how much the at t Tom Warner deal is going to come up in this
Speaker 5:  episode. It's gonna come up a lot at
Speaker 5:  t Bought Time Warner, the only thing that that resulted in was
Speaker 5:  the grayscale four three Snyder cut that, that's what happened.
Speaker 5:  They bought at t bought Time Warner and then Zach Snyder was like, these
Speaker 5:  dorks have money and berated them with an online harassment campaign into
Speaker 5:  completing the Snyder cut the, the pinnacle of which was a gray
Speaker 5:  scale four three Snyder cut, which you can go watch right now. It's how Justice
Speaker 5:  is Gray. It continues to exist on the ServiceNow HBO Max. But
Speaker 5:  that in terms of concrete results of at and t
Speaker 5:  buying Time Warner, that is it. As near as I can tell,
Speaker 5:  oh many oh, thousands of jobs were lost. Oh, just a little side note.
Speaker 6:  Minor detail. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Many, many, many thousands of layoffs. But you got a four three gray scale
Speaker 5:  Snyder cut. It's in four three 'cause he, he wanted it to be an imax,
Speaker 5:  but no one has an IMAX screen in their house. So he is like tall. So
Speaker 5:  we're gonna go with four three, that literally his explanation four, three,
Speaker 5:  whatever. That's the, the only result of at t buying Tap Warner that you
Speaker 5:  can still see to this day or that resulted really in anything at all.
Speaker 5:  This turned out to be a bad idea because it turns out you can't build your
Speaker 5:  entire business on one movie.
Speaker 5:  It's really the only thing that happened. So they at and t sells Time Warner
Speaker 5:  to Warner Bros. Discovery to Discovery. David Zoff.
Speaker 5:  He's like, well you got this asset called HBO Max. That's the thing. That's
Speaker 5:  the streaming service that's already out. I'm gonna turn it into a competitor
Speaker 5:  Netflix by dumping all my stuff on it. Right. And then he renames it
Speaker 5:  Max. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  He smooshed Discovery Plus and HBO Max
Speaker 6:  together and called it Max essentially.
Speaker 5:  Yep. And also on this literally the same day he killed the
Speaker 5:  CNN plus streaming service that at t Time Warner had launched
Speaker 5:  just before selling their, their entire company to Discovery.
Speaker 5:  As of today, both of those big decisions have been completely rolled back.
Speaker 5:  Yep.
Speaker 6:  CNN Plus coming back. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  CNN Plus is coming back as a standalone streaming service. HBO Max
Speaker 5:  is now HBO Max again. And the discovery content has been pulled out of it.
Speaker 5:  Literally, oh, by the way, thousands of people have been laid off along the
Speaker 5:  way. Yep. Like, none of this has worked. And mostly people have
Speaker 5:  lost their jobs and now they're, you know, they're doing this acute marketing
Speaker 5:  campaign where they're like, we know we, we screwed. It's like, no, you really
Speaker 5:  screwed up.
Speaker 6:  This is such an unbelievable disaster that I like
Speaker 6:  I I you cannot put too fine a point on how stupid this company has been
Speaker 6:  throughout every single bit of this process. And, and they are, they're trying
Speaker 6:  to play it off like a joke they did in the press release announcing
Speaker 6:  this. They included the, the Ross and Rachel. We were on a break
Speaker 6:  thing, which like a cool timely cultural reference guys,
Speaker 6:  everybody knows what friends is now.
Speaker 6:  And then they did a thing where there was like the, the white smoke coming
Speaker 6:  out and they were like, we've picked a new brand. And it's like, no, no,
Speaker 6:  no. What happened? It's your idiots.
Speaker 5:  Like, and
Speaker 6:  You were over and over and the very, very thing that everybody said
Speaker 6:  the first day you announced this, which is that this is monumentally stupid
Speaker 6:  because you are taking the best brand in entertainment and just
Speaker 6:  deleting it from existence in the name of every
Speaker 6:  nonsensical thing that you wanna put on this platform. They're just unwinding
Speaker 6:  it completely. And then now again, there, there are lots of rumors
Speaker 6:  and some really good reporting out there that suggest that this company is
Speaker 6:  about to split up again. Like truly we are just going to have
Speaker 6:  accomplished nothing except burning a ton of money and losing many,
Speaker 6:  many jobs. Bad thing over and over and over again. They're
Speaker 5:  Really good at that thing. They're
Speaker 6:  Really good at that thing.
Speaker 5:  They're really good at cost cutting. We rail against mergers on the show
Speaker 5:  constantly. The thing with mergers, in particular mergers with Time Warner
Speaker 5:  is that all they do is delete jobs and make everyone look stupid. Yeah. Like
Speaker 5:  if you're out there being like, I could do a better job with this. I should
Speaker 5:  buy Time Warner. I I urge you to walk into the ocean and never look back
Speaker 5:  because that will be a more successful outcome for you than buying Time
Speaker 5:  Warner. It is the kiss of death. A OL Time Warner was a company
Speaker 5:  I used to work at it and, and GA was part of a OL Time Warner. And it
Speaker 5:  destroyed that company. It, it broke it in half care. Switcher wrote two
Speaker 5:  books about it. One of them has great greatest hell of any business book
Speaker 5:  ever. There must be a Pony in here somewhere. It's a quote from
Speaker 5:  I believe a Time Warner exec who said, this is a giant pile of shit in our
Speaker 5:  entire thesis. Is there has to be a pony in here somewhere.
Speaker 6:  My God. That's
Speaker 5:  Amazing. Incredible.
Speaker 6:  That is a really good line.
Speaker 6:  That's really good.
Speaker 5:  Incredible. You should just go read it. It's just a bunch of egos who think
Speaker 5:  they can just like manufacture a thing out of nothing. And that has been
Speaker 5:  the story of Time Warner this whole time. I guess this time it's just Warner
Speaker 5:  Time Inc. The other part of Time Warner was sold to, to Mark Benioff, CEO
Speaker 5:  of Salesforce, who immediately invested in Humane and then had Time
Speaker 5:  Magazine named the Humane Pin. One of the best inventions of the year
Speaker 5:  doing great. Everybody. So that's going great over there. Yeah. But you just
Speaker 5:  see that the problem is you keep buying the media asset and then
Speaker 5:  treating it like a commodity and thinking that's gonna work. And
Speaker 5:  thinking in particular that you can make something that isn't
Speaker 5:  fancy, fancy, just 'cause you have the Warner Brothers Library.
Speaker 5:  And so, you know, with a OL it was, we're gonna make a OL fancy by having
Speaker 5:  this big media company and people will buy a OL because of it. Essentially
Speaker 5:  the same thesis for at t at t's thesis was we will
Speaker 5:  preload like bite-sized versions of Game of Thrones on mid-range Android
Speaker 5:  phones. And that's why people will choose us instead of Verizon.
Speaker 5:  I don't have to say anything else about that. And then
Speaker 5:  Discovery's thesis was, David Zav is a mid market
Speaker 5:  reality schlock stir and he is gonna become a titan of
Speaker 5:  Hollywood by having Warner Bros and doing all this stuff.
Speaker 5:  And he immediately was like, what if instead of caring about the new
Speaker 5:  fancy thing I bought, I loaded it up with my mid-market schlock. And
Speaker 5:  you remember that slide from the beginning where they were like, here's the
Speaker 5:  stuff we make for women and here's the stuff we make for men. Yeah. And we're
Speaker 5:  like, bring these icons together. And it was, it was just such a, a
Speaker 5:  two sway of thinking about anything like
Speaker 5:  content people, humanity. Like it's like, this is an
Speaker 5:  NBA fever dream that will result in nothing but layoffs. And and here we
Speaker 5:  are. Well
Speaker 6:  Even in the most generous reading of what
Speaker 6:  happened that came true and Netflix just absolutely kicked
Speaker 6:  its ass at it up and down. Like even if you wanna say there is
Speaker 6:  room for one sort of all encompassing general purpose
Speaker 6:  at all things to all people, every level of content
Speaker 6:  streamer, that's Netflix. It was obvious then that it was gonna be
Speaker 6:  Netflix. And it has become even more entrenched as Netflix since
Speaker 6:  then. Like the idea was truly to come out
Speaker 6:  and out. Netflix. Netflix and Boy have a lot of companies died attempting
Speaker 6:  to out Netflix. Netflix.
Speaker 7:  Which is fascinating 'cause Netflix still has not figured out how
Speaker 7:  the like good movie part of making movies and Warner Brothers
Speaker 7:  like, as much as that's not going particularly well,
Speaker 7:  they at least still make movies people wanna watch. And Netflix has really
Speaker 7:  figured out how to do the like mid-tier totally average
Speaker 7:  reality show that they can just fill the library with.
Speaker 6:  Well, right. I ironically Netflix's whole thing,
Speaker 6:  like, do you remember years ago we were talking about like, can Netflix become
Speaker 6:  HBO before HBO could becomes Netflix? And the answer was like, actually neither
Speaker 6:  one happened, but Netflix didn't need to become HBO. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  What it realized is that we're just going to release so many
Speaker 6:  mediocre Chris Hemsworth movies that we're gonna make up for it in volume
Speaker 6:  and we're gonna have a lot of C minus action movies and just
Speaker 6:  infinity reality shows. And that solves most of our problem. And that actually
Speaker 6:  making good movies is really hard, but making a lot of like eh, movies is
Speaker 6:  pretty easy and all it costs is money. And so like Netflix has just
Speaker 6:  decimated the competition in that particular game. Yes. And so now
Speaker 6:  reading through all the stuff that David Zaslav in particular is
Speaker 6:  saying, it is the most like disingenuous
Speaker 6:  way of being like, I was wrong and we got our ass kicked. And so
Speaker 6:  we're gonna go back to our old strategy, which is what if we just made good
Speaker 6:  things and if the good job is just to make good things, you know, it's the
Speaker 6:  best brand ever for making good things. HBO like this is
Speaker 6:  what everybody said when they did it first. Like, why would you light on
Speaker 6:  fire the thing that most signifies quality entertainment?
Speaker 6:  And now they're like, what if we did quality entertainment?
Speaker 7:  I can't think of a single rebrand that's really like gone over well. So there's
Speaker 7:  always, there's always the knee-jerk reaction, but there truly, I cannot
Speaker 7:  think of another rebrand where for like, from the
Speaker 7:  moment it happened for years afterward, like
Speaker 7:  up through, you know, leaders in the industry saying
Speaker 7:  it was a bad idea forever. And that is what has happened with the
Speaker 7:  Max rebrand, right? Like we get to Ted Sarandos like a month ago being like,
Speaker 7:  what were they thinking? Which like at that point it's like, I, I
Speaker 7:  don't know. Do you, do you stick with it out of pure shame or do you just
Speaker 7:  take the hint from the guy who's really successful?
Speaker 5:  Well there's David, you've made the point many times that Netflix knows
Speaker 5:  its only real competition is YouTube. And once you have that
Speaker 5:  realization that you're competing for minutes in the day and the only real
Speaker 5:  competition for those minutes are video games and YouTube. Yep. You do two
Speaker 5:  things. One, you start making video games, which Netflix has started to do.
Speaker 5:  And two, you realize, oh, we're not here for fancy. Right.
Speaker 5:  The minutes in the day are being consumed by us on YouTube. Right, right.
Speaker 5:  Like we're we there's no CGI I here, wait and gentlemen, there
Speaker 5:  should be 'cause I think I should be dd, but we'll get to that.
Speaker 5:  But like, you know, YouTube content is fundamentally cheap. It's
Speaker 5:  vastly cheaper than the the stuff that HBO makes. And so Netflix has
Speaker 5:  just realized they can occupy a place on the middle of that cost curve
Speaker 5:  and have a huge amount of volume that's slightly better than YouTube. Yep.
Speaker 5:  And that's gonna be great. And I think what Z
Speaker 5:  Love wanted to do was play that exact same game
Speaker 5:  with stuff that doesn't feel like YouTube at all. That feels like weird cable
Speaker 5:  reality programming that is like just kind of fine. Like, it,
Speaker 5:  it it, it's not even a thing. It's not even a thing that YouTube offers you,
Speaker 5:  which is at least it's mostly real people talking to you. Right,
Speaker 5:  right. It's, it's like this other thing that still has these like weird high
Speaker 5:  production costs. And so Netflix is starting to get into it. They're gonna
Speaker 5:  relaunch Star search. Right. They've got John Mullaney doing
Speaker 5:  a live talk show. Yeah. But that stuff feels different. It like, it
Speaker 5:  qualitatively feels different than old school cable
Speaker 5:  reality programming. It qualitatively feels different than YouTube. It occupies
Speaker 5:  a different space and they're winning on the time. And then you're like,
Speaker 5:  sure, here's whatever garbage Netflix movie of the month. It's just like
Speaker 5:  the next thing you can watch, I think HBO's game is like White
Speaker 5:  Lotus, right. Like appointment prestige
Speaker 5:  programming that costs a bunch of money. Yeah. I I I don't know if that will
Speaker 5:  be successful. I don't know if he's trying to sell it again. It does feel
Speaker 5:  like he's trying to sell it again, but man, like
Speaker 5:  to just have missed it strategically so hard
Speaker 5:  because you could have built that stuff with HBO.
Speaker 6:  Right. And now they're saying this is the strategy, right?
Speaker 6:  Like they're just coming out and being like, oh, what we understand now is
Speaker 6:  that customers don't want just more stuff to watch. They
Speaker 6:  want the high quality stuff. And it's like, yeah,
Speaker 6:  that's, that's the HBO pitch. That's how HBO became this
Speaker 6:  like titanic least successful thing on
Speaker 6:  cable like that it worked. If you just have an
Speaker 6:  ongoing run of the busiest show on television,
Speaker 6:  which I think HBO has done more successfully probably than
Speaker 6:  every other network combined over the last several decades.
Speaker 6:  You can win and it works. It's hard. It's very
Speaker 6:  hard and you cannot manufacture it out of nothing. But the fact that HBO
Speaker 6:  has like built the culture that keeps this stuff coming is very impressive.
Speaker 6:  And so to look at that and be like, oh, we're just gonna sort of cast
Speaker 6:  that off to the side then to only several years later turn around and
Speaker 6:  realize, oh, people like good shows is just so
Speaker 6:  backwards and insane to me. Like to just completely ignore every
Speaker 6:  actual asset you have and then turn around and be like, oh, we had these
Speaker 6:  assets, those are cool. It's like, what are you doing? Just drives me
Speaker 6:  insane.
Speaker 5:  The story of HBO is super fascinating and where it came from and this challenge
Speaker 5:  of constantly trying to re-up
Speaker 5:  the creative 'cause the show end, right? It's just like, it's over
Speaker 5:  now. Like we, the white Lotus has to exist because the
Speaker 5:  previous HBO because succession is over. Right. Right. Like that was, has
Speaker 5:  really always been the engine of HBO. We did a decoder episode with Felix
Speaker 5:  Gillette and John Colan who wrote a book called It's Not tv, the Spectacular
Speaker 5:  Rise Revolution of Future of HBO. It's a great book which just details it.
Speaker 5:  We'll link that episode, you should go read that book. But they've gotta
Speaker 5:  get back to that. Right. It's not clear what Engine makes
Speaker 5:  the next white Lotus at HBO anymore. That's the problem.
Speaker 5:  And if they are trying to sell it, it's also not clear who would buy it
Speaker 5:  because that's just an expensive, risky proposition compared to here's a
Speaker 5:  bunch of cheap stuff, we hope you watch it. Which is kind of what they're
Speaker 5:  all doing right now.
Speaker 6:  I think Netflix should buy it and just rebrand as HBO
Speaker 6:  just as for one day as a bit, just to really knife
Speaker 6:  David Zov again,
Speaker 5:  Zoff should be fired. I I'm just gonna say it. This has been
Speaker 5:  such a disaster. Yes. That whatever border, and I
Speaker 5:  realize he's the one who bought it and his company and his deal. And if you
Speaker 5:  read the tiktoks of the deal back when he bought Warner Bros, he was
Speaker 5:  the savior, right? He like pitched at and t on this deal. They
Speaker 5:  at and t needed out because they were, they, they woke up one day and realized
Speaker 5:  they were at and t and this was, this had been a huge boondoggle and he,
Speaker 5:  we like rescued it by engineering the steel and all, you know, he's obviously
Speaker 5:  the source and all these stories. He like all these stories like describe
Speaker 5:  the ballrooms and restaurants and that they made the deal in
Speaker 5:  and it's like, dude, you sucked so bad. Like everyone saw it
Speaker 5:  coming. You pissed off everyone by canceling shows right away by
Speaker 5:  taking tax breaks on things that were already done, whether or not they were
Speaker 5:  good. Just a, just a mess. A a creative
Speaker 5:  financial mess from the start because this man does not know what
Speaker 5:  he's doing. And if there's a board of directors there, you
Speaker 5:  know, in the same way that like maybe Tesla's board of directors should take
Speaker 5:  a hard look at how the company's going and they won't. I it feels like
Speaker 5:  the Warner Bros discovery Board should take a hard look at what has happened
Speaker 5:  to that company under this management and be like, maybe somebody else
Speaker 5:  should do this. Yeah. Maybe when we, when maybe when we sell Warner Bros,
Speaker 5:  we ought to rethink this whole situation. 'cause this style of management
Speaker 5:  is effectively the only product they have consistently shipped is layoffs.
Speaker 6:  And Jake, to your point, it's not like this is a thing that is only obvious
Speaker 6:  in retrospect. Every everyone who was paying attention
Speaker 6:  has been saying this the whole time, including their competitors
Speaker 6:  who don't normally say things out loud about the Yes. Who but who were happy
Speaker 6:  to be like, boy it seems weird that if if you have HBO you just
Speaker 6:  stop calling it HBO.
Speaker 7:  I really can't think of any other company that has had such a like
Speaker 7:  obstinate position. Right. Like neli to to what you're saying.
Speaker 7:  They've just been fighting with everybody. Right. Everybody's telling them
Speaker 7:  this name change is bad. Everybody's telling them, Hey, maybe you should
Speaker 7:  release that movie everybody wants to watch. And they're, they're just like,
Speaker 7:  no, we're just gonna like pocket it. We we're, we're gonna save a
Speaker 7:  little bit of cash by not finishing it. Dude,
Speaker 5:  They lost Christopher Nolan.
Speaker 7:  Right, right. Like that is Heads would be spinning
Speaker 7:  at like any other functional studio. Yep. Like
Speaker 7:  people would be, would have lost their job over that. Right. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  People put so much work into
Speaker 7:  curating a roster of directors that they can rely on and getting the
Speaker 7:  best, you know, movies and shows and, you know, creators
Speaker 7:  to their studio. Those things take like ages to
Speaker 7:  build and they just lost it in, in, I mean weeks. Right.
Speaker 7:  Like he just right out the door. And it's just been a few years of that and
Speaker 7:  it, it, it is puzzling what the strategy is supposed to
Speaker 7:  be there.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The fact that I had to watch Oppenheimer on Peacock is maybe the worst
Speaker 6:  thing that David SLO
Speaker 7:  Did.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Now you've mentioned Peacock, So I need to disclose
Speaker 7:  Oh right. Just sort of a roundabout
Speaker 5:  Way. Their usual block of entertainment disclosures.
Speaker 5:  NBCUniversal, whose parent is Comcast is a minority investor in Roxy
Speaker 5:  Media. They, they, they hate us. Comcast does.
Speaker 5:  And we'll get to why
Speaker 7:  Shortly.
Speaker 5:  'cause we c we cover them as an ISP like the thing that we do. I
Speaker 5:  executive producer of Netflix show, which you can watch called the Future
Speaker 5:  of It, it pays us no money when you watch it. So fine.
Speaker 5:  That deal, that deal is long since over and in general we subscribe to all
Speaker 5:  these streaming services. I, there used to be more and we have a TikTok account,
Speaker 5:  it's at to Coder pod. It's like whatever you want. It's, we're, we're, we're
Speaker 5:  all tied up in all these things. But you know, it's not like these
Speaker 5:  companies have any love loss for our coverage.
Speaker 5:  The Nolan thing is like particularly interesting, right? Like you have a
Speaker 5:  director whose name alone allows you to be like, we're gonna spend
Speaker 5:  $400 trillion on a series of movies that are a
Speaker 5:  deep introspection on the nature of love and memory. And then, and they,
Speaker 5:  they will all be hits
Speaker 5:  cool. It's like, you don't lose that guy. No
Speaker 6:  One will understand any of them.
Speaker 5:  What? And he's like, what? We're just gonna, we're gonna let that guy walk.
Speaker 5:  And it's because they insisted on, on releasing day and date
Speaker 5:  with the streaming service. 'cause they, they thought the streaming service
Speaker 5:  was the point. And if you are Warner Bros, the point is making the
Speaker 5:  movies. If you're HBO the Point is making the great shows, not the
Speaker 5:  streaming service. Yes, you need to have the business to support that effort.
Speaker 5:  But the thing that's valuable is the work. You know, we talk about Netflix,
Speaker 5:  they're quickly coming to place where the thing that's valuable is the service
Speaker 5:  and the work is just sort of fine and it's medium and it it, it propels it
Speaker 5:  along and everyone is jealous of that. But you can't get there
Speaker 5:  unless you have their scale and you never will. Even
Speaker 6:  Netflix is, is starting to run into troubles with that. Right? Like there
Speaker 6:  was all this reporting a while ago about the, after the huge Barbie hit,
Speaker 6:  Greta Gerwig is doing Chronicles of Narnia movies and they had this big fight
Speaker 6:  over Greta Gerwig wanted it to be in theaters because people
Speaker 6:  who make films want them to be in theaters. Netflix was like, no, we don't
Speaker 6:  do theaters. And so they had this big fight and eventually Greta Gerwig won
Speaker 6:  and it's gonna get a theatrical run. So like Netflix is, is
Speaker 6:  desperately trying to get away from the work, mattering in in a lot of ways,
Speaker 6:  but I think is still able to play that game the right way.
Speaker 6:  And all David Zaslav seems to be able to do is just swing from zero
Speaker 6:  to a hundred. Those are his only two moves.
Speaker 7:  I don't really know what's in Netflix's interest at this point. To, to
Speaker 7:  not a a allow those theatrical runs. Right. Especially if you're going to
Speaker 7:  make movies that are allegedly supposed to be, you know, big
Speaker 7:  budget hits. That's how you build buzz. People
Speaker 7:  like seeing things in theaters. Don't get me wrong, it's great. Like I,
Speaker 7:  during the pandemic when I could just be like, boop, zoom like
Speaker 7:  boop and, and watch Dune on like the first. Like it's great. Love it.
Speaker 7:  But if you're gonna, you know, upset an entire community
Speaker 7:  of people who you need to rely on to make the stuff that makes your
Speaker 7:  business, maybe you should just do that. Right. Especially if it's going
Speaker 7:  to make you a lot more money. There's
Speaker 5:  Just a vanishing number of people with the leverage to do that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like, and I think it's in Netflix's interest to make sure there, there's
Speaker 5:  never another Christopher Nolan. Mm.
Speaker 6:  Right. I mean the, the F1 movie this summer is gonna be a really interesting
Speaker 6:  test case here because it is, it is such a big swing.
Speaker 6:  It's a big movie. It's gonna be in theaters, it's Brad Pitt. A lot of people
Speaker 6:  are paying attention that like, it's gonna be super ugly
Speaker 6:  for Apple if this doesn't work. And I've heard a bunch of people who are
Speaker 6:  really concerned that it is not going to work. And unless this
Speaker 6:  thing is a big giant hit, it's gonna, I suspect make every streamer
Speaker 6:  look even more sideways at the idea of like really giving these
Speaker 6:  things a public run. Like they don't share numbers for a reason and you have
Speaker 6:  to when it goes to theaters.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I have a lot of feelings for that F1 movie.
Speaker 5:  I suspect it will not be a hit just having watched the trailers. I think
Speaker 5:  they're trying to Days of Thunder F1, you know what I mean? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And like
Speaker 5:  Days of Thunder only worked 'cause it was, it was Top Gun again.
Speaker 5:  Like literally it was just, they were like, well that was a great movie.
Speaker 5:  We haven't invented sequels yet. It's the eighties. We're gonna do Top Gun
Speaker 5:  Two
Speaker 6:  Top Gun but on the ground. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And it was like way more expensive and way worse in like lots of ways and
Speaker 5:  it whatever. But like
Speaker 5:  literally like structurally that movie worked because you're like,
Speaker 5:  what Tom Cruise is gonna do is drive faster than everyone else at the end
Speaker 5:  of this movie. Yep. And like F1 fans know that
Speaker 5:  that is not a thing an F1 car can just do, do you know what I
Speaker 5:  mean?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They're all pretty much going as fast as they can all the time. Right.
Speaker 5:  And the cars are different in a way that NASCAR cars are like, there's like
Speaker 5:  a literally a plot point in, in
Speaker 5:  in Days of Thunder where they're like, you have to learn how to drive the
Speaker 5:  car. And he is like, sure. And like, you can't do that in F1.
Speaker 5:  Like, like this movie is going to make no sense 'cause they're gonna try
Speaker 5:  to Days of Thunder F1 and every F1 fan is gonna be mad.
Speaker 6:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  We'll just see how it goes. It's
Speaker 6:  Gonna go great. What could possibly, what could possibly go great
Speaker 5:  Also the the last Brad Pitt movie, the George Clean Wolfs
Speaker 5:  on Apple tv. Like didn't, it was fine. It was extremely fine.
Speaker 6:  It was extremely, it was the most plain movie I've watched in a long
Speaker 6:  time.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean it it, it was, it was like so deeply fine
Speaker 5:  in a way that like you get the sense they were trying to make Mr. And Mrs. Smith
Speaker 5:  again, but like George Clooney was Angelina Jolie and you're
Speaker 5:  like, well there's still, there's still an odd amount of sexual attention
Speaker 5:  here. Like Oh yeah. Much more than I expected.
Speaker 6:  Oh
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But not, it's not
Speaker 6:  Mr I ship the two of For sure.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Anyhow, we'll see how that goes. There's more streaming news in this
Speaker 5:  zone because Yeah. None of these people can stop asking you for money.
Speaker 5:  Speaking of plans that have gone away and come back and once again
Speaker 5:  risen. ESPN is launching its own app for $30 a month. 'cause I think
Speaker 5:  they've realized the cable bundle can't save Disney. It's, it's, it's over.
Speaker 5:  Fox is gonna launch it's sports app. It's called Fox One.
Speaker 5:  It doesn't launch for the NFL season. That's when you would do it. It's not
Speaker 6:  Technically just sports, it's also for, you know, right
Speaker 6:  wing propaganda and, and various other things. But it's mostly for sports.
Speaker 6:  All of these are mostly for sports.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. 'cause that's what they have the rights to. Right. And they've all
Speaker 5:  spent billions of dollars buying these rights. Yes. I And
Speaker 5:  like there's just moves that are, YouTube has Sunday ticket, they're gonna
Speaker 5:  stream in NFL game for free when the season kicks off.
Speaker 5:  There is just a thing here where like live sports is the last thing that
Speaker 5:  can bring everyone together. Like it's not even award shows anymore because
Speaker 5:  no one's seen any of the movies.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like there's just a thing here that's like really happening and
Speaker 5:  it's at the end of this, you're kind of like, man, we're gonna be paying
Speaker 5:  substantially more than cable bundles ever were.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. And there was a, there was a great thing going around the other
Speaker 6:  day after all this got announced. 'cause to your point that's you just named
Speaker 6:  three new places to watch football this coming season. And,
Speaker 6:  and now it's like you're up to legitimately like 10 streaming services
Speaker 6:  you're gonna need if you wanna watch all the games
Speaker 6:  next year of the NFL season. 'cause like Netflix has Christmas games again,
Speaker 6:  they're, they're spread across all the different services again. Like it's
Speaker 6:  awful and it's only gonna keep getting worse because that to your point,
Speaker 6:  is the only thing that these companies have found that lots and lots of people
Speaker 6:  will reliably go to on purpose and jump through
Speaker 6:  whatever hoops they have to. Like, I will, I will do whatever is required
Speaker 6:  to watch football is only true about football and basically nothing else.
Speaker 7:  There's also something interesting, interesting there in, in that, I can't
Speaker 7:  think of anything else where like the rights are so spread out
Speaker 7:  like that, right? Like it's not like YouTube can get one Spider-Man
Speaker 7:  movie. Like that's just not a thing. Right. With ip It it, but the,
Speaker 7:  the, the licensing deals for all the different networks are
Speaker 7:  so spread out and split up that you have the situation where, I have no idea
Speaker 7:  why YouTube was only able to acquire one
Speaker 7:  NFL game, but people are gonna go find it there because they like
Speaker 7:  football, they like the NFL, they're going to watch it and you just
Speaker 7:  can't do that with anything else since they're able to get the property onto
Speaker 7:  their platform. And it just works like beyond the fact that yes, obviously
Speaker 7:  sports is incredibly popular and people would watch it no matter what.
Speaker 5:  Well also the, you know, the the rights holders are are differently
Speaker 5:  situated. So if you are, well it's, it's funny 'cause
Speaker 5:  Disney owns everything now, but at the time if you were Marvel
Speaker 5:  you could sell Spider-Man to, to
Speaker 5:  Sony and X-Men to Fox
Speaker 5:  and the rest of the characters you would like make your own weird movies
Speaker 5:  on with John Favreau. And that turned out to be a really big deal. Right.
Speaker 5:  And they didn't know what would work and what wouldn't work. Right.
Speaker 5:  Sports leagues every game is like, it
Speaker 5:  has a value in a moment of time and then that value goes to zero. And so
Speaker 5:  they are very much incentivized to not sell like
Speaker 5:  franchises or long running things to let people go and try to get value out
Speaker 5:  of over time. They're very much incentivized to be like, all right, you can
Speaker 5:  can have Thursday and you can have Sunday and you can have, you know, the
Speaker 5:  slate of games during the week because after it's done
Speaker 5:  there's no residual value.
Speaker 6:  Right. They have to make an event of it
Speaker 5:  Every single
Speaker 6:  And that incentivizes them 'cause they,
Speaker 5:  It's over for.
Speaker 6:  That's done. There's,
Speaker 5:  There's no catalog value. And you can see they don't even really care about
Speaker 5:  like old highlights and like Right, right. Like they're just like, whatever.
Speaker 5:  You can have it. 'cause all that is just advertising for whatever's gonna
Speaker 5:  happen next in a way that like, you know, Marvel
Speaker 5:  gets tons of values from Avengers and Game continuing to exist forever.
Speaker 5:  And it, it is like, it's just a very different posture for the leagues and
Speaker 5:  they are, they have become incredibly good at milking it
Speaker 5:  in a way that I would say has forced
Speaker 5:  many people to consider sailing the stormy seas.
Speaker 6:  And, and it's easier and easier all the time to do so. But no,
Speaker 6:  I mean, and you look at it,
Speaker 5:  You get a boat for nothing. And
Speaker 6:  Like the way that you get all of this stuff is like the, the
Speaker 6:  NFL in particular has done a really good job of
Speaker 6:  getting around its own contracts. Like they keep coming up with
Speaker 6:  new days to have games. They keep calling the games new kinds of things.
Speaker 6:  They keep putting them in new places because they have these
Speaker 6:  incredibly specific deals about where things
Speaker 6:  can be and when, and I mean if you remember, it wasn't all that long ago
Speaker 6:  that Verizon had NFL games
Speaker 6:  specifically on mobile, but you could only watch them on your phone because
Speaker 6:  that was the deal that Verizon had made on mobile. So if you wanted to watch
Speaker 6:  NFL games on your phone, you had to have Verizon. But if you had Verizon,
Speaker 6:  you couldn't watch NFL games on anything other than your phone. Like the
Speaker 6:  NFL is now worth so much money. And it, it is the only
Speaker 6:  thing that actually can claim to be an event that way.
Speaker 6:  Like you're seeing baseball deals go down and other sports league are going
Speaker 6:  down in their their deals because no one is
Speaker 6:  tuning in in that way. And people will not jump through hoops to sign up
Speaker 6:  for Amazon just to watch a Cincinnati Reds game anymore.
Speaker 6:  But they will with football games. And so the, the price keeps going up and
Speaker 6:  they keep finding new ways to slice and dice it. And it is truly, truly
Speaker 6:  awful as a fan, but as a, like the Harvard
Speaker 6:  Business School case study is like pretty spectacular.
Speaker 5:  It's very funny that even the NFL's like slicing and dicing of its schedule
Speaker 5:  into different days, the days have be, have gotten reputations. Like
Speaker 5:  you just know that you can drink your way through a Thursday half football
Speaker 5:  game
Speaker 6:  Fine.
Speaker 5:  Like the value of these different things. If it's funny how they just like
Speaker 5:  sort themselves out. Alright, we got to, we wanna end here
Speaker 5:  on again, just to remind everyone, the only thing David SLO has ever
Speaker 5:  created is layoffs. Yep. And Max was a disaster and he stole my child's name,
Speaker 5:  which I'm still pissed about, but now it's back.
Speaker 6:  You're gonna name your second child HBO. Right? Just to, just to really bring
Speaker 6:  it full circle
Speaker 5:  Baby boy Peacock Patel is
Speaker 6:  Oh, I like that.
Speaker 5:  It's naming this kid's hard. It's, it's, it's very challenging. I I will
Speaker 5:  accept your recommendations. Max actually has a very strong point of view
Speaker 5:  and she's gonna win because we have nothing, we have nothing to stand up
Speaker 5:  to her with right now. So let me know what, let me know what you think. All
Speaker 5:  right. We have a take a break. We're gonna come back. There's lots gonna
Speaker 5:  talk about, I'm gonna episode of verse House
Speaker 5:  All right, we're back. We're gonna do it. We're gonna, we're gonna pay off
Speaker 5:  the thing that we teased in the intro, which I would say we have a
Speaker 5:  50% success rate of doing. Yeah. Seems generous, but
Speaker 2:  I'll take it.
Speaker 5:  So we're, we're gonna do it. Lots and lots of news this week. Lots of gadget
Speaker 5:  news. Lots of tech news. We gotta start with like a finally,
Speaker 5:  I I feel like a finally is worth it. Apple has announced that what
Speaker 5:  it is now calling CarPlay Ultra is going to arrive
Speaker 5:  it's shipping first on new Aston Martin cars and then if you
Speaker 5:  have a new Aston Martin with the latest infotainment
Speaker 5:  system, you can go to your dealer and get a software update and then you,
Speaker 5:  you two will have CarPlay Ultra then they announced there is coming to a
Speaker 5:  bunch of other car car companies. Porsche is supposed to do it. They
Speaker 5:  announced that Hyundai Kia and Genesis would also get it, which are new partners.
Speaker 5:  No timelines in any of this stuff. Yeah. CarVal Ultra is a concept
Speaker 5:  we've covered very closely, like so closely that when I was
Speaker 5:  searching for our own coverage and I typed Neli Patel CarPlay
Speaker 5:  Google generated full AI summary of my opinions
Speaker 5:  about CarPlay.
Speaker 5:  Like we, there's a lot of us talking about CarPlay over the years. So several
Speaker 5:  years ago with 2023, I wanna say Apple announced Next
Speaker 5:  Gen CarPlay and it was just a picture of the, you know, an interior of
Speaker 5:  a car with lots of screens and it was all CarPlay. And they're like, we're
Speaker 5:  doing it. And then they put up a slide, if you remember this, they put up
Speaker 5:  a, a slide with like every Car Maker's logo.
Speaker 5:  And what we learned is that many of those car makers were surprised
Speaker 5:  by their inclusion on this slide. Like they're like, what are you talking
Speaker 5:  about? Yeah. Because they all had regular CarPlay, which people like,
Speaker 5:  and Apple was just like, of course, of course they're gonna do what we tell
Speaker 5:  them to do. And they, they were not ready for this. A year later
Speaker 5:  last year, apple had announced no partners for next generation
Speaker 5:  CarPlay. They had said to Porsche and asked Martin would do it by the end
Speaker 5:  of last year. And that didn't happen. And then like
Speaker 6:  Sneakily removed that mention from their website. Yeah, it was, it,
Speaker 6:  it's, it got further and further away as time went on, it seemed,
Speaker 5:  And then they announced a bunch of technical details about how this next
Speaker 5:  generation of CarPlay would work. I wrote a lot about that. I took a lot
Speaker 5:  of meetings. I've had a lot of car company CEOs on decoder and
Speaker 5:  asked them straight up, are you gonna do this? And most of them have said
Speaker 5:  no. Famously at Mercedes, CEO Lanius said, no,
Speaker 5:  Rivian, CEO RJ Sccr said, no. We've had the heads of product
Speaker 5:  from GM on, he, he was not impressed by, it's like
Speaker 5:  there's a lot of car companies that are like, we are not gonna give up our
Speaker 5:  interface to Apple. Like we have our own ideas about software and services.
Speaker 5:  You might think they're horrible ideas, and in many cases they are. Yep.
Speaker 5:  But they are their own companies and they would like to own their own relationships
Speaker 5:  with customers. And that's just how it goes. So Apple had to re-architect
Speaker 5:  all of this from, we're gonna take over all your screens and
Speaker 5:  CarPlay will be the future of the car to this literally
Speaker 5:  multi-layered approach to what the car companies control and what Apple controls
Speaker 5:  and all these like hybrid bits and bobs in the middle. It has taken 'em
Speaker 5:  forever to get even one of these cars shipped with these deals in place.
Speaker 5:  And the way I would characterize it is that it's a complete walk
Speaker 5:  back. Like they've, they're announcing CarPlay Ultra and yes,
Speaker 5:  there's all this stuff you can do in the car with your phone now, but if
Speaker 5:  you just take a minute to like look at what it is, you're like, oh,
Speaker 5:  they, they're, it's kind of nothing like, I, I don't
Speaker 5:  wanna be like too rude. It's, it's something, it was, obviously it's a long
Speaker 5:  time and they, but they had to do it. But the actual
Speaker 5:  practical effect of it is so small.
Speaker 7:  I'm genuinely confused what they have put in all of this work for CarPlay
Speaker 7:  makes a ton of sense, right? It is fantastic. You can use your phone to
Speaker 7:  control things in your car. It gets rid of a bunch of the worst parts of
Speaker 7:  car controls CarPlay Ultra. Like, do I need an
Speaker 7:  iOS themed speedometer? Like I, that seems like, what else does it
Speaker 7:  do? What does it do for me that meaningfully improves the car experience?
Speaker 7:  What does it do for Apple?
Speaker 5:  So I know exactly what it does for Apple, which is as you're using your apps
Speaker 5:  in the car and you're pushing the buttons in the apps, those apps are actually
Speaker 5:  running on your phone and Apple's collecting its 30% cut.
Speaker 5:  That's what it does for Apple, right? It puts their operating system and
Speaker 5:  their business model front and center as you're operating your car.
Speaker 5:  That's a big deal. That's their business. And it keeps
Speaker 5:  the automakers from putting their business models front and center of the
Speaker 5:  car, which is the entire tension. GM's entire, like
Speaker 5:  conception of itself right now is like we're a software vendor and it's like,
Speaker 5:  are you, and I dunno if that's real or not, but like that's what they wanna
Speaker 5:  do. They want have services in the car. Tesla's conception of Itself's very
Speaker 5:  much as a software maker. So as Rivian, like they believe that they should
Speaker 5:  own a customer relationship of people doing stuff in the car, particularly
Speaker 5:  as a car start driving themselves. So for Apple, a CarPlay Ultra is
Speaker 5:  if you're gonna buy stuff in your car, we want 30%
Speaker 5:  Apple. Like what, what else is their business model?
Speaker 7:  I see. So there's, this is a long play, right? Like I'm not, I'm not
Speaker 7:  playing
Speaker 7:  got Angry Birds in the car right now, but like eventually, you know, yeah.
Speaker 7:  It's, and and it'll, it'll theme itself based on how fast my car is
Speaker 7:  automatically driving,
Speaker 5:  Right? The idea is that, that there shouldn't be another software ecosystem
Speaker 5:  that you participate in your car, right? And you can kinda dress straight
Speaker 5:  line like people like CarPlay, like we should do more with CarPlay. And
Speaker 5:  then there's this real tension in the industry over, well
Speaker 5:  eventually the cars will drive themselves and we're gonna turn the all these
Speaker 5:  screens into shopping malls and who gets the money and who gets, keeps credit
Speaker 5:  cards. And, and, and that's just gonna play itself out. The, what the
Speaker 5:  automakers have like really been wondering about is like, Hey,
Speaker 5:  we don't want all the cars to look the same. Right? You, you get
Speaker 5:  into an Aston Martin, it should look different than a Porsche. It should
Speaker 5:  look different than a Hyundai. So we need all this design control, which
Speaker 5:  Apple did not want to give up initially. And so they ended in this place
Speaker 5:  where I suspect CarPlay Ultra
Speaker 5:  will just stop being relevant very fast. Because
Speaker 5:  what they've done is they've broken the car's UI
Speaker 5:  into layers. And so there's one layer that runs
Speaker 5:  locally in the car that has nothing to do with your phone that has been themed
Speaker 5:  with by Apple and the car maker together. That's like your speedometer, your
Speaker 5:  turn signals the odometer, which you can't screw with federally, right?
Speaker 5:  Like there's some stuff that you just can't connect to
Speaker 5:  a phone like you, it has to be there. So then the automaker gets that
Speaker 5:  locally. Then there's the first time you plug your, you know, your
Speaker 5:  CarPlay phone into your CarPlay Ultra car, it like
Speaker 5:  downloads a bunch of themes and graphics packages that Apple has designed
Speaker 5:  in connection with the car maker, right? So I'm guessing what that means
Speaker 5:  is Apple designed it for them. Like no knowing Apple, they, they did it
Speaker 5:  for the car maker and that downloads to your car and then you get a bunch
Speaker 5:  of themes for this speedometer and other stuff that are still local,
Speaker 5:  like the car's doing them. But the, the design comes
Speaker 5:  over the air from Apple through your phone and then you can like click through
Speaker 5:  it and then you get stuff like maps in the cluster and all the stuff. And
Speaker 5:  then the last piece, which is I think super
Speaker 5:  interesting 'cause it's the thing that Apple I think had to give up is
Speaker 5:  called punch through ui where the car maker has a bunch
Speaker 5:  of stuff that it wants to do
Speaker 5:  the rear view camera. Yep. The controls for a
Speaker 5:  fancy audio system, the massaging seat controls like a lot
Speaker 5:  of this stuff where it doesn't want to make
Speaker 5:  it twice, right? Here's whatever custom fancy feature we've built
Speaker 5:  for this car. We don't want to redesign it with Apple.
Speaker 5:  That just comes through CarPlay, it punches through the CarPlay
Speaker 5:  interface. And so you push a button and you just see the Car Maker's ui.
Speaker 5:  So now you have this like mishmash of stuff, which is exactly ends the
Speaker 5:  promise of Apple will take over all the screens in your car.
Speaker 5:  'cause now it's gone from, at least it's bad. But Consi now it's, 'cause
Speaker 5:  now it's gone from it's bad car maker ui, but at least it's consistent to,
Speaker 5:  it's mostly Apple design stuff. And if you hit the wrong button, the
Speaker 5:  Carmaker's bad UI shows up and you've gotta use that screen. And I don't,
Speaker 5:  I just like, dunno how that's gonna play out. Do
Speaker 6:  You remember back in the day with like smart TVs, everybody would do their
Speaker 6:  really like overwrought skin on top of Android, but then you'd open up settings
Speaker 6:  and it would just be like the basic honeycomb Android thing. Like that's
Speaker 6:  what this is. And it's, it's not good ui. But I
Speaker 6:  also feel like there's been this macro shift since Apple launched this
Speaker 6:  the first time three years ago,
Speaker 6:  people went buttons like this. I I just went back and looked at,
Speaker 6:  there's a, there's a picture in Apple's press release
Speaker 6:  happily announcing that it has launched CarPlay Ultra, which sure.
Speaker 6:  Compared to the picture that they showed off the, when it was called
Speaker 6:  Next Generation CarPlay at ww DC back in 2022. It was even earlier
Speaker 6:  than I remembered. And the, the thing
Speaker 6:  from 2022 is just screens everywhere, right? So the, the
Speaker 6:  way it, it imagines this is sort of one wide horizontal
Speaker 6:  screen all the way across the front of the car and then big huge
Speaker 6:  infotainment thing in the middle that looks sort of like standard CarPlay
Speaker 6:  only more. So that was the idea and that was how everybody was showing
Speaker 6:  off concept cars back in the day. The Aston Martin one
Speaker 6:  is a pretty small screen in the center of a console
Speaker 6:  with a bunch of buttons. Like it just, it just looks like a car screen.
Speaker 6:  And so it's actually like a pretty small CarPlay display. And then
Speaker 6:  Jake, to your point, the only new thing here is a
Speaker 6:  speedometer that Apple designed that you can put, you can put Apple
Speaker 6:  Maps in, in the center of the instrument cluster so that you can see it,
Speaker 6:  you get a little tiny heads up display and there's a couple different color
Speaker 6:  themes. Yeah. Like the, the ambition of this thing, at least as
Speaker 6:  it's been rolled out now again, there, there might be more cars, there might
Speaker 6:  be other stuff going on, but at least this first instantiation of it is so
Speaker 6:  much smaller than what Apple was pitching at the
Speaker 6:  beginning. That it, it's kind of, if it had just described this, we
Speaker 6:  would've been like, oh sure, that kind of makes sense. That that's cool.
Speaker 6:  It's like a, it's like an extension of the look of CarPlay onto the other
Speaker 6:  screen that you look at in your car. But
Speaker 5:  Again, functionally it is not. Right. The thing you're gonna
Speaker 5:  get from we skinned the cluster is
Speaker 5:  between the speedometer and the tachometer is a middle display
Speaker 5:  that can show another view of CarPlay apps. Yeah. Which lots
Speaker 5:  of cars already have now. Right? So like functionally Yep. They Apple
Speaker 5:  designed the speedometer and then you asked more. It's like, oh, that's,
Speaker 5:  that's nothing. Right? Like Right. And then it's the Center of CarPlay
Speaker 5:  experience is still the same as it was. If you look at the picture, it's
Speaker 5:  still just a grid of icons. It is, it's not meaningfully new in that way,
Speaker 5:  except some more controls have been integrated into CarPlay
Speaker 5:  and because of punch through ui you can push a button and like adjust the
Speaker 5:  fancy speaker system using the native interface of the car
Speaker 5:  maker. But that, that was a click away before. Right. It, it
Speaker 5:  wasn't that, it was just like functionally it's not that much more different.
Speaker 5:  Right. At all.
Speaker 6:  If Apple had announced that in 2022, it probably would've shipped in 2022.
Speaker 6:  Do you know what I mean? Like Yeah. If if it had just explained it that
Speaker 6:  way, the way that you just explained it, all the automakers on that slide
Speaker 6:  would've been like, yeah, sure, fine. Whatever you wanna, you wanna let it
Speaker 6:  show Apple Maps between this speedometer and the tecom while you're driving?
Speaker 6:  Sure. Great. Fine.
Speaker 5:  But and they did because the original CarPlay, which by the way will continue.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. They're just gonna keep making regular CarPlay. This is CarPlay Ultra
Speaker 5:  that is going to continue where you still get mirroring of maps
Speaker 5:  onto the, the center cluster. And lots of cars have that. And in fact,
Speaker 5:  every time another car is launched with it, people have been confused
Speaker 5:  because they assume that that is next generation CarPlay. Yeah. And we have
Speaker 5:  run story after story being like, no, that's just regular CarPlay. Next
Speaker 5:  Gen CarPlay is when your phone begins to
Speaker 5:  operate more like the interface of the car directly, like all of the
Speaker 5:  screens directly in this weird hybrid fashion are
Speaker 5:  operated by with Apple design products that come from your phone.
Speaker 6:  Right. The idea was that you should be able to control the temperature of
Speaker 6:  the cabin through CarPlay.
Speaker 5:  Right. And so that, so that's one that's really interesting. Right? If you
Speaker 5:  look at Apple's own designs of what an HVAC screen should look like, it's
Speaker 5:  not some beautiful Johnny Ive reinvention of an HVAC
Speaker 5:  screen. It's not Steve Jobs showing all the old smartphones and mean like
Speaker 5:  here's why they suck. Like here's the new I it's just an HVAC screen.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like it down to like the weird sliders and the sync button for the multiple
Speaker 5:  zones that like every car maker has, like they didn't actually do it. Right.
Speaker 5:  It it is just Apple design riff on a very
Speaker 5:  standard HVAC screen. So if you're a car maker, I, when, when
Speaker 5:  as these cars come out, I would say the HVAC screen is the thing to
Speaker 5:  look at to see how important this is. Because if the car makers give that
Speaker 5:  to Apple, then they think there's some value there. If they do the punch
Speaker 5:  through UI where they just show their own HVAC
Speaker 5:  screen, you will know they do not give a shit. Yeah. That this is just another
Speaker 5:  feature on the spec sheet. Every car YouTube review that I've ever watched
Speaker 5:  that literally, whoever, it doesn't matter who, it's Doug DeMiro Forests
Speaker 5:  Marquez on the auto focus channel, they wave at the center screen and like
Speaker 5:  it has CarPlay Android Auto and they just move on 'cause they don't care.
Speaker 6:  Yep.
Speaker 5:  Right. And like, that's how you will know that this thing matters or doesn't
Speaker 5:  matter if everyone just punches through their own HVAC controls.
Speaker 6:  But the other thing that has happened is we've gone back to buttons
Speaker 6:  like, again, rewind three years ago. And there was this idea that actually
Speaker 6:  what we want is a car cabin full of screens. And
Speaker 6:  overwhelmingly customers told car companies, no, you know, what I
Speaker 6:  want is buttons. I want to, I want to be able to feel the temperature
Speaker 6:  control so that I don't have to look for it while I'm driving down the highway.
Speaker 6:  And like company after company has gone back to saying, okay, we're gonna
Speaker 6:  actually have physical controls in the car. And I
Speaker 5:  Think there's one other thing driving that I, I agree. Buttons are great.
Speaker 5:  Buy a car with buttons, you know, send the signal in the market that, you
Speaker 5:  know, be the hero America needs.
Speaker 5:  But also a bunch of these car makers put in all these screens and they realized
Speaker 5:  they had no idea what to do with them. Right. Like sure at all. Even
Speaker 5:  that CarPlay, that first CarPlay made from 2022, it has like five
Speaker 5:  calendars on it because they just didn't know what to fill the pixels with.
Speaker 5:  Right. They're like another clock widget that'll do it. And, and you know,
Speaker 5:  the thinking is like some applications will be developed to fill these screens
Speaker 5:  and there's nothing You're so Right. It
Speaker 6:  Has a, it has a, it has a music widget that is just like the progress
Speaker 6:  bar of the song that is, it's gotta be three feet wide. Yeah. It's
Speaker 5:  Incredible. Yeah. You know, we have a passenger screen
Speaker 5:  in our Grand Cherokee. We've never turned it on. I have all the, I had all
Speaker 5:  these dreams that Becky would like drive me around. I watch like watch football
Speaker 5:  on the passenger screen and it's like five HDMI dongles later and like,
Speaker 5:  nope, I'm just gonna watch it on my phone. Which is almost as big as the
Speaker 5:  screen. I test drove a Cadillac Vista
Speaker 5:  for a weekend. It's great. It's their new three row electric ev I'm gonna
Speaker 5:  write about it. It it's great. It's a great car. It has huge screen in it.
Speaker 5:  Like one of those big curvy Cadillac ods. And I was just like, what is all
Speaker 5:  this? What, what do you, I I have three maps open right now. I have
Speaker 5:  a three foot podcast time elapse slider. Like what
Speaker 5:  is this for the, the new Escalate iq, which
Speaker 5:  is even bigger and has even more screens. You're like, oh, this is, it's
Speaker 5:  10, it's 10 maps.
Speaker 5:  Like maybe, maybe like three different Mac applications. Like why not Let's
Speaker 5:  let's have a good time. And I think they realized the utility of these screens
Speaker 5:  was dropping. Like there was no nothing to use them for. Really.
Speaker 5:  People weren't using apps and shopping on them and then the customers were
Speaker 5:  like, we hate touching these screens. Yep. And
Speaker 5:  yeah, I think Apple got caught into that like, larger trend, but I also think
Speaker 5:  they, they just oversold what they were trying to do and all the car makers,
Speaker 5:  like, why would we give you our customers this way?
Speaker 6:  And all the customers were like, I don't care about any of this. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And we still get a lot of notes whenever we cover a CarPlay. I'm not a CarPlay
Speaker 5:  fan. I, we, we use it in our older cars. I bought a
Speaker 5:  box, I've, I have this like 2016 Mercedes C
Speaker 5:  43. It does not have any like, it's the worst screen in the world. And I
Speaker 5:  bought a box. I literally had the radio and I bought a box that
Speaker 5:  sits, you plug the radio into the box and the box into the screen and it
Speaker 5:  hijacks the screen to put CarPlay on it. That's great. That's, it's like
Speaker 5:  I upgraded, it's a total hack and that's like fine. Right?
Speaker 5:  Sure. But we don't use it in our cars that are good.
Speaker 5:  Like my not garbage cars. We like, don't use this thing. And I, there's a
Speaker 5:  lot of reasons for that and kind of the number one is CarPlay is a
Speaker 5:  single application interface. You can get widgets, right?
Speaker 5:  So you can have a, a music player and the map open at the same time, but
Speaker 5:  they're both widgets. They're not actually the apps. Right. And what we want
Speaker 5:  is the map open and the music player open so you can like screw with it.
Speaker 5:  So we just mount a film like everyone does. And I, this doesn't solve that
Speaker 5:  core problem. Hold
Speaker 6:  On, hold on. Statistically everyone uses CarPlay.
Speaker 5:  This is not true. It's not true. Lots and lots
Speaker 5:  of people. This is now I'm just gonna issue bug requests to Apple.
Speaker 5:  This what is the show for? So if you look right now in like various support
Speaker 5:  forums, they just changed CarPlay so that no matter
Speaker 5:  what you're doing on your phone, it happens in CarPlay. And
Speaker 5:  the thing that a lot of people had figured out was you could take Google
Speaker 5:  Maps out of CarPlay, you can open a CarPlay preferences
Speaker 5:  on your phone and you can take Google Maps out. Oh sure. Or you
Speaker 5:  just hit the minus button. So then you have Google Maps open on your phone
Speaker 5:  and your music or podcast or whatever running on CarPlay, which was the number
Speaker 5:  one use of CarPlay. When we hear from listeners or readers about why they
Speaker 5:  like CarPlay, it's, I have 45 audio apps. Yep.
Speaker 5:  Right. I have, I have whatever ebook reader I'm doing. I have not my podcast
Speaker 5:  apps. Like it's, they're all perfect. I don't wanna mess with them. I don't
Speaker 5:  wanna log into GM's weird Android instance. Like I just wanna use my apps.
Speaker 5:  They've curated on my phone. They all have CarPlay. They go on that screen.
Speaker 5:  That's fine. And then a lot of people were taking Google Maps out so they
Speaker 5:  could basically have two monitors. Yeah. And they would mount the phone with
Speaker 5:  Google Maps and they would've the music on CarPlay and Apple broke
Speaker 5:  it. Interesting. So you can take Google Maps out and then
Speaker 5:  the phone is still like, no, we're sending this to CarPlay. And there's like
Speaker 5:  furious forum posts about it because that's how a lot of people
Speaker 5:  were still using that to have two different screens at once. Sure. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Including me, and I'm very annoyed about this. I'm just complaining about
Speaker 5:  my almost 10-year-old card that gets me nowhere with anyone.
Speaker 5:  But like there's, there's something there that's really powerful that next
Speaker 5:  generation CarPlay doesn't solve, but that even like GM's like crazy,
Speaker 5:  like giant curved screen kind of solves. 'cause you can put Google
Speaker 5:  Maps in the cluster and it's just Google Maps and then you can
Speaker 5:  have the music player and it's really big and it's like, oh, with all the
Speaker 5:  screen you should just let me run two apps at once. And they haven't quite
Speaker 5:  gotten there. Maybe they will one
Speaker 6:  Day. I mean this is, this is from the company that makes the iPad. Are you,
Speaker 6:  are you shocked by this fact?
Speaker 5:  Again, it's like your point about buttons is there, but it's like, oh man,
Speaker 5:  they put in all these screens in the car and they forgot to build any apps
Speaker 5:  for them and they forgot the number one. Like why do people have three monitors?
Speaker 5:  It's not to run one big app
Speaker 5:  like you wanna run. Like that's why you want lots of windows. Like,
Speaker 6:  We'll see, I want three linear feet of one app in my car.
Speaker 5:  I just wanna call one thing out. Apple gave one publication early
Speaker 5:  Hands-on with Car Play. I believe it was Top Gear. We embedded
Speaker 5:  the video. Top Cruise. You could watch it. It's great. Almost everything
Speaker 5:  is our reporting like down to like Mercedes CO
Speaker 5:  Laia said he wouldn't use That's us. That's decoder. And then the explanation
Speaker 5:  of that video of like how it works, that's a, that's us. We, we wrote that
Speaker 5:  story again. When you just ask Google about our play, it's like Neela hates
Speaker 5:  it. Like, it's like very fun.
Speaker 5:  So we're gonna get our own hands on soon. I'm excited to play with it.
Speaker 5:  Wwc is coming up around the corner. Very interesting. They announced this
Speaker 5:  weeks before wwc. The, in another world, this is a highlight
Speaker 5:  announcement, right. And there's an Aston Martin sitting there and everyone
Speaker 5:  like does hands on the Aston Martin, but they announced it early. You wonder
Speaker 5:  if they're gonna have more WC or if this was a distraction from them. All
Speaker 5:  right, I can continue complaining about CarPlay.
Speaker 6:  Let's not,
Speaker 5:  Are you sure I got another 20 minutes? I mean
Speaker 6:  That's what decoder
Speaker 5:  Is for. That's true.
Speaker 5:  Go watch the No literally no shade the top Gear people. It just, it was just
Speaker 5:  very funny. I was like, it's a good video. Watching this video. I was like,
Speaker 5:  oh, that's just, that's that's source test. Again, there
Speaker 6:  Was one thing in that video that I really appreciated, which is that he too
Speaker 6:  is confused about when it's Wired CarPlay and when it's wireless CarPlay
Speaker 6:  because he, he plugged it into his car and it launched the thing that said
Speaker 6:  set up wireless CarPlay. And it's like, which one, what, which one did I
Speaker 6:  do here? Which is a feeling that I have constantly all the time
Speaker 6:  driving
Speaker 5:  Around next the CarPlay Ultra is only wireless. That plugin is just the initial
Speaker 5:  download of assets. So you plug in your phone, I see the phone is like, I've
Speaker 5:  got a library of assets for car makers that Apple is designed with everybody.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna da we're gonna go update the, the database of assets and then
Speaker 5:  download the right ones to your car.
Speaker 6:  I so fundamentally do not believe in the idea
Speaker 6:  that I should have to have an iPhone in order for my car to work properly.
Speaker 6:  Like you're just, that's this is, this is the problem with CarPlay Ultra
Speaker 6:  that I have always had is that does not make sense to
Speaker 6:  me. The fact that my car is somehow not feature complete unless I own an
Speaker 6:  iPhone is just backwards. Like this
Speaker 5:  Is the other thing that's that why is Apple it they
Speaker 7:  Could, they could just throw in an iPhone for the cost of an Aston Martin.
Speaker 7:  I, that's
Speaker 6:  Not a huge, honestly, like I I, anyone who buys an Aston Martin can afford
Speaker 6:  several iPhones. Like it's, it's a, it's a principle thing for me. Like my,
Speaker 6:  my phone and my car should
Speaker 6:  not require each other to have a complete experience. I'm fine if one
Speaker 6:  wants to add to the other like Sure, okay. And
Speaker 6:  CarPlay and Android Auto are like interesting competitive experiences or
Speaker 6:  whatever. But if, if my car is not feature complete without my phone,
Speaker 6:  we have done something wrong as a society.
Speaker 7:  Fundamentally. I I agree with you and you're correct. As somebody who primarily
Speaker 7:  experiences cars via rentals, it, it drives
Speaker 7:  me crazy when it has a baked in thing. I just,
Speaker 7:  right. My phone has everything on it. It's fully up to date, it has all my
Speaker 7:  preferences. Boom, plug it in. Easy done. I am like, I find
Speaker 7:  that to be just delightful. Sure. It, you, you are correct
Speaker 7:  that a car should function.
Speaker 5:  David, I can get you in a 2008 DB nine for 17 five tonight
Speaker 6:  And then I can buy the CarPlay screen on TikTok and we're good to go.
Speaker 7:  That So
Speaker 6:  I'm cooking. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  All right. Just in honor of the fact thats has, I'm gonna quickly shop for
Speaker 5:  Cadillac Escalades while David moves on to whatever's next.
Speaker 6:  We should talk about the Android announcements just for a couple of minutes
Speaker 6:  here. So Google io is next week
Speaker 6:  and I think Google just has a lot of other
Speaker 6:  AI stuff to talk about. So they just did all the Android stuff early.
Speaker 6:  They announced a bunch of new stuff for Android 16, including a
Speaker 6:  whole new design language that they call Material three expressive, which
Speaker 6:  is a stupid name for what I think is actually like a very cool yeah. Looking
Speaker 6:  thing. Like it's just really funny that looking at phones
Speaker 6:  have gotten, they've gotten so much more like sterile and
Speaker 6:  straightforward over time and Google is like, what it feels like playful
Speaker 6:  and colorful and everything was purple and it's very Gen Z and I'm like
Speaker 6:  very cool and young. So it works for me too. And I just,
Speaker 6:  I don't know. I like it. They're, they're making the animations more playful.
Speaker 6:  There's a lot more for developers to do in terms of like fonts and
Speaker 6:  widgets and sizes and shapes of things and users can
Speaker 6:  customize it a lot. And I've given material
Speaker 6:  u kind of a hard time over the years because it was just like, oh, your wallpaper
Speaker 6:  has some brown in it. What if everything was brown? But there's something
Speaker 6:  about this and the idea that actually, yeah, I should be able to make everything
Speaker 6:  look the way that I want instead of just apple's weird idea
Speaker 6:  about tinting that I've come to really like, and I think Google is like
Speaker 6:  onto something here.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I, the new design is really fun. I am a little skeptical
Speaker 7:  of the implementation material. U it it, it is
Speaker 7:  not a big jump from Material U right? It it is fundamentally the same thing
Speaker 7:  just made a little bit wackier. Yeah. And if you use lots
Speaker 7:  of different things on an Android phone,
Speaker 7:  you know, the, the implementation of Material U has
Speaker 7:  not changed I think basically at all since it was announced like four years
Speaker 7:  ago. Right? Sure. It's the same five widgets. Right. And, and you still
Speaker 7:  see in the material three expressive whatever it is,
Speaker 7:  you know, demo slides that they're showing. It's the, it is the same weather
Speaker 7:  widget and the same clock widget that we saw four years ago. Right. Those
Speaker 7:  are still on my home screen because those are the only widgets that
Speaker 7:  theme themselves properly. Right. Like true, I really want a step counter
Speaker 7:  widget, right? Google owns Fitbit, they have Google
Speaker 7:  Health or whatever it's called. Neither of those have a material
Speaker 7:  expressive whatever widget. Right? A lot of apps now
Speaker 7:  do support the, the icon theming, which is great, but not all of them
Speaker 7:  do. And
Speaker 6:  There is something truly awful by the way, about when your home screen has
Speaker 6:  a bunch of apps that all fit the theme and then like two that haven't updated.
Speaker 6:  And it just, there's nothing that kills a vibe quite like the one app that
Speaker 6:  steadfastly refuses to play nice with the operating system.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And I think like unlike on, and look a Apple has made some,
Speaker 7:  I think some errors with the way they have done theming, but I do think that
Speaker 7:  one thing Apple has to it its advantage is when they do something their
Speaker 7:  developers listen. And so when Apple changes the theme of its operating system,
Speaker 7:  which we may see next month, I suspect
Speaker 7:  you'll see a lot of apps developers, you know, moving
Speaker 7:  forward to update and theme in that style to reflect what the operat system
Speaker 7:  is supposed to feel like. And I don't know, using Android apps that most
Speaker 7:  of them reflect the feeling of material you, or
Speaker 7:  material design or, you know, whatever's coming next Android feels different
Speaker 7:  and it's nice and I think it looks lovely and there are places when, where,
Speaker 7:  you know, those effects are able to be added into third party apps,
Speaker 7:  right? Like I see the little squiggly playback line on the Spotify
Speaker 7:  widget in the notification shade. It's great. It's nice. I I I wanna be clear,
Speaker 7:  like I think the design is really fun and I think the Android has become
Speaker 7:  sort of a, a, a, a much more like lively looking operating system in that
Speaker 7:  way than iOS. But I I I think like
Speaker 7:  coming up with this big design refresh is step one
Speaker 7:  and step two is following through with it. It is, it is having people make
Speaker 7:  widgets. It is having people support theming. And
Speaker 7:  Google did not do that with Material U and it is not clear
Speaker 7:  to me that they're, they have a push behind material three expressive either.
Speaker 7:  So that is where my skepticism is. And I, I'm, I hope,
Speaker 7:  I hope that they're able to, you know, get some people on board with it.
Speaker 7:  'cause I, it would be really fun and delightful to have all my icons be the
Speaker 7:  same color and have all these fun, you know, widgets. The
Speaker 6:  Bar is on the floor,
Speaker 7:  Jake. Yeah. Yeah. All
Speaker 6:  My icons be the same color.
Speaker 7:  Right. It's not happening. This
Speaker 6:  To me is so indicative of how weirdly Google has started
Speaker 6:  to handle Android. Like for so long, Android had
Speaker 6:  versions that it launched that were a thing that like Google
Speaker 6:  would do a bunch of updates to Android at once and be like, look, a new version
Speaker 6:  of Android, it had a dessert name like it, it was a thing. And that has just
Speaker 6:  stopped now. Like we don't even really
Speaker 6:  pay attention to new versions of Android anymore, which is like maybe a failing
Speaker 6:  of ours, but I think it's mostly a failing of Google's.
Speaker 7:  No, no, no. I mean this is the thing, a couple years back we were like, Hey,
Speaker 7:  we, we reached out to Google, we're like, Hey, did you guys say
Speaker 7:  the word Android during this Google io keynote? And they're
Speaker 7:  like, yeah, you know, and like it, okay, we had, we had missed, but
Speaker 7:  they, they were specifically not mentioning Android version numbers because
Speaker 7:  they want to blur it. They want it to just be like they're these iterative
Speaker 7:  things. Well,
Speaker 6:  And it's because it is such a disastrously fragmented Yes.
Speaker 6:  Thing that if, if they don't tell you what version number it is, you can't
Speaker 6:  put up the chart with how low the updates have been to that version number.
Speaker 6:  Right. And like Apple made such a meal out of it every year
Speaker 6:  showing all of the phones that had been updated to the new iOS versus all
Speaker 6:  of the phones that had been updated to the new Android. And it was always
Speaker 6:  ugly. And I think Google just rather than try to fight, just kind of
Speaker 6:  gave up and decided to hide. And I think that is a bummer.
Speaker 5:  There is a back and forth there. Right? The cynical view, which
Speaker 5:  is correct, but cynical is that Google is largely
Speaker 5:  base operating system supplier to Samsung at least expressed in this country.
Speaker 5:  Sure. Samsung is all the Android market share. And it doesn't matter
Speaker 5:  what material three expressive is because Samsung's gonna put one UI
Speaker 5:  on top of Android and that, and that's what you get. Right. And all that
Speaker 5:  really matters is, does Google push security updates fast enough for the
Speaker 5:  people with Samsung phones as, as the operating system vendor? And the capabilities
Speaker 5:  of each successive operating system version are now
Speaker 5:  very small even in iOS world, right? Yeah. The, the, the
Speaker 5:  real differences between iOS 13 and 14 are, are nothing.
Speaker 5:  Right? It's nothing like, there's some stuff
Speaker 5:  your phone will insist on summarizing your text messages, even if you turn
Speaker 5:  Apple intelligence off. That's a feature exists on iOS now.
Speaker 5:  But the, the sort of like incremental value to app developers to users
Speaker 5:  for successive operating system versions is just
Speaker 5:  smaller and smaller every year. Yeah. Okay. So that's like the very cynical
Speaker 5:  view. Like Google has blurred these version numbers
Speaker 5:  because really it just has to provide base Android to Samsung, which will
Speaker 5:  then do one UI stuff and it doesn't matter. 'cause the whole point of Android
Speaker 5:  is search volume Sure. And now maybe
Speaker 5:  Gemini queries, right? And there's a whole interest drop about that. The
Speaker 5:  less cynical version of this is that actually creates freedom for
Speaker 5:  Google's design team to say it all looks different now,
Speaker 5:  right? We're, we're, we're pushing the boundary of what Android can look
Speaker 5:  like and feel like with things like material three expressive. Because
Speaker 5:  no one will be mad at us when we change it because no one has it.
Speaker 5:  Right? A bunch of pixel owners will be excited 'cause they signed up for
Speaker 5:  this. This is, this is why you buy a pixel at the end of the day,
Speaker 5:  is to get Google's vision of Android. So if we make it different, they'll
Speaker 5:  be excited 'cause they got something no one else has. And that will create
Speaker 5:  whatever exclusivity around the pixel. I don dunno if that actually works
Speaker 5:  out, but that's the argument you would make. That's like the less cynical
Speaker 5:  argument of like the opportunity that's created by the fact that Samsung
Speaker 5:  is the volume player in Android and Google can be like the very tip of the
Speaker 5:  spear. Has Google done a great job being the tip of the spear of the Android
Speaker 5:  ecosystem? It has not. No. And I think that's the opportunity they're missing.
Speaker 5:  Those
Speaker 6:  Can both be true at the same time, right? They, that is Google has, has
Speaker 6:  lost control of its destiny in that way. But it has,
Speaker 6:  it has moves it can do even as kind of a bit player in its own
Speaker 6:  universe. And that's, that's, that's so sad. I mean that's what it is.
Speaker 6:  But that's, and that's fine. But I think Jake to,
Speaker 6:  to your point, like the challenge for Google has been
Speaker 6:  to like propagate its good ideas. And I think
Speaker 6:  just pitting what, what Google launched this week next to all of the stuff
Speaker 6:  we've seen about what's coming from iOS, which is this like Vision Pro based
Speaker 6:  everything in sort of 3D space, even more like cold and
Speaker 6:  sterile in space Ag. Look, I'm vastly
Speaker 6:  prefer Android. Like the, the ideas about what your phone should look like,
Speaker 6:  I, I resonate with what Google is up to so much more than what Apple is up
Speaker 6:  to. But un until,
Speaker 6:  and unless you get all at at least enough people to buy into this that
Speaker 6:  it feels coherent and good. It's gonna feel the way Android
Speaker 6:  always has, which is like a mishmash of a decade's worth of ideas. And that
Speaker 6:  feels bad. And so it's like the Google has always struggled to get
Speaker 6:  to that tipping point where it's like, okay, I actually understand
Speaker 6:  what this thing is trying to do and it feels consistent no matter where I
Speaker 6:  am. And Android never feels consistent.
Speaker 7:  They have guaranteed that the home screen on pixel phones is gonna look really
Speaker 7:  cool for the next three years. Yes. And and and I think it's very possibly
Speaker 7:  going to end there and I hope it doesn't, but, but that is what it is.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, no, I I think that's right. And it's, it's the thing Google is
Speaker 6:  invested in, in like a real way is making sure Gemini is
Speaker 6:  everywhere, right? And, and Google is fine if you don't take its aesthetic
Speaker 6:  ideas, but it is going to beat you up until you put Gemini
Speaker 6:  everywhere. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Or pay, pay you lots of money, which it's paying Samsung lots of money. Gemini,
Speaker 6:  It's gonna beat you up with dollars.
Speaker 5:  Just, just throw money at you. Yeah. Just Mr. Beast at the YouTube
Speaker 5:  upfronts, Mia Sato was, was at the upfronts and she
Speaker 5:  said, Mr. Beast got on stage and says, no one tells you how heavy money is.
Speaker 5:  Which is a all time quote. 'cause he's, he's the one with
Speaker 5:  suitcases full of money. And that's Google, right? They're like, Samsung,
Speaker 5:  would you like to know how heavy this money is? Do
Speaker 6:  You think he understood the true like, emotional depth of that sentence?
Speaker 6:  No one understands how heavy money is. It's very good. He is like, wow. It's
Speaker 6:  very
Speaker 5:  Good.
Speaker 5:  We'll see, I mean I, I'm excited for io I think we're, you know, from everything
Speaker 5:  we've heard, there's going to be a push towards, you know,
Speaker 5:  Google's next set of platform ideas around ai, around mixed reality, around
Speaker 5:  all this stuff. I think that stuff will be exciting. It's weird 'cause material
Speaker 5:  three expressive, I mean, it's, it, it,
Speaker 5:  there's an argument that like skew morph, issm is coming back, right? These
Speaker 5:  like very tactile, very real feeling textures. And
Speaker 5:  I don't know how that plays with all of the other kinds of experiences that
Speaker 5:  all these companies wanna build. But you don't want a bunch of like leather
Speaker 5:  and felt in your AR classes. Like that's really weird. That's just super
Speaker 5:  goofy. And I think that's why Apple is headed towards this like sterile,
Speaker 5:  like literally it looks like aero glass from Windows back in the day. Right?
Speaker 5:  Like they're headed towards computer interfaces. 'cause if you want the real
Speaker 5:  world to come through your glasses, you want computers on top of it and
Speaker 5:  Google's in this other direction and we'll just see. I'm sure they have some
Speaker 5:  idea about how comes together. That's kind of what I'm interested to see
Speaker 5:  at io.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Agreed.
Speaker 5:  All right. We should move on. There's like, wait,
Speaker 6:  Hold on. Before, before we move on, we just need to just
Speaker 6:  brief shout out to the public reemergence
Speaker 6:  of our good friend and former colleague Dieter Bone who was on
Speaker 6:  stage virtual stage, stage, quote unquote stage
Speaker 6:  doing stuff. And boy were people excited to see Dieter.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Basically just doing phone hands ons. Yeah. He
Speaker 6:  Just did phone hands ons. He just was he he remains Dieter.
Speaker 6:  It was nice.
Speaker 5:  He's and he was like the surprise treat at the end of the video. You should
Speaker 5:  go watch it. It's great. Yeah. But he is like, look, this one opens, that
Speaker 5:  one closes. It's like very good.
Speaker 6:  Dieter still loves phones and I will forever love Dieter for loving
Speaker 6:  phones. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I'm excited for io. Yeah. I I assume io this year, this is next
Speaker 5:  week is just gonna be Gemini talk like
Speaker 5:  top to bottom. Like here's everything we do better than chat GPT. Yep.
Speaker 6:  That is certainly the, the vibe that I'm getting from, from all
Speaker 6:  the, all the rumors and reporting so far is like, Google is
Speaker 6:  I think, clearer than ever about what it's about as a company.
Speaker 6:  And the thing that it is about is Gemini feel about that however
Speaker 6:  you want. But Google is going to, the, the pivot to Gemini is very,
Speaker 6:  very real.
Speaker 5:  There's this got unearthed in the docs of one of the Google
Speaker 5:  trials internal notes from Google meetings
Speaker 5:  that they are thinking of redoing the entire search
Speaker 5:  stack with an LLM as the base.
Speaker 6:  Oh wow.
Speaker 5:  This is a big deal. Like that's where we're at with Google and Gemini. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So we're, we're gonna go there. I'll be there. Our team will be there.
Speaker 5:  Lots of interviews, lots of hands-on, lots of probing questions about
Speaker 5:  wither the web. That's my job at Google. A I just walk around and be like,
Speaker 5:  what about the web?
Speaker 5:  We'll see how it goes.
Speaker 6:  Love this.
Speaker 5:  It's gonna be great. All right. We gotta take a break. We'll be back with
Speaker 5:  the lightning round.
Speaker 5:  All right, we're back. The lightning round unsponsored
Speaker 5:  for flavor. Can I actually, can I, can I, can we do a digression
Speaker 5:  about sponsorship and flavor? Sure. I have a lot to say
Speaker 5:  about what's going on in the world of advertising. I always say the, the,
Speaker 5:  that we're unsponsored for flavor. 'cause I want people to, to think when
Speaker 5:  they hear sponsor integrations, oh, there's, there's less flavor here.
Speaker 5:  You can't pay to tell us what to do. You can go read our ethics policy. Our
Speaker 5:  ethics policy is basically you can't tell me what to do, which, if you can
Speaker 5:  get into a line of work where the thing you're selling is the inability of
Speaker 5:  anyone to tell you what to do. Like I highly recommend it. I'm not saying
Speaker 5:  digital media is is a great or stable career, but one thing it does offer
Speaker 5:  is the ability to say, you cannot tell me what to do.
Speaker 5:  It's good. That's what I like about it. And that's what we sell here. That's
Speaker 5:  subscribe to The Verge. That's, that's what you're buying from us. Everything
Speaker 5:  else is turning into the worst kind of
Speaker 5:  marketing integrated sponsorship that I can possibly think of. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  it's like everywhere now. So we are talking about Warner Bros. Discovery
Speaker 5:  Upfronts and all these media companies are having them. Warner Bros launched
Speaker 5:  story verse this week where you can just
Speaker 5:  buy their like IP library and make ads out of it.
Speaker 5:  I hate this
Speaker 13:  So much.
Speaker 5:  Like, you know, they did Batman versus Batman. That's part of story verse
Speaker 5:  where like, state Farms showed up and they're like, we'd like to buy some
Speaker 5:  Batman stuff. And Warner Bros was like, yeah, you can make ads outta this.
Speaker 5:  That's what this is for. It's to turn it into advertising. And now they've,
Speaker 5:  they've done a couple of these pilots, and I'm not saying these ads were
Speaker 5:  bad, but like their business model is now we make this
Speaker 5:  IP and you can show up and turn whatever is in our catalog into
Speaker 5:  advertising.
Speaker 7:  This is the thing that makes the most sense of all of the zaz love
Speaker 7:  actions, right? Like it all comes back to this, right? Like, oh, we
Speaker 7:  have things that people like that we can ring more money out of.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. Absolutely. And you know, it's funny, they announced this name
Speaker 5:  change and we were looking at all their press releases and Emma, who like
Speaker 5:  was covering this, I was like, the actual story here is this ad product,
Speaker 5:  right? Where their catalog, the whole Warner Bros catalog is now
Speaker 5:  able, like it's for sale to be remixed into advertising.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's what it's for.
Speaker 6:  We're so few steps away from, and we've uploaded a bunch of assets
Speaker 6:  for you to use generative AI to just make ads against, it's right, it's right
Speaker 6:  there. Put this right next to Mark Zuckerberg's thing that he was talking
Speaker 6:  about where he's like, we're gonna let you make AI ads. And it's like, we're
Speaker 6:  gonna let you make AI Batman ads is like, it's just right there.
Speaker 5:  And, and it's right there. It's, it's been there in the background of all
Speaker 5:  these companies for a long time. So
Speaker 5:  NBCU, Comcast, our favorites,
Speaker 5:  their sponsors for SNL 50 this season were getting sketches on
Speaker 5:  air, right? So like Maybelline oh was a big sponsor and they did a bunch
Speaker 5:  of stuff with the cast and VW was a big sponsor and every episode of
Speaker 5:  SNL had that sketch. The Californians. Yep. But it was just a VW
Speaker 5:  but that was marked as advertising. You know that Sketch, the Jennifer Coolidge
Speaker 5:  or Anna Grande? Everyone's Jennifer Coolidge sketch. Yep. I think Dana Carby
Speaker 5:  was in it. Maybelline Maybelline is a title sponsor of
Speaker 5:  SNL 50 and they got a sketch on air. Oh wow. They went viral 'cause it was
Speaker 5:  very funny. But that's just integrated brand advertising. And what is that
Speaker 5:  sketch? It's just all sing Maybelline 50 times over.
Speaker 5:  Like what? And that's like, whatever. It's a comedy show. Fine. Integrate
Speaker 5:  the brands. It's product placement all you want. Okay, here's the last one.
Speaker 5:  This one like drove me over the edge this week. There's a new
Speaker 5:  documentary F1 documentary on Netflix about Kimmy Antonelli
Speaker 5:  the new driver for Mercedes.
Speaker 5:  It is literally a WhatsApp commercial. Like when you open it
Speaker 5:  on Netflix, the interface, you know where it says like what the show is
Speaker 5:  about. The first words are
Speaker 5:  sponsored by WhatsApp. Ugh. It doesn't even tell you what it is. The,
Speaker 5:  like, literally the first things you see are sponsored by WhatsApp and then
Speaker 5:  it's like the story of Kim Manson taking over Louis Hamilton seat and the
Speaker 5:  Mercedes. And then you start the show and you know,
Speaker 5:  it's just like a 40 minute documentary about like the 17-year-old kid getting
Speaker 5:  to drive a car. Like this is catnip for me. And
Speaker 5:  like in the title sequence, it's like presented by WhatsApp and then the,
Speaker 5:  the, the doc is tons and tons
Speaker 5:  of fake WhatsApp conversations and staged
Speaker 5:  WhatsApp video calls.
Speaker 6:  Oh
Speaker 7:  That's, oh that's really weird.
Speaker 5:  Right? So like everything
Speaker 6:  You said until that is like, I'm like fine, whatever. Like
Speaker 6:  get your money to make your documentary however you want
Speaker 6:  Art and commerce Sure. Knock yourself out. But then, ugh.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like Toto Wolf calls Kimmy Antonelli to tell him to take, you know,
Speaker 5:  he's getting the job. And the first words he said in that call
Speaker 5:  are, we've set up this WhatsApp call.
Speaker 6:  Oh my God.
Speaker 5:  Brutal. Also the video quality I call horrible, horrible advertising
Speaker 6:  For WhatsApp.
Speaker 5:  And they're like, you know, I I like posted on Blue Sky about this. And people
Speaker 5:  are like, you know, race cars are all about advertising and like Sure. You
Speaker 5:  know, the, the team speak button on the steering wheel in Mercedes is a WhatsApp
Speaker 5:  icon. 'cause they have a long fine whatever. Like get your bag. I don't care.
Speaker 5:  I'm just saying the actual content is advertising now. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like these things have collapsed. Like we are just viewing
Speaker 5:  advertising to the point where the first line of the description of the thing
Speaker 5:  is this is a WhatsApp commercial. And then you watch and you're like, oh,
Speaker 5:  this is super a WhatsApp commercial. I have a friend who's been in
Speaker 5:  like every kind of video production, like movies,
Speaker 5:  TV shows, advertising. And his, he's like, the end
Speaker 5:  of this is someone who's gonna win the Academy Award for best picture.
Speaker 5:  And the producer who accepts the award will be an advertiser.
Speaker 5:  Right. The, the end of this collapse of wow. Everything turning into marketing.
Speaker 5:  Everything is an ad for everything on YouTube is an ad for Ag G one. Right?
Speaker 5:  Like, like that's all it is. Like everyone's just trying to build these channels.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So that they can do branded content, integrate in the thing. And at
Speaker 5:  the end of it you're gonna be like, best picture goes to Coca-Cola. It's,
Speaker 5:  this is his theory. I and I have laughed at him for years and I, I watched
Speaker 5:  this WhatsApp thing. I was
Speaker 6:  Like, that feels, that feels kind of right
Speaker 5:  Anyway, unsponsored for flavor. Do you know what I mean?
Speaker 6:  So, okay, here's, there's a weird
Speaker 5:  Thing. WhatsApp can't tell me what to do.
Speaker 6:  This whole conversation, we're gonna run this episode as a WhatsApp
Speaker 6:  video call.
Speaker 5:  I have said WhatsApp ine a lot. So you never don't
Speaker 6:  Even get paid for it. Maybe we're the idiots.
Speaker 5:  I mean, in many ways we are the idiots.
Speaker 5:  Everyone else is like driving their acid Martins around.
Speaker 5:  That's all I'm saying. I'm buying $200 boxes for man Amazon to retrofit
Speaker 5:  CarPlay and my 10-year-old car. Like, it's a very different world we live
Speaker 5:  in. But
Speaker 5:  I much prefer not being told what to do. Hmm. And I assure you, all
Speaker 5:  the people who do these integrations, they get told what to do.
Speaker 6:  The best career advice I ever got was from somebody who told me that every
Speaker 6:  time you do well in your career, you're gonna get to choose between power
Speaker 6:  and autonomy. And you should always choose autonomy. That's pretty good.
Speaker 6:  That's good advice.
Speaker 5:  Anyway, if you'd like to sup continue to support us just yelling
Speaker 5:  at companies and not being able to be told what to do, you can subscribe
Speaker 5:  to the verse. That's the, that's the engine that powers this whole little
Speaker 6:  Operation. That's how Neli gets his ass in. Martin.
Speaker 5:  It's, look, I'm, I'm telling you right now, I can get you into a
Speaker 5:  2007 Escalade with 159,000 miles on the clock for
Speaker 5:  89 95. David,
Speaker 6:  I mean, I'm down We go split seats. The three of us
Speaker 5:  If you wanna go up model, you wanna spend a little bit more I get you in
Speaker 5:  2014. Platinum, platinum Slade. Now
Speaker 5:  98 K on the clock. 16, nine.
Speaker 6:  No, I think, I think we go, we go smaller 'cause we're gonna retrofit it
Speaker 6:  as our mobile podcast studio.
Speaker 5:  So you gotta rip out the inside.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Because we don't need the fancy stuff.
Speaker 5:  Every time I despair about the car industry, I remind myself that you can
Speaker 5:  just buy an old Escalade for no money. And that is a viable option.
Speaker 5:  It's like the best thing you can do with your, your car budget is be like,
Speaker 5:  I'm, I'm buying an old Escalade. I'm not saying 'cause it's like a great
Speaker 5:  or reliable car that the previous owners have treated them. Well, I'm saying
Speaker 5:  that at any moment if you're like, I'm a little in the dumps, you're like,
Speaker 5:  I could just buy an Escalade
Speaker 6:  That does make I, I feel better. Do you see what I'm saying? That's real.
Speaker 5:  Like I can get 180 9 0.95. All right David. It's
Speaker 5:  time.
Speaker 6:  Oh my God. Ne Now we have a countdown of these. We only get to do so many
Speaker 6:  of these until we have to stop for a minute. So we,
Speaker 5:  Both of my children will be doing them in
Speaker 6:  It's time for America's favorite podcast. Within a podcast.
Speaker 6:  Brendan Carr is a dummy.
Speaker 5:  All right. This week on Brendan Carr is a dummy. We have, what I can only
Speaker 5:  describe is a moral dilemma.
Speaker 6:  Unlike, I guess the other ones are not moral dilemmas. It's just moral outrage.
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 5:  Moral outrage. Usually in Brendan Carr is a dummy, we present. But one story,
Speaker 5:  which is Brendan Carr, who is a traitorous moron, shows up and says, I would
Speaker 5:  like to use the power of the government to chill your speech. And then we
Speaker 5:  point out that the First Amendment exists and Brendan's ideas are bad and
Speaker 5:  that he should feel bad about himself. And then we essentially threaten invite
Speaker 5:  him to come on the show and defend himself. Yeah. That's the,
Speaker 5:  that's the structure of the thing. It's, you know, you buy the box of cereal,
Speaker 5:  you get the marshmallows, everyone's happy. We, we sell what we sell here.
Speaker 5:  That's the structure behind cards. Done. Love it. And I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm
Speaker 5:  aware right? You gotta hit product. You, you, you gotta sing your hits. You
Speaker 5:  know, today, this week we're changing it up.
Speaker 5:  All right. We're going country
Speaker 5:  because
Speaker 5:  it's it. I can't identify who the villain of the story is except for
Speaker 5:  everyone. And then, and then you, you have no idea what to do. So this week
Speaker 5:  our, our boy Brendan
Speaker 5:  threatened to investigate Dish Network for not
Speaker 5:  using the spectrum. It obtained after T-Mobile bought Sprint.
Speaker 5:  And it was given Boost Network to run as our nation's
Speaker 5:  fourth wireless carrier.
Speaker 6:  Oh, we have a real worst person. You know, makes a great point. Kind what
Speaker 6:  I'm situation.
Speaker 5:  You see what I'm saying? You see, don't worry, there's a, there's a twist
Speaker 5:  coming. Okay. But that's the heart of it, right? Is Brendan woke
Speaker 5:  up and he realized
Speaker 5:  for a reason that I'll come to that, it turns out
Speaker 5:  Dish Network is not a viable fourth wireless carrier in
Speaker 5:  the United States. That project Gen Five sis their
Speaker 5:  plan to somehow use
Speaker 5:  AWS and a technology called Open ran to build a very,
Speaker 5:  to very quickly build. A fourth National wireless carrier
Speaker 5:  came to nothing.
Speaker 5:  By the way, it's called Gensy. 'cause they saw Genesis with a five. This
Speaker 5:  is a real thing. I'm not kidding. We, we've done a lot of coverage Yep. Of
Speaker 5:  Project Genesis over the years. Project Gen Fivey. And it, it has effectively
Speaker 5:  come to nothing. It launched in like two markets with one phone,
Speaker 5:  like a Motorola Edge. We sent Mitchell Clark to like use
Speaker 5:  this phone back in the day. And he was like, this sucks. This is, this is
Speaker 5:  in 2022. Nothing has happened since 2022. At one point there was an entire
Speaker 5:  crypto scam grafted onto the back of Project Genesis. Like
Speaker 5:  everything except Building Network. And if you'll remember,
Speaker 5:  this all came about because Brendan's predecessor at the
Speaker 5:  FCC Ajit Pi under the first Trump administration
Speaker 5:  rubber stamped T-Mobile buying Sprint. And
Speaker 5:  the solution they came up with to the reduction of competition in the
Speaker 5:  United States was to say, okay, you can buy Sprint and
Speaker 5:  you have to sell some spectrum and boost to
Speaker 5:  Dish Network, which is gonna wake up and realize that
Speaker 5:  it's a viable national wireless carrier and preserve
Speaker 5:  competition so that we'll still have four national carriers in the country.
Speaker 5:  This was their plan. They allowed this merger to happen, which resulted
Speaker 5:  in thousands of layoffs and higher
Speaker 5:  prices. 'cause we reduced competition. And they said Dish Network will
Speaker 5:  fix it. Dish Network is gonna stand up a new network using this new technology
Speaker 5:  called Open Ran, which is interesting. OOO Open Ran
Speaker 5:  is the idea that the, the hardware and software inside of a cell tower
Speaker 5:  should be more interoperable. So like more companies can provide it. And
Speaker 5:  this is way you avoid big dependencies on a company like Huawei, which is
Speaker 5:  controlled by the Chinese government. This is a real problem. And the way
Speaker 5:  we're gonna do is by making things interoperable to promote competition.
Speaker 5:  That has not played out. I would just point out just like, no, none of this
Speaker 5:  happened. No, it was all good ideas. Pie. The Guy stuff Dish Network did
Speaker 5:  not build the network. So Brandon has notice this has happened and he wrote
Speaker 5:  a letter to EchoStar, which owns Dish Network. And he said, I've directed
Speaker 5:  agency staff to begin a review of Echo Star's compliance with its federal
Speaker 5:  obligations to provide 5G service throughout the United States per the terms
Speaker 5:  of its federal spectrum licenses that you hold a number of FCC
Speaker 5:  spectrum licenses that cover a significant amount of spectrum. You haven't
Speaker 5:  used them. Obviously EchoStar says
Speaker 5:  it, it warned its investors that we, we have made it wireless
Speaker 5:  network. No one can see it, but it's there. And then it, it quote cannot
Speaker 5:  predict with any degree of certainty the outcome of the SEC proceedings.
Speaker 5:  One, because I think it can predict the outcome. And two,
Speaker 5:  because you can't predict Brendan. Right? Like Brendan's gonna be like, have
Speaker 5:  you thought about being 25% more racist? You'll be fine. Like, that's like
Speaker 5:  a n normal outcome of a Brendan car investigation. Okay, so
Speaker 5:  here's the twist first, Brendan is investigating a deal his own predecessor
Speaker 5:  made, and no one can predict the outcome, at least of all the company. So
Speaker 5:  that's one. That's weird, right? Why is Brendan doing this?
Speaker 5:  Come on. You already know. Everybody knows why, because SpaceX wants
Speaker 5:  the spectrum and Brendan wants to give it to his buddy Elon Musk.
Speaker 6:  This is getting so boring. It's like, at least, at least like I, I was
Speaker 6:  genuinely in this moment rooting for Brendan to have like, made a good
Speaker 6:  decision that it's like, and and in the name of journalistic credibility,
Speaker 6:  we're like, we gotta give Brendan one this week.
Speaker 6:  But no, but
Speaker 5:  I don't know it, it's true that I've railed against Dish Network. Sure.
Speaker 5:  Stupid idea for years.
Speaker 5:  But where did this come from? What's the evidence that Brendan is tying this
Speaker 5:  investigation to?
Speaker 5:  SpaceX said one of its satellites measured the power spectral density levels
Speaker 5:  in the bands that Dish Network has and found the dish's use of those bands
Speaker 5:  as diminish, diminish the best. So just SpaceX is like, we
Speaker 5:  look, hey, we took it upon ourselves. We pointed one of our satellites at
Speaker 5:  the entire country, measured on the spectrum usage. And trust us, bro,
Speaker 5:  they're not using it. So can we have it? And Brendan immediately fired off
Speaker 5:  a letter saying you're not using it. I, within an investigation, SpaceX
Speaker 5:  says, SpaceX said The spectrum that Dish is using remains
Speaker 5:  ripe for sharing among next generation satellite systems that seek to
Speaker 5:  finally make productive use of the spectrum for consumers and first responders.
Speaker 5:  First of all, the spectrum was being used before
Speaker 5:  they sold spread to T-Mobile and gave the spectrum to Dish network.
Speaker 5:  I'm not saying Sprint was a great company, they sucked in a variety of ways,
Speaker 6:  But it was in fact using the spectrum. But it was
Speaker 5:  Using
Speaker 6:  The spectrum use Sprint people
Speaker 5:  Did. And then, yeah, and then finally make use of this spectrum for consumers
Speaker 5:  and first responders. It's like, yeah, like all the other companies exist.
Speaker 5:  Like if you would like to get first responders better cell coverage using
Speaker 5:  the spectrum, you would give it to one of the companies that actually
Speaker 5:  operates a wireless network, right? That would be the outcome. You wouldn't
Speaker 5:  be like SpaceX, can you horsepower up a new solution
Speaker 5:  the same way you ask Dish Network to horsepower up a new network?
Speaker 5:  What are we doing here? So we'll see what happens. There's we'll link, there's
Speaker 5:  a bunch of reporting about this. We'll link to it. But this weekend, Brandon Carr
Speaker 5:  is a dummy. He has done the right thing for the
Speaker 5:  stupidest possible reason. And the funniest thing about this is
Speaker 5:  it's his predecessor's deal. They promised us
Speaker 5:  when they made this deal allowing T-Mobile to buy Sprint,
Speaker 5:  the Dish Network would meet its commitments to stand up a fourth wireless
Speaker 5:  network using the spectrum, using the boost assets.
Speaker 5:  And everyone knew, just like we knew with Max, that this would
Speaker 5:  never happen. Never in a million years would this happen.
Speaker 5:  And every time we reported on it and the reporting consisted of,
Speaker 5:  we're gonna go to Las Vegas and see if there's a wireless network there,
Speaker 5:  they would be like, you don't know what you're talking about. Ridiculous.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Don't let the mergers happen. I it, this is just more merger
Speaker 5:  chaos. Do you know what the best thing to happen to the
Speaker 5:  American wireless industry is? The single best thing that's happened in the
Speaker 5:  past 15 years to the American wireless industry at t was blocked
Speaker 5:  from buying T-Mobile. Yeah. That's by far the best thing
Speaker 5:  that happens to the American wireless solution.
Speaker 6:  And then they uncarrier.
Speaker 5:  Yep. And they hired John Ledger and they at and t had to pay a bunch of money
Speaker 5:  in a breakup feed at T-Mobile. So T-Mobile got recapitalized important,
Speaker 5:  important piece of puzzle. But that only happened 'cause they were blocked
Speaker 5:  from buying it. And then John Ledger showed up and said, what is this industry
Speaker 5:  what I have to be competitive now? I'm gonna do a bunch of stuff to make
Speaker 5:  this industry more competitive, to win some customers and try to succeed
Speaker 5:  instead of just cashing out and letting at and t burn
Speaker 5:  money, making 4, 4, 3 grayscale Batman movies
Speaker 5:  compete. It makes everything better. As always. I would
Speaker 5:  respond to the many critics who show up to say that I'm, you know, just some
Speaker 5:  woke DEI hire by pointing out that the only consistent opinions that I expressed
Speaker 5:  on the show regarding politics are that free markets are good. Competition
Speaker 5:  makes for better products, and you should be a little bit less racist than
Speaker 5:  Brendan. And that's all I'm really asking for. And if you think that's super
Speaker 5:  liberal, that's fine, but I, I don't know about that.
Speaker 5:  Anyhow, that's been Brendan Cars, the dummy b Brendan, as always. If you
Speaker 5:  have the wherewithal, the emotional fortitude, or even the raw intelligence
Speaker 5:  to show up and defend these back asswards decisions, you're welcome.
Speaker 5:  On our shows. You the fanciest CEOs in the
Speaker 5:  industry show up under coder and defend themselves to me and they're able
Speaker 5:  to do it. I don't think you can do it. I don't think you're gonna show up.
Speaker 5:  I think you're a dumb coward. But if you want to, the door's always open,
Speaker 5:  my friend.
Speaker 6:  Maybe he has Project Gen five sis and just like can't
Speaker 6:  access this podcast.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. He's out there collecting one quarter of an NFT at a time every time
Speaker 5:  he sends a text message Boost Mobile
Speaker 5:  that's been Brenna Carr's dummy America's favorite podcast. In the podcast.
Speaker 6:  It was great. It was a great one. I treasure them all even more now knowing
Speaker 6:  we will have to take a break because God help Jake, if he has to do this
Speaker 6:  every
Speaker 7:  Week, I I'm gonna have neli just like do a little voice memo on his phone.
Speaker 7:  I, I assume he'll, he will, you know, have some crazed moment in the middle
Speaker 7:  of the night when he needs to, to let out some steam. And we'll just
Speaker 7:  play that right into the mic. Maybe. Can
Speaker 5:  You imagine if you could send a letter to the FCC being like, I've, I've
Speaker 5:  graded my own homework and I should get the spectrum.
Speaker 7:  I mean, we, we should have just been putting that at the end of all of our
Speaker 7:  articles, like, Hey, this dish thing isn't happening. Can you give it to
Speaker 7:  us? Like we'll use it. Yeah. I
Speaker 5:  I i, it, it is just very funny that we pointed a satellite who knew that
Speaker 5:  works and just like measured this guy's user. It's like, you don't have to
Speaker 5:  do that much work, man. You just have to be like, does this exist? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  you can go to the website project gen fivey.com. It's still there.
Speaker 5:  It's, it's called the Gen five sis five g.com. And
Speaker 5:  the la the last media and press update, like the newest
Speaker 5:  one is from 2022. And the headline is, dish adopts
Speaker 5:  America's chaos engineering platform to test and
Speaker 5:  ensure reliability. It's, and it's like, oh God.
Speaker 6:  First of all, chaos Engineering is a new name of our product design firm,
Speaker 6:  and I'm very excited about it. We're gonna do, it's like teenage
Speaker 6:  engineering, but like much worse. It's chaos engineering. And that's us.
Speaker 6:  I'm, I'm limited
Speaker 5:  Into it. It's, it, I I believe it's a rif you know, a Netflix used to have
Speaker 5:  the Chaos Monkey
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. Which
Speaker 5:  Was its reliability tester where it would just, it would, it would simulate
Speaker 5:  just like people pulling servers outta the racks. I think that's what this
Speaker 5:  is. But it's just very funny that they put out a press release
Speaker 5:  release. I don't know, man. Anyhow, Brandon, if you're listening, I can get
Speaker 5:  you into a 2015 Cadillac escalated luxury for 80, 18 7
Speaker 5:  out the door. All right, let's talk. Yeah. All right. We need a power clean
Speaker 5:  here, David, what do we got? Can we talk
Speaker 6:  About Airbnb, which is like all the only thing I can
Speaker 6:  think about the last four eight hours. So Airbnb this week,
Speaker 6:  basically, like, it wants you to think it completely pivoted the
Speaker 6:  company. And, and Brian Chesky is out here. Steven Levy had a big piece in,
Speaker 6:  in Wired
Speaker 5:  Amazing photos in that piece.
Speaker 6:  Oh, they're, they're very good. And it's, it says some, the, the headline
Speaker 6:  is something like Airbnb is in midlife crisis mode, which I'm sure Airbnb
Speaker 6:  is not wild about, but it's kind of true. And it describes this like fever
Speaker 6:  dream that Brian Chesky had, in which he decided
Speaker 6:  to completely change what Airbnb is doing. Ironically, in the middle of all
Speaker 6:  of the open AI chaos that we covered, he was like a central figure
Speaker 6:  in sorting all this stuff out and
Speaker 6:  was like somehow inspired by this to go
Speaker 6:  create similar chaos at his own company. So they go through this whole thing
Speaker 6:  and Airbnb is now trying to pivot hard
Speaker 6:  into being more than just like, places to stay, but they're doing like
Speaker 6:  experiences, which they've kind of done in the past, but they're doing much
Speaker 6:  more aggressively now. And then services, like local services
Speaker 6:  where you are, I guess I just find this all
Speaker 6:  very weird. Like Airbnb seems to want
Speaker 6:  to be fancy Yelp,
Speaker 5:  But with transactions in it, that's the difference. Mm. You never transact
Speaker 5:  in Yelp, right? Yelp is a search engine, right? And you're like, find me
Speaker 5:  a, a hairdresser. And then it like shows you a list and there's reviews and
Speaker 5:  whatever, but you don't like do anything else. You just use it. And
Speaker 5:  people favor for listings. This is very much more like, I'm,
Speaker 5:  I need a haircut. I'm gonna open Airbnb and some like vetted
Speaker 5:  barbers and hairdressers will be available to me and they'll come to my house
Speaker 5:  and cut my hair
Speaker 7:  While you're on vacation while
Speaker 5:  You're on, or if not, which is like,
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I, I do think the, the single most interesting thing that they changed
Speaker 7:  here is when you open the app, there's three tabs. It is like
Speaker 7:  places to stay, experiences, services. The default
Speaker 7:  tab that it opens to is the experiences tab, which is just not
Speaker 7:  what Airbnb is known for. So I, I think like, you're right Eli,
Speaker 7:  they're pushing this very hard and there's a world where you just open this
Speaker 7:  and you order a private chef for the night to your house where you live,
Speaker 7:  even when you're not staying somewhere on vacation. I, I, I
Speaker 7:  think it's sort of a weird concept, but it makes a lot of sense, right? Like
Speaker 7:  if you're only using Airbnb for one thing, then it's only one, you know,
Speaker 7:  thing place that they can make money. But now if they can sell you
Speaker 7:  experiences to do while you're in that place, if they can sell me experiences
Speaker 7:  to do while I live here in New York City, like that is a big
Speaker 7:  new market for them.
Speaker 6:  And that is actually, that is a market. No one is doing a very good job of
Speaker 6:  like, I don't know if you guys ever have this experience, but I have it all
Speaker 6:  the time where it's like, oh, what's going on near me this weekend? And the
Speaker 6:  answer is, you check 58 websites and you end up on like an Eventbrite listing
Speaker 6:  for a thing you've never heard of. And that's the best you can do. And at
Speaker 6:  various times, different companies have tried to tackle the, like,
Speaker 6:  what's going on around me? Problem. Nobody's ever done a very
Speaker 6:  good job of it. And it, I I think you're right Jake, that there is a big
Speaker 6:  opportunity and a big business there and being the one that is like
Speaker 6:  a a anywhere you are, even if it's at home, if you want to like explore
Speaker 6:  and find stuff to do, come here.
Speaker 6:  Airbnb makes a certain kind of sense as that platform, except that it's been
Speaker 6:  trying to do that and failing for a really long time.
Speaker 6:  And so now to double down on that, but then also add, like, I just don't
Speaker 6:  know that I need, I am on vacation and I wanna find a place to get a
Speaker 6:  massage is like a unsolved problem, right?
Speaker 7:  And it's, everything on there is like a little hokey right now and
Speaker 7:  admittedly it's touristy stuff. Like it's fine, right? But it's like, do
Speaker 7:  a pizza tour, right? Get a photo in Times Square. Well,
Speaker 5:  I mean, you're in New York and it's like,
Speaker 7:  That's what, that's what you're here for. It's fair. Like you may as well
Speaker 7:  do it there, but yeah, I I I'm not
Speaker 7:  sure if that is what is going to solve it for people, right? Like
Speaker 7:  they, they have offered these things already and maybe it just feels more
Speaker 7:  legitimate because it's now like front and center in the app.
Speaker 7:  It's certainly more convenient. Right. You were probably gonna go on that
Speaker 7:  pizza tour.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I'm thinking about it. Brian Chesky is actually on decoder
Speaker 5:  tomorrow as we're speaking. I'm, I'm preparing to interview him tomorrow
Speaker 5:  about all this stuff. This is, I think his third time on the show. He is,
Speaker 5:  he's great on decoder. He loves explaining how he thinks. So I'm very curious
Speaker 5:  if he's doing the same thing that I've seen from other companies. Like
Speaker 5:  Uber just had an event this week. D the CEO of Uber also
Speaker 5:  taped a decoder this week. And you know, their, their whole thing is like
Speaker 5:  route sharing and scheduling your commute and Uber one subscriptions and
Speaker 5:  all of these companies, they were kind of like, push a button for a service
Speaker 5:  one time or you know, a few times a week. Or in Airbnb's case, like maybe
Speaker 5:  a couple times a year, they're like, we want you to use this every day. Like
Speaker 5:  that's how they're gonna grow. They all think they're gonna grow in this
Speaker 5:  way. Like you need a relationship with Uber and you're gonna schedule
Speaker 5:  commute an Uber that you do every single day and you're gonna have this like,
Speaker 5:  ongoing relationship with Uber. That's, that's a big part of their growth,
Speaker 5:  right? Yeah. For revenue anyway. It's kind, it feels like the same
Speaker 5:  move for Airbnb.
Speaker 6:  Well, and in the same way that they're like, we have this core underlying
Speaker 6:  technology that like, Airbnb is fundamentally like a guest
Speaker 6:  and host matching platform, right? And it's like if you, if you just expand
Speaker 6:  that out, you get to, well, people need to book things
Speaker 6:  and people need to have things booked. So sure we'll do that.
Speaker 6:  But like, there's a lot of those, those out in the world. I
Speaker 6:  don't know, I just, I'm, I am, maybe you're right in
Speaker 6:  Eli, that being the one that processes the payments and manages it all is,
Speaker 6:  is meaningful.
Speaker 6:  But I'm just not sure. I'm like, if I, if I wanna find a place to have dinner
Speaker 6:  near my Airbnb, I have a hard time imagining that the
Speaker 6:  first thing I'm gonna do is open the Airbnb app.
Speaker 5:  Well, I mean that's, that's their challenge. I gotta teach people to do that.
Speaker 5:  I think it's, i I I think that side of it is like different 'cause
Speaker 5:  you know, the, there's 10 chefs available in my, my area
Speaker 5:  and it's like, yeah, I have no idea how to get a private chef.
Speaker 5:  Especially if I'm on vacation. And I think there's a lot of people that are
Speaker 5:  like, okay, I've, I like, you know, my whole friend group is gonna rent a
Speaker 5:  house and it would be sick to have a private chef and like now it's a
Speaker 5:  button. And like if you can just build that muscle that's like, oh, I could
Speaker 5:  do that at home. Yes, there's something there. Again, I'm excited to talk
Speaker 5:  to Brian tomorrow. I I share a lot of these same doubts. Will
Speaker 6:  You ask Brian if he has any friends who aren't billionaires? Because that
Speaker 6:  the thing you just described is a billionaire problem.
Speaker 5:  I don't think it's a billionaire problem. I, I think the reason people get
Speaker 5:  big Airbnb houses is 'cause if you can split the cost with enough
Speaker 5:  people, it starts to feel reasonable, right? And
Speaker 5:  I'm, I, I've never actually booked a private chef. I don't know if the math
Speaker 5:  works the same way for private chef. I'm still scrounging pennies
Speaker 5:  to buy a Cadillac skate for 89 point 95. But
Speaker 5:  it, that's how that math works for a lot of people, right? We can all get
Speaker 5:  our own hotel room or we can pool our money and get a sick house where we
Speaker 5:  can like I hear that all the time. If you can add onto that,
Speaker 5:  I mean this is my entire thesis about limos in Las Vegas, right? Like
Speaker 5:  it's no fun to be in a limo by yourself. Like
Speaker 5:  that's the saddest you can be is drunk in Vegas alone in a limo
Speaker 5:  like that, that is as Drake as I've ever felt my entire time.
Speaker 5:  But you, you put 10 people in. This is the best experience I've ever had.
Speaker 5:  Right? And there's just something about that that I, you can see them trying
Speaker 5:  to tap into here. I don't think it's, I need to find a restaurant near me.
Speaker 5:  I think, I think it's some, it's some other thing that's like, can we make
Speaker 5:  this a little bit more special as a group?
Speaker 6:  That's fair. I, and I I, I can see that
Speaker 6:  working. I just don't think that road is very long.
Speaker 6:  Like there's just not the list of things that qualify under that rubric
Speaker 6:  just isn't huge.
Speaker 5:  I do wanna make one addendum to my, my limo comment, which is one year at
Speaker 5:  CESI got a Cadillac Escalade limo from the airport by myself. And I took
Speaker 5:  it to Shake Shack by myself in that ruled
Speaker 6:  That, that, I mean,
Speaker 5:  Las Vegas the only city in America, in the world I think where you can just
Speaker 5:  summon an Escalade limousine. Like you just like walk outside of a building
Speaker 5:  and be like, do you have a giant limo? And like 10 guys are like, oh yeah,
Speaker 5:  here I am. Can't have that experience anywhere else in the world. You gotta
Speaker 5:  that's why it's, that's what it's for.
Speaker 5:  I mean, I, I know other people think we has other purposes, but
Speaker 6:  No, that's it. That's
Speaker 5:  Not, there's the one. Yeah, but it's, that's what it's for. Alright, we gotta,
Speaker 5:  we gotta write this up. I'm gonna ask Brian Jetski how many people he is
Speaker 5:  ever. If he's ever been drunk alone in alone tomorrow.
Speaker 9:  That's good.
Speaker 5:  Let me know if you've got your shirts by the way. Party speaker update. Speaking
Speaker 5:  of that, many, many, many photos of party speakers this week on,
Speaker 5:  on like on transportation. We got one on an
Speaker 5:  airport shuttle, which seems deeply rude. Like, don't do that.
Speaker 5:  No confined spaces are not where party speakers go. Lots of
Speaker 5:  Nashville Bachelor party bike buses with party speakers on them. That's a
Speaker 5:  thing. And then here's the thing I want to know just to wrap this up.
Speaker 5:  So many pictures of party speakers, maybe a company called Ion, which I believe
Speaker 5:  is a house brand of, of one of the major retailers. I'm not sure if you
Speaker 5:  know what ION is, if you know who run Ion, lemme know.
Speaker 5:  That's the next phase of our investigation. 'cause I think they'll talk.
Speaker 5:  I've been trying to get onto the Sony party speaker team for years. Like
Speaker 5:  I've gone to the highest levels of the s Sony Corporation and been like,
Speaker 5:  I know people in Japan. I will send them to the party speaker team and
Speaker 5:  they're like, not today that, that's some like Apple
Speaker 5:  design lap shit. You know what I mean? Like the room where they put the cup
Speaker 5:  holders in, the party speakers. I think the I people.
Speaker 5:  All right, that's it. That's for cha for,
Speaker 9:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 9:  you. Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one.
Speaker 9:  The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media Media Podcast
Speaker 9:  network. Our show's produced by Will Pour Eric Gomez and Brandon
Speaker 9:  Keefer. And that's it. We'll see you next week.