# Transcript
ID: 85c21e52-5241-4713-85ef-1eda16888438
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-6085400793422067167/-5441834408049713462/s93290-US-6898s-1749813459.mp3
Description: There's a lot of news this week, so today's episode turned into a whole bunch of lightning rounds. Nilay, David, and The Verge's Jake Kastrenakes talk through all the vibes and news at WWDC, and why F1 seemed to outshine everything else. We also talk about the Switch 2 launch, and the news this week that Microsoft and Asus are building Xbox handhelds in both clever and confusing ways. After that, we run through for a bunch of AI news, including the ongoing decline of Google traffic to the web, the new Dia browser, and Sam Altman's ideas about how much water ChatGPT uses. Finally, it's time for another edition of Brendan Carr is a Dummy, followed by the news of Warner Bros. Discovery breaking up, some very fast flash drives, and a new Meta messaging app.
Speaker 3:  Hello and welcome to Our Chest, the flagship podcast of America's bestselling
Speaker 3:  video game console.
Speaker 3:  See, it's topical. It's not snarky.
Speaker 1:  I know. That was, that was it.
Speaker 3:  It wasn't mean. I can do it.
Speaker 2:  I feel like you were really trying to prove it. See,
Speaker 3:  See everybody
Speaker 2:  That wasn't the most
Speaker 3:  That's, that's where we are. It's one or the other. There it is. It's either
Speaker 3:  Mario Cart or
Speaker 3:  there was a moral panic about this game Smash Super. It was like smash TV
Speaker 3:  or something, I don't know. And it was like you were, you were doing a riot
Speaker 3:  in a shopping mall. Perfect. Okay.
Speaker 1:  That is a really great premise for a video game.
Speaker 2:  Is this eight bit like, what are we talking here?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it was like eight bit. Oh, I found it. It's a smash TV is a 1990
Speaker 3:  arcade game and then it came out as Super
Speaker 3:  Smash TV on the S Nest and the Genesis. Mm. And it was
Speaker 3:  the, the theme of the game was borrowed from Robocop.
Speaker 2:  Oh wow.
Speaker 3:  And then in the, in the game, you're playing on the most violent game show
Speaker 3:  of all time in the not too distant future of 1999. And the goal is
Speaker 3:  to survive while earning cash and prizes, including
Speaker 3:  VCRs and Toasters.
Speaker 2:  How has this not been made into a movie? I don, this is like a perfect
Speaker 2:  premise for 2025. You
Speaker 1:  Just described Squid Game, you know that, right? They did Squid Game,
Speaker 3:  But there was like a straight Oh. And if you, if you, you cannot
Speaker 3:  collect enough keys. You go to a bonus level called the Pleasure Dome where
Speaker 3:  you can collect hundreds of blue bikini glad women,
Speaker 3:  you know, there was a full, there was just a full moral
Speaker 3:  panic about this game. I, for obvious reasons. And now it's just Squid game.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that's like, that's like a pretty medium black mirror
Speaker 1:  episode premise. What you just, what you just said. That's really good.
Speaker 3:  Anyway, Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of the pleasure to,
Speaker 3:  it's been unusually morning on The Vergecast these past few weeks. Mostly
Speaker 3:  David Pierce's fault, I have to say. So I'm just trying to, I'm trying to
Speaker 3:  keep, keep our theme alive. Anyway, I have your friend David Pierce is here.
Speaker 2:  Hello.
Speaker 3:  Jay Castran is here.
Speaker 2:  Hey, good to be here.
Speaker 3:  A lot has gone on this week. Obviously. I just came back from wwe C My brain
Speaker 3:  is basically mush After that experience. The switch two came
Speaker 3:  out. We should talk about that. We got lightning round after lightning round.
Speaker 3:  Brendan, Brendan, there's a, we gotta talk about six G because of Brendan.
Speaker 3:  It's just getting dumber and dumber over there every day. You guys,
Speaker 3:  media companies continue to merge and Unmerge just unprecedented rates.
Speaker 3:  Just a lot going on. And then I missed most of it 'cause I was
Speaker 3:  at Apple Park where talking about
Speaker 3:  the F1 movie just took precedent over like everything
Speaker 1:  You say that, but like, it really seemed like that, like the main thing
Speaker 1:  from afar that it seemed like Apple cared about this week was F1.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, it was, it was the intro to the keynote. It was
Speaker 1:  all over the place at Apple Park. They, I, they did a screening for press.
Speaker 1:  It was like
Speaker 3:  With an F1 car in the middle of the Steve Jobs theater, like the, the top
Speaker 3:  part.
Speaker 1:  Oh, wild.
Speaker 3:  It's a big empty area and many different things have been
Speaker 3:  staged in this big empty area. But this was an F1 car. It was what I was
Speaker 3:  told Alison was there. I was not there. I was podcasting with John Gruber
Speaker 3:  and
Speaker 1:  Then like Tim Cook, who, who was sort of mysteriously absent from a lot of
Speaker 1:  stuff. This week was in a big, I think it was a variety profile
Speaker 1:  that was largely about like F1. It's just, this is like Apple's
Speaker 1:  flagship product is now like a Brad Pitt movie. Yeah. Which is just a weird
Speaker 1:  state of affairs.
Speaker 2:  The thing that's great about F1 at a developer conference is that nobody
Speaker 2:  there is even remotely qualified to, to assess whether it
Speaker 2:  is the right thing to do or a good thing like that is not like,
Speaker 1:  They're just like,
Speaker 2:  Hey, here's this thing. It's for a totally different audience. It's probably
Speaker 2:  good.
Speaker 3:  Well that's very much reflected in the, like the TBOS segment of wwc where
Speaker 3:  they announced like the pictures are bigger and there's more content and
Speaker 3:  those are the features of TBO S. Like no new ideas. I will say like
Speaker 3:  it's, WC has two tracks. There's a big consumer track, which is the part
Speaker 3:  that we cover, and then there's an actual developer track where they get
Speaker 3:  into the nitty gritty of how you can use different AI models
Speaker 3:  And I x code to make swift, like that's all there. It's just
Speaker 3:  tucked away. They had a bunch of like sub stackers there, like fashion and
Speaker 3:  culture sub stackers who did a meet and greet with Tim.
Speaker 3:  Sure. Right. But what's really interesting is Tim did nothing about
Speaker 3:  Apple's products. The only big press that Tim did was
Speaker 3:  that profile and variety with Lewis Hamilton where they talked about F1.
Speaker 3:  And I encourage everyone to read it because
Speaker 3:  Louis Hamilton convinced the author of that profile that he was impressed
Speaker 3:  at at the, the skyline of San Jose.
Speaker 3:  Like, I don't, there's, I can't, that's how, that's where, that's where that
Speaker 3:  profile begins is like they're on the roof of Apple Park together and
Speaker 3:  the, he's like, is that San Jose? And Tim Cook is like, it is. And
Speaker 3:  then they like stand there and admire the beauty. And I'm like, San Jose
Speaker 3:  is is very pretty. It's very pretty. No,
Speaker 1:  In California, I lived in San Jose. I am, I'm qualified to
Speaker 1:  opine on the skylight of San Jose. The skyline of San Jose does not
Speaker 1:  exist. That's like interesting. It's weird. There's like four
Speaker 1:  buildings. That's not a skyline. That's four
Speaker 3:  Buildings. But if you read the profile, it's like even Lewis Park was taken
Speaker 3:  in by Apple Park And I, you know, apple Park is very pretty, but it's been
Speaker 3:  around for a while now. And it, it it's been,
Speaker 3:  it's just a familiar thing. Like lots of people have been there for lots
Speaker 3:  of reasons. Louis Hamilton is a knight who like
Speaker 3:  routinely drives the most expensive cars in the world around Monaco.
Speaker 3:  Like I just get the feeling like maybe, maybe this room with no furniture
Speaker 3:  in it was not that impressive too.
Speaker 1:  So Matt, when Matt Bella from Puck was on this show a month or
Speaker 1:  so ago, he basically was like, I I, my question for him was essentially like,
Speaker 1:  why are all these big tech companies so invested
Speaker 1:  in being part of the streaming wars when it seems to mostly be all downside?
Speaker 1:  And, and basically what he said is like, don't underestimate how much
Speaker 1:  really wealthy people want really famous friends. And I just look at that
Speaker 1:  picture of Tim Cook and Lewis Hamilton and I'm like, oh, I get it. Like that's,
Speaker 1:  this is why you do
Speaker 3:  It. There's a, there's an entire side of it. Not like it's fine variety.
Speaker 3:  They're the trade publication of Hollywood. Sure. They do glossy features
Speaker 3:  on new movies all the time. It's like that's, that's their function. And
Speaker 3:  I'm glad they did it because I get to read it. But you just read it as a
Speaker 3:  tech reporter and it, they're like, apple invented cameras for this
Speaker 3:  movie and it's like, did they, what are the cameras like? And there's no
Speaker 3:  further there. No follow-up is given. It's like, I guess, I
Speaker 3:  guess they did. There
Speaker 1:  Was a really big GQ story about the movie that actually had some of that
Speaker 1:  detail on how they made the thing. It was pretty cool. But they're like,
Speaker 1:  I mean this is as universally
Speaker 1:  promoted a movie as I can remember in a long time. Like Apple
Speaker 1:  is partly, you know, it's Brad Pitt and it's the guy who made Top Gun Maverick.
Speaker 1:  And so it's like a big name production, but also it's very clear that Apple
Speaker 1:  is putting like absolutely everything it has behind this movie being a
Speaker 1:  huge hit. Which is just fascinating.
Speaker 3:  I surprised a lot of Apple people with my extensive knowledge of the movie
Speaker 3:  Days of Thunder and my many questions about whether they had just made Days
Speaker 3:  of Thunder again and whether there was as much cocaine on the set of F1 as
Speaker 3:  there was on Days of Thunder. And like literally at one point
Speaker 3:  someone from Apple looked at me and said, you know a lot about Days of Thunder.
Speaker 3:  So I'm, I'm dying to know that's, that's my only angle on this movie. Like,
Speaker 3:  did they make Days of Thunder again? But Tim only did press
Speaker 3:  about the movie. He only did photo ops with, I I
Speaker 3:  you would call them culture reporters. Like, and that's great. That's what
Speaker 3:  he did. That's what they got. No product conversation. The
Speaker 3:  person who talked about products the most was Craig Federighi. And
Speaker 3:  mostly what he did in those conversations with Lance ov, with Joanna Stern
Speaker 3:  with a few others, he apologized for AI not being
Speaker 3:  ready. And that's, it's, Tim is not on the
Speaker 3:  hook for that in any way, shape or form. And I, you can, that's
Speaker 3:  kind of the wwc right over here we're gonna have this conversation about
Speaker 3:  Siri and why it didn't happen and what's gonna happen next. And over here
Speaker 3:  we're gonna celebrate F1 and that's the CEO and it's this guy who's accountable
Speaker 3:  for the mistake and this guy who's hanging out with the race car driver.
Speaker 3:  And that feels a little upside down to me. I don't like did you guys
Speaker 3:  perceive that from the outside? It was very much the sense on the ground
Speaker 3:  there remotely. I feel like it was not, I mean the F1 stuff
Speaker 2:  Was certainly not as prevalent remotely.
Speaker 2:  I think the AI thing like was very loud, right? Because I think, you know,
Speaker 2:  coming into it from the past like year of Apple, right?
Speaker 2:  Their last WDC, what they, they went all in on ai. And
Speaker 2:  it's funny, I've, I feel like I've seen some folks say like,
Speaker 2:  why, you know, why is Apple being held up? Why do they have to do ai? Why,
Speaker 2:  why does it matter if they get this AI done in time? It's like what? Apple
Speaker 2:  promised it. Apple went like, yeah, really big last year
Speaker 2:  saying that AI was part of their identity. They redefined AI as an
Speaker 2:  acronym with their name in it. They ran ads promoting
Speaker 2:  these features. Fast forward a year and AI
Speaker 2:  is really just this like very shallow thing throughout the conference
Speaker 2:  now, you know, in fairness it did have a lot to show with, with
Speaker 2:  Liquid Glass in every single possible location. But
Speaker 2:  yeah, that, that felt like the big one and the fact that they did not
Speaker 2:  talk about it and then only kind of like threaded it into these interviews
Speaker 2:  after the fact where they kind of just like e even then,
Speaker 2:  you know, you said Craig apologized, but I, I feel like he gave kind of the
Speaker 2:  same exact explanation to everybody where he was like, well it was kind of
Speaker 2:  ready but not ready enough. Yeah. And we're like,
Speaker 2:  but like what, what does that mean? Like every other company has
Speaker 2:  done this. You guys have more money than I don't know
Speaker 2:  anyone on earth. How can you not get
Speaker 2:  something working?
Speaker 3:  Wait, I want, actually, I wanna be fair. No one else has pulled this off.
Speaker 3:  We'll come to this 'cause we're gonna talk about Alexa plus later on in the
Speaker 3:  show, no one else has done this. Like zero companies have pulled off the
Speaker 3:  thing that everyone wants to pull off and Apple has this problem where they
Speaker 3:  can't say agent 'cause that's the word everyone else is using. But the idea
Speaker 3:  that you have some like agent that like uses the apps for you is like a is
Speaker 3:  a thing. Everybody wants to do it and Google has come sort of the closest.
Speaker 3:  That's
Speaker 2:  Fair. But they're not even halfway there. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  They're not even like they're, but they're, and there are excuses. We won't
Speaker 3:  ship the bad one and everyone else is bad, which is very Apple. Yeah. But
Speaker 3:  everyone else is like shipping the bad one. Like you can just buy a pixel
Speaker 3:  phone and like talk to it for six hours, you know, like it's fine.
Speaker 1:  The like true legacy of chat GPT is going to be that every, it made
Speaker 1:  everybody comfortable with shipping the bad one, right? Yeah. Because it's
Speaker 1:  like, if you remember before chat GPT Google, which was like working on
Speaker 1:  all of this stuff internally, it was like, well this stuff sucks, why would
Speaker 1:  we ship it to people? And then chat GPT, they were just like, eh, we don't
Speaker 1:  know if this is anything. It's a research preview. Here you go. And it like
Speaker 1:  set the world on fire and now all of a sudden everybody had to ship all of
Speaker 1:  their bad stuff just to prove they had a bad thing to ship. And, and Apple
Speaker 1:  let itself get caught up in that, which is yeah, very
Speaker 1:  unapply in that sense.
Speaker 3:  You know, if Apple had made a chat, Bott can, you know, in, in
Speaker 3:  all these interviews that they did, they said they were never gonna make
Speaker 3:  a chat bot and they were just trying to pin a chat bott on 'em. And that's
Speaker 3:  not what they're trying to make and fine. But if they just made one, can
Speaker 3:  you imagine just how absolutely anodyne it would be
Speaker 3:  to comply with being Apple? Like they have like some brand problems
Speaker 3:  here where, you know, like I'm assuming there's not one lick of sex
Speaker 3:  in the F1 movie, right? Like the Apple just like, it doesn't exist for them
Speaker 3:  like in any other content. Like it is the most androgynous company that has
Speaker 3:  ever existed in the history of the world. Like it's just liquid glass,
Speaker 3:  you know what I mean? Like it's just smooth. That's it. That's Apple. And
Speaker 3:  so like that chat bots thrive on having personality and like open eyes always
Speaker 3:  talking like, oh this was too nice, it's too obsequious, we're gonna dial
Speaker 3:  it. Backrock is just out there, right? Elon's like it's me and someone's
Speaker 3:  like, this is horrifying. Like there's an element of danger to the chatbot
Speaker 3:  'cause it is just talking to you that can you imagine if a chatbot talk like
Speaker 3:  an Apple executive in an interview? Like there's a problem here that you
Speaker 3:  know. And so look, my point Jake is yes, they
Speaker 3:  haven't done it nearly as, they haven't shipped anything as bad as anyone
Speaker 3:  else, but everyone else is still kind of bad and doesn't work. And I think
Speaker 3:  they should say like the apple of old Steve Jobs of old have been like, look
Speaker 3:  at this garbage.
Speaker 1:  Yep.
Speaker 3:  Like look at this. Like, we're not doing this. And he, he, he just like won't
Speaker 3:  bring they can't bring themselves to do it for whatever reason. And that
Speaker 3:  they're, I think they're just, they're kind of trapped in a, a puzzle of
Speaker 3:  their own making.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I I think that's like a, a fair enough argument. And I think again,
Speaker 2:  if they had done nothing last year, we'd be like, we, you know, we, we could,
Speaker 2:  we could impugn all of this onto them, right? Like they're waiting to ship
Speaker 2:  the right thing, but like instead they're stuck in a situation where
Speaker 2:  Siri has existed for a decade and it is the bad version
Speaker 2:  of the chatbot. Yeah. They promised a better version and now
Speaker 2:  it's like, you know, if if they just ship, honestly, like again, if they
Speaker 2:  just ship chat GBT, we'd be like, it has some problems. It has but it's better
Speaker 2:  than Siri currently is.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I don't need to belabor this. Joanna did the best of these interviews.
Speaker 3:  She pushed them really hard.
Speaker 3:  She like really hard good on her for doing that. And then I
Speaker 3:  was on a podcast with her. We were the guests who replaced Craig
Speaker 3:  Federici and Greg s Schack or whoever, whatever. I think the last year was
Speaker 3:  Mike Rockwell. John Gruber always has a talk show with Apple executives.
Speaker 3:  He asked for a decade and they declined his invitation this year. And Joanna
Speaker 3:  And I were the dancing monkey fill-ins and we had a great time, but we just
Speaker 3:  honestly had a great time. Especially 'cause Joanna had just interviewed
Speaker 3:  them. So if you want more unpacking of all of that, you can listen to the
Speaker 3:  talk show. It was fun to do. Thanks for John. Thanks to John for having us
Speaker 3:  on the, the only thing I just wanted to unpack was like, this was a weird
Speaker 3:  one and like a lot of ways it was, it was just a weird one.
Speaker 3:  And usually Apple is very confident like this. They're doing what
Speaker 3:  they're doing. And this year for the, the split between
Speaker 3:  the confidence of Hollywood style marketing of a race car movie and the
Speaker 3:  sort of like back foot,
Speaker 3:  the rest of the industry is pursuing AI in one way and, and we don't think
Speaker 3:  it's good enough and we will, we will try to explain but
Speaker 3:  never not really explain like it was on the ground kind of drawing.
Speaker 1:  It was weird to watch because it was, it was, I mean Apple doesn't do anything
Speaker 1:  like this. Not deliberately, but this felt particularly deliberate
Speaker 1:  in the sense that like, you go and read and watch some of the stuff that
Speaker 1:  Craig Feder in particular was saying. I mean, and, and he had a, he
Speaker 1:  had the speech just nailed right? And, and they, he was unusually
Speaker 1:  accessible in a bunch of different ways. They were, they talked to a bunch
Speaker 1:  of different people and just said the same thing over and over
Speaker 1:  and over again. And that's not to say it's not true, it's just like clearly
Speaker 1:  this was the, the message that they had and they were like, not only do we
Speaker 1:  have to communicate all this stuff that we think is cool and exciting and
Speaker 1:  why liquid glass is great, we also have to explain
Speaker 1:  where Siri is. And it is, it's very clear the company knows that.
Speaker 1:  And ordinarily, like we always make fun of Apple for pretending that
Speaker 1:  anything it doesn't want to exist just doesn't exist. And you, you can feel
Speaker 1:  that Apple is like, it, it knows, it has to acknowledge this stuff
Speaker 1:  in a way that is awkward for Apple to try and do. And even
Speaker 1:  at the very beginning of the keynote on Monday for Craig to be like, yeah,
Speaker 1:  we're we're shipping this stuff. We're we're still working on it. It's not
Speaker 1:  quite ready, it's coming later this year. Very unapply. And you, you can
Speaker 1:  tell this company is just like very much on its back foot with a lot of this
Speaker 1:  stuff right now.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And a lot of, by the way that the, the speech, it was
Speaker 3:  them saying John Gruber was wrong,
Speaker 3:  like directly, like there's a bad narrative out there about this and what
Speaker 3:  they mean, what they have meant this entire time is we hate John's blog post.
Speaker 3:  We are mad at him. And for it's like fine, like
Speaker 3:  John Gruber is maybe the most influential Apple blogger of all time.
Speaker 3:  He remains so he has been like Steve Jobs used to like send his blog post
Speaker 3:  to people to be like, here's yes, this is what I think too. Great.
Speaker 3:  He's he has achieved that goal, but it's just pretty wild. The disparity
Speaker 3:  between a trillion dollar company and literally one guy, they're not mad
Speaker 3:  at like the New York Times. They're mad at one guy.
Speaker 1:  Well they're also mad at the New York Times. Like
Speaker 3:  In a way that you're like always like, yeah, supposed to, like everyone in
Speaker 3:  America is perpetually angry at the New York Times. They feed on your hate
Speaker 3:  and they drive subscriptions to their games because of it. Like
Speaker 3:  that's their job. They're the New York Times. They're, they're owned by a
Speaker 3:  billionaire family and they have 10 million lawyers and have apples and apple
Speaker 3:  and that's fine. This is one guy, like
Speaker 3:  literally one guy, like he at one point he was like, I'm one guy,
Speaker 3:  like the Virgin newsroom dwarfs John Gruber by a DX,
Speaker 3:  right? Like it's
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  He's one guy. And that dynamic was one of the like
Speaker 3:  truly the weirdest parts of this where what they meant was we're mad at that
Speaker 3:  one blog post.
Speaker 1:  If I'm intuiting the dynamic here correctly. It seems like what,
Speaker 1:  what Gruber said in that post, what earlier this
Speaker 1:  spring was basically that what Apple showed was
Speaker 1:  more or less a lie. Like it was, it was a concept video disguised as
Speaker 1:  a product demonstration. And Apple is
Speaker 1:  saying no, it was just a really bad product
Speaker 1:  that we were demonstrating. And it's like,
Speaker 3:  I, I guess
Speaker 1:  That's an argument, but I'm not sure that's as compelling as you think that
Speaker 1:  it is.
Speaker 3:  Right. What they said to everyone was that was real code. Right. And it just
Speaker 3:  didn't mean our quality standards. Right. Okay.
Speaker 1:  We made a bad thing, but we made a thing
Speaker 1:  is a is a really interesting version of a defense against the, the spirit
Speaker 1:  of Gruber's argument, which is that Siri sucks and Apple should feel bad
Speaker 1:  about it.
Speaker 3:  Right? And then somewhere in Apple's culture, the decision that they could
Speaker 3:  get away with it was made. Right? Right. And then if you're gambling
Speaker 3:  like that, especially in a prerecorded video, when the bill comes due, someone
Speaker 3:  has to pay it. And that's really his argument. Like he, I don't think he
Speaker 3:  ever says they lied. And he says, I think the title is something is Rotten
Speaker 3:  in the state of Cupertino. Like what he means is something in the culture
Speaker 3:  has gone awry to the place where you're, because you have these prerecorded
Speaker 3:  videos, you can get away with a little bit more. Like, do you know what else
Speaker 3:  was real code that was definitely not up to Apple's quality
Speaker 3:  standards. The iPhone that Steve Jobs demoed at the first iPhone event. Right.
Speaker 3:  Like that, that was a demo on Rails. Like famously there was a
Speaker 3:  magic path through the demo that would prevent that iPhone from crashing
Speaker 3:  and any deviation from it would've crashed the phone. Yep. And the whole
Speaker 3:  iPhone team was like doing shots through that demo
Speaker 3:  as Steve Shots got through it. 'cause they were like so worked up and nervous
Speaker 3:  and they were all completely hammer drunk at the end of it. It's like, great
Speaker 3:  stories, you can go find it out, out on the internet, but he took the risk
Speaker 3:  and the risk is what would've absolved them of a delay.
Speaker 3:  Right. He's like, I actually used this thing, I actually showed it to you.
Speaker 3:  It's not quite up to our standards. We're gonna keep working on it. People
Speaker 3:  are like, well we believe you. The prerecorded demo
Speaker 3:  eliminates the risk. It can be even worse. There can be no magic path.
Speaker 3:  'cause it's a prerecorded demo,
Speaker 1:  Right? Like how many tries did it take you to get this to work once the way
Speaker 1:  that you needed it to in order to shoot it? It's very different from what
Speaker 1:  it used to be, which is like Craig Federighi walks up to a laptop on
Speaker 1:  stage and uses it in front of you. Yeah. Like it, it's just a completely
Speaker 1:  different dynamic.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So I like, again, it was just that vibe was weird
Speaker 3:  and that's what I, I was just immersed in it for like several days and in
Speaker 3:  the meantime, like the switch to is coming out and Microsoft is announcing
Speaker 3:  an entirely new like, handheld strategy for Xbox. And I'm like looking at
Speaker 3:  our list, I'm like, all this other stuff happened and that stuff is basically
Speaker 3:  like, I, I don't even know how to describe it. It was like an alternate
Speaker 3:  reality where like there's the highest of highs like Lewis
Speaker 3:  Hamilton in a race car and the weirdest of lows. Yeah. So
Speaker 3:  let's talk about the other stuff again, if you want to hear me dive way more
Speaker 3:  into the weirdness of Apple Talk show, I I assume we'll be out. You can also
Speaker 3:  watch it in a Vision Pro. It was a full event, a packed theater. It was really
Speaker 3:  fun to meet everybody who was there.
Speaker 1:  Spatial neli is, I don't think a thing I'm ready for. I tell you it was
Speaker 3:  True. It was really weird. Lots of cameras on stage and then a 360 camera
Speaker 3:  in the middle. It was fun. Anyhow, you can go listen to the talk show or
Speaker 3:  watch it I guess. But the Switch two came out and it's like very, like we
Speaker 3:  have a lot of them on our team. People have been playing them, people are
Speaker 3:  buying them at incredible rates, but then there's like the inevitable problems
Speaker 3:  of scale. David, what's going on?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So the, the vibes around the switch two
Speaker 1:  launch have been strange in the sense that like
Speaker 1:  the, there were, I mean, going all the way back to like the day they
Speaker 1:  announced, it was also the day that Trump announced tariffs with like the
Speaker 1:  big, you know, sign on the lawn of the White House. And so
Speaker 1:  everything was thrown into chaos and nobody knew what it was gonna cost or
Speaker 1:  whatever it was gonna ship. But the thing ends up shipping people had an
Speaker 1:  unusually easy time buying it, I think, which A lot of people took to
Speaker 1:  mean maybe demand was not as high as we expected.
Speaker 1:  We talked a little bit about this last week, but like I was able to just
Speaker 1:  walk into Target on launch day and buy one. I heard from
Speaker 1:  lots of people who also did Chris Grant on
Speaker 1:  our in at from Fox Media was very excited. He saw my post about how easy
Speaker 1:  it was to get one and he went and got one and was very thankful. So like,
Speaker 1:  everybody's like, okay, maybe this thing isn't the hit that we thought it
Speaker 1:  was. It's just a better switch. And then Nintendo puts out
Speaker 1:  data earlier this week that said it sold 3.5 million of them over
Speaker 1:  the basically the long launch weekend, which would make it the fastest selling
Speaker 1:  game console of all time, which is a huge
Speaker 1:  number full of context. Right. And actually, actually what
Speaker 1:  it suggests is that what Nintendo did
Speaker 1:  was manage its supply chain for a launch better than
Speaker 1:  any console in the history of video games. Right. Which is like, not a
Speaker 1:  small thing, but it it, it appears that both tons of people
Speaker 1:  wanted this thing and Nintendo had enough of them, which is like a
Speaker 1:  pretty remarkable accomplishment in the current world that we live in.
Speaker 1:  Reviews are still coming out. No one got one ahead of time, which was an
Speaker 1:  interesting and and odd thing that doesn't often happen with things like
Speaker 1:  this. But so reviews are still coming out. I
Speaker 1:  think there's a pretty good chance that by the time you're hearing this episode,
Speaker 1:  Andrew Webster's review will be live. He's also gonna be on the show next
Speaker 1:  Tuesday talking about it.
Speaker 1:  But like all of them say sort of the same thing, which is like yeah, it's
Speaker 1:  a really great switch.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. My sense of reading all the reviews And I read a bunch on, on the plane
Speaker 3:  on the way home yesterday was, And I could not bring
Speaker 3:  myself to buy an OLED switch. Like I have the original switch and like after
Speaker 3:  a while you're like, man, this screen is small and bad. I should get an OLED
Speaker 3:  screen. And then you like look at it, you're like, this is, this is just
Speaker 3:  a switch with an oled. I can't spend this money. I have children. Like,
Speaker 3:  like no, and then this is enough. This is
Speaker 3:  enough to make you buy a new switch. But it's then it's a new switch.
Speaker 1:  Right? And, and there's, there's this weird dynamic of it is both,
Speaker 1:  I think a, a nearly perfect upgrade to
Speaker 1:  the switch in the sense that it, like, it made all the things that you didn't
Speaker 1:  like better and it made all of the things that you already liked
Speaker 1:  better than that. But there is like, there are no new ideas here
Speaker 1:  in a way that I think Nintendo's bar for
Speaker 1:  launching things that are like weird and wild and wonderful is so high
Speaker 1:  that you're like, my mind has not been blown by something. I never even
Speaker 1:  imagined a game console could do Four outta 10. And you're
Speaker 1:  like, wait, hold on.
Speaker 3:  Like, what, what are we
Speaker 1:  Supposed? So it's just, it's been a very strange phenomenon. And I will say
Speaker 1:  the biggest concern I've heard so far
Speaker 1:  has been about battery life. People have done a bunch of tests and, and there's
Speaker 1:  some indication that like the switch to battery life is as much as like
Speaker 1:  half of the switch oles battery life, which is bad
Speaker 1:  like, like two hours of battery life bad, which is bad.
Speaker 1:  And it's bad enough that Nintendo is now saying it might be a bug, which
Speaker 1:  is like dangerously close to a, you're holding it wrong Yeah. Explanation
Speaker 1:  for this kind of stuff. And so that's, that's a little sketchy and
Speaker 1:  weird. But in general, outside of not being as exciting
Speaker 1:  as some people wanted, this is all going exceptionally well for
Speaker 1:  Nintendo.
Speaker 2:  I got one Monday I've been playing Zelda. It's delightful. It really, it's,
Speaker 2:  it is a switch and everything is a little bit better. It is what it should
Speaker 2:  be for, for this year. I, the thing that I think is a little bit underwhelming
Speaker 2:  about it right now is not necessarily the hardware. I think one of the things
Speaker 2:  that's so wonderful about the original switch is by
Speaker 2:  virtue of being a little bit behind all the other consoles,
Speaker 2:  it just has this incredible library of old games from other consoles Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That it can now play because it's capable enough. And so now
Speaker 2:  theoretically the switch too is unlocking the ability to play a whole
Speaker 2:  wave of games that the original switch wasn't capable of.
Speaker 3:  Can you get Smash TV on the switch too? That's what I'm asking right now.
Speaker 3:  Maybe
Speaker 2:  That, that, that age rating might not be supported by
Speaker 1:  Nintendo.
Speaker 2:  But the problem is on day one, that stuff is not there.
Speaker 2:  Right. You can play cyberpunk. That is crazy. You can play
Speaker 2:  in upgraded No Man Sky. That's
Speaker 1:  Cool. Fortnite sick,
Speaker 2:  Right? Fortnite Okay, great. But like, you know, I'm playing through
Speaker 2:  Zelda and it's like I'm playing the final five
Speaker 2:  side quests that I did not finish earlier. Like it, it's, you know,
Speaker 2:  So I, I'm very excited. I think this is going to be
Speaker 2:  a, a fantastic handheld eventually, but what I'm looking forward to
Speaker 2:  is okay, eventually Red Dead Redemption two, which
Speaker 2:  I have never been able to play because I only have a switch is gonna come
Speaker 2:  to the Switch too. Yeah. And it will look very good that day is not today.
Speaker 2:  That's also like
Speaker 1:  A perfect switch to game. 'cause it's, so much of it is just like, ride a
Speaker 1:  horse for 45 minutes and like this, you can just sit on the couch and ride
Speaker 1:  a horse for 45 minutes. Like that's the dream. Which
Speaker 2:  By the way is also the appeal of Zelda.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, it's true. Like, it's great. Would you like to walk through a forest
Speaker 1:  all night? Like Sure.
Speaker 2:  You're the only games I play
Speaker 3:  Zelda's one of the few games that involves that level of grinding
Speaker 3:  that I can tolerate because it doesn't feel like a job. And like so many
Speaker 3:  of these games I'm like, I have a job. Like I'm, I already do so much grinding.
Speaker 3:  Have you seen my email?
Speaker 1:  There's a lot of that in, in Red Dead, frankly. That's what I'm saying. Do
Speaker 1:  you wanna go milk the cows this morning? And it's like, no, I, it's 2025.
Speaker 1:  I don't have to do that anymore.
Speaker 3:  But Zelda is very much, it's very different. It's like you, you, you have
Speaker 3:  to cook and it's like, this is delightful actually, I don't know why, because
Speaker 3:  you cook the magic. I won't do this for myself. Right.
Speaker 3:  I'm excited for it. I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm goading myself into buying one
Speaker 3:  at some point. Like, I, I just need one more game. I think it's not Breath
Speaker 3:  of the Wild for me. I've played Breath the Wild a lot. Breath of the Wild
Speaker 3:  again, but better when I've already done luck rendering. We'll see. But it's
Speaker 2:  Coming. Here's the thing, I I think give it a year and that library will
Speaker 2:  be there. And right now it's like if you want Mario Kart, great and if
Speaker 2:  not, eh, you, you
Speaker 1:  Can, I also think if you're a Nintendo, you, you are absolutely fine with
Speaker 1:  this outcome. Right? Like, I was actually thinking about this earlier that
Speaker 1:  most companies spend a lot of time caring about and perfectly
Speaker 1:  trying to time their launch weekend and sort of bring everything in one place
Speaker 1:  and make it a huge event. Nintendo ships like one console
Speaker 1:  every eight years And I think is not super concerned
Speaker 1:  with what happens in the first four days. That said, it sold three and a
Speaker 1:  half million of them in the first few days. So like, it's, it's a real have
Speaker 1:  your cake and eat it too situation. But I think if all of this goes well,
Speaker 1:  this will be a notably better console like on
Speaker 1:  Labor Day Weekend than it was at launch day. Oh,
Speaker 3:  I think it's the holidays that matter the most, right? Like they've sold
Speaker 3:  a lot of them, but they will have the inventory, they will understand their
Speaker 3:  supply chain fluctuations and maybe they'll understand a tariff and they
Speaker 3:  will have a better library of games through a market. Totally. Holidays good
Speaker 3:  for them.
Speaker 3:  Somewhat related. Microsoft announced a vastly more confused strategy about
Speaker 3:  handheld game this week. Oh my god,
Speaker 1:  I cannot tell you how much I've read about this. Trying to figure out if
Speaker 1:  any of it makes any sense. They
Speaker 3:  Announced new Xboxes that you can hold in your hand that don't play Xbox
Speaker 3:  games just to be a hundred percent clear on what happened.
Speaker 1:  Right? Yeah. That's no, that's, that's right. That's, yes. It's
Speaker 3:  Weird. It's a, it's just a weird thing that they did.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And they're like not being super clear about this either, right. Like
Speaker 2:  if you were just to watch this video, you're like, sick. It's an Xbox that
Speaker 2:  plays Xbox games and it's like Xbox asterisk. Like what,
Speaker 2:  what is an Xbox game? Yeah. That's not
Speaker 1:  Clear. So the launch here is is we've, we're in the middle of this like
Speaker 1:  run of game launches and game events. Summer Game Fest,
Speaker 1:  which used to be E three, it was last week. They've just done a, we we've
Speaker 1:  heard about a million new games, all of which are gonna ship at some point
Speaker 1:  in the next century over the last like eight days. And at one
Speaker 1:  of these
Speaker 1:  Microsoft and a Seuss announced two new
Speaker 1:  devices that are just like wrong ally handhelds,
Speaker 1:  except they run this like brand new Xbox focused
Speaker 1:  version of Windows, which is an insane sentence that I look forward to talking
Speaker 1:  about. Yep. But did it in this very like, casual way where it was like, it
Speaker 1:  was mostly a gears of war demo. And then they were just
Speaker 1:  like, here's this new handheld that is actually the future of our entire
Speaker 1:  portable gaming strategy.
Speaker 2:  They would not allow anybody to take photos of it operating currently, by
Speaker 2:  the way.
Speaker 3:  Oh, that's, that's perfect.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's really, it's very weird. And it's also called the a
Speaker 1:  Seuss r Xbox Ally and the a Seus Rog Xbox
Speaker 1:  Ally X, which is bad and everyone should feel
Speaker 1:  bad who came up with a name that is that many words long.
Speaker 1:  But it's all just very weird. And I think the, the strategy as I understand
Speaker 1:  it, and, and again that is, that is a leap that I'm about to take
Speaker 1:  here because I don't understand it, is that instead of
Speaker 1:  trying to basically make Xbox
Speaker 1:  specific things, what what Microsoft is trying to do is
Speaker 1:  shove the Xbox software and windows ever closer together
Speaker 1:  so that what you get on a handheld in particular is not
Speaker 1:  Xbox software, like, which would be sort of windows underneath, but it's
Speaker 1:  like all Xbox on the top. But it is actually essentially Windows
Speaker 1:  optimized for Xbox with like, it's, it's like Android, but with a custom
Speaker 1:  launcher is like essentially what Microsoft is trying to do with Windows
Speaker 1:  and Xbox.
Speaker 3:  That's the classic winning strategy of a custom
Speaker 1:  Launcher. Yeah. Right. So you, you turn this thing on and Tom Warren has
Speaker 1:  covered this a bunch for us. I'll put some links in the show notes, but the
Speaker 1:  way he describes it, it, it loads some of windows but not
Speaker 1:  all of Windows and then loads this Xbox launcher on top. So the
Speaker 1:  idea is Windows should use less memory and thus run faster, which is a good
Speaker 1:  thing. 'cause it just absolutely crushes most of these handhelds. And then
Speaker 1:  the layer on top is, is what looks like an Xbox launcher
Speaker 1:  that'll launch not just your Xbox games, but all of the other games that
Speaker 1:  run on PCs. So like steam store stuff and things like that.
Speaker 1:  Notably, like you said, not Xbox games. You can stream Xbox
Speaker 1:  games. Oh good. You can't, they are PC games that you are playing
Speaker 1:  on your Xbox handheld. And so it's like, there there is this like
Speaker 1:  mush of all of Microsoft's many things into
Speaker 1:  a handheld software that kind of, sort of looks like an Xbox.
Speaker 2:  I I think you can see the trajectory, right? Like they lost to the PS four,
Speaker 2:  they lost to the PS five and now they're like, okay, wait a second.
Speaker 2:  We, we run Windows, we run possibly the biggest gaming platform that
Speaker 2:  exists and
Speaker 3:  Windows to the consumer most relevant as a gaming platform.
Speaker 2:  Yes. Right. And So I think when you look ahead, what is the next Xbox?
Speaker 2:  If there is a singular next Xbox, it's like perhaps it is
Speaker 2:  this Windows thing, right? They're doing a pretty hard, a pretty aggressive
Speaker 2:  pivot. And I think in some ways they're looking at it as maybe they don't
Speaker 2:  actually have a lot to lose given the state of the Xbox in the console
Speaker 2:  race. This
Speaker 1:  Is just such an old school Microsoft strategy to me though. And I don't mean
Speaker 1:  that as a compliment. Like in the Steve Balmer days, the thing was
Speaker 1:  all Windows everything, right? Like we are, we are going to put Windows on
Speaker 1:  everything and that is how we are going to win. We are the Windows company,
Speaker 1:  so we're gonna put Windows on phones and we're gonna put Windows on your
Speaker 1:  desktop and we're gonna put Windows everywhere you can think of. And Satya
Speaker 1:  Nadella came in and said, actually that's the wrong like, level of abstraction
Speaker 1:  at which to put our focus what we are as a cloud company. And they were like,
Speaker 1:  the bet is not on Windows, the bet is on the internet. And like we are going
Speaker 1:  to power data centers and that's going to be very successful. And they've
Speaker 1:  been doing that with the Xbox, right? Like Game Pass is the big bet for the
Speaker 1:  Xbox, right? That like, instead of having a, a console that I plug a disc
Speaker 1:  into and play games on it, anything with a screen becomes an Xbox, right?
Speaker 1:  Like that's the whole marketing strategy. That's what they're trying to do.
Speaker 1:  And now they're just like, rather than build
Speaker 1:  good software, they're just trying to shove Windows back into it. And I'm
Speaker 1:  like, no, you, you missed, you missed the point of all of this, which is
Speaker 1:  that it doesn't all have to be Windows because it shouldn't all be Windows.
Speaker 3:  Well there's weirdness there. I mean, I I do
Speaker 3:  enjoy it. Like bomber's version of Windows everywhere
Speaker 3:  manifested in like Microsoft trying to conquer the living room with
Speaker 3:  Windows, right? And, and for years they would announce a new
Speaker 3:  attempt to put a Windows PC in your living room, culminating in the
Speaker 3:  Xbox One, which ran a cut down weird version of Windows
Speaker 3:  with an Xbox launcher on top of it. And then like this whole plan did
Speaker 3:  IR blaster control your satellite box or something that did not
Speaker 3:  work. It just didn't work. And then they, you know, they moved
Speaker 3:  on and they, they're like, the Xbox is the Xbox again, we're totally focused
Speaker 3:  on gaming, it's this custom thing. But in the meantime, the
Speaker 3:  the handheld market
Speaker 3:  was the, became basically the switch and a bunch of steam deck clones
Speaker 3:  and the steam deck, right? And if you're gonna go compete with that, you're
Speaker 3:  like, oh, this is taking market share from us in any way. Then
Speaker 3:  you're stuck with, they don't want Xbox games, they want PC games here.
Speaker 3:  Like what gamers are saying is we wanna take our PC games on the go and you
Speaker 3:  can't be like, here's some console games on the go because I
Speaker 3:  don't think they can compete with the gamers who want PC games. And that
Speaker 3:  might be the strategy error. Do you know what I mean? Like that might actually
Speaker 3:  be the mistake.
Speaker 1:  So you have to go backwards from where is our big library of games
Speaker 1:  into a handheld Yeah. Because that's just what Microsoft has to do.
Speaker 1:  Because
Speaker 3:  If you're like, the future of the Xbox is more accessible PC gaming,
Speaker 3:  you are cruising your way towards putting Windows underneath the TV again.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Like you're, they're headed there. Tom basically wrote this story for
Speaker 3:  us. Microsoft just teased this next gen Xbox console and nobody noticed.
Speaker 3:  Right. And his point is, if you look at these handhelds that are
Speaker 3:  basically ways to run PC games in cut
Speaker 3:  down power restricted environments that acknowledge the existence of
Speaker 3:  Steam, but still have Windows, you can run your Windows games.
Speaker 3:  Oh, that's gonna be the next, it's obviously this is how the next Xbox will
Speaker 3:  work. Yeah. Somewhere in there it was like, what happens to the Xbox library?
Speaker 3:  'cause that is pretty important to a lot of people. And I I I, that's
Speaker 3:  the answer that I think Microsoft hasn't even gestured at. And then the additional
Speaker 3:  weirdness is they didn't make this handheld, someone else made this handhold.
Speaker 1:  Well, and there was some news recently that Microsoft actually killed a project
Speaker 1:  or, or paused a project to build something like this. So it
Speaker 1:  is, it is like in, it seems to be running further and further towards
Speaker 1:  we want to be a software provider and a games provider, not the
Speaker 1:  hardware system. Right.
Speaker 3:  They wanna be Steam. Yeah. Being Steam is a better business than being Windows
Speaker 3:  in in the gaming industry right now, which is really weird.
Speaker 1:  That is, yeah, that's true.
Speaker 3:  And so you'd rather be Steam where you're like collecting your credits and
Speaker 3:  like taking percentages of the transactions as opposed to
Speaker 3:  Microsoft, which collects a license when you buy your PC and like
Speaker 3:  you only do that once, like most of the time they don't even
Speaker 3:  get a cut of your GPU, right? Like the things you might upgrade on pc, Microsoft
Speaker 3:  doesn't get a piece of, and they certainly a piece of the transactions that
Speaker 3:  are kind the platform, they wanna be Steam. So they're shipping a thing that
Speaker 3:  looks way, way more like Steam by the way that that launcher, they haven't
Speaker 3:  given a name, it's just they keep calling it the single screen experience
Speaker 3:  or the full screen experience, which is just like, guys give it a name. Knowing
Speaker 1:  Microsoft, that's just what it'll be.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, it's a weird one. I it's, it's interesting to see the gaming
Speaker 3:  market just like shake up, like all, you know, game studios are coming and
Speaker 3:  going like it's a topsy-turvy time in games and then there's Nintendo
Speaker 3:  that's like Mario Kart 3.5 million sold.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I do think though that we are running
Speaker 1:  headlong into the, like the handheld is the future
Speaker 1:  of gaming era here. There's like, there's been a bunch of
Speaker 1:  news about a PlayStation six portable
Speaker 1:  that's starting to, you know, all of that is like super early rumors about
Speaker 1:  a thing that's gonna launch in like two or three years, but is like, that's
Speaker 1:  the, that's the scuttlebutt that's out there as like these flagship devices
Speaker 1:  might start to look more like the Switch than the PS five. Like
Speaker 1:  quickly.
Speaker 3:  This is just my theory that the Samsung Frame TV Harold's the, the
Speaker 3:  Death of Hollywood people don't want TVs, man. Yeah. They don't want
Speaker 3:  'em, they want handhelds, they want, they everybody wants to be playing their
Speaker 3:  own weird PS five handhold on the couch next to someone else playing a weird
Speaker 3:  se rock ally next to someone playing a switch.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Jake, what's your switch playing setup? Are you a, are you a handheld
Speaker 1:  guy or are you docked on the tv?
Speaker 2:  I I, yeah. No, it's, it's almost exclusively tv. Okay. But like, and yet
Speaker 2:  I don't think I would buy it if it was not also a handheld console. Like
Speaker 2:  knowing I can,
Speaker 2:  yeah. I don't know. It's, it's wonderful to be able to take it on the go.
Speaker 2:  But
Speaker 1:  Have you brought it on the Subway yet?
Speaker 2:  I'm not crazy. No. Subway
Speaker 1:  Switch was one of the most like transformative gaming experiences I've ever,
Speaker 1:  like sincerely. It
Speaker 2:  Is. I do see so many people using them on the subway.
Speaker 3:  Does the new Switch have better support for Bluetooth headphones? Someone
Speaker 3:  say yes. It, yes.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Better is such a low bar.
Speaker 3:  You see what I'm saying? It
Speaker 1:  Is better. It's not good, but
Speaker 3:  It's better. But I'm saying subway switch was also a transformative experience
Speaker 3:  for everyone else on the subway. Yeah. So
Speaker 2:  Speakers are better on it.
Speaker 1:  Well now it has two USBC ports so you can, you can plug in your headphones
Speaker 1:  a little more easily, which is something. But yeah, I think, I think it's,
Speaker 1:  it's, it's gonna be a very handheld e next like
Speaker 1:  18 months. And I think there's a decent chance that if Microsoft can't figure
Speaker 1:  out how to push all this stuff together in a way that makes sense, it's going
Speaker 1:  to have had the right idea and still lose
Speaker 3:  Microsoft.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, fair enough. A couple other little bits in our
Speaker 3:  gadget lightning round, by the way, this would've been a gadget lightning
Speaker 3:  round in case you hadn't noticed.
Speaker 1:  Yes. We're going so fast.
Speaker 3:  Nothing. Phone three coming to the US is actually happening.
Speaker 1:  Very exciting. So nothing is launching its next phone
Speaker 1:  and its first over ear headphones, which I'm actually very intrigued by
Speaker 1:  on July 1st. So like in three weeks. And
Speaker 1:  over the course of the run of this company, they've gotten sort of increasingly
Speaker 1:  USE the, the last, the, the
Speaker 1:  phone two I think worked on a couple of carriers in the US and like worked
Speaker 1:  fine on others but wasn't sort of officially supported.
Speaker 1:  But now, so the, the news about the phone three is it's gonna be on sale
Speaker 1:  on Amazon in the us which I actually think is a pretty big deal. And in Nothing
Speaker 1:  store it'll support at and t and T-Mobile
Speaker 1:  and is going to be like an actual like honest to god US phone,
Speaker 1:  which I think is pretty cool. Nothing has surprised
Speaker 1:  me over the years in that it continues to make like pretty interesting, pretty
Speaker 1:  compelling phones. The company
Speaker 1:  was always like, we're doing phones so that we can do the next thing. And
Speaker 1:  part of me is like, is the next thing just over your headphones? Like, I
Speaker 1:  don't know. But it is, it is maybe the most
Speaker 1:  compelling non gigantic smartphone maker
Speaker 1:  left. And So I find myself continuing to root for
Speaker 3:  It. There's this book out now called Apple in China. It's by Patrick McGee.
Speaker 3:  He was the Financial Times correspondent on Apple
Speaker 3:  for years. He was, you gotta read this book. This book is incredible. It
Speaker 3:  has all kinds of like bits and bobs in about Apple in China and including
Speaker 3:  like how they figured out how to manufacture their first iMac and how badly
Speaker 3:  that went. And Fox on swooping in with a pirated reverse
Speaker 3:  engineered iMac to prove that they could do it at scale. It's very good.
Speaker 3:  Anyway, the point I'm, I'm bringing this up in the context of nothing because
Speaker 3:  a lot of that book is about Apple basically creating the Chinese phone ecosystem
Speaker 3:  by training all these engineers at all these factories and how to do the
Speaker 3:  things. Oh, interesting. And then the Chinese government and Chinese companies
Speaker 3:  realizing they could just take those engineers away and swap in new engineers
Speaker 3:  and Apple would've to train those too. And that became sort of like the basis
Speaker 3:  of the piece between Apple and the Chinese government. Super
Speaker 3:  fascinating stuff. And what's really interesting about that is
Speaker 3:  there's a part where Huawei gets in trouble with US government and to
Speaker 3:  save itself it spins out honor it's like budget phone division, right? Which
Speaker 3:  is the competitor to apo, which was where nothing came from.
Speaker 3:  And this is all, this ecosystem is created because Apple trained all
Speaker 3:  these engineers. And then like there has been all these battles, And I'm
Speaker 3:  only bringing this up because nothing has gotten to a place where it is
Speaker 3:  an interesting competitor to Apple. But it came out of that ecosystem
Speaker 3:  like in very real ways. And I I if
Speaker 3:  you're interested in these phones and like what they can do and whether they're
Speaker 3:  better than Apple, if if you have, if you're that sort of person and many,
Speaker 3:  many, many, many Vergecast people are, you should read this book just to
Speaker 3:  get a sense of the foundation of where these companies came from and why
Speaker 3:  they're able to kind of like
Speaker 3:  collect a bunch of interesting ideas from the, the Chinese iPhone
Speaker 3:  supply chain and design ecosystem and seemingly
Speaker 3:  outpace apple, Which is just totally fascinating
Speaker 1:  To me. Yeah, that's really interesting. Dom Preston on our team has just
Speaker 1:  like, every week seems to just like drop a story about
Speaker 1:  some wild China brand phone that we'll never see in
Speaker 1:  the US and every single time it's like, look at this weird thing they did
Speaker 1:  with the camera. And we are just like, everybody is just starting to push
Speaker 1:  past into weird new ideas about what smartphones can be.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And it's, and it's because of this incredible base of manufacturing
Speaker 3:  there, which by the way is like the reason for tariffs and blah blah blah,
Speaker 3:  blah. Like it's all there. I I I can't recommend this book enough. And it's
Speaker 3:  so funny, after you read the book, you look at things like The Nothing Phone
Speaker 3:  Free and you're like, oh, I have a totally different perspective on these
Speaker 3:  devices. Hmm. They, they came from like a different ecosystem
Speaker 3:  than the one that we are used to. But that ecosystem was seeded by the
Speaker 3:  success of the iPhone swap stuff. Speaking of totally weird products to
Speaker 3:  make no sense. HP has revealed a $25,000 piece of hardware
Speaker 3:  to do Google Beam, which is Google's like 3D TV video conferencing
Speaker 3:  system. This is a victory. 'cause the first Google beams are
Speaker 3:  like totally custom and cost like a million dollars. And we're only prototypes
Speaker 3:  25,000. I mean, this is a corporate video conferencing product. And to be
Speaker 2:  Clear, you need at least two of these. Correct. This is not, you can't
Speaker 2:  just spend 20 5K
Speaker 3:  Or you have a friend right. At another company. Oh
Speaker 2:  Yeah, yeah,
Speaker 1:  Yeah. True. If But if you just have the one, you're
Speaker 1:  basically just gonna be like the best looking person on your Google meet
Speaker 1:  and that's it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. If you have two. So this, this is the thing that used to be Project
Speaker 1:  starline, the, the like fancy conferencing thing that has been
Speaker 1:  inside of Google for like a decade. They've been running on this for forever
Speaker 1:  and it's super fascinating and they, they rebranded
Speaker 1:  it to Beam. It was just this year, right? It was like a month ago. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And now our, our actual actually they're
Speaker 1:  shipping is strong, but products with names exist. This thing is called the
Speaker 1:  HP Dimension. Perfect. And it has, the spec list is just truly
Speaker 1:  fantastic. It has a 65 inch light field display with six high
Speaker 1:  speed cameras inside the bezel. And the idea is
Speaker 1:  that it, it is able to basically map you
Speaker 1:  and your space to turn you into like a three-dimensional thing that sits
Speaker 1:  on the other side of the screen from the person
Speaker 1:  that you're talking to. And I've done a demo of this in the past and it is
Speaker 1:  the, the effect is amazing. Like it is really sincerely the
Speaker 1:  best version of this thing I have ever tried in my life. Yeah. But
Speaker 1:  it's again, like Jake said, this is $50,000 worth of
Speaker 1:  equipment. And I look at this and I'm like, who, who is this actually
Speaker 1:  for
Speaker 3:  Sergei Brin?
Speaker 1:  Maybe, maybe this is like, this is just gonna be every
Speaker 1:  CEO is gonna have this and this is just gonna be how they talk to each other.
Speaker 3:  Well, so the, the one piece of weirdness here,
Speaker 3:  it's a single user product, but you can't have this in a conference room
Speaker 3:  with like six people talking about a conference. Oh, true. Right. So there
Speaker 3:  are a lot of enterprise video conferencing products that cost this much.
Speaker 3:  By the way, the $25,000 doesn't come with a license to run Google Beam.
Speaker 3:  That's a separate, that's just like a separate monthly charge or something.
Speaker 3:  It's very, it's very good. All that's perfect. Love it. But usually you buy
Speaker 3:  that for a conference room and so you get the value out of all that money
Speaker 3:  in a conference room. This is for one person talking to one person in
Speaker 3:  his life, like a manner as possible, which I think is perfect. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  The effect is really convincing. Like, I, I use it like a year and a half
Speaker 2:  ago or something and it, it looks great and it feels great and you know,
Speaker 2:  to the extent that video calls are kind of uncomfortable, I think this does
Speaker 2:  away with a lot of that. But it still feels like one
Speaker 2:  of those things where the, the end goal of this has to
Speaker 2:  be to shrink this way down and make it like, I don't know,
Speaker 2:  $250 because the, this is just not a thing that
Speaker 2:  can scale. Like th there's not going to be a a world in which
Speaker 2:  companies outfit every single conference room with these in part because
Speaker 2:  again, you need a dedicated room for a single
Speaker 2:  person Right. To have a video call.
Speaker 1:  But the problem is, And I I suspect this is what Google continues to run
Speaker 1:  into, is as soon as you make it smaller, you kill the effect. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  The thing only tracks if you look like you and you
Speaker 1:  don't look like you on a 10 inch screen, even if it's the most amazing,
Speaker 1:  perfectly rendered version of you. Oh, come
Speaker 3:  On, I want to talk to Tiny 3D David really badly.
Speaker 1:  Just me. But you can put me in your pocket is like, yeah, that's what we're
Speaker 1:  going for. It's
Speaker 3:  Like, Hey buddy, have you tried this notion update?
Speaker 1:  Like I was just about to say the, the Facebook portal stuff is like,
Speaker 1:  that's a version of the hardware I have always imagined for this that like,
Speaker 1:  that's what you try to get to. It's a thing I can put on top of my television
Speaker 1:  or it's a thing I can just have as like my secondary screen that I use for
Speaker 1:  calls. But again, that's really hard because
Speaker 1:  you need the person to be lifesize in order for them to appear lifesize.
Speaker 1:  And So I think I just, I I totally agree with you Jake, but I also don't,
Speaker 1:  I don't know how you get to that point. Like maybe this thing just
Speaker 1:  doesn't scale in any meaningful way and maybe Google it just is gonna have
Speaker 1:  to be fine with it.
Speaker 3:  I'm actually, it's the display as always. It's the display that fascinates
Speaker 3:  me the most. So they keep calling a light, light field display, which is,
Speaker 3:  you know, we, I haven't seen a beam device up close. Like they
Speaker 3:  had them at io but I wasn't allowed to go and like walk up to them. The
Speaker 3:  early versions of starline, it was very much just a wave guide on in the
Speaker 3:  front of a tv. Like it was more complicated than that. But that's what it
Speaker 3:  was, you know, and I'm sure this is more complicated than that, but that's
Speaker 3:  still what it is. And those things, glasses
Speaker 3:  free 3D in that way tends to be optimized for a single viewer
Speaker 3:  in a specific spot. And there are some new interesting glasses free
Speaker 3:  3D technologies that are sort of out there there, there have been some like
Speaker 3:  overheated articles lately that are like three Ds back baby. And it's like,
Speaker 3:  I don't know about that, but Sure. And that's the, that's your multi-user
Speaker 3:  problem really. Can the display show 3D to multiple people in multiple
Speaker 3:  spots around the room. I truly do not know the answer to that for Beam.
Speaker 3:  I've known the answer for everything else for a long time that has required
Speaker 3:  glasses, right? And then your product is said, what are you gonna do? Like,
Speaker 3:  that's, that's the end of that. So we'll see. I'm excited about it. Like
Speaker 3:  I do love a new display. I, I, I love a new display technology And I
Speaker 3:  certainly think it's time for some more interesting video conferencing ideas
Speaker 3:  that are not Zoom. Making an AI avatar view to pretend to pay
Speaker 3:  attention to meetings like that is an innovation unto itself. But
Speaker 3:  I don't think it's the right one.
Speaker 1:  So, no, my, my ongoing assumption, And I think the, the plan all along
Speaker 1:  has been that be like a neat, really high end
Speaker 1:  thing and most of the best features will eventually sort of trickle down
Speaker 1:  into Google Meet in less impressive ways that this gets to be
Speaker 1:  the, the like tip of the technological spear. And I, I assume it's like
Speaker 1:  a victory inside of Google that they got HP to actually make and ship one
Speaker 1:  of these things because now they get to like, keep making it. Oh, I
Speaker 3:  Mean, HP just got the best toy for, its like enterprise demos of all time.
Speaker 1:  Totally. Yeah. This be, this is the thing you trot out in every meeting you
Speaker 1:  ever have with potential customers from now. Like, I get why all of this
Speaker 1:  exists. I just, I have a hard time imagining it, like showing up in a
Speaker 1:  WeWork near you anytime soon. Look,
Speaker 3:  3D displays are back and you're gonna get a 3D laptop and we're all gonna
Speaker 3:  talk to tiny versions of each other on Google Beam. It's gonna be amazing.
Speaker 3:  Alright, that's the first lightning round. We gotta take a break. We have
Speaker 3:  a second lightning round and then I'm told there's even a third.
Speaker 3:  Can you imagine? It's wild here on The Verge chest. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  All right, we're back. I'm told this is AI lightning round. It's not
Speaker 3:  sponsored by an AI company. It's for flavor. So
Speaker 3:  Unsponsored, now that we have had sponsors, again, I feel like I need to
Speaker 3:  rework this entire pitch. Basically what I'm trying to say is, you can't
Speaker 3:  buy us for any price.
Speaker 1:  We're flavorful no matter what.
Speaker 3:  I did ask Apple to send me home in an Aston Martin with CarPlay Ultra,
Speaker 3:  and the vibe was like, will you break the rules for that? And I was like,
Speaker 3:  no, but I like saying it. And that was like literally the,
Speaker 3:  of the conversation.
Speaker 3:  So, well, that's where we're at is like, I'll, I will make jokes
Speaker 3:  about breaking our, our very strict ethics policies for an Aston Martin
Speaker 3:  and above. But even then, probably not, but like, that's where you gotta
Speaker 3:  be. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  I think that's right. Yeah. You, everybody has, everybody has limits, you
Speaker 1:  know what I mean? Like, if you can't, if you can't be bought for any price,
Speaker 1:  I don't trust you. You know what I mean?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. I just, I don't know what it is. It's, it's more than an Aston Martin.
Speaker 3:  Right. That's what I got for you. It's, it's,
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Let's explore from there. It's
Speaker 1:  next year you And I are gonna go to the
Speaker 3:  technically ongoing, but they're gonna go back up in price. So
Speaker 1:  a lot of time talking to people about like the death of linear television
Speaker 1:  and cable and that whole bundle, which everybody thought would,
Speaker 1:  would take a long time. And there would be a bunch of money on the way down.
Speaker 1:  And it's like, okay, we're gonna, we're gonna build this new era of entertainment
Speaker 1:  while we sort of coast on the slowly dying, but still
Speaker 1:  very profitable previous way that it existed. And that actually
Speaker 1:  what happened is all of that just died immediately. And now everybody is
Speaker 1:  scrambling in, businesses are falling apart. And that is exactly the same
Speaker 1:  thing that's happening on the web. Like I think it, it has been sort of
Speaker 1:  intellectually true for a couple of years that most people knew they
Speaker 1:  couldn't rely on Google search forever. I think everybody always knew it
Speaker 1:  was fraught to rely on Google search, but it worked for a long time. And
Speaker 1:  there was just this sense of like, okay, this is not going to be
Speaker 1:  the thing for us forever. Right? Like people have known that since Google
Speaker 1:  started doing like the answer boxes on search results. And there was
Speaker 1:  this sense of like, okay, over time Google is going to be less and less interested
Speaker 1:  in sending clicks to our website and more and more interested in just keeping
Speaker 1:  you inside of Google products. Everybody kind of knew that. Well,
Speaker 3:  They kind of knew it, but the incentive to not believe it
Speaker 3:  was so overpowering that they didn't know it,
Speaker 3:  right.
Speaker 1:  Because to do you know what
Speaker 3:  I mean?
Speaker 1:  Because to to lean into that and to work with that
Speaker 1:  requires essentially completely upending the business
Speaker 1:  of being online. Like a, a thing I think I
Speaker 1:  didn't realize until recently is like almost every
Speaker 1:  publisher in particular online, has only ever existed in
Speaker 1:  the Google world. It's not like everybody did the, the like Facebook style
Speaker 1:  pivot to video. And then that all fell apart and the, a lot
Speaker 1:  of stuff went away, but also a lot of people sort of knew what to go back
Speaker 1:  to. Most of these places have not ever done
Speaker 1:  this. And by this I mean like online publishing, media journalism,
Speaker 1:  whatever you wanna call it out in a world where Google is not
Speaker 1:  the main source of people and traffic on the internet. So
Speaker 1:  it, it comes to this existential crisis of like, if I don't believe
Speaker 1:  in Google anymore, what do I do? And I think, again,
Speaker 1:  because Google was so huge and so successful and because the, the
Speaker 1:  abyss of whatever else we have to do was so huge and unknowable,
Speaker 1:  people just didn't really try. But then what has happened is this,
Speaker 1:  this like slow gradual decline everybody was betting on that would give us
Speaker 1:  like a generation of technology to figure out what's coming next is just
Speaker 1:  happening. Like it is happening like minute to minute and day to day in front
Speaker 1:  of our eyes. The Wall Street Journal had a big story this week
Speaker 1:  going through a bunch of different, like Huffington Post and, and the Wall
Speaker 1:  Street Journal and the Washington Post, And I think Business Insider was
Speaker 1:  the other one showing these just like dramatically down sloping
Speaker 1:  charts Yeah. Of traffic from Google. And Business Insider has done layoffs
Speaker 1:  and they have quotes from a bunch of the folks at the other publications
Speaker 1:  being like, we, we now can see the obvious trend
Speaker 1:  line toward Google Zero, which has caused you Neli to
Speaker 1:  just take victory lap after victory lap.
Speaker 3:  They won't say Google Zero. If you hear someone say, our Google traffic is
Speaker 3:  gonna zero, I need you to jump out of a bush and say, that is called Google
Speaker 3:  Zero, a term coined by Neil Patel in
Speaker 1:  2022. You owe six. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  In addition to your crashing revenues, you now owe a royalty fee for acknowledging
Speaker 3:  your crashing rev revenue.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But so it, we are like, we, we have gone from this being a, a theoretical
Speaker 1:  eventuality to like, it is, it is happening in front of us right now.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It's interesting. Like Google, there are Google changes all the time, right?
Speaker 2:  This, there, this is a thing that's happened for years where there have been
Speaker 2:  winners and losers as Google makes changes to its algorithm.
Speaker 2:  And I think what is particularly unique about this one is that there are
Speaker 2:  no winners, right? It's not like there is some subset of
Speaker 2:  publishers, or I don't even know, like companies online that have figured
Speaker 2:  out a way to crack this, at least that I have heard of.
Speaker 3:  Wait, there's a, there's a weird set of winners. It's not a great set of
Speaker 3:  winners. Reddit is a winner in all of this, right?
Speaker 3:  Like Google has made it gone out and made a deal with Reddit, and they know
Speaker 3:  that Reddit is a rich source of actual human content that it can synthesize
Speaker 3:  to get the answers to questions. YouTube oddly a winner in this.
Speaker 3:  Google owns YouTube, but it's a winner. I was gonna say, but like, you know
Speaker 3:  what I mean? Like, there are media platforms where people are, that are winners
Speaker 3:  in this. They're just not publishers that pay people money to
Speaker 3:  make news, right? And so, you know, and Google will just, And I should disclose
Speaker 3:  like open AI has a deal like that with Fox Media and a bunch of other publishers.
Speaker 3:  None of that is sending us the traffic that would counteract Google.
Speaker 3:  By the way, to be clear, our Google traffic is in decline. So is everyone
Speaker 3:  else's. We have just been paranoid freaks for so long that we're,
Speaker 3:  we've been talking about it forever on this show, but also in our business,
Speaker 3:  that's our redesign. And so we've just been hedged against it.
Speaker 3:  And when I run out and talk to other publishers about it, or other executives
Speaker 3:  on decoder or wherever else, this is what I mean by the incentives to not
Speaker 3:  believe it. I've had media executives look me in the eye and say things like,
Speaker 3:  you think people are gonna stop searching? And they cannot separate the concept
Speaker 3:  of search from Google as a company upon which they have a business dependency,
Speaker 3:  right? And so people are searching, they might be searching more than ever.
Speaker 3:  Google will tell you they're searching more than ever. They're just not getting
Speaker 3:  links to publishers as answers. They might be getting links to Reddit, like
Speaker 3:  Google's like, we're sending more traffic to the web than ever. And the question
Speaker 3:  that I have to which there is no answer, is where is that
Speaker 3:  traffic going? Who are these winners? It can't all just be Reddit,
Speaker 3:  right? It has to be other stuff. And it's just unclear what that other
Speaker 3:  stuff is. Like where has the traffic gone? So I
Speaker 3:  Jay, I mean, And I don't, none of those AI deals are paying anyone nearly
Speaker 3:  enough money to counteract the loss of revenue as you can obviously tell.
Speaker 3:  But it's, I just, I don't want to it, they're not keeping
Speaker 3:  everything for themself. It's just unclear who the true winners will be.
Speaker 3:  Nick Thompson at The Atlantic,
Speaker 3:  he keeps talking about optimizing the content to
Speaker 3:  be tr like show up in the ai search results as the next generation of
Speaker 3:  SEO. That is a Galaxy Brain idea. But I'm starting
Speaker 3:  to see pop up everywhere, right? To be like, we wanna make sure we
Speaker 3:  become part of the AI generated answer wacky,
Speaker 3:  but that, like the SEO community is already talking about that as well. But
Speaker 1:  E even in inherent in that is the bet that
Speaker 1:  if we are the one that surfaces in the answer, actually what people will
Speaker 1:  do after reading the answer is click the links. And
Speaker 1:  at least in my behavior and what I observe in other people, that is sure
Speaker 1:  not the case. And that is sure, not the product goal is to send you
Speaker 1:  out of chat GPT or Gemini or whatever.
Speaker 3:  I mean, Sundar will say that is the, the goal of AI overview and that people
Speaker 3:  search more AI overview and that means they inevitably click more. There
Speaker 3:  is no public data backing that up, right?
Speaker 1:  What they say also is that the people who go are more
Speaker 1:  engaged because basically they've, like, by the time they get to your
Speaker 1:  website, they're already halfway down the rabbit hole. And that it's actually
Speaker 1:  like the, the people who are coming are the people who
Speaker 1:  are serious, right? And it's like, well, okay, yes. But the whole business
Speaker 1:  of Google forever was fundamentally predicated on the people who
Speaker 1:  were not serious and there being lots and lots and lots of them, right? And
Speaker 1:  it was like, it's, I mean, it's what it was. And it's for, for so many people,
Speaker 1:  it's the, the huge bet of internet publishing for so long
Speaker 1:  was that you can, with enough volume, pennies turns into
Speaker 1:  dollars, right? Yeah. Like that's, that's the bet. And, and there was so
Speaker 1:  much of it that it was like, we don't have to be good. We just have to be
Speaker 1:  voluminous. And as long as we can get enough people coming to our crap by
Speaker 1:  accident, we will make a lot of money on it. And that is the thing, to Jake's
Speaker 1:  point, that is just dead. There's just, it's not, they're not pointing it
Speaker 1:  anywhere else. They're not changing the way that they think about it. It's
Speaker 1:  just dying. And so it's like if you're good at product reviews,
Speaker 1:  it's dying. If you're bad at product reviews, it's dying. And there Google
Speaker 1:  is, I think spent a long time trying to pretend that
Speaker 1:  it was optimizing for quality and just trying to get rid of the sort of bad
Speaker 1:  scammy stuff that is basically just like copying and pasting Amazon reviews
Speaker 1:  and pushing it toward other stuff. And increasingly it's like, no, what they've
Speaker 1:  done is just knife the entire, like product review and buying
Speaker 1:  guide world from Google. And they're fine with that.
Speaker 3:  I, I mean there's so much scams there that it might be fine. Like,
Speaker 3:  I don't know, there's something happening there with the old web
Speaker 3:  that people didn't like anyway,
Speaker 1:  Right?
Speaker 2:  Wait, did people not like the old web or
Speaker 2:  is it that because of Google's incentives, the old web got completely
Speaker 2:  corrupted and now Google is solving its own problem?
Speaker 3:  Oh, it's completely that. Yeah, it's that one.
Speaker 1:  But I think, but I don't think those are different things, right? Like the,
Speaker 1:  the outcome is the same. And I think like recipe sites are the perfect example
Speaker 1:  of this, right? Like the, the running joke of the internet is that recipe
Speaker 1:  sites are awful because you go to a recipe blog, you click on the thing to
Speaker 1:  get the recipe, and what you get is like six popup video ads
Speaker 1:  and 2000 words about the person's Thursday before they get to the actual
Speaker 1:  thing. And it's a bunch of H twos telling you like different kinds of substitutions.
Speaker 1:  And it's just an immeasurable amount of barely useful information. The
Speaker 1:  thing is, every single pixel on every single one of those sites exists because
Speaker 1:  of a of SEO. Like they are, they are ruthlessly optimized
Speaker 1:  to get to the top of Google search results because there is a lot of money
Speaker 1:  in being the first thing people click on when they search for chocolate chip
Speaker 1:  cookies that is going to die. Because
Speaker 1:  now when you search chocolate chip cookie recipe, it just gives you a recipe.
Speaker 1:  It doesn't give you links, it doesn't give you anything else. It just gives
Speaker 1:  you a recipe. And so all of these sites are gonna have to figure out, okay,
Speaker 1:  not only do I, am I able to undo all of this SEO
Speaker 1:  stuff, I have to figure out an entire new strategy for getting people to
Speaker 1:  come to my website. And I think, and we've talked about this on the show,
Speaker 1:  right? Like long term, there are things about that that are really great.
Speaker 1:  Like the, the, the amount of time publishers have spent
Speaker 1:  thinking about Google versus the amount of time they've spent thinking about
Speaker 1:  their audience vastly skewed in the wrong direction over the last two decades.
Speaker 1:  Not true of everybody, but true, more true than it should be.
Speaker 1:  So like that, that incentive is going to go back in the right direction of
Speaker 1:  like, the only thing we have left is to take care of our audience because
Speaker 1:  Google won't just gin one up for us every day. The
Speaker 1:  problem is, in the interim, many, many, many, many
Speaker 1:  businesses will die and many, many, many people will. And
Speaker 3:  They already, like we even covering literally the words Google Zero
Speaker 3:  for at least three years. Yeah. And we have done, we have headlines of Google
Speaker 3:  Zero and the Mia wrote an incredible feature about the
Speaker 3:  incentives and how they shape webpages that we can link and like, you know,
Speaker 3:  the webpage animates into place. Like we've done endless coverage of this.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Here's the front of the recipe war that I'm very curious
Speaker 3:  about. 'cause this dynamic of, I hate that the recipe content is
Speaker 3:  buried for me. I'm just gonna make a tool that scrapes recipes and then everyone's
Speaker 3:  gonna yell at like, well known in the SEO era. Yep.
Speaker 3:  The recipe bloggers get to yell at those people for taking their labor, blah,
Speaker 3:  blah blah. Never. Okay. There are now infinite tools to
Speaker 3:  scrape and store the recipes from like TikTok chefs,
Speaker 3:  but the TikTok videos are inherently monetized by the platform themselves.
Speaker 3:  Yes. And the games they play to win the TikTok algorithm wars
Speaker 3:  have nothing to do with the recipes. Right? Like in, in kind of the same
Speaker 3:  way. But they're getting the video views. And so all these new
Speaker 3:  recipes store all these new like recipe cataloging and
Speaker 3:  storage tools that promise to like save the recipes from Instagram
Speaker 3:  and TikTok that you love most and well like index then and dah dah dah, don't
Speaker 3:  actually take economic value from the creators. 'cause you, they sort of
Speaker 3:  implied that you have watched the video,
Speaker 1:  Right? 'cause the video is the thing, they don't care about the recipe
Speaker 3:  The same way the video is inherently itself monetized inside a distribution
Speaker 3:  algorithm does not change the content in like that specific way.
Speaker 3:  I'm dying to know, like, I'm very much dying to know if the
Speaker 3:  same kind of dynamic plays out where everyone gets mad at the recipe app
Speaker 3:  people, I suspect it will not because the economics are so different.
Speaker 3:  And I that, that to me is like a, a view into what's happening across the
Speaker 3:  web where I'm desperate to get any
Speaker 3:  eyeball onto this webpage. So desperate that when you land here, I
Speaker 3:  will attack you, I will mug you, I will put pop-up ads and
Speaker 3:  subscription boxes and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. All of your face. Because
Speaker 3:  the chances of getting a visitor are so infinitesimally small. I have to
Speaker 3:  make as much money from every single visitor as I can. Yep. Whereas a
Speaker 3:  TikTok video just makes money in the algorithm and then you make another
Speaker 3:  one and you like, it makes money in the algorithm and you have distribution
Speaker 3:  that doesn't put as much pressure on monetization. And
Speaker 3:  that's, that's just a big story that the web's distribution made everybody
Speaker 3:  so desperate for so long, but nobody could see their way through it. Nobody
Speaker 3:  in the web. Maybe we do, people don't like our redesign, but like we
Speaker 3:  try very hard to compete on user experience and webpages. We don't have pop-up
Speaker 3:  ads and weird banners and all this stuff, but the sites that
Speaker 3:  do are doing it. 'cause that's the only way they can make money. 'cause there's
Speaker 3:  no other referral source to get onto their pages. Right. I don't know what
Speaker 3:  happens next. I I think the web turns into like an application
Speaker 3:  platform. Like at a big, big level. I think the future of the web is not
Speaker 3:  as a media platform. I think it is as an application platform.
Speaker 3:  And like thinking of the web as an application platform changes how we think
Speaker 3:  about web browsers. I think it's changing how Google's thinking of Chrome
Speaker 3:  and David, you just covered Dia, the new browser from the browser
Speaker 3:  company that replaces arc and that's sort of predicated on this idea
Speaker 3:  that like something else is happening on the web.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's, its whole thesis is essentially that
Speaker 1:  you're gonna spend most of your time a on the web
Speaker 1:  and b inside of apps on the web. And, and it's whole
Speaker 1:  idea is like, okay, well you want a chat bot that can see that
Speaker 1:  stuff, right? And it's like, wouldn't it be cool if there was a a, an
Speaker 1:  AI assistant that knew everything that I was doing in Slack and knew
Speaker 1:  everything that I was doing in my email and could see all my Figma files
Speaker 1:  and it's like, oh, there's only one layer that can do that and it's the browser.
Speaker 1:  But to your point that that thing is not like all the demos I saw and all
Speaker 1:  the stuff I heard from the folks at the browser company, like they're not
Speaker 1:  intrigued by the idea of like summarizing news articles for you. Right? They're
Speaker 1:  like, you're in, you're, you're doing job interviews. This is like an
Speaker 1:  example I got from a few people. You're doing job interviews and you have,
Speaker 1:  you have a Slack thread in which you're talking about all the potential candidates
Speaker 1:  and you have their, their resume in a Google doc and you have
Speaker 1:  their scorecards from their interviews and you ask the bot to summarize it
Speaker 1:  and it is able to pull from those things because all of those things are
Speaker 1:  web apps that just are exist in a tab.
Speaker 1:  All of it is, it's an app platform. Right. And this is like, it's, it's not
Speaker 1:  that different from like what Apple imagines someday future good
Speaker 1:  Siri to be on the iPhone. It's
Speaker 3:  Not different from what anyone imagines about anything like Right. We
Speaker 3:  are gonna, we're gonna lace together all of your apps and they can all talk
Speaker 3:  to each other and you'll have a natural language interface to a bunch of
Speaker 3:  capabilities that broadly the industry is
Speaker 3:  coalesced on this being the future.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And the, the bet is just at which layer should that thing exist in
Speaker 1:  order to have the most power. Right. And Apple's bet is
Speaker 1:  it's a, the operating system and Diaz's bet is it's in the browser.
Speaker 2:  Well the browser is like, right, we, we saw this already when OpenAI tried
Speaker 2:  to launch operator. Right. It it is just running in a browser.
Speaker 2:  It is an agent that is poking around a browser trying to get things done
Speaker 2:  for you, but it is not your browser. And so we can't get anything done for
Speaker 2:  you. Right. And So I think like fundamentally, it's pretty clear that Dia
Speaker 2:  is probably the right approach even at an operating system level.
Speaker 2:  It doesn't necessarily have the permission for all that stuff in your browser.
Speaker 2:  Right. The problem is, I don't think any bot can reliably
Speaker 2:  do any of that stuff yet.
Speaker 1:  So I will say one thing I thought was really interesting is in talking to
Speaker 1:  the folks at the browser company about this, they went way down the road
Speaker 1:  of like pure agentic ai. Like how do we
Speaker 1:  actively do stuff for you on these websites that we have access to? Because
Speaker 1:  one of the things that you get as the browser is cookies. And if you have
Speaker 1:  cookies, you essentially have a logged in state to every
Speaker 1:  app that I'm logged into, which is just a vast amount of power to have
Speaker 1:  over what's going on on the web. And so they were like, well sure
Speaker 1:  we, we have what we need to go in and control your Spotify
Speaker 1:  for you or book stuff for you on Airbnb. And what they discovered is that
Speaker 1:  a, the tech for that doesn't really work and it certainly
Speaker 1:  doesn't work reliably enough to do it on your behalf. And also it feels bad.
Speaker 1:  The idea of just basically sitting passively while your browser uses itself
Speaker 1:  actually was not an enjoyable experience for people. And I felt very
Speaker 1:  vindicated hearing them say that, that they were like, we ran this down and
Speaker 1:  it doesn't work and people don't want it. And I'm like, oh, I agree. I come,
Speaker 1:  they're like, and they're like, maybe that's where we'll get, and some of
Speaker 1:  this will be possible and you'll be able to say the assistant, like, you
Speaker 1:  know, go do this and this and this and this app for me and that'll be great.
Speaker 1:  But the idea that that works right now, they were like, we,
Speaker 1:  we ran it down as far as we could and it just doesn't work. And I was like,
Speaker 1:  oh good. That's, that's also my exact
Speaker 3:  Experience.
Speaker 3:  I I'm gonna come off Nic, an AI booster and I'm not in, I'm not,
Speaker 3:  I'm just, I think there are major flaws with the AI industry. There's a fatal
Speaker 3:  copyright flaw, which we will talk about in one second. And then there's
Speaker 3:  like, can LLMs actually do this and scale flaw, which might just like
Speaker 3:  upend this whole thing. Like the rate of improvement of LLMs is the core
Speaker 3:  technology for the AI industry maybe,
Speaker 3:  right? Like, and there's actually a paper out of Apple this week in which
Speaker 3:  the answer is a hard no. Yeah. Like we've hit a wall and that's the end of
Speaker 3:  it. Who knows? I don't know. I'm gonna come off like a booster. I'm just
Speaker 3:  saying I'm aware of these like core flaws and climate. We're gonna talk about
Speaker 3:  climate a second too. There's all this stuff. The thing that has
Speaker 3:  changed my mind recently is I'm watching people
Speaker 3:  not do a bunch of prompts to get answers. Not make a
Speaker 3:  bunch of, you know, VO three videos, although people are making lots of VO
Speaker 3:  three videos. I'm watching people create application logic
Speaker 3:  in automation platforms out of AI agent capabilities.
Speaker 3:  Right. In a way that is like the stuff they're doing is not
Speaker 3:  important. It's, some of it is just like straight up content piracy.
Speaker 3:  Like take all the most viral videos on TikTok, make
Speaker 3:  faceless YouTube shorts about them and then republish them as YouTube
Speaker 3:  shorts And I will collect money for free and all this is happening instead
Speaker 3:  of an AI based automation platform called N Aden. Okay, great. Like
Speaker 3:  we're, here's the, here's the slot machine at scale. Right? But what
Speaker 3:  that is, is application logic. They're building new apps in a new
Speaker 3:  way using new tools. They're using new emergent
Speaker 3:  standards like MCP to go query a bunch of databases and write to a bunch
Speaker 3:  of spreadsheets and then create content and publish it to other places. And
Speaker 3:  they're moving stuff around there. A bunch of call center logic is being
Speaker 3:  automated on these platforms. Right. Someone talks to you and it goes and
Speaker 3:  gets an answer and spits it back to you. That stuff reminds
Speaker 3:  me a lot of the, the like original Web
Speaker 3:  2.0 where the idea was all of these
Speaker 3:  services have APIs and you can like make new things out of APIs by
Speaker 3:  mashing them up the entire website. Mashable was
Speaker 3:  like founded because people were making so many interesting things
Speaker 3:  by remixing APIs. There were, remember there's a service called Yahoo Pipes.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Yahoo Pipes ruled like we ran a lot of end gadget
Speaker 3:  on weird Yahoo Pipes. Automations. Sorry, what was Yahoo
Speaker 3:  Pipes? Yahoo Pipes is this like dragon drop service builder
Speaker 3:  that was basically like, you can take an API it was like if this than that,
Speaker 3:  but for like web. Oh my god.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It was it was awesome. It was great.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. The rules and all of that was the original promise of Web 2.0. We're
Speaker 3:  gonna build all these services and then you can at some level of API abstraction,
Speaker 3:  you can build new services by mashing them up. And literally, this is where
Speaker 3:  Mashable as a website came from, then it went away.
Speaker 3:  All that went away. Like Facebook, like closed down the internet basically.
Speaker 3:  They said we are gonna do all these services in a proprietary way and we
Speaker 3:  won't talk to anyone else. And that was the end of that. I'm only
Speaker 3:  making the comparison 'cause I see what people are doing with MCP
Speaker 3:  with these automation platforms with a bunch of age agentic, no
Speaker 3:  code tools. And I'm like, oh, I see this parallel. Right? I
Speaker 3:  see a bunch of people making applications in a new way using new standards,
Speaker 3:  having some like straightforwardly depressing ideas
Speaker 3:  about what the application should do. Sure. But like there's an energy there
Speaker 3:  that is unlike the energy of I don know crypto, right?
Speaker 3:  Where the only goal was ever to make number go up or take a cut of transactions,
Speaker 3:  which is just the least inspiring economic model of all time.
Speaker 3:  It was this like that was all financialized. This is very much like the
Speaker 3:  kids are making toys and they're having a good time doing it and
Speaker 3:  they're posting tiktoks about the toys they're making and the other ideas
Speaker 3:  that that is inspiring them to have. And there's,
Speaker 3:  I just know that there's usually something there, there are all these
Speaker 3:  other flaws. The, there's a fatal copyright flaw. There's a really, really,
Speaker 3:  really important climate flaw that everyone should talk about more. There
Speaker 3:  is just an LOM technology flaw that who
Speaker 3:  knows. But in the meantime there's this like little thing, like
Speaker 3:  there's this little green shoot of activity that it feels like,
Speaker 3:  oh, we're about to re-architect how applications work.
Speaker 1:  Right?
Speaker 3:  M-C-P-M-C-P is like fundamentally a conversation about what is an API, how
Speaker 3:  should APIs work? And that stuff is like, you know, fundamentally
Speaker 3:  interesting.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I think I, I've come to see AI as like two separate things that
Speaker 1:  really need separate words. And the one is, is like
Speaker 1:  AI as essentially tool building systems. And
Speaker 1:  I think the, the thing I hear over and over from people is that like
Speaker 1:  it, the, the coding use of generative
Speaker 1:  AI has like already found product market fit. Like however much code
Speaker 1:  you think you use is being written by ai. The the
Speaker 1:  actual answer is much higher. Like much, much higher. And
Speaker 1:  it's, it's everywhere and it works and it is powerful and it is in use in
Speaker 1:  vastly mainstream ways. Like the, the idea of vibe
Speaker 1:  coding like is here and it works. And I, I generally
Speaker 1:  agree, I think it's very cool. I think like one level of
Speaker 1:  above that is the question of like, is any of this worth it?
Speaker 1:  Which I think is like a good and valuable question, but it is a separate
Speaker 1:  question. Right? Like it, that piece of it works. I don't think there's any
Speaker 1:  question about that. And I think there's a really interesting road down
Speaker 1:  that that is also the same question about like, is AI going
Speaker 1:  to get us closer to curing cancer? Like Yes. And that that stuff is real
Speaker 1:  and it's working and it's meaningful. Again, is it worth, it is a fair
Speaker 1:  question, but like that stuff is real. The flip side, And I think this is
Speaker 1:  the thing that gets us tripped up because we conflate these two things is
Speaker 1:  should my computer be my friend? Seriously? And this, this is
Speaker 1:  the thing that I have come to is like the, the, the question of
Speaker 1:  like, do we think as humans it is good
Speaker 1:  that people are building relationships with ai? Chatbots
Speaker 1:  is a completely separate And I think equally important question in
Speaker 1:  all of this, and it has nothing to do with the other thing. Like cursor is
Speaker 1:  not your friend cursor is just this like unbelievably powerful
Speaker 1:  AI tool for building things. It's not, it's not trying to bang you.
Speaker 1:  It's not trying to like give you advice about how to live your life. But
Speaker 1:  then there is other stuff that is very explicitly doing that, like the
Speaker 1:  replicas and the characters of the world. And then there's all this stuff
Speaker 1:  in the middle that's like, chat GPT is is nice to you
Speaker 1:  because you'll use it more if it's nice to you. Like that's just real.
Speaker 1:  But then they tipped that over where it was like it got weirdly nice to you
Speaker 1:  and then people didn't want to use it anymore and they had to roll that back.
Speaker 1:  And this is like, all this stuff is being tuned so that you'll
Speaker 1:  use it and it's like, it's an engagement machine in the way that like social
Speaker 1:  media is an engagement machine. And I think that's the thing that
Speaker 1:  I'm trying to sort of separate and reckon with separately because like,
Speaker 1:  as a, as an infrastructure for product making,
Speaker 1:  AI is like very powerful and everywhere And I think
Speaker 1:  is is essentially inevitable at this point. But this question of like, should
Speaker 1:  I hang out with my computer? I think we should spend a lot more time
Speaker 1:  thinking about and talking about.
Speaker 3:  I would separate that. I I I agree with that separation. I, I, I think I
Speaker 3:  would do it differently. Okay. There's, and it, it's just
Speaker 3:  really about the hype of, of the industry. There's,
Speaker 3:  I can see the old web going away because Google has decided to answer the
Speaker 3:  questions itself and some of those answers are wrong because the AI isn't
Speaker 3:  actually smart and can't be trusted. Well,
Speaker 1:  Right. There's that.
Speaker 3:  And then right next to that is, you know, Sundar saying
Speaker 3:  to me on decoder, we're gonna start to do
Speaker 3:  web app deployment on the search result page, like zero shot
Speaker 3:  vibe coded custom web apps when you search for something. And that is a very
Speaker 3:  powerful new idea about search. I don dunno what those web apps are gonna
Speaker 3:  be. All of their ideas are like, we made a chart of baseball statistics and
Speaker 3:  it's like, well do we have to, we're literally boiling the oceans for is
Speaker 3:  it worth it to your point? Right? Then there's the right next to that. If
Speaker 3:  you believe in any, all that's gonna happen and Google's making it happen.
Speaker 3:  There's that we are going to reconceptualize the web itself
Speaker 3:  as a new kind of application environment where
Speaker 3:  agents are able to go and talk to what are effectively
Speaker 3:  databases and services and kind of like construct new capabilities for
Speaker 3:  you. That's a big, big, big, big, big idea.
Speaker 3:  Like maybe the biggest idea in the history of application development
Speaker 3:  that we're gonna take the web from a series of user interfaces that you can
Speaker 3:  click around on, which is already a remarkably big idea. Yeah. That changed
Speaker 3:  the entire nature of computers. And we're gonna say we're abstracting the
Speaker 3:  user interface away to an a bot or an agent or whatever. And the services
Speaker 3:  themselves are just like coin operated databases.
Speaker 3:  And you show up and you say Uber, do you have cars? And Uber says, I do have
Speaker 3:  cars. That'll be $3 from me to tell you what cars you have. And then you
Speaker 3:  pay the fee and it tells you your car and off you go, okay.
Speaker 3:  Right. Like and then you gotta pay Uber. It's transaction fees on top of
Speaker 3:  that.
Speaker 3:  That's a big idea about how you would build new kinds of capabilities in
Speaker 3:  the world.
Speaker 2:  Do do we think that's gonna happen though? Do we think that Uber is going
Speaker 2:  to open up that API for Google?
Speaker 3:  I mean basically, I mean what, what Dara has said to me is we're gonna try
Speaker 3:  it at first 'cause it'll be cool and if it's really cool and everyone likes
Speaker 3:  it, we're gonna charge a lot of money for it. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, because this is my question, right? Like if they open a specific API
Speaker 2:  for Google, then like probably Google's going to wanna cut of that
Speaker 2:  too, right?
Speaker 3:  Well so it's not a specific API for Google. It's more like they'll open up
Speaker 3:  an MCP server and your agent can show up and maybe your agent is run
Speaker 3:  by Google or maybe you're running it luckily who knows how any of this will
Speaker 3:  work. It'll show up and be able to like, instead of having to issue known
Speaker 3:  API commands, it can in a more natural languagey way,
Speaker 3:  say I've got a person who needs a car. Do you, do you have cars?
Speaker 3:  Right? And you won't need this like big database of API commands.
Speaker 3:  It'll just be like, yeah, I do. They're very expensive. Yeah. Right. Do you
Speaker 3:  have money? And then like a third service will be like, I'm here to process
Speaker 3:  your transaction. That will also cost money and maybe all that makes everything
Speaker 3:  too expensive and untenable. Right? But you just have these like
Speaker 3:  vastly more resilient APIs. Like that's how I've been thinking about
Speaker 2:  It. It's just So I feel like what you're describing is the AI version of,
Speaker 2:  of the app store versus the web. Yep. Where it's like, that
Speaker 2:  would be great. It would be really nice if everything worked nicely.
Speaker 2:  And all I see is a way for Google to take a big cut of money on every
Speaker 2:  single thing it's doing. I
Speaker 3:  Think that might be what Google sees too, right? I mean there's a reason
Speaker 3:  they're all cha Microsoft chasing, Google's chasing it. And the, the fight,
Speaker 3:  the reason I was like, yep. When you said the app store, the fight is that
Speaker 3:  the whole industry is chasing this on the web. That's where
Speaker 3:  the industry is going. Mm. The web MCP big web
Speaker 3:  services. How do we, can we buy Chrome from Google if the, if
Speaker 3:  the government makes Google sell Chrome, can we light up a new browser
Speaker 3:  called Dia instead of Arc? Our old browser, the browser company's a startup.
Speaker 3:  There's no reason for them to burn down their existing browser other people
Speaker 3:  don't use. Yeah. Right. They had to start over 'cause that's the future
Speaker 3:  they see. And you gotta re-architect the whole idea if you're like all of
Speaker 3:  this new application, logical exist on a web in new ways, and maybe
Speaker 3:  we're not clicking around yet, right? Maybe we're just summarizing here.
Speaker 3:  But owning the, owning the browser, owning the literal application layer
Speaker 3:  is important. And then there's Apple, which thinks
Speaker 3:  all of this is gonna happen inside apps locally on your phone.
Speaker 3:  Boy is that risky. Boy is that existentially risky for Apple?
Speaker 1:  I mean, gosh, it's like, it's so weird that everybody believes the thing
Speaker 1:  that they are heavily financially incentivized to believe is gonna be the
Speaker 1:  one that comes True.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. But I mean the iPhone already exists as a vessel for other people's
Speaker 3:  services, right? Like chat GBT is nothing,
Speaker 3:  nothing really happens on the iPhone when you open the chat GBT app, right?
Speaker 3:  So like there's just some thing where like if you think the user
Speaker 3:  interface is moving because of ai, it's not because people are in
Speaker 3:  love with their computers. Like that's the, that's the distinction that I'm
Speaker 3:  making is there's a part of AI that is very much about
Speaker 3:  where the applications go, what the platform shift looks like, what even
Speaker 3:  is an application or an API in this new world. And then there's
Speaker 3:  Sam Altman being like, I've developed artificial general intelligence and
Speaker 3:  you will, you will marry your computer, right? And I need a trillion dollars.
Speaker 3:  And it's like, well that's just hype, right? Like what you
Speaker 3:  need is a bunch of money to take down Apple's application model.
Speaker 3:  Or maybe Sam Altman really believes he's gonna fall in love with his computer.
Speaker 3:  I don't, I don't know the answer to that question. Like, I
Speaker 1:  Mean, ironically if you're Sam Altman, there's way more money in being the
Speaker 1:  one who takes down Apple's application model than in making people fall in
Speaker 1:  love with their computers.
Speaker 3:  But I think that's where they're going and that's why I think that's what,
Speaker 3:  why they're doing this, Johnny I deal. Right? The next platform has to
Speaker 3:  overtake the iPhone application model. Yeah. The distinction to me,
Speaker 3:  like I think that will Kevin Russ eventually leave his family for
Speaker 3:  chat GPT again, I, my my, my sincere thanks to
Speaker 3:  Kevin for allowing me to continue to make this joke.
Speaker 3:  But I, it just feels like a sideshow and like
Speaker 3:  it's a sideshow that justifies the hype, but
Speaker 3:  it's not, I don't think it's actually the thing I agree, you know, it's funny
Speaker 3:  is like in all of this chum Amazon announced
Speaker 3:  that a million people now have Alexa Plus and I have only ever met one person
Speaker 3:  who has Alexa. Plus
Speaker 1:  You met some, I have met zero people.
Speaker 3:  There was one person at the talk show. I, I basically asked this question
Speaker 3:  of the room at the talk show. I was like, does any of you, any of these 700
Speaker 3:  or however many people were there? Does anybody have Alexa plus a million
Speaker 3:  people do? And one guy, I was like, yes. And then we asked, is it any good?
Speaker 3:  And there was like silence and everyone watched it was like very funny. And
Speaker 3:  then he came up to me afterwards, his name is Don McCaskill. He's the CEO
Speaker 3:  of Flicker. He's the guy
Speaker 3:  who has Alexa Plus that feels right. And we talked to, and Andre And I talked
Speaker 3:  to him for a minute. It was very nice for, for him to be there, for him to
Speaker 3:  talk to us about it. And he is like, it's fine. It's sort of fine. And at
Speaker 3:  WIC works it's, it's better than they think it is, but it's not very good.
Speaker 3:  It was like, it was basically a takeaway. We should just have him on to talk
Speaker 3:  about Flickr and then his also his experiences with Alexa plus,
Speaker 1:  Yeah, a hundred percent love this idea. But
Speaker 3:  That's like where we're at. It's like a Amazon shipped it, they promised
Speaker 3:  they were gonna do it and it's like me and Google has promised
Speaker 3:  it and like they might be the closest and with, you know, some of the stuff
Speaker 3:  Gemini can do on a Samsung phone is like, you can just talk to, you can just
Speaker 3:  talk to it and you can be like, turn off my Bluetooth and like it'll kind
Speaker 3:  of do it. That's, that's the state of the art, you know, like it's
Speaker 3:  all this stuff is gonna change but none of it works yet. And so you can give
Speaker 3:  shit to Apple but like none of it works yet. And
Speaker 1:  Until it like really, really, really works, it's a
Speaker 1:  bad product. Like this is not the kind of thing that can be successful
Speaker 1:  at like a, you know, 70% success rate.
Speaker 1:  This thing you're supposed to talk to and interact with all the time, if
Speaker 1:  it like, is kind of good. It's actually really bad and it's, it's
Speaker 1:  gonna be in kind of good for a pretty long time I think. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  The last thing we should talk about here, Sam Altman put out a long blog,
Speaker 3:  blog post as he is want to do. Yeah. I always wonder
Speaker 3:  if he has chat g did he write the blog posts?
Speaker 1:  He said he didn't, but he said in his tweet that this was probably the last
Speaker 1:  blog post he would write without chat GPT.
Speaker 3:  Alright, Sam.
Speaker 1:  And I just like, there's so many executives now who are like,
Speaker 1:  I didn't even have to do anything. I just used AI to do this. And it's like,
Speaker 1:  are you trying to fire yourself? Like, like what a cool way to
Speaker 1:  tell on yourself for being bad at your job.
Speaker 3:  There's a very funny, like from the late nineties early two
Speaker 3:  thousands image, it's like a meme, it's
Speaker 3:  like a proto meme. I don't know how to describe it. Will Joel, our senior
Speaker 3:  creative director And I send it to each other all the time and it has a title
Speaker 3:  that's like lifecycle advertising, career evolution,
Speaker 3:  and it's told through application icons. So it's like you start as a junior
Speaker 3:  account designer and you've, and the icons like the Photoshop icon
Speaker 3:  and then it's like Photoshop illustrator and then it's flash, which is very
Speaker 3:  funny. This is how old this meme is. And then at some point they add Excel
Speaker 3:  to the stack and then some point the entire stack goes away. And it's the
Speaker 3:  Microsoft entourage icon again, how old this is. That was an email client
Speaker 3:  that Microsoft had. And the very last one is Chief creative Officer and it's
Speaker 3:  just a bottle of champagne. That's really good. I will dig this up. We'll
Speaker 3:  find a way to share this. It is, it makes me laugh every time and literally
Speaker 3:  will And I send it back and forth to each other all the time. 'cause we both
Speaker 3:  live in a meeting zone now, like constantly. That's what I think of every
Speaker 3:  time an executive says Chachi Peter wrote this for me. Like, oh, you're just
Speaker 3:  the bottle. Yep. Your job is just the bottle.
Speaker 3:  The fact that you can fire off text is sort of irrelevant to your actual
Speaker 3:  job. That's amazing. Anyhow, the blog post is titled The Gentle Singularity.
Speaker 3:  It is very long, very convoluted and Sam Altman Ways and basically the
Speaker 3:  thesis is a GI is already here. Like, I don't know how else to explain his
Speaker 3:  thesis. He's like, it's already happening. Just sit back, enjoy the ride
Speaker 3:  and gimme a trillion dollars.
Speaker 3:  And in it, he, he makes this claim that the average chat GBT
Speaker 3:  query uses roughly one fifteenth of a teaspoon of water. And I think that
Speaker 3:  means the climate concerns are finally getting to Sam Almond, right? We're
Speaker 3:  lighting up new coal and gas plants, we're building data centers faster than
Speaker 3:  we were building data centers than ever. Justine Calm on our team who
Speaker 3:  covers climate for us. She And I are having this conversation and
Speaker 3:  she's like, the thing is data center use was basically flat and then AI showed
Speaker 3:  up and now it's skyrocketing.
Speaker 2:  Hmm.
Speaker 3:  Right. So we, we, it's not that like com using computers is bad.
Speaker 3:  It's that this new thing is like inefficient and we're, we're just, the
Speaker 3:  demand for data centers has skyrocketed because of it.
Speaker 3:  What do you think, like I look at this stat, I'll read the full quote. This
Speaker 3:  is from Sam Altman people. Lemme actually let me read the full
Speaker 3:  stat from Altman's blog post And I wanna get your reactions to it. Quote,
Speaker 3:  people are often curious about how much energy a chat bet query uses. The
Speaker 3:  average query uses about 0.34 watt hours about what an oven would use in
Speaker 3:  little over a second or a high efficiency light bulb would use in a couple
Speaker 3:  minutes. And then he says the cost will converge too near the cost
Speaker 3:  of the electricity itself. And he says this thing up on 15th of a teaspoon
Speaker 3:  of water. Those aren't great stats. What do you think?
Speaker 2:  I don't know exactly how much water. I don't know any
Speaker 2:  piece of electronics like it should use. I don't know. I don't know what
Speaker 2:  a good amount of a teaspoon is. So, so it's a, it's it's like,
Speaker 2:  this makes it sound really tiny, but I don't actually know what this means.
Speaker 2:  It's interesting. I I I kind of wanna separate this, or at least in my mind
Speaker 2:  to separate this as two different things. I think a lot of the like, oh,
Speaker 2:  AI is terrible. It's boiling the oceans. That feels like a way of actually
Speaker 2:  just dismissing AI rather than genuine
Speaker 2:  concern about climate to me, in a lot of ways, that being said,
Speaker 2:  as we're talking about data center use is
Speaker 2:  dramatically increasing. Electricity use is dramatically increasing and these
Speaker 2:  companies that made these climate goals are now having a much more difficult
Speaker 2:  time reaching them. I think that has compounded by
Speaker 2:  the current electricity plans of the administration that
Speaker 2:  is in office, which is not making it easier to get clean energy
Speaker 2:  online. So
Speaker 2:  I don't know. IIII think it is very
Speaker 2:  interesting that this has
Speaker 2:  boiled up enough to reach Sam Altman that he feels that he has to defend
Speaker 2:  against it. This doesn't really feel like a meaningful defense in any way
Speaker 2:  to me,
Speaker 2:  but you know, when you're measuring it by teaspoons of water, that's like
Speaker 2:  not, you're clearly trying to downplay it. You're tr yeah. You, you are
Speaker 2:  not actually trying to solve it. You're trying to say, look, it's, it's so
Speaker 2:  small you can't actually tell what it is. I I don't wanna
Speaker 2:  like, it, it kind of like disturbs me to know like that any
Speaker 2:  amount of water is disappearing when I'm using technology. I mean, I assume
Speaker 2:  we're all drinking a little bit of water listening to this podcast, but like
Speaker 2:  I, I don't know what the right number is. And I think it's very,
Speaker 2:  it, it is funny to think of it as individual chat GPT queries
Speaker 2:  versus
Speaker 2:  the data centers themselves.
Speaker 3:  I'm obliged on behalf of our most pedantic listeners to say the water doesn't
Speaker 3:  disappear, it's just diverted into a different part of the water cycle. But
Speaker 3:  that's not people drinking it or being used in farmlands, right? Like that's
Speaker 3:  the problem. Like you're using the water elsewhere.
Speaker 3:  That's the problem, right? Like the water is being diverted to this use as
Speaker 3:  opposed to whatever higher value use you might believe exists. That's
Speaker 3:  weird. Like we should just acknowledge that that's a weird outcome of this.
Speaker 3:  The other thing that really gets me, and David, I think you've spent more
Speaker 3:  time like using AI tools than I have in this way. Like no one
Speaker 3:  does, but one chat GPT query.
Speaker 1:  Well, right, I mean I think it's, it's just a stupid way to
Speaker 1:  quantify this stuff, right? And I think we, we've talked a lot about how
Speaker 1:  much this stuff costs. Like we know OpenAI loses money
Speaker 1:  every time you do the query. Like that's just true. It continue. They,
Speaker 1:  they're just burning money happily as they grow.
Speaker 1:  But yeah, the, the, these things are designed for like long conversations
Speaker 1:  and some of the numbers that we've seen are like, there are some estimates
Speaker 1:  out there that Chad GBT gets more than a billion queries a day.
Speaker 1:  A billion fifteenths of a teaspoon is still an awful lot of water.
Speaker 1:  And So I think again, it's, it's this question of
Speaker 1:  it's the is it worth it question, right? Like all this stuff is trade-offs
Speaker 1:  and it's like to the data center point that there have been all these
Speaker 1:  issues recently where these massive data centers are being built in these
Speaker 1:  communities that just don't want massive data centers because it, it changes
Speaker 1:  the look of your community, it changes the electrical grid of your community.
Speaker 1:  Like all of these things are happening downstream of
Speaker 1:  this belief that AI is going to change the way that we do everything and
Speaker 1:  we have to build enough infrastructure to support it. And so sure
Speaker 1:  the cost will come down towards the cost of electricity, but still what that
Speaker 1:  means is a vast amount of the electricity of my town is going to
Speaker 1:  be diverted to doing AI queries. Like I don't,
Speaker 1:  we, we should decide how we feel about that, right? One way or another. And
Speaker 1:  even if it's not a a, a huge amount
Speaker 1:  right now, have you seen the growth that OpenAI is projecting?
Speaker 1:  Like this is not going to flatline at this
Speaker 1:  number of queries per day. If Sam Altman is right, we are all going to do
Speaker 1:  a 15th of a teaspoon of water, thousands of times a day for
Speaker 1:  billions of people around the world. And like that changes things. How
Speaker 3:  Much water do you think it took to fall in love with Kevin Reese? Gallons
Speaker 1:  Easily
Speaker 3:  Gallons, hundreds of gallons
Speaker 1:  Like Olympic sized pools worth at that point,
Speaker 3:  Kevin, I will give you two Olympic pools in exchange for your
Speaker 3:  wife and child.
Speaker 3:  Again, my, my continued things to, I've asked, I want everyone to know, I've
Speaker 3:  asked him if I can keep making this joke and he looked very tired and said
Speaker 3:  yes, that's it. And So I just need to make that clear.
Speaker 1:  Resignation and permission, I guess are the same thing in, in this case,
Speaker 3:  He's the one who chose to put it on the front page of the New York Times.
Speaker 3:  That wasn't my decision.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I would also, we should move on for this, but I would also just point
Speaker 1:  out that the, the this, there is absolutely nothing that Sam
Speaker 1:  Altman offers in this post to substantiate that particular claim.
Speaker 1:  And in fact, it is vastly smaller than what lots of other
Speaker 1:  researchers have said. Like, like orders of magnitude smaller.
Speaker 1:  And so either Sam knows something that we don't and he should tell us how
Speaker 1:  he got to that number or
Speaker 1:  maybe that's chat GPT.
Speaker 3:  It's also worth
Speaker 1:  Noting chat. GPT also estimates much higher if you just ask Chad GPT I'm
Speaker 1:  Water it uses it's estimates are much higher than Sam.
Speaker 3:  It's just li it's just thinking about Kevin. We should ask Microsoft
Speaker 3:  'cause it runs on Azure. So Yeah. One last, well,
Speaker 3:  very quickly before we move on. Climate one Fatal Flaw. The other fatal flaw
Speaker 3:  they keep talking about is copyright law. And Disney and Universal sued Midjourney
Speaker 3:  this week for copyright infringement because you can just generate
Speaker 3:  their characters. You can just generate Marvel characters and, and, and DC
Speaker 3:  characters. You can just do it
Speaker 1:  Not just, and you don't even have to do the thing where you like ask around
Speaker 1:  it. You can just be like, show me Simpsons and it'll just do that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. I'm confused how this took so long. Like this is it like, it's
Speaker 2:  just, there it is right there. Like the lawsuit is just filled with
Speaker 2:  AI images of Shrek. Like, it's s like
Speaker 3:  Insane. That's I meant insane. It wasn't DC characters, it was Shrek that
Speaker 3:  was on my mind. This is a big problem. It by the way, that's the same that
Speaker 3:  as the New York Times lawsuit. The lawsuit, their complaint is filled with
Speaker 3:  the thing just generating times articles Yep. Or information from times articles.
Speaker 3:  The analysis that I've read is,
Speaker 3:  you know, open Eyes kind of losing that lawsuit against the Times meta,
Speaker 3:  you know, they torrented a bunch of books and there's emails in their discovery
Speaker 3:  in their case where their researcher was like, should we torrent a bunch
Speaker 3:  of books? And I'm like, what else are we gonna do? I'm like, that's bad.
Speaker 3:  And so you see the most aggressive rights holders, Disney,
Speaker 3:  the most aggressive copyright litigant in history being like, oh we
Speaker 3:  can, we, we got it. We're gonna crush these guys there. There's some weird
Speaker 3:  outcomes when Disney wins. Its copyright paddles. Like that is a real,
Speaker 3:  be careful what you wish for situation with Disney in particular,
Speaker 3:  but this is a fatal flaw for this industry to the point where Nick Clegg,
Speaker 3:  who used to run meta like policy stuff, la
Speaker 3:  I think last week was like, if we make artists, if we pay artists or ask
Speaker 3:  for their permission, the AI industry will fail. And then Disney's like,
Speaker 3:  here we are so fatal flaw for this industry. I like,
Speaker 3:  I I see this like thing happening with applications on the web and blah blah,
Speaker 3:  blah. I wanna be clear, there are some fatal flaws that are gonna have to
Speaker 3:  be overcome that I don't think money alone can overcome.
Speaker 1:  This is what I mean by the, is it worth it? Question. Right? Like we, the,
Speaker 1:  we are starting to understand the list of what it costs
Speaker 1:  literally and figuratively to do the AI thing
Speaker 1:  all of these tech companies are trying to do. And to them,
Speaker 1:  the the answer is yes, it's worth it, right? Like, is is it worth the destruction
Speaker 1:  of the, the art business in the world? Yes. Clearly
Speaker 1:  the answer is yes. Is it worth like a flattening of how we think about
Speaker 1:  all of the stuff that we make as a society? Clearly, yes. Is it worth all
Speaker 1:  the climate stuff? Is it the answer is just yes. All the way across the board.
Speaker 1:  They think it's worth it. And like a lot of other people are
Speaker 1:  standing up and being like, no, the fact that you can't do this without stealing
Speaker 1:  every artistic work this has ever been created means you shouldn't
Speaker 1:  do this. Like, we just, it's just how like the, we should
Speaker 1:  have the other side of that conversation too. I also wanna say just
Speaker 1:  kudos to Disney again for like having its lawyers
Speaker 1:  write bars. Like this is, we're in a, we're on such a good run
Speaker 1:  of just sick ass burns in legal filings.
Speaker 1:  I just, this, it's right at the beginning of this filing. It just says, midjourney
Speaker 1:  is the quintessential copyright free writer and a bottomless pit of plagiarism.
Speaker 1:  You know, somebody wrote bottomless pit of plagiarism and then just like
Speaker 1:  fist bumped a bunch of dudes in suits around a table.
Speaker 3:  That's how lawyers do their writing. They, they just are like,
Speaker 3:  Steve, read this
Speaker 3:  Co Steve, the complaints are being written to be read by the public.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. This is a new thing. Jonathan Ter, the DOJ attorney who filed
Speaker 3:  the against Apple and one and all the Google cases, basically, he was like,
Speaker 3:  yeah, the first 10 pages are for the public to read. This is how we write
Speaker 3:  them now. Totally. So it's a good one. We will link it. We can read it, but
Speaker 3:  fatal false. All right, we gotta take a break. We're gonna come back with
Speaker 3:  the lightning round. May or not be sponsored. Who knows? I don't know.
Speaker 3:  That's the whole point, is that, I don't know. We'll be right back.
Speaker 3:  All right. We're back. Lightning round unsponsored for flavor Again,
Speaker 3:  I just made that up because I needed to say something after we had sponsors,
Speaker 3:  but what I really mean is that no one can pay us to do anything, which
Speaker 3:  I apparently, I've been so loud about lately that people think that
Speaker 3:  like, I, I won't look like I, I can't even be in the presence
Speaker 3:  of advertising, which is a very hard way to live as an American. Congratulations.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. The people are like, oh, the ads are, you go, you have to leave the
Speaker 3:  room. I'm like, I'm fine. But that's where I see,
Speaker 1:  I'm starting to think you're easily bought. There's a real, like, you know,
Speaker 1:  me thinks that off protest too much thing going on here where I'm like, maybe
Speaker 1:  Neli iss on the take and he's just yelling loudly about it. I
Speaker 3:  Don't know. Have you heard of the new Pegasus GS nine yacht? David,
Speaker 3:  it's delightful. If you have the means,
Speaker 3:  all right, it's time.
Speaker 1:  Oh my God, I've, I've gone all the way around from excitement about this
Speaker 1:  to, I can't believe we have to keep doing this. We're gonna keep doing it.
Speaker 1:  It's time for America's favorite podcast within a podcast 2026
Speaker 1:  Webby award-winning podcast within a podcast. Brenda Carr is a dummy
Speaker 1:  neli. How does this keep happening? What happened this week? It
Speaker 3:  Does keep happening. I will say it's getting dumb on a meta level, right?
Speaker 3:  Where like, it's, it's just so dumb that
Speaker 3:  like the ecosystem is getting dumb.
Speaker 3:  So this week on Brendan Cars a dummy, we don't have a lot of Brendan stuff
Speaker 3:  himself, which is
Speaker 1:  Fascinating. Oh, I see. We're talking like Brendan dumb ripple effects,
Speaker 3:  Like extremely stupid ripple effects of Brendan's behavior
Speaker 3:  are causing other people to have to be like just
Speaker 3:  monumentally stupid.
Speaker 1:  Okay.
Speaker 3:  In order to keep up with him,
Speaker 1:  The new name of this segment is Brendan Carr made us All Dummies.
Speaker 3:  That's where we're going. Or they have to react to him in ways that are like,
Speaker 3:  like just plainly no normal human being should react to, right? No,
Speaker 3:  no one should have to behave this way. So I have three this week. The first
Speaker 3:  is by far my favorite, like by far one
Speaker 3:  of the best emails we have ever gotten here at The Verge, right up there
Speaker 3:  with the conspiracy theories I used to get about Steve
Speaker 3:  Jobs stealing technology, and then they would all end with, he then died.
Speaker 3:  If you're an old school VERGE House listener, you know, but like I used to
Speaker 3:  like do dramatic readings of this, of, he then died on like the End GAT podcast
Speaker 3:  right up there with the Foxconn emails where the guy would end them all with
Speaker 3:  Leave Us alone when I, we'd ride up at the Fox on Factory not being there.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, right up here only instead of being a weird anonymous poet,
Speaker 3:  this is TI Network's communications people. So if
Speaker 3:  you were call Brendan in the first Trump administration,
Speaker 3:  Ajit Pie and the Trump administration broadly inked a
Speaker 3:  deal in which T-Mobile was allowed to buy Sprint, which reduced the number
Speaker 3:  of National Wireless competitors from three to four. And to solve this
Speaker 3:  very obvious problem where reducing competition raises prices, they gave
Speaker 3:  a bunch of spectrum to Dish Network, which had no network, which made promises
Speaker 3:  that it would stand up a nationwide wireless network, become the fourth carrier,
Speaker 3:  and send shockwaves through the market. And look around,
Speaker 3:  right? The, this mark that it does not exist. The, it's been years, right?
Speaker 3:  That was the first Trump administration. It's been years. No one is using
Speaker 3:  this network. They, they had a, a stat that they, like 1.3 million people
Speaker 3:  have access to this network. There are 300 plus million people in America.
Speaker 3:  No one, no one is on this network. They do operate, yeah, boost Mobile, which
Speaker 3:  is a prepaid network. That's a big network. A lot of people use it, but the
Speaker 3:  majority of people who are Boost customers are actually sort of like using
Speaker 3:  at t and T-Mobile's networks. They're just like roaming onto it. This is
Speaker 3:  a big problem. Anyhow, SpaceX decided they would take it upon
Speaker 3:  itself to study whether or not Dish Network existed,
Speaker 3:  that they noticed it, didn't they? And they just asked for the spectrum.
Speaker 3:  And Brendan responded in his corrupt, sort of lackadaisical fashion by saying,
Speaker 3:  I have an opening investigation. I'm gonna give this spectrum to SpaceX.
Speaker 3:  Dish Network has responded to this. They have
Speaker 3:  threatened to declare bankruptcy to preserve their spectrum through the bankruptcy
Speaker 3:  proceeding. 'cause that's their big asset. This would prevent, right? They're,
Speaker 3:  they're, they're playing a smarter political game than Brendan, who again
Speaker 3:  is an idiot. Anyhow, we got this email because we've even covering this,
Speaker 3:  I keep pointing out that Brendan created this problem through his own corruption
Speaker 3:  out of a solution that the previous Trump administration, his former Boss
Speaker 3:  Pi created for him. He's an idiot. This is how it goes. Here's the
Speaker 3:  email that we got from EchoStar, which ends Dish Network and Boost Mobile.
Speaker 3:  Hi folks. Given the vers continuing coverage of Echo Star's interaction with
Speaker 3:  the FCC and Chairman Carr, I wanted to share the blow with you as we lay
Speaker 3:  out in our filings with the FCC, our network in fact exists.
Speaker 3:  My T-shirt, it says my network exists
Speaker 3:  like just a top 10. It's tough. It's just like, it's, it's incredible. And
Speaker 3:  it goes on to say we offer a high quality 5G service to 80% of the US population
Speaker 3:  on our own network, which I, and that network has won coverage and
Speaker 3:  reliability recognition across the country. That's for Boost. We've come
Speaker 3:  a long way in four years when other carriers have had decades to build a
Speaker 3:  network. The two questions I have is why are people still being issued at
Speaker 3:  t and T-Mobile SIM cards? And I sign up for Boost, which is a real thing
Speaker 3:  you can see people talking about and where is it? Where's the
Speaker 3:  advertising? Where's the customer acquisition? Where is this network
Speaker 3:  that you are totally exists? Yeah, send me a phone.
Speaker 3:  Send me a phone that runs on Project Gen five sis that runs
Speaker 3:  natively on your network and doesn't run to at and t in
Speaker 3:  New York. I live in New York City. If you're gonna stand up a network for
Speaker 3:  80% of the population, presumably I can get
Speaker 3:  service in New York City, right?
Speaker 3:  Just, I'm just saying our network can fax this. So that's one my easily.
Speaker 3:  And this is what I mean, he's just made everyone else have to have to be
Speaker 3:  stupid. Send me the phone. We're wide open to it. I sent 'em an email
Speaker 3:  back, said I had a lot of questions, but I was traveling and they, they were
Speaker 3:  just like, safe travels. No scheduling. So a follow up.
Speaker 3:  Alright, second one. We've talked about the other commissioner on the FCC
Speaker 3:  right now, Anna Gomez a lot. All of the other commissioners are gone. They
Speaker 3:  all quit. The other democrat, Jeffrey Starks quit. The other Republican Nathan
Speaker 3:  Simington quit. No one knows who's gonna get nominated to replace him. Trump
Speaker 3:  has nominated no Democrats to anything. FCC is supposed to have a quorum
Speaker 3:  of three, but they're actually five three from the incumbent party, two from
Speaker 3:  the opposing party. They right now they got Anna Gomez.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, Brendan. So we actually interviewed and
Speaker 3:  Anna's on tour just talking about what a, a monster Brendan is. Like,
Speaker 3:  literally, she's like on a first night tour. We talked about this a lot.
Speaker 3:  She did an interview with Lauren Finer at one of the stops on, on on this
Speaker 3:  tour. Lauren talked to her And I just wanna say, this is just like one of
Speaker 3:  the funniest Brendan, far a dummy quotes we have.
Speaker 3:  She just said to Lauren Finer, actually, I have a good working relationship
Speaker 3:  with Carr. It is what it is. He knows that I need to speak out and we have
Speaker 3:  a relationship where I can tell him my concerns. And Lauren said, do you
Speaker 3:  know why Trump hasn't fired you? And she just said, no,
Speaker 3:  no. Can you imagine Brendan's like, here's this person
Speaker 3:  who's just touring the country saying that I
Speaker 3:  suck and that I'm a threat to American free speech. And
Speaker 3:  yeah. Yeah. I, I accept her concerns also. I have no idea why my boss hasn't
Speaker 3:  fired her, but if she goes, the FCC is functionally
Speaker 3:  useless. I
Speaker 1:  Love the idea of having like a weekly one-on-one with your boss where you're
Speaker 1:  like, here are all the new reasons. I believe you're a danger to democracy.
Speaker 1:  And they're just like, Hmm, this is your meeting. You, you, you tell me what
Speaker 1:  you wanna talk about.
Speaker 3:  What are the blockers? Do you think this
Speaker 1:  Is your time? Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Exactly. It's very good. It's very good. So that's the second one. You should
Speaker 3:  read that piece by Lauren. It's very good. It's a good interview. I've been
Speaker 3:  trying to get Anna to come on one or more of our shows. We'll keep working
Speaker 3:  on it. Okay, then last one Brendan tweeted, he, this is a Brendan one,
Speaker 3:  but it downstream of Brendan's the dc As you know, Brendan loves giving a
Speaker 3:  spectrum. So Brenda Tree this week, president Trump locked in another great
Speaker 3:  win for this country. Freeing up spectrum is key to America's economic prosperity,
Speaker 3:  national security, blah, blah, blah, blah. And really this is about a Trump
Speaker 3:  post where he says, Trump is congratulating Ted Cruz and Roger Wicker and
Speaker 3:  Tom Cotton for their quote, amazing deal on spectrum. And he says, this is
Speaker 3:  serious power for American leadership on six G
Speaker 3:  David.
Speaker 1:  Oh God,
Speaker 2:  It's time. We've made it.
Speaker 3:  So as part of the big beautiful Bill, there's some compromise where Ted
Speaker 3:  Cruz has been mad at the Pentagon for hoarding spectrum for years and years
Speaker 3:  and years. Everything about this
Speaker 1:  So new.
Speaker 3:  It's true. This is, I'm I'm not wrong about this. So it's part of this bill,
Speaker 3:  the big beautiful bill, which is not passed. Ted Cruz has agreed that the
Speaker 3:  defense department can keep part of the three gigahertz band and then like
Speaker 3:  the in the middle from 7.4 to 8.4 gigahertz band. And the rest
Speaker 3:  can go into what's called the spectrum pipeline. It auctioned for new five
Speaker 3:  and six G services. This bill has not passed. It may not
Speaker 3:  pass.
Speaker 3:  Six G doesn't exist just to be a hundred percent clear. Correct? Correct.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. FI 5G came to nothing. And in other parts of the governance, it, it
Speaker 3:  seems relatively clear that at any moment RFK will will tell you that 5G
Speaker 3:  less you see through time or something.
Speaker 1:  Oh yeah. Bill Gates did 5G to you when COVID happened. I think
Speaker 1:  that is what that was.
Speaker 3:  So anyway, so Brandon is congratulating Trump on congratulating Ted Cruz
Speaker 3:  on a spectrum plan that is nowhere near reality. But this will
Speaker 3:  preserve American leadership in six G. We're doing great. Everybody,
Speaker 1:  Everyone should be so embarrassed who had to be involved in that in any way.
Speaker 3:  It's, and and that to some extent, that's just normal politicking, right?
Speaker 3:  Like we're all congratulating ourselves, but it's like Brendan
Speaker 3:  man, like read the room. Like everyone thinks 5G sucked. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  All right. We need a pallet cleanser. This pallet cleanser is ridiculous.
Speaker 3:  Why is this here is zip pound cleanser.
Speaker 1:  I'm so excited about this because the, what, what brings The Vergecast
Speaker 1:  more joy than making fun of David Zla and his stupid decisions.
Speaker 2:  This this we're making fun of Brendan. This is the definition of business
Speaker 2:  success. What is happening here?
Speaker 1:  Jake, do you wanna, do you wanna explain what happened here? Walk us through
Speaker 1:  it. Well,
Speaker 2:  Warner Bros discovery, which correct me if I have
Speaker 2:  this wrong, was created by the merger of Warner Media.
Speaker 2:  And discovery is now and again, that was very
Speaker 2:  recently, what, two, three years ago. Like so recently they have now announced
Speaker 2:  plans to split themselves in half into two companies.
Speaker 2:  And I'm trying to figure out exactly what this, this is, this looks like,
Speaker 2:  but again, tell me if I have this wrong. It looks roughly like one
Speaker 2:  half is gonna be studios. Let's call this roughly
Speaker 2:  Warner Bros. And another is gonna have a bunch of television
Speaker 2:  networks, which I don't know, seems a little discovery ish to me.
Speaker 2:  They're
Speaker 1:  Name these companies
Speaker 2:  Warn are they not just splitting themselves back up into roughly the original
Speaker 2:  companies, but now one has a boatload of debt?
Speaker 3:  Yeah. That's that's the move, that's what you do. This is, this is
Speaker 3:  what Comcast is doing with NT Outrageous.
Speaker 2:  This is insane.
Speaker 1:  It's really, honestly, it's, it's pretty incredible. And meanwhile,
Speaker 1:  basically what has happened is nothing and David Zaslav got
Speaker 1:  a hundred million dollars. Hmm. Like that, that's essentially what we've
Speaker 1:  accomplished in the last couple of years with these two companies is,
Speaker 1:  is we are right back where we started except David Soff made a hundred million
Speaker 1:  dollars
Speaker 2:  And we got to rebrand HBO Max like
Speaker 1:  Five times.
Speaker 3:  So here's the Zoff memo to the company announcing the separation.
Speaker 3:  While the work, since the merger has been challenging at times,
Speaker 3:  the work
Speaker 5:  Being rebranding one service over and over again,
Speaker 5:  they've done else
Speaker 1:  Done a very bad job ever
Speaker 3:  Since. No, there's been a lot of investor presentations that where David
Speaker 3:  Zla was like, the pink stuff is what chicks like this is real by the way.
Speaker 3:  Oh yeah. We, we, that deck exists. We've talked about it anyway. While the
Speaker 3:  works inside merger has been challenging at times ultimately have succeeded
Speaker 3:  in strengthening each element of our business by bringing together the Discovery
Speaker 3:  and Turner Networks. We've created a leader in live and unscripted television
Speaker 3:  with a truly global footprint operating industry leading margins. We've transformed
Speaker 3:  our direct to consumer offering as HBO Max is one of the few world's, few
Speaker 3:  global and meaningfully profitable streaming services. And then by fusing
Speaker 3:  creative brilliance with operational excellence, we've made strong progress
Speaker 3:  returning our film and television studios to industry leadership. I don't
Speaker 3:  believe that one at all actually.
Speaker 1:  I don't really think any of those are true.
Speaker 3:  It, I So Jake TI think the answer is they combined all the
Speaker 3:  stuff, they remixed it into dying cable
Speaker 3:  company with debt and new look streaming company. So it's
Speaker 3:  not quite Warner Bros in Discovery. It's like the worst parts of
Speaker 3:  both go over here and then maybe the future is over here.
Speaker 3:  Yeah,
Speaker 1:  I mean ironically what, what the streaming company
Speaker 1:  gets is also all of the content. So it's like
Speaker 1:  all of the things that have a chance are gonna be over here and all of the
Speaker 1:  things that our cable networks are gonna go over, I mean it's
Speaker 1:  it's bleak what's going in that second company. And that thing is basically
Speaker 1:  just being set up to fairly rapidly die on top of
Speaker 1:  a giant pile of debt while the other one just gets to go and try
Speaker 1:  to turn HBO max into Netflix. Like
Speaker 1:  that's what, that's what this is. They're trying to streamline the thing
Speaker 1:  so the one company can try to go be Netflix and so far
Speaker 1:  everyone who has tried to be Netflix, which is many, many, many companies
Speaker 1:  had failed fairly spectacularly at trying to be Netflix. Except Netflix,
Speaker 1:  which is doing a very good job.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And Netflix is the pure play. Everyone else has tried to do it by
Speaker 3:  bootstrapping the, the excess margin of the dying cable business into the
Speaker 3:  content to make Netflix. And that's where they've all failed. And now as
Speaker 3:  David has pointed out, the cable business are dying all getting rid of them.
Speaker 3:  So Comcast disclosure, NBC Universal part of Comcast
Speaker 3:  investor in our parent company, Vox Media, but they don't like us for reasons
Speaker 3:  that will be instantly made clear. As I continue speaking, Comcast is spinning
Speaker 3:  off all of its dying cable companies into a new company called Versent
Speaker 3:  so they can die or get reborn in any way and they're gonna hold on to
Speaker 3:  Peacock and all the streaming stuff in the Olympics.
Speaker 3:  This is I think the same move.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I think this is, this is exactly the same.
Speaker 3:  It's it's the same move I I have heard because
Speaker 3:  CNBC is part of the new version thing. There's some excitement,
Speaker 3:  lots of trepidation, some excitement that they'll be free
Speaker 3:  of the machine and they can try new things in a way that being part of the
Speaker 3:  machine would not let them in the past.
Speaker 3:  I don't know if anybody at Discovery Turner feels is gonna
Speaker 3:  feel that way.
Speaker 1:  No, it's just a really interesting moment. I mean the other, the other streaming
Speaker 1:  thing that happened this week was Disney finally finished the deal to buy
Speaker 1:  the rest of Hulu and there is now some noise
Speaker 1:  that the end of Hulu is kind of n right? Like
Speaker 1:  all of this stuff is just gonna be roped into Disney plus ESPN
Speaker 1:  is doing its flagship thing that's gonna start to be piped further and further
Speaker 1:  into Disney Plus. Like the, we're sort of back in a
Speaker 1:  bundling phase of some of this stuff in a really interesting way that like
Speaker 1:  HBO Max is trying to be Netflix and Disney is trying to be
Speaker 1:  Netflix and everybody is, is pulling everything they
Speaker 1:  possibly can into these like mega streaming services, offloading
Speaker 1:  everything that isn't those things. Because like you said, they thought there
Speaker 1:  was gonna be money in those for a long time and there is, there is no longer
Speaker 1:  money in those and just the only path forward
Speaker 1:  is to try and be Netflix and boy does that look like suicide right now
Speaker 1:  for all of these companies.
Speaker 3:  This pallet cleanser sucks. I'm I'm doing a another one. Can
Speaker 1:  I give you a better one?
Speaker 3:  Okay. You do one and I'll do one.
Speaker 1:  All right. You No, you do yours 'cause we gotta go. What's
Speaker 3:  Yours? I I kind of wanna see if we had the same one.
Speaker 1:  You go.
Speaker 3:  All right, mine is that PNY just announced the dual link V three flash
Speaker 3:  drive, which has both USBA and USPC connectors
Speaker 3:  but supports USB 3.2 gen two that enables read speeds of up to
Speaker 3:  a thousand megabits per second and right speeds of up to 800 megabits per
Speaker 3:  second. It's 32 99 for 2 56 6 at
Speaker 3:  32 99 for 2 56. But it's is the fastest flash drive that
Speaker 3:  exists. So you can
Speaker 1:  Fill your flash drive in two seconds.
Speaker 3:  I'm just, that's a pallet cleanser, baby sick flash
Speaker 3:  drive. That's a pallet cleanser. What was yours?
Speaker 1:  Do people still use flash drives?
Speaker 2:  Have you ever tried to print something outta the office? Hmm.
Speaker 2:  Okay, now
Speaker 1:  That's fair.
Speaker 2:  USBC into my laptop USBA into the printer.
Speaker 2:  Hey, boom. Done. I'm expensing this.
Speaker 3:  Oh yeah. How do you think I get these images onto the frame tv? Ancient flash
Speaker 3:  drives,
Speaker 1:  Man, that story sucks for both of you. Yeah, I
Speaker 3:  What was yours? I
Speaker 1:  Just wanted to talk about Thread's dms for like two seconds. Alright, because
Speaker 1:  I think
Speaker 1:  I Threads, which I have spent a lot of time talking about, it's very slow
Speaker 1:  product development. They announced this week that they're starting to roll
Speaker 1:  out a DM inbox that is actually separate from Instagram. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  that's good. A lot of people not excited about that who are like, oh cool,
Speaker 1:  you know what Meta Needs is another messaging app. And I that's fair
Speaker 1:  and Meta now has thousands of messaging apps that none of which talk to each
Speaker 1:  other. But I also think a Threads DM thing is a good idea
Speaker 1:  and that like, it's, it's threads is gonna end up being one of those accounts
Speaker 1:  that like everybody has but nobody really pays attention to.
Speaker 1:  And I think like as Twitter continues to fall apart, one thing I miss is
Speaker 1:  the like relatively accessible messaging system to reach almost
Speaker 1:  anybody. And Threads I think is gonna turn into that.
Speaker 1:  That's my theory.
Speaker 3:  Interesting
Speaker 1:  That it's, it's just gonna be an inbox that everybody kind of has and you
Speaker 1:  check sometimes and it's fine. And like maybe that's only useful to
Speaker 1:  me as a reporter who like constantly wants to ask people about their stupid
Speaker 1:  iOS home screens, but I think that's like, it's a good
Speaker 1:  idea for threads to have dms, I think.
Speaker 3:  Isn't that LinkedIn?
Speaker 1:  Yeah, but I don't want it to be, it's, it's like it, yeah. I see what saying
Speaker 1:  it has been threatening to be LinkedIn in a way that really bums me out because
Speaker 1:  every time I have to use LinkedIn, it makes me sad and
Speaker 1:  it like, it used to be Twitter, the like how do I reach out to a stranger?
Speaker 1:  Twitter was the closest thing we had to that. And I think Threads is
Speaker 1:  smart to try and take that mantle And I think is going to do it fairly quickly.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  All right. It was a fine pal cleanser. I think the the cool USB drive is
Speaker 3:  better. You let us know, you can email us something, you can call someone
Speaker 1:  Also if you have a really weird esoteric use for a flash drive that you wanna
Speaker 1:  tell us about. I very much wanna hear about it. Dead
Speaker 3:  Serious. What's the number, what's the
Speaker 6:  Number again?
Speaker 1:  You can call 8 6 6 version one one. You can email us Vergecast at The Verge
Speaker 1:  dot com, all kinds of stuff. We, we're gonna do a lot of hotline stuff this
Speaker 1:  summer, so keep keep questions coming. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  All right. That's it. That's The Vergecast Rock roll.
Speaker 6:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 6:  you. Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one.
Speaker 6:  The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network.
Speaker 6:  Our show is produced by Will Por, Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer. And that's
Speaker 6:  it. We'll see you next week.