# Transcript
ID: 01ff5ab4-5c97-4570-985a-ec65f51f2dd0
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/2294660125556505452/-3876712916471697097/s93290-US-5197s-1753664590.mp3
Description: Summer blockbusters like the new Superman and Jurassic World movies may be doing great at the box office, but promoting them is more complicated than ever. The old celebrity playbook of magazine profiles, TV chat shows and press junkets isn’t enough in an era of audience fragmentation. Publicists now have to strategize which podcasts to make time for, and whether their clients will eat chicken on YouTube with Amelia Dimoldenberg or Sean Evans.
This week on The Vergecast, guest host Mia Sato talks to Vulture’s Fran Hoepfner to break down the ever-changing new media circuit, whether you’re a beloved A-lister, a formerly-beloved A-lister, or an aspiring A-lister.
Then, we take a deep dive with Sarah Fackrell into a controversial legal tactic brands are using to go after online sellers hawking everything from grumpy cat T-shirts to closet hooks.
Finally, Victoria Song joins Mia to answer a Vergecast hotline from a listener wondering whether an AI translator will be able to keep up with his partner’s Colombian mother. If you’ve got a question for us, call 866-VERGE11 or e-mail vergecast@theverge.com.
Speaker 2:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of talking about other people
Speaker 2:  eating chicken on other podcasts, but we don't eat chicken on this podcast.
Speaker 2:  I'm Mia Sato and I'm going to be taking over the Tuesday show while David
Speaker 2:  is on parental leave for a few weeks. On today's show, we're talking about
Speaker 2:  summer blockbuster seasons. There's movie after movie coming out and
Speaker 2:  celebrities want to get their project in front of you, or
Speaker 2:  maybe they just wanna put themselves in front of you. We're gonna be talking
Speaker 2:  to Fran Hoffner, a news writer at Vulture, and a friend of mine
Speaker 2:  who wrote a really excellent piece back in June about the crazy
Speaker 2:  hoops that celebrities now have to jump through in order to get attention
Speaker 2:  in an age of fragmented media consumption and at a time when
Speaker 2:  linear television is on the decline. After that, we're going to talk
Speaker 2:  about the flood of cheap knockoff and copycat products that you have
Speaker 2:  no doubt seen online before. In an age of cheap
Speaker 2:  copycat products, brands have found a way to go after dozens or even
Speaker 2:  hundreds of storefronts that they say are infringing on their IP rights.
Speaker 2:  But what happens when someone is wrongly accused of IP infringement?
Speaker 2:  There's a new crop of lawsuits called Schedule A, that's something of a legal
Speaker 2:  trend. Right now we're talking with law professor Sarah Fackrell about
Speaker 2:  what these lawsuits do and how they could hurt competition online. Later
Speaker 2:  on, we'll have my colleague v song on to help me answer a question about
Speaker 2:  AI translators. But first I have to go unbox 20 Labu
Speaker 2:  Boo Blind boxes. This is The Verge cast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back to The Vergecast. My first guest today is Fran Hoffner.
Speaker 2:  She's a news writer at Vulture and she did a great piece back in June
Speaker 2:  about all the weird ways celebrities try to get our attention in an
Speaker 2:  age when audiences are fragmented into a million pieces Since its summer
Speaker 2:  blockbuster season, I thought it would be a great time to talk about how
Speaker 2:  celebrities are navigating this new media circuit and all the
Speaker 2:  highs and lows and weird moments that this has created.
Speaker 2:  Fran, maybe just like describe what is the new media circuit? Who are the
Speaker 2:  main players? Where does this content live? Where does it look like out in
Speaker 2:  the world? The new media circuit lives
Speaker 2:  98% on the screen of a phone. It is vertical
Speaker 2:  video interviews and video podcasts
Speaker 2:  such as this, such as this, such as The Vergecast we're, we're on the new
Speaker 2:  media circuit right now. I have to eat chicken after this.
Speaker 2:  And it's talking with a lot of the time
Speaker 2:  a kind of internet celebrity that
Speaker 2:  exists somewhere between civilian and fellow
Speaker 2:  celebrity that actors and musicians and
Speaker 2:  people on press tours now talk to. So we have the Chicken shows Chicken
Speaker 2:  Shop Day. Can I
Speaker 6:  Ask you a question? Oh yes. What's it like doing this all the
Speaker 6:  time? What do you mean all the time? I do other things? Do you ever eat anything
Speaker 6:  other than this? No
Speaker 2:  Hot ones.
Speaker 7:  Hey, what's going on everybody for First Week Feast, I'm Sean Evans and you're
Speaker 7:  watching Hot Ones. It's the show with hot questions and even hotter wings.
Speaker 7:  And today we're joined by Owen Wilson.
Speaker 2:  There are more reels and TikTok centric shows like
Speaker 2:  Subway takes.
Speaker 8:  So what's your take?
Speaker 9:  Fundamentally, everyone is a good person. A hundred
Speaker 8:  Percent disagree. I can think of countless examples of bad people. I'm
Speaker 8:  not even gonna rattle off.
Speaker 9:  People are not bad. They're infected.
Speaker 2:  And part of the new media circuit is to
Speaker 2:  show that the person promoting the project is a person. We're
Speaker 2:  so normal. Completely. I'm completely normal. It's actually totally,
Speaker 2:  it's frequently at least project agnostic. Mm. They
Speaker 2:  almost don't even ever talk about the project at hand, but instead just
Speaker 2:  talk to whatever host about whatever
Speaker 2:  inanities that Yeah, they wanna talk about. Sit down and open up
Speaker 2:  vibes sometimes or sit down and be silly. Yeah. Anything to more
Speaker 2:  further the name of the person on the show than the project, because
Speaker 2:  maybe movies aren't selling as well, maybe people aren't watching TV how
Speaker 2:  they used to, but if that person can stay in the zeitgeist, maybe
Speaker 2:  there's still another movie to do or another TV show. And it's
Speaker 2:  all about trying to establish or reestablish
Speaker 2:  sort of like who are our A-listers, who are, who are people
Speaker 2:  who are getting people to engage with things. And this circuit is both
Speaker 2:  trying to cement that, but also kind of spreading
Speaker 2:  everyone out in a way where almost no one is able to stand out in the past.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's, so it's interesting because like the level of celebrity feels
Speaker 2:  like it has really been through the ringer, or like the levels of
Speaker 2:  celebrity, what makes someone an Alister versus just like very, very
Speaker 2:  saturated or famous or known. So we'll talk about that
Speaker 2:  a little bit later, but how does a new media circuit interact with like the,
Speaker 2:  what we would think of as the traditional media circuit? You go on daytime
Speaker 2:  television, you do a late night show, maybe you do like a glossy magazine
Speaker 2:  cover or a spread. Like how do these things kind of
Speaker 2:  collide? Do celebrities do both? Do they do
Speaker 2:  mostly the traditional thing with a sprinkle of, you know, a TikTok takes
Speaker 2:  show? Like what? What is the structure? I think they're doing about half
Speaker 2:  and half, but it's been interesting to watch
Speaker 2:  the more traditional forms like late night and daytime tv
Speaker 2:  and even legacy magazines now also have to adhere to the
Speaker 2:  new media circuit. Like you want the late night clips to make it onto
Speaker 2:  TikTok or Instagram reels, Vogue Wired,
Speaker 2:  vanity Fair all have their own video series that are also on TikTok
Speaker 2:  And Instagram such as The Vergecast. Exactly. Yeah. This clip will be going
Speaker 2:  around on TikTok, thank God. And going viral I'm sure. And going viral.
Speaker 2:  We're offending the traditional media circuit actually that's right. By doing
Speaker 2:  this podcast. So true. I think about, what is it, the Spirit
Speaker 2:  tunnel on the Jennifer Hudson show. Oh my, yes. That's like
Speaker 2:  built for scrolling. Yes. So stars
Speaker 2:  are still having to do these circuits, but now those traditional circuits
Speaker 2:  have to adhere to what goes on the phone. Yeah. I think
Speaker 2:  almost the only unchanging medium to some degree is SNL Mm.
Speaker 2:  Which used to be the main place people would go to make fun of themselves.
Speaker 2:  And now it feels like everything is designed to prove the person in question
Speaker 2:  can make fun of themselves. What is there like a winning formula for this?
Speaker 2:  I get, we'll talk about sort of what you laid out in your piece And I actually
Speaker 2:  have a case study that I think you nailed. But like how are
Speaker 2:  PR teams and publicists thinking about like the ingredients
Speaker 2:  to like a winning press tour? A winning press tour?
Speaker 2:  It really depends on the type of person on the press tour.
Speaker 2:  For younger stars and especially musicians,
Speaker 2:  there's a kind of blanket strategy. Anything they can do, they
Speaker 2:  will do, they'll do the newsletters, they'll do the video podcasts.
Speaker 2:  I think traditional media to them, glossy covers and late
Speaker 2:  night sets feels like the furthest away. So you'll see those
Speaker 2:  people way more on your phone than you will in those traditional mediums.
Speaker 2:  But I think by the time they usually hit traditional mediums, it feels like
Speaker 2:  it's too late. Mm. I feel like by the time I saw Chapel Rone on
Speaker 2:  Colbert, I was like, this is already a famous person. Yeah. She, she maybe
Speaker 2:  doesn't need to be doing this. Yeah. The more
Speaker 2:  established celebrities will do a mix of both,
Speaker 2:  but there usually winds up being at least one silly thing.
Speaker 2:  Usually it's chicken related hot ones. It's so weird that it's all chicken.
Speaker 2:  I know. And it's like you kind of only get to do your chicken thing
Speaker 2:  once. Yeah, I would like to say, so it's like you do it and then you gotta
Speaker 2:  do something else next time you get to eat chicken once in your life and
Speaker 2:  no more. Yeah. You have to, you have to decide when you're gonna play your
Speaker 2:  chicken card. Yeah. Like some of the people who are hosting these shows,
Speaker 2:  writing these newsletters are celebrities in
Speaker 2:  and of Right? Like they are celebrities. That's sort of what's become interesting
Speaker 2:  is like I don't think we can keep feigning that someone like Amelia Dem Oldenberg
Speaker 2:  who does Chicken Shop Date or Britney Broski who does Royal Court
Speaker 2:  and a ton of like YouTube stuff. These aren't like regular people in
Speaker 2:  terms of like how you And I are. Yeah, sort of. I don't know. They're
Speaker 2:  also not media really. And they're not media, but they're doing
Speaker 2:  interviews and, and so there's this weird in-between
Speaker 2:  where maybe it's supposed to be kind of
Speaker 2:  jarring to see like Timothy Chalamet and Britney Broski in conversation,
Speaker 2:  But that actually makes perfect sense. These are just two famous people.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, absolutely. It's all become almost kind of the interview magazine
Speaker 2:  thing of celebrities interviewing celebrities. Yeah. Yeah. Just
Speaker 2:  like for the video squirrely era. Era. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  In your piece you laid out like a couple different types
Speaker 2:  of celebrities such as the Fresh-Faced, aspiring
Speaker 2:  Alister, the redemption seeker, the, like I said,
Speaker 2:  the kind of buzzy politician. So who is the redemption seeker? We're gonna
Speaker 2:  talk about a current redemption seeker on this circuit right now, but what
Speaker 2:  describe the redemption seeker? The redemption seeker is not
Speaker 2:  necessarily a canceled person. Frequently is not a canceled person,
Speaker 2:  but someone who has a perhaps less than savory
Speaker 2:  public relationship, maybe they've gone through a
Speaker 2:  divorce, maybe there was a cheating scandal. Maybe there was some kind of
Speaker 2:  legal scandal that they were in. There's been drama on the sets
Speaker 2:  of one of their films or TV shows. Their
Speaker 2:  press tour has to become a kind of gentle
Speaker 2:  mea culpa. They can't just run through that thing and pretend like none
Speaker 2:  of that ever happened. There has to be some kind of tacit acknowledgement
Speaker 2:  or I think people just hound them. Maybe they don't see it, but in comments
Speaker 2:  they'll be like, what about this? Talk about this. And so there's a kind
Speaker 2:  of gentleness that lets this person be like, Hey, I'm
Speaker 2:  human, but also maybe be able to laugh about what's going
Speaker 2:  on with them a little bit. Yeah. And in your piece,
Speaker 2:  you laid out a game plan for the redemption seeker. So there's Podcast
Speaker 2:  Pond, I love the names. Also there's Podcast Pond, then you do
Speaker 2:  guys being dudes, peak Chicken Coop after you are guys being
Speaker 2:  dudes. Then cover Story Creek, then daytime
Speaker 2:  tv. And there's someone who I found
Speaker 2:  was pretty much matching this beat for Beat bar for Bar
Speaker 2:  and that's Brad Pitt. Yeah. He is promoting his F1 movie
Speaker 2:  and he has hit a lot of these things. He did the podcast interviews,
Speaker 2:  a sort of sit down serious video podcast interviews.
Speaker 2:  He was reading Thirst tweets on a Buzzfeed show. I think
Speaker 2:  we have a clip of that that we can roll. This is like Guys being Dudes Peak.
Speaker 2:  Let's see what it looks like. I
Speaker 10:  Have an overwhelming urge to lick Javier Barden. You know I say that one
Speaker 10:  too. I just say that one too. When you, the time when I'm not around all
Speaker 10:  the time. Overwhelming urge, just a lick. That's a lick
Speaker 10:  back, front side, just top to bottom
Speaker 2:  Comparing how Brad and how Javier Barde
Speaker 2:  approached the F1 press tour was very interesting. Talk more about that.
Speaker 2:  Javier Barda did sort of this circuit where he's sometimes very
Speaker 2:  silly, but he also went on the view to talk about Gaza
Speaker 2:  and spent a lot of time on red carpets invoking Gaza and
Speaker 2:  made it very political in a way we have not seen stars of that
Speaker 2:  caliber do quite yet. I think it's maybe a little
Speaker 2:  different for Javier ridden because he's ostensibly like a European
Speaker 2:  star that he doesn't have to maybe totally play by the same rules or he doesn't
Speaker 2:  care to play by the same rules. But comparing that to
Speaker 2:  Brad Pitt playing Frisbee golf with Jimmy Fallon in tie dye
Speaker 2:  pajamas creates quite a strange contradiction.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Of men of a certain age especially. Right. Yeah. It kind of suggests
Speaker 2:  to me too that like Brad Pitt is the redemption seeker and Javier
Speaker 2:  Barham is like maybe more of like the legend type
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Category. Also like on Guy being Dudes
Speaker 2:  Peak, I was like kind of struck by how exact your
Speaker 2:  prediction or your prescription of this was because he
Speaker 2:  literally did like a broy video with Lad Bible. You know what what I mean?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, yeah. Like it's just like this is guys being dudes.
Speaker 10:  It's Aidas not Adidas. It's Adidas. I know. It's what I
Speaker 10:  It's biscuit, not cookie. No biscuits and gravy, man. May
Speaker 10:  It's chips you ever had biscuits and gravy. You are so American man.
Speaker 10:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  He has done sort of the glossy magazine thing. He did a GQ
Speaker 2:  story that I kind of skimmed and then
Speaker 2:  command for Angelina Jolie and Kids. And there was like one mention
Speaker 2:  and it's completely non-specific. Yeah. It's where he said
Speaker 2:  his divorce being finalized isn't actually that major. Yeah. Which is crazy.
Speaker 2:  It's like, okay, it's the main thing. I believe you. Yeah. Why do you think
Speaker 2:  that the new media circuit, I mean I guess in this case this was a
Speaker 2:  traditional media thing, but across all these different stops that he made,
Speaker 2:  Angelina Jolie does not come up really. And it's interesting because
Speaker 2:  like we call it media, but mostly it's just like hanging out with friends
Speaker 2:  and your friends are not going to ask you on camera about allegations that
Speaker 2:  you like abused your wife. So it feels
Speaker 2:  very much like it is just an extension of
Speaker 2:  his own personal marketing. There's like no, he's not really bumping up against
Speaker 2:  any walls or like uncomfortable conversations.
Speaker 2:  Absolutely. I think his team is probably keeping him very, very protected
Speaker 2:  from any question. Yeah. He doesn't want to answer. And by doing
Speaker 2:  something like reading thirst tweets, it looks like he's being a kind of
Speaker 2:  vulnerable talking to Dex Shepherd about addiction. That's a kind of vulnerable,
Speaker 2:  but it's not actually addressing the elephant
Speaker 2:  in the room. And I think with Pitt specifically and
Speaker 2:  with celebrities who I think have some kind of legal thing
Speaker 2:  attached to whatever they're seeking redemption from, it's very possible
Speaker 2:  that they like actually cannot talk about what's going on
Speaker 2:  in X, Y, Z terms as part of whatever
Speaker 2:  settlement that they've agreed on. But with Pit, it's that
Speaker 2:  then everything he does is so silly and he did this Fallon skit.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Which is so funny in lieu of like even talking to Fallon. Yeah. So
Speaker 2:  tell us about the skit. They were playing Frisbee golf in the park.
Speaker 2:  Fallon is like, I had like an awesome weekend playing Frisbee golf with my
Speaker 2:  buddy and like we did some crazy shots and I'll show you the video. And it's
Speaker 2:  supposed to be, even then, it's supposed to be like surprising that like
Speaker 2:  Brad Pitt would even like talk to Jimmy Fallon. It's like, again, these are
Speaker 2:  two extremely famous people and they're both in these like tie dye
Speaker 2:  jammies and they're doing these really
Speaker 2:  edited and manipulated crazy Frisbee golf
Speaker 2:  shots. Here
Speaker 11:  We go, alright, four 20 Pink Pony Club
Speaker 11:  caricature Cat Rescue my month stilts, and finally hit
Speaker 11:  that idiot on the back of the head. BOL. Best o luck.
Speaker 2:  And what it's showing or proving is completely
Speaker 2:  incomprehensible to me, especially because they're only in the
Speaker 2:  shots where they're throwing and catching the Frisbee respectively. So it's
Speaker 2:  also not even really with or about them, but
Speaker 2:  it just becomes like another silly little thing to prove that like
Speaker 2:  Serious Bread Pitt is not above having fun. Yeah. Once in a while.
Speaker 2:  I think that also kind of goes back to your earlier point where often
Speaker 2:  these appearances on these sort of the sort of like third rail
Speaker 2:  shows or podcasts or whatever are not about the thing that they're actually
Speaker 2:  working on. It is more just like them as a person, we need to
Speaker 2:  saturate your feeds. Right. With Brad Pitt's face,
Speaker 2:  I wanted to say also like looking through all of these stops
Speaker 2:  on the new media press tour. It is
Speaker 2:  so, so so striking how much it's mediated by like
Speaker 2:  third party platforms like TikTok and YouTube.
Speaker 2:  And I'm curious like how much of the quote unquote
Speaker 2:  algorithm comes in here, right? Like is it, is
Speaker 2:  it enough that celebrities just show up on Chicken shop date and show up
Speaker 2:  on Subway takes or show up on recess therapy? Or is there
Speaker 2:  like some level of you throw all these things out there and see
Speaker 2:  what hits? Yeah. Are there any, I guess, show
Speaker 2:  appearances that you've seen that did not work? Whether, whether it was because
Speaker 2:  the algorithm didn't like it or because people didn't like it or because
Speaker 2:  it just was a weird fit? Yeah, absolutely. There are shows that don't
Speaker 2:  work all the time. I think. I mean they didn't need
Speaker 2:  something like this, but I think Hugh Jackman and Ryan Reynolds doing Chicken
Speaker 2:  Shop Date, very unfunny, very strange, no
Speaker 2:  rapport.
Speaker 12:  Does your wife know they're on a date right now?
Speaker 13:  She does know that. She does, yes. Okay, good. And the only reason I'm allowed
Speaker 13:  and here is that you know, she's your number one fan. Ooh.
Speaker 13:  Oh my God. That is right. Brooke from Gossip Girl
Speaker 13:  Loves You.
Speaker 12:  Serena.
Speaker 12:  Serena,
Speaker 13:  Blair, Blair,
Speaker 12:  Serena.
Speaker 2:  I mean a movie like Deadpool does not need that. But I also think about,
Speaker 2:  say Kate Blanche doing her press run
Speaker 2:  for Black Bag. She's an amazing actor. Black Bag is a
Speaker 2:  great movie. She really hit the new media circuit this time around. She
Speaker 2:  went on Lost Cultas, she did Subway Takes and she spent a
Speaker 2:  lot of time on those shows. Either
Speaker 2:  kind of not finding the right tone of how to be on those shows
Speaker 2:  or just reiterating old bits that she's done. I think people talk about
Speaker 2:  when she gripes about like leaf blowers in every single interview. And it's
Speaker 2:  like, I don't know if this is like as charming or as relatable to
Speaker 2:  complain about her landscapers as Right. She thinks it is. No,
Speaker 14:  I, so that's one thing. It's like I don't understand leaf blowers And I
Speaker 14:  don't understand golf. No. See, this is the thing. Not only are leaf blowers
Speaker 14:  ugly and they're noise polluted and then your neighbors hate you. Yeah.
Speaker 14:  If I see a leaf blower, I will. I go from Naugh to a
Speaker 14:  thousand. I just, I cannot, it's all that is wrong with the human
Speaker 14:  race.
Speaker 2:  It's not really her fault. And I don't think it's like Las culture
Speaker 2:  East's fault either, but she's not media trained
Speaker 2:  to be silly on camera and podcast for a whole
Speaker 2:  hour. She's not an especially silly person. Yeah. And what she does is
Speaker 2:  come off as kind of try hard and
Speaker 2:  disingenuine and it just doesn't really hit. Yeah. There's nothing
Speaker 2:  that stands out from it. And I think that happens all
Speaker 2:  the time. I think a lot of these publicists and teams are
Speaker 2:  just trying to blanket their person as far
Speaker 2:  and as much as their client is willing to go. And then you just
Speaker 2:  have to hope something hits. Yeah. At that point, who is
Speaker 2:  benefiting from like Cape Blanche being on Subway takes or whatever? Is it
Speaker 2:  Subway takes having like a massive win? Or is it
Speaker 2:  her kind of getting in front of maybe a younger, more online audience? Like
Speaker 2:  who is winning here? I don't think anyone is winning in that situation because
Speaker 2:  I think, think younger audiences are not caring about her on that show. And
Speaker 2:  maybe Subway Takes is benefiting slightly, but she's
Speaker 2:  using recycled material Yeah. On there. And that's sort of what became frustrating
Speaker 2:  for many watching late night, is you would just hear the same stories over
Speaker 2:  and over again. And I think part of what the new media cycle
Speaker 2:  purports to do is that by like making people work in these
Speaker 2:  weird structures or games or these really long-winded conversations
Speaker 2:  that something notable will come out of this person
Speaker 2:  pretending to have their guard down. Yeah. But if there isn't
Speaker 2:  that moment, it just, it kind of just doesn't happen. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I wanna talk about another case study. Charlie XCX, her stock
Speaker 2:  went up massively in the last like year and a half. I, tell me if I'm wrong,
Speaker 2:  I would put her in your structure as maybe the fresh faced aspiring
Speaker 2:  Alister ish. Yeah. She's been around. She's definitely been around. But I
Speaker 2:  think that category also appeals to someone who's trying to jump up
Speaker 2:  a level. And I think for a long time she was a kind of niche
Speaker 2:  celebrity. I would put someone like Carly Ra Jepsen in that category too,
Speaker 2:  which is like, she has fans. She's been around forever, but she
Speaker 2:  has no sort of Taylor Beyonce Yeah. Stadium type of
Speaker 2:  artist. Yeah. So what was Charlie Xc X's cycle
Speaker 2:  promoting her album Brat? Like, like what, what, what is the strategy there?
Speaker 2:  She said yes to everything. I'm hard pressed to think of something she didn't
Speaker 2:  agree to do. And I think part of what
Speaker 2:  was so interesting about the Brat Remixes album, which I think is
Speaker 2:  great, is she kind of tacitly acknowledges like, I'm so tired. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I've been like, I'm milking this thing, I'm milking this thing, I'm exhausted.
Speaker 2:  I've sort of lost what this thing is actually about,
Speaker 2:  which felt even more honest than some of the confessional nature of the
Speaker 2:  original Brad. But she agreed to do everything
Speaker 2:  and sometimes that really worked for her.
Speaker 2:  She had a great New York magazine cover. Yes she did. And you know,
Speaker 2:  sometimes she's like on Howard Stern. Yeah. Which is sort of like, are the
Speaker 2:  stern listeners listening to Charlie XCX? The Howard Stern
Speaker 2:  interview is crazy. I'm actually gonna play a clip from my
Speaker 2:  computer because I was like cackling watching this. It, it's like a
Speaker 2:  generational clash.
Speaker 15:  Charlie XCX is here. Very excited to speak with her. Charlie's
Speaker 15:  out on her sweat tour. Wow. Great to see you. Do you like
Speaker 15:  Weezer? Are you, are you hip to Weezer?
Speaker 16:  Me?
Speaker 15:  Yeah, yeah,
Speaker 16:  Yeah. I How do you feel? I've, I've worked with R Rivers once
Speaker 16:  before.
Speaker 15:  No kidding. When was that?
Speaker 16:  Yeah, it was back in, when
Speaker 15:  Was that? On Sucker?
Speaker 16:  It was Howard. Yes. Yes. Yeah. And he's, he was really
Speaker 16:  cool actually. And I, I love that song that you were just playing.
Speaker 16:  So Yeah, I think they're, they're pretty cool. They're pretty good.
Speaker 2:  And this goes on for an hour and 10 minutes and it's like
Speaker 2:  compared to her on Los Calista. It's just, I'll play
Speaker 2:  a clip from that too because I was like, this is actually crazy how different
Speaker 2:  it is.
Speaker 17:  We're recording this, we're gonna release it. I'm closer to the album release.
Speaker 17:  But you're, you're going on Seth with, with Troy.
Speaker 18:  Yeah. Yeah. And then watch what happens live. Are you on with the housewife?
Speaker 18:  Do you know? No.
Speaker 19:  I'm so sad about that.
Speaker 18:  You're just on solo?
Speaker 19:  No, it's another man. Okay.
Speaker 18:  I
Speaker 19:  Couldn't tell you who it is. Yeah,
Speaker 18:  Exactly. No, no problem. And I love that we will find out later who it is
Speaker 18:  when the episode airs and we'll be like, oh, that's who. And
Speaker 19:  I'll be like, it's, I
Speaker 18:  Love you. I love such a How Martha Vineyard. I love that show.
Speaker 18:  Exactly. Exactly. Exactly.
Speaker 19:  No, I don't know. I think his name's Joe.
Speaker 18:  Joe. Joe. That's, he sounds Biden, he sounds Joe Biden. It's
Speaker 18:  you and Joe Biden. And honestly, he's gonna ask you to be vp. Yeah.
Speaker 18:  It's gonna be amazing. You're gonna really burn it down. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Even the way she is sitting is crazy. Completely. And she wild
Speaker 2:  with all love and respect seems exhausted in both of those. Yes. But in one,
Speaker 2:  she's tired and having fun. Yes. How much of the new media circuit
Speaker 2:  and appearances live strictly online never to be talked
Speaker 2:  about in person? Almost all of them. Almost all of them. It's a, it's a
Speaker 2:  really online format. I think it's rare that even some
Speaker 2:  of these get like extended cuts beyond their like requisite minute
Speaker 2:  and a half if there're Yeah. If they're really little things also. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That's part of the new media circuit that feels really unique is
Speaker 2:  that like, like you said, a lot of these things are recorded for the
Speaker 2:  cut. Right. For, for the TikTok cut and
Speaker 2:  people will have quote unquote seen it, but they actually saw like
Speaker 2:  45 seconds of that interview. Yeah. Nobody's watching. Nobody.
Speaker 2:  Well maybe people are, but I think most people are simply
Speaker 2:  scrolling to it and then scrolling away and not going to YouTube to watch
Speaker 2:  the full thing or whatever. Yeah. And I think what's interesting about a
Speaker 2:  lot of these forms, there are certainly some that are the
Speaker 2:  exception to the rule. A lot of these you can really only do once. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  And most people are only doing them once. Yeah. There are a couple formats
Speaker 2:  like letterbox four favorites. Yes. Where they'll hit people
Speaker 2:  multiple times and maybe they'll be like a different metric. I think that's
Speaker 2:  a really great like recyclable format. And I think some
Speaker 2:  games that people have to do, there's a great, I mean I guess it's more of
Speaker 2:  a radio show, but there's a great BBC radio game that
Speaker 2:  I've started to think is maybe the most genius of all of these new media
Speaker 2:  things that I didn't get to include in my piece, which is they play a game
Speaker 2:  where the guest has to call three different famous people in their
Speaker 2:  phone. And the host have to guess whether the person when they pick up is
Speaker 2:  sitting or standing. Oh my God. That's really funny. It's so simple.
Speaker 18:  Yoyo,
Speaker 20:  Are you standing up or sitting down?
Speaker 18:  I'm sitting down right now. Yes. Yes. We
Speaker 20:  A bunch of, I said he was gonna be sitting down. Yeah mate. I'm on the BBC
Speaker 20:  radio breakfast show and we are playing this game called Stand Up, sit Down.
Speaker 2:  Whoever they call is always so annoyed. They're like, what do you what? And
Speaker 2:  then they just get the answer and then they're like, okay, see ya. Whoa.
Speaker 2:  It's really quick. And it's like, this shouldn't work as well as it does,
Speaker 2:  but it is actually quite endearing. Yeah. It's also
Speaker 2:  just, I can't help but think it is made for short form video
Speaker 2:  Completely. Like that is a structure. The structure is, or like, I guess
Speaker 2:  the, the mission is come up with a show that is like 30 seconds or
Speaker 2:  less and just do it, recycle it over and over and
Speaker 2:  over. Yeah. Something we were talking about with like red
Speaker 2:  carpet coverage at Vulture specifically is like if someone is coming
Speaker 2:  down that line and sees the vulture microphone, do
Speaker 2:  they know what is gonna come out of like my mouth? Mm. Because if they don't
Speaker 2:  know that maybe they don't wanna stop by when they see that letterbox
Speaker 2:  microphone, they know what's gonna happen. Yeah. There it feels
Speaker 2:  like a sort of an extension of a, a issue or
Speaker 2:  reality I guess that I think a lot about, which is like the line between
Speaker 2:  news and media and journalism and then everything else. And
Speaker 2:  increasingly it's just one bucket. Like when I was
Speaker 2:  doing research for this show, I learned
Speaker 2:  that Kiki Palmer had decided not to run an interview she did with
Speaker 2:  Jonathan Majors in her like public statement about why they decided
Speaker 2:  not to run it. She was like, I'm a journalist and people
Speaker 2:  should be able to trust that. Like I'm coming from a neutral place. I I give
Speaker 2:  people a platform to like say what they do And I don't judge. And I was like,
Speaker 2:  that's crazy. Yeah. You're, you're a, you're not a journalist. I love Kiki
Speaker 2:  Palmer, but you're not a journalist. No, not at all. And it, it, it's interesting
Speaker 2:  to me that like the thing about the Vulture mic, you,
Speaker 2:  you don't have a quick are these people sitting or standing thing?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Like you might ask like we a real thing we're working there, but Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But you might ask a real thing, right? Yeah, absolutely. And sometimes
Speaker 2:  like when I've done red carpets, you know, publicists will often come
Speaker 2:  down the line first to be like, so-and-so's coming, you have two questions,
Speaker 2:  blah, blah blah. And sometimes they'll specify we're not doing silly questions.
Speaker 2:  Oh wow. Don't do silly questions or don't do anything
Speaker 2:  adjacent to the movie. Sometimes we have like New York based questions. Okay.
Speaker 2:  New York magazine. Yeah. And they're like, don't do it movie only.
Speaker 2:  And one time it was also told like, this person is
Speaker 2:  funny, my client is funny but they'll, you don't need
Speaker 2:  to prompt them. Let them be funny on their own terms and don't set them up
Speaker 2:  with a silly question. They don't wanna do that. Mm. And it was like, okay,
Speaker 2:  I won't do that. And lo and behold like a serious question, got a funny answer
Speaker 2:  from this person. But I think the teams with
Speaker 2:  these people keep them really protected from anything that they don't
Speaker 2:  want to be doing. Yeah. Does the existence of the new media circuit
Speaker 2:  change how you work as a journalist?
Speaker 2:  I think it puts a lot of pressure to
Speaker 2:  come up with questions that have relatively short answers that are not
Speaker 2:  yes or no, but are also not too long-winded or heady.
Speaker 2:  I think people are not really caring about the answers to those questions,
Speaker 2:  which is a shame 'cause it's questions like that that make me want to be
Speaker 2:  a journalist and, and probe and question like why
Speaker 2:  things are the way they are. Red carpets are really stressful 'cause there's
Speaker 2:  so little time everyone is like jockeying over each other that
Speaker 2:  it's not always the environment for something serious. But I think that's
Speaker 2:  also why like Javier Barde talking about Gaza on the red carpet
Speaker 2:  is like he only really has like 90 seconds with some of these people and
Speaker 2:  he's using that to do that, which I think is great. Yeah. There's
Speaker 2:  also the, I feel like maybe something we touched on a little bit, didn't
Speaker 2:  say directly is that like when people go on these shows, a lot of what
Speaker 2:  is discussed is very controlled. There are you, you show up to the, you know,
Speaker 2:  the person comes on set and I'm assuming a lot of these people are told do
Speaker 2:  not ask about this thing. Right? Yeah. Like these are not
Speaker 2:  organic in the way that maybe we would hope or maybe you know it it's
Speaker 2:  just more
Speaker 2:  scripted almost. Yeah, completely. I think many of these things are
Speaker 2:  set in stone prearranged. I mean Kareem who does Subway
Speaker 2:  takes recently told the story of how Kamala Harris was supposed to
Speaker 2:  be on, they had a pre-approved take that she was
Speaker 2:  gonna do and then at the last minute they switched it up and it all went
Speaker 2:  sideways and it never ran. Yeah. Yeah. And so it's also
Speaker 2:  that these properties and these teams are not equipped
Speaker 2:  to improvise. Yeah. And that often is bad for everyone.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. They also also, it feels like these teams of, you know, the people
Speaker 2:  who run these shows or do these shows often they're small, you scrappy
Speaker 2:  and they're not equipped to push back either. For the most part
Speaker 2:  like this, this is a structure, you know, we talk a lot about like access
Speaker 2:  journalism and the way that that can skew coverage. But
Speaker 2:  this is like the final boss of that where like your
Speaker 2:  guests, the reason you make the show, the thing you put produce depends on
Speaker 2:  you having access to these people. Yeah. And If you go off script or If you
Speaker 2:  break some sort of like agreement or If you insist on maybe
Speaker 2:  holding their feet to the fire in a way they don't like, like that ends that.
Speaker 2:  Right. Yeah. Yeah. Our version now of holding someone's feet to the fire
Speaker 2:  is making them feel uncomfortable in a very controlled way. Yeah. Whether
Speaker 2:  that's eating very spicy chicken or a kind of stilted
Speaker 2:  awkwardness that comes with some of these like more modern new media figures
Speaker 2:  like Harry Daniels that's holding feet to fire. Yeah. But it's not in actual
Speaker 2:  sort of content of what we learn from these people. Does
Speaker 2:  all of this go away if like a platform
Speaker 2:  implodes? Like what is the future of Chicken Shop
Speaker 2:  Date or Hot ones if like YouTube
Speaker 2:  changes in some significant way? I think we're seeing it a little bit
Speaker 2:  with Chicken Shop Date where we're seeing Amelia Dem Oldenberg get brought
Speaker 2:  on as like an official red carpet spokesperson for the Oscars
Speaker 2:  and other awards shows. It's been interesting that they've been kind of
Speaker 2:  pivoting her, like pushing her into like an Entertainment Tonight Space
Speaker 2:  or like a talk show Right. Kind of space. And
Speaker 2:  I think that's a great fit for her honestly. I really, I really like what
Speaker 2:  she does And I think that show has a very clear ethos And I think she
Speaker 2:  has a really combative ethos that like, obviously it's not David
Speaker 2:  Letterman but it calls to mind sort of the combative nature Yeah. Going on
Speaker 2:  Letterman. Yeah. Yeah. It's fun to watch. Yeah, absolutely. I think YouTube
Speaker 2:  is only getting bigger and bigger. I don't know at this point what could
Speaker 2:  happen to YouTube that would change the metrics of some of these shows.
Speaker 2:  You And I were at the YouTube upfronts. Yeah. And they were saying people
Speaker 2:  are watching YouTube on their TVs. Yeah. It's not just a phone thing. So
Speaker 2:  I think we're gonna get longer and longer YouTube things. I mean
Speaker 2:  I semi recently watched a five hour YouTube video over many days
Speaker 2:  like that has become a very regular
Speaker 2:  way to consume media. Yeah. So to close this,
Speaker 2:  let's say you are a guest host of a popular tech podcast who is filling in
Speaker 2:  for your coworker who is out on parental leave,
Speaker 2:  what would you suggest? I would maybe it's like a fresh-faced
Speaker 2:  wannabe, a lister. What shows should they go on hypothetically? Well
Speaker 2:  I think you need to go on Call Her daddy. Mm. Yeah. I think you
Speaker 2:  need to be playing up maybe sort of a woman in stem
Speaker 2:  angle to be like Yeah, you know, you know about tech and you know about
Speaker 2:  computers, but like, hey, like you also love clothes. I'm relatable. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  completely. And maybe you wanna do like a perfectly imperfect
Speaker 2:  list and newsletter Yes. To pull in like a younger audience. Yes. But also
Speaker 2:  show that you're sort of out there perusing, have kind of
Speaker 2:  taste. I think for Fresh Face people,
Speaker 2:  a lot of what they need to do is be a kind of cultural taste maker or prove
Speaker 2:  to some degree that they're both kind of approachable but also a real head.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. About their field. So maybe you could go in the Criterion Closet too.
Speaker 2:  I was gonna say, should I go in the closet? Why not? Yeah, I would love to
Speaker 2:  go into the Criterion Closet I wanted to ask you, but I kind of forgot about
Speaker 2:  that too. Like the way that brands or
Speaker 2:  existing companies like Manufacture a moment like that, like
Speaker 2:  Criterion definitely got it shit together and figured out
Speaker 2:  a way to make the closet a thing letterbox too with, with the, they did a
Speaker 2:  great, they did a great job of it And I think what they've done is kind
Speaker 2:  of create a non gamified interview form
Speaker 2:  that lets the person in question be as smart
Speaker 2:  as they are or want to be. And there's no wrong answers. Yeah. They're doing
Speaker 2:  something where they can say absolutely anything. It'll look good, it'll
Speaker 2:  look cool. There's that great clip of Malcolm Washington
Speaker 2:  and John David Washington in the Criterion Closet and Malcolm Washington
Speaker 2:  is like talking about I think like Rome Air or some French director and
Speaker 2:  like really going long. And then John David Washington just goes like, Jackie
Speaker 2:  Jen Boxhead. Know what I'm saying? And it's like, yeah, that's, those are
Speaker 2:  both right. Yeah. Those are two correct ways to be doing that kind
Speaker 2:  of thing. And I think those are what I'm most impressed by when I watch
Speaker 2:  because it's both letting the subject have a ton of
Speaker 2:  control. But I do think a lot of the time they say really interesting things.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And there's also, I think in those cases the audience
Speaker 2:  receives it well no matter what you do really, it's like a structure that,
Speaker 2:  because there are no wrong answers,
Speaker 2:  viewers will be like, so true Queen. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Like you took Pride
Speaker 2:  and Prejudice starring Keira Knightly. Or they'll be like oh eight
Speaker 2:  and a half. Like you know what's up. Oh they're serious. They're serious.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Is there any one of these shows you would wanna be
Speaker 2:  on where you're like, Ooh, that would be fun for me? I was thinking about
Speaker 2:  this, prepping for this because I find,
Speaker 2:  I don't think I could do a podcast. It's just simply way too long. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Like with you, this is fun to talk be, but like I don't want to
Speaker 2:  be in like snuggled up in a chair with Alex Cooper.
Speaker 2:  I feel like Timothy Schlamme did the thing where he just like went and bought
Speaker 2:  records with Nard war. Yeah. Right. Yeah, I would do that. Yeah, that would
Speaker 2:  be really fun. I would do the Criterion Closet. I'm not eating
Speaker 2:  chicken on camera. Simply not doing that. So I think I, I like these
Speaker 2:  things where there's like an activity that you go and do. Yeah. What about
Speaker 2:  you? What would you be on? I wanna go on Marin so bad. Mm. And now it's ending.
Speaker 2:  Oh, it's kinda the worst news for me. But I, I really love him And I think
Speaker 2:  he was kind of a pioneer in the space ala Howard Stern, but
Speaker 2:  I think Marin kind of pioneered what like the Dax Shepherd.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Guys being dudes thing is now with the, which is like
Speaker 2:  confessional and sensitive while also being kind of masculine.
Speaker 2:  And I just think unlike many people doing what he does
Speaker 2:  now, he's a really great interviewer. Yeah, yeah. I know. Push back a little.
Speaker 2:  People are bad at interviewing, he will push back and he will make people
Speaker 2:  uncomfortable. And the best episodes of that show are when both of them are
Speaker 2:  so uncomfortable. Yeah, I, I guess I would also like to be on Dua Lip a's
Speaker 2:  book club podcast or whatever. Oh yeah, she actually seems like, obviously
Speaker 2:  again these are controlled and she's definitely getting a list of things
Speaker 2:  not to ask about. But I would talk books with Dua Lipa I
Speaker 2:  think. And you heard it here first. We're available for bookings if anyone
Speaker 2:  wants us. Who? Who wants me? Who want me?
Speaker 2:  Thank you Fran. This fun. Thank you. We have to take a break
Speaker 2:  now, but when we're back, we're going to talk with Sarah Fackrell about a
Speaker 2:  questionable legal tactic that is all the rage in Chicago. For some reason
Speaker 2:  we'll
Speaker 2:  t-shirts on Redbubble? A fan of the country music star Loop combs
Speaker 2:  and a random Amazon seller called Accents all have in common.
Speaker 2:  They've all been accused of allegedly infringing on someone else's trademark
Speaker 2:  or design patent. But these lawsuits aren't just your run
Speaker 2:  of the mill intellectual property law cases. They're just a handful of
Speaker 2:  examples of a unique type of lawsuit that have become something of a trend.
Speaker 2:  In the last few years, the woman who is selling t-shirts online
Speaker 2:  was sued by the owner of the Grumpy Cat trademark. I don't know If you remember
Speaker 2:  this, there was the kind of sad looking cat that
Speaker 2:  spawned a million memes and a movie. She earned one
Speaker 2:  single dollar from selling a t-shirt and later found out that she was being
Speaker 2:  ordered to pay a hundred thousand dollars. In the Luke Combs case
Speaker 2:  that went viral a few years ago, a Florida based fan who was selling
Speaker 2:  homemade drink tumblers on Amazon with combs likeness on them was
Speaker 2:  ordered to pay $250,000 and she didn't even
Speaker 2:  know she was being sued. In the case of the Amazon seller accents,
Speaker 2:  the China-based company had $50,000 in earnings frozen
Speaker 2:  in their Amazon seller account over products that a judge later ruled
Speaker 2:  likely didn't infringe on a design patent at all. So how
Speaker 2:  exactly does this legal tactic work and who benefits and who's at a disadvantage?
Speaker 2:  Welcome to the weird and ruthless world of Schedule A cases and to
Speaker 2:  help me explain what's going on here, I have Sarah Fackrell, a professor
Speaker 2:  at Chicago Kent College of Law at Illinois Tech. Let's get into it.
Speaker 2:  Okay Sarah, so why are these cases called
Speaker 2:  schedule a lawsuits? Where does this name come from?
Speaker 22:  Well that's a name that just sort of bubbled up from the way that
Speaker 22:  the main players started naming their cases. Stepping
Speaker 22:  back a little bit, this is a relatively new form of mass defendant
Speaker 22:  IP litigation and the original cases started,
Speaker 22:  there was something like big brand versus doe's one
Speaker 22:  through a hundred or something, right? Like a John Doe lawsuit you might
Speaker 22:  have heard of. And then eventually they started saying, well it's
Speaker 22:  big brand versus the defendants that are listed on Schedule
Speaker 22:  A, which is just a separate document that was filed separately
Speaker 22:  apart from the complaint, at least in some courts. And
Speaker 22:  so what they were doing was instead of saying this is Apple versus Samsung,
Speaker 22:  and that's right there on the face of the complaint, they were saying here's
Speaker 22:  Apple versus a bunch of people and we're not gonna tell you who their names
Speaker 22:  are. At least not publicly, at least not at first.
Speaker 22:  And so a lot of people, myself included, started calling these schedule
Speaker 22:  a cases 'cause it was just an easy way to refer to them. And this model,
Speaker 22:  even though in practice the case names can differ,
Speaker 22:  that separate document can have a different name. For example, some of them
Speaker 22:  call it exhibit A or whatever it, it can have a different name,
Speaker 22:  but the major players started captioning these cases
Speaker 22:  Schedule A. And so that's the name that seems to have stuck, at least with
Speaker 22:  practitioners and judges here in Chicago.
Speaker 2:  And on the schedule a form, it's not just like a couple
Speaker 2:  storefronts or defendants named, right? It's like dozens, sometimes
Speaker 2:  even hundreds. What have you seen there?
Speaker 22:  Yeah, so I will say I have not been able to
Speaker 22:  exhaustively empirically study all of these cases yet. It's a
Speaker 22:  fire hose. It's literally impossible to to keep track of everything. But
Speaker 22:  what I've seen from my impre imperfect efforts to pay attention to
Speaker 22:  what's going on is I've seen anywhere from a
Speaker 22:  couple dozen on the low end, maybe even fewer, sometimes
Speaker 22:  even maybe three or four. But usually the dozens is
Speaker 22:  the low end to over a thousand and they don't sue the
Speaker 22:  defendants using their legal names. This is another big difference between
Speaker 22:  a schedule a case and a normal case. So in a normal case, If you wanna sue
Speaker 22:  someone, you have to figure out what their actual legal name is and if it's
Speaker 22:  an individual, what's their actual name, which can be hard if you're suing
Speaker 22:  like a celebrity or something. And if it's a company, right, is it Starbucks
Speaker 22:  Corp or Starbucks Inc or whatever you're supposed to figure that out and
Speaker 22:  sue them under their proper name. In these cases though, the plaintiffs
Speaker 22:  say, well we don't know what the real names of these sellers are, so please
Speaker 22:  let us use their online storefront name or some
Speaker 22:  other similar signifier as an alias. So they're suing people
Speaker 22:  under aliases. That's where these names come from that you'll see
Speaker 22:  when the defendants are able to show up, it's usually their storefront name.
Speaker 22:  And then eventually we may or may not actually learn their real name.
Speaker 2:  Hmm. What does putting all of these storefronts onto
Speaker 2:  one copyright or design patent suit do? Like what is
Speaker 2:  the benefit that plaintiffs get by throwing them all onto one
Speaker 2:  form, whether it's called schedule A or exhibit A or whatever it is.
Speaker 22:  The reason why you wanna sue a thousand people together instead of filing
Speaker 22:  a thousand different lawsuits is because it saves you money.
Speaker 2:  Classic, classic.
Speaker 22:  It saves you money and perhaps time and effort, right? But money's the big
Speaker 22:  one. You're supposed to pay a fee of about $400 for a federal lawsuit.
Speaker 22:  So if I file one lawsuit against a hundred defendants,
Speaker 22:  that's a lot cheaper than filing a hundred defendants, a 400 bucks pop,
Speaker 22:  right? So they wanna save money is the big thing.
Speaker 22:  And I think that's why bundling these cases is so important to this
Speaker 22:  business model. They could literally sue everyone separately, but not if
Speaker 22:  they wanna make money.
Speaker 2:  I wanna back up a second and just be like, I think we should say that people
Speaker 2:  can agree that the internet does have a lot of cheap junk.
Speaker 2:  There are products for sale that infringe on someone else's rights. We've
Speaker 2:  seen, you know, designers or businesses complain about this constantly
Speaker 2:  with valid reasons to be upset and you know,
Speaker 2:  the knockoffs or the ES or the infringing products are everywhere, but
Speaker 2:  schedule A suits work differently than maybe a traditional
Speaker 2:  trademark case might. So what are the different moving parts here that
Speaker 2:  actually make these suits so effective for plaintiffs?
Speaker 22:  Absolutely. And this larger question of how do we police our IP rights on
Speaker 22:  the internet has lasted as long as there's been an internet, right? This
Speaker 22:  is not a new question, this is just a new evolution
Speaker 22:  as Professor Eric Goldman has written about who studied sort of the
Speaker 22:  evolution on the trademark side. We've also seen on the copyright side,
Speaker 22:  some people who used to file mass copyright lawsuits are now filing schedule
Speaker 22:  A cases. So you're right that this is an old problem, but this is a new
Speaker 22:  solution and it's actually pretty clever and sophisticated when it's done
Speaker 22:  right. So the heart and soul of a Schedule eight case
Speaker 22:  is the asset freeze. The lawyers who perfected this
Speaker 22:  litigation model figured out a way to convince judges
Speaker 22:  they, they should not only allow them to sue hundreds of people altogether,
Speaker 22:  not only let them sue them without knowing their real legal names,
Speaker 22:  not only let them sue them in the form of their choice, which is often,
Speaker 22:  but not always Chicago. But also to let them freeze
Speaker 22:  the accounts of these defendants before they even know they've been
Speaker 22:  sued in legal language we call as an ex parte TRO or a
Speaker 22:  temporary restraining order and they come in and say, Hey judge, look these
Speaker 22:  defendants, we have reason to believe that they are all bad and nefarious
Speaker 22:  Chinese counterfeiters or at least foreign counterfeiters, but they often
Speaker 22:  call them Chinese, which is a, a separate issue in these cases, right? Yeah.
Speaker 22:  They say we have reason to believe that these are all nefarious foreign
Speaker 22:  counterfeiters and judge, unless you freeze their Amazon seller account
Speaker 22:  right now, unless you freeze their eBay account right now, unless you freeze
Speaker 22:  their PayPal account right now, they are going to abscond with their ill-gotten
Speaker 22:  gains and just disappear into, you know, the far reaches of
Speaker 22:  the internet. And for a variety of reasons they've been able to convince
Speaker 22:  judges that this is correct, even when the defendants don't actually
Speaker 22:  fit those profiles. And so this key that they go in,
Speaker 22:  they find a bunch of sellers on, you know, name your platform,
Speaker 22:  eBay, Etsy, whatever you have. And they say, judge,
Speaker 22:  we think they infringe our rights. Here's a little proof and please
Speaker 22:  freeze all their accounts so we can figure this out.
Speaker 2:  And most of the time that's working right? Like most of the time the judges
Speaker 2:  are like, sure,
Speaker 22:  Yeah, we're still, I, I'm actually working with a co-author trying to get
Speaker 22:  some good empirical data on this. But just anecdotally,
Speaker 22:  it seems like a rubber stamp a lot. Not all judges,
Speaker 22:  some judges have become skeptical, but a lot of judges for
Speaker 22:  quite a while now seem to have accepted these cookie cutter
Speaker 22:  boilerplate complaints and said, oh here's another one and we're gonna freeze
Speaker 22:  that and freeze that. And you can imagine this is a really, really, really
Speaker 22:  powerful remedy. If you're in a lawsuit, you have
Speaker 22:  their money and you've, they often usually freeze the whole
Speaker 22:  account, not just whatever you sold. So let's say that I sold
Speaker 22:  one accused product for 4 99, but I happen to have
Speaker 22:  $350,000 in my account. That's what gets frozen
Speaker 22:  and it's sort of just luck based on the disbursement schedule. And so
Speaker 22:  you could imagine If you were a defendant and you've got your money
Speaker 22:  tied up, right, varying degrees, maybe it's, you know, nothing 'cause you
Speaker 22:  just got a disbursement, maybe it's a thousand bucks, maybe it's a hundred
Speaker 22:  thousand bucks. That's not normally how we start litigation. Normally you
Speaker 22:  find out that someone sued you and we have these little steps we take, but
Speaker 22:  these defendants often I'm told find out
Speaker 22:  they have been sued when they notice their account's frozen. Yeah.
Speaker 22:  And then the platform's like, hey, go talk to the plaintiff's lawyers.
Speaker 22:  Yeah. And If you might not have even seen the complaint or the papers or
Speaker 22:  have had any notice at all and that's extraordinary.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I wanted to pick up on one of the cases that I mentioned earlier,
Speaker 2:  this Amazon seller accents, which I should clarify for
Speaker 2:  listeners that it's spelled not like accents. It's spelled
Speaker 2:  a CC capital E-N-C-Y-C. And I had to go to like
Speaker 2:  the attorney that represents accents to be like, can you please tell me how
Speaker 2:  you pronounce this name? But it's called accents. It is a China
Speaker 2:  based Amazon seller. They sell like really random things that you might need
Speaker 2:  around the house, you know, hooks or like sticky, like suction
Speaker 2:  cup things for you know, hanging something or whatever. And what you
Speaker 2:  were describing, this TRO, this temporary restraining order happened exactly
Speaker 2:  to them. They were selling one hook that was like, you put
Speaker 2:  it on in your closet and you can hang a handbag from the hook. It's
Speaker 2:  like a double-sided hook. They were selling those hooks and they got an email
Speaker 2:  saying, Hey, there's an issue with this listing. We've taken it down and
Speaker 2:  also your seller account is frozen. The money ended up growing to
Speaker 2:  like $50,000 because they were still making sales on their
Speaker 2:  other products, which were not affected. They just couldn't get their money
Speaker 2:  out. And like you said, they had no idea that they were being named in a
Speaker 2:  schedule a suit until it was kind of too late for them. Right. Already
Speaker 2:  their business is being thrown in disarray, it's around the holidays, they
Speaker 2:  can't, they can't get their earnings. So I wanted to ask
Speaker 2:  just like, is this something that should be happening? Is
Speaker 2:  this normal, I guess for like you said for Schedule A, it kind
Speaker 2:  of has become extraordinary, but a temporary restraining order like this,
Speaker 2:  like you said, is only supposed to happen for very, very specific
Speaker 2:  reasons and very rarely applied.
Speaker 22:  Yeah. In theory a temporary restraining order is supposed to
Speaker 22:  maintain the status quo so we can figure out what's going on, right? So,
Speaker 22:  so to take like a real property example, if a company was going to demolish
Speaker 22:  a building where I'd painted a mural And I thought I had a right to have
Speaker 22:  them not demolish my mural. If I wait until they demolished the
Speaker 22:  whole building, it's too late. So I might go to the court and ask for a
Speaker 22:  temporary restraining order and be like, Hey, don't let them bulldoze the
Speaker 22:  building until we can figure out the art law issue. That's sort of a classic
Speaker 22:  example of A TRO. This is different because
Speaker 22:  again, normally defendants are allowed to use their money while litigation's
Speaker 22:  going on. And sometimes these ts are written incredibly broadly.
Speaker 22:  Like sometimes they're just like, okay, you can't use your Amazon account.
Speaker 22:  But I've seen some recently that are more like, you can't spend any money
Speaker 22:  in any bank account.
Speaker 2:  How do you live?
Speaker 22:  I, that's the thing, right? How do you buy food? How do you hire a lawyer?
Speaker 22:  More importantly, right? So what happened with accents is not unusual
Speaker 22:  on its facts, but what's unusual about it is they were able to get a lawyer.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 22:  That doesn't always happen for a variety of reasons.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's something I wanted to talk about too is just, you know, it feels
Speaker 2:  like there's a real power imbalance in a lot of these cases because
Speaker 2:  there are, sometimes they're big companies, but sometimes they're not that
Speaker 2:  big who are actually going after all of these sellers. But by and large,
Speaker 2:  from what I understand, the people being named as defendants are like
Speaker 2:  individuals selling something they're making, or foreign
Speaker 2:  companies who maybe like don't speak the language, don't know any lawyers
Speaker 2:  in Chicago that they can hire to defend them. And
Speaker 2:  accent's attorney told me that, you know, most of the time you go to court
Speaker 2:  and there can be hundreds of defendants named and there's not a single person
Speaker 2:  right in the courtroom there to represent these
Speaker 2:  people. It's just the plaintiff's kind of pushing things along.
Speaker 22:  Yeah, we don't actually have a lot of good information about who the defendants
Speaker 22:  are actually, because they're named using aliases. And
Speaker 22:  because of all the secrecy, a lot of these records remain under seal
Speaker 22:  for quite a long time, if not forever. And so we can't really know
Speaker 22:  systematically who's being sued. But like you said, as far as we can tell,
Speaker 22:  it's a variety of companies. Sometimes it's just an individual, sometimes
Speaker 22:  it's a little company, sometimes they're in America, sometimes they're not.
Speaker 22:  We don't really know as outsiders, right? I mean, maybe some of the plaintiff's
Speaker 22:  lawyers have some insights that we don't. So that
Speaker 22:  asymmetry in these cases is really, really striking. And even when
Speaker 22:  there's a hearing, it's often pretty quick. I've seen
Speaker 22:  judges say, okay, plaintiffs, you can have your TRO, we're going to have
Speaker 22:  a preliminary injunction hearing, which is what you're supposed to do If
Speaker 22:  you want a longer initial freeze. And
Speaker 22:  sometimes they only have a matter of days. And so
Speaker 22:  imagine that you are who the plaintiffs always say these defendants are,
Speaker 22:  right? You are someone in another country who is selling products
Speaker 22:  online and you find out in the middle of the night that there's gonna be
Speaker 22:  a hearing in two days in some city you've never even heard of in the middle
Speaker 22:  of North America, right? Like how, how do you
Speaker 22:  even start to defend yourself? I mean, I wouldn't know what I would do if
Speaker 22:  I was in the other shoes, right? If someone sued me in China, And I'm a
Speaker 22:  lawyer, I'm a law professor, I have connections. I don't know what you do
Speaker 22:  If you are just a normal person. And so
Speaker 22:  these cases move so quickly because they're motivated by this
Speaker 22:  narrative of, you know, bad, nasty, nefarious people need to be, you know,
Speaker 22:  clamped down on, or it'll just be whack-a-mole on the internet forever.
Speaker 22:  But what happens when that's not the case? Parties can't always fight every
Speaker 22:  bad claim, even the ones that lack merit, right? Sometimes it's just
Speaker 22:  not worth it, right? Hey, that hook wasn't making us money anyway. Let's
Speaker 22:  just quit selling it. Right? Or that t-shirt, no one bought it anyway. We
Speaker 22:  don't care. We'll just cancel, we'll quit. So there's a certain threshold
Speaker 22:  of how much even has to be frozen before rationally, economically, if you're
Speaker 22:  in a position where you can make those sorts of judgments even makes sense
Speaker 22:  to call a lawyer.
Speaker 2:  Something that struck me in all three of the cases, the grumpy cat,
Speaker 2:  Luke Combs, and then accents case, is that the
Speaker 2:  actual earnings that these defendants at least who are responding to the
Speaker 2:  suit are reporting are so small. The grumpy Cat T t-shirt seller
Speaker 2:  made literally $1. She sold one shirt
Speaker 2:  and it didn't have like the photo of the grumpy cat on
Speaker 2:  it. It was just like a cat that looked kind of sad, an illustration of a
Speaker 2:  cat that looked kind of sad. The Luke Combs fan, which that story also kind
Speaker 2:  of blew up because he, I think, tried to make it right afterwards. But the
Speaker 2:  Luke Combs fans sold like $380 of homemade
Speaker 2:  merch and then accents sold less than
Speaker 2:  $500 of these handbag hooks. It's not like their main seller. They, I don't
Speaker 2:  think care if they sell these handbag hooks, but the
Speaker 2:  plaintiffs are seeking sort of enormous default judgments.
Speaker 2:  So, you know, a hundred thousand dollars, $250,000, 900,000
Speaker 2:  I think was the accents case for, you know,
Speaker 2:  500 bucks of hooks that a judge later found likely weren't infringing in
Speaker 2:  the first place. So like how do plaintiffs justify this?
Speaker 22:  That's a great question and it's actually another
Speaker 22:  really big concern with those freezes that I talked about
Speaker 22:  before. So what the plaintiffs do is they say, Hey, we're entitled to do
Speaker 22:  this freeze because we could get this kind of remedy that qualifies, at
Speaker 22:  least theoretically under their theory of Supreme Court precedent, which
Speaker 22:  hasn't really been strongly tested yet. Certainly not any court of appeals
Speaker 22:  that I know, but we are eligible for potentially this type of damages. So
Speaker 22:  you should let us freeze their assets is the argument. But then they turn
Speaker 22:  around at the end and ask for a totally different kind of
Speaker 22:  damages. Ones that would not justify that initial
Speaker 22:  asset freeze. And a number of judges, well at
Speaker 22:  least a couple of judges have started to
Speaker 22:  really bristle at that, right? You are coming in
Speaker 22:  and saying you want this, but then you're asking me for that. And so there's
Speaker 22:  this sort of mismatch and perhaps
Speaker 22:  a feeling that there is perhaps some kind of bait and switch going on or
Speaker 22:  something like that in addition to just the extraordinarily large numbers
Speaker 22:  because these big numbers are statutory
Speaker 22:  damages. But the problem is, is there's a really big
Speaker 22:  mismatch between actual harm being done and the damages being
Speaker 22:  awarded, which is bad on a couple of levels, right? First it just
Speaker 22:  seems really unfair. And that's a problem beyond just for
Speaker 22:  the parties involved because I think it makes our courts look bad,
Speaker 22:  right? Our judiciary and our legal system depends,
Speaker 22:  at least in part, on being trusted and respected. And when
Speaker 22:  you go around saying that someone's gotta pay half a million dollars because
Speaker 22:  they sold one $5 widget, that isn't a great
Speaker 22:  look for the court system, let alone for just larger, more pure ideas
Speaker 22:  of justice. And so I think that's why cases like the Luke Combs case,
Speaker 22:  why the, like the Curtis case, the grumpy Cat T catch a lot of people's
Speaker 22:  attention because it just seems and is fundamentally
Speaker 22:  unfair.
Speaker 2:  I guess we could talk about like the status of the Grumpy Cat T case.
Speaker 22:  Yeah, the grumpy Cat T case. Actually I just checked so, so one thing when
Speaker 22:  we were talking grumpy Cat T and Schedule A is, you have to clarify which
Speaker 22:  Grumpy Cat T schedule a case, they're
Speaker 2:  Very litigious, right? The owners,
Speaker 22:  I did a docket search And I found over 60 cases
Speaker 22:  wow. Schedule A in the Northern district, which is a lot.
Speaker 22:  And you know, in that one, a couple of the defendants had
Speaker 22:  fought back, including pro se right? Without a lawyer. And
Speaker 22:  the judge actually did end up granting
Speaker 22:  those three defendant's motions to dismiss. Hmm.
Speaker 22:  So really great news for those three defendants.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 22:  Not so great news for all of the other defendants who were faced with
Speaker 22:  identical allegations that the judge said, that's not good enough
Speaker 22:  to be sued in my court. But because they didn't fight back, I
Speaker 22:  assume there's gonna be default judgments entered against them if there
Speaker 22:  aren't already.
Speaker 2:  Yeah.
Speaker 22:  And that's just kinda extraordinary to me. I, I don't think that
Speaker 22:  once the judges decided that's insufficient as a matter of law, I don't
Speaker 22:  think has to accept it. And that's added on top of the fact that like you
Speaker 22:  alluded to before, the merits in that case were not particularly
Speaker 22:  the strongest. So in that exact one, the Curtis one that you
Speaker 22:  mentioned, you know, they have this word mark, they've registered the word
Speaker 22:  grumpy cat or the phrase grumpy cat for use in connection with various products.
Speaker 22:  And If you look at their filings, they say that exactly
Speaker 22:  what she did wrong was call it a grumpy cat pattern in the
Speaker 22:  description of the product. So I've got this fabric or shirt that looks
Speaker 22:  like a cat who is grumpy.
Speaker 22:  That's not the kind of thing that trademark laws was stop you from doing
Speaker 22:  right? You're allowed to call a grumpy cat. Grumpy cat, as long as you're
Speaker 22:  noting it in a way that makes people think that that was made, sponsored,
Speaker 22:  or approved by the Grumpy Cat company, which
Speaker 22:  I'm always surprised was a real thing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Also, I should say that the real grumpy cat, his name, his, I'm not
Speaker 2:  sure if it was a he or she tartar sauce died several years ago,
Speaker 2:  like RIP tartar sauce. But grumpy Cat T is, you know, for all
Speaker 2:  intents and purposes, not really a thing anymore.
Speaker 22:  Yeah. So we had this meme that became monetized by a company
Speaker 22:  and now like you said, the cat has passed on and the trademark
Speaker 22:  remains. So, I mean, lots of questions there, but
Speaker 22:  again, only the three defendants who showed up got relief. And
Speaker 22:  that's unfortunate.
Speaker 2:  Most people probably aren't familiar with Schedule A cases and
Speaker 2:  certainly a lot of the people who are actually being sued aren't. But
Speaker 2:  there's one group of people that is very familiar with Schedule A cases people
Speaker 2:  practicing in the northern district of Illinois. I have a couple numbers
Speaker 2:  from Eric Goldman at the Santa Clara University School of Law.
Speaker 2:  So he counted 7,700 cases,
Speaker 2:  40% of which were filed after January 1st, 2024,
Speaker 2:  naming 1.5 million defendants. And by
Speaker 2:  his count, 88% were filed in the northern district of Illinois.
Speaker 2:  And it's kind of become an epicenter of these kinds of cases. What is
Speaker 2:  going on in the northern district of Illinois? What's happening in Chicago?
Speaker 22:  Well, I mean that's the billion dollar question, right? And I don't think
Speaker 22:  anyone really has one single answer.
Speaker 22:  I think, think we're seeing a lot of cases here because the judges
Speaker 22:  let them happen here. So what do I mean by that? The schedule A
Speaker 22:  model depends on convincing judges to
Speaker 22:  exercise their discretion at various key parts of a case
Speaker 22:  in very specific ways. You have to be able to convince the
Speaker 22:  judges to exercise their discretion to, for example, let you
Speaker 22:  freeze the assets. You have to convince them to use their
Speaker 22:  discretion to let you serve the defendants by email, which is another
Speaker 22:  key part of this. You have to convince them to use their discretion to join
Speaker 22:  a whole bunch of defendants together to sue a whole bunch of people together.
Speaker 22:  And it varies other points, it's all about convincing judges to
Speaker 22:  use their discretion. And so as a very practical matter, they're
Speaker 22:  filing cases here because the cases work here. Hmm. And why exactly do the
Speaker 22:  cases work here is the harder question?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. If one piece of that breaks,
Speaker 2:  does schedule a kind of fall apart or can they try to figure out ways
Speaker 2:  around that?
Speaker 22:  Well, that's a great question and we're starting to see some natural
Speaker 22:  experiments to some degree on that. So
Speaker 22:  it's hard, right? So the northern district is actually a pretty big
Speaker 22:  federal bench. There's a lot of judges compared to certain districts.
Speaker 22:  So even If you've got two or three or five who are skeptical,
Speaker 22:  there's still like 20 who are totally okay with this, right? The question
Speaker 22:  is then how do you respond? And we've seen defendants
Speaker 22:  respond in different ways. Sometimes we've seen them dismiss
Speaker 22:  their cases and refile and hope to get a new judge in the same
Speaker 22:  district. And we know this because other judges have noticed and called
Speaker 22:  them out for that. Judge Therp has done this quite a bit
Speaker 22:  here in the northern district. We have seen cases where
Speaker 22:  they go and they file in a completely different district, right? Fine, you
Speaker 22:  don't like my, my joinder judge, I'm gonna go file in Pittsburgh. And
Speaker 22:  this is interesting because the idea of
Speaker 22:  forum shopping to a certain degree is totally tolerated
Speaker 22:  and okay under the law, right? If I have a case that under the, the
Speaker 22:  relevant rules could equally be filed in Chicago and Pittsburgh,
Speaker 22:  normally I, as the plaintiff get to choose, there's not anything inherently
Speaker 22:  wrong with that. Where it starts to get messy is like this
Speaker 22:  case we recently saw where plaintiffs
Speaker 22:  filed their case in Chicago get a judge. They don't like dismiss the case
Speaker 22:  and refile against the same defendants and maybe other people somewhere
Speaker 22:  else. Hmm. I've seen a fair number in Atlanta recently.
Speaker 22:  Nike for some reason, likes to file in Atlanta. Hmm. As far as I can tell,
Speaker 22:  we've seen a number in Pittsburgh. We, I just saw one in
Speaker 22:  Kansas. Huh? That was the first one I saw.
Speaker 22:  It's about salt and pepper shakers and the Yeah, the judge just
Speaker 22:  granted the TRO.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. One thing that really drew me to schedule A cases
Speaker 2:  and really fascinated me was that it kind of flips the script
Speaker 2:  a little bit. And we think of infringement and counterfeiting obviously as
Speaker 2:  problems that exist online. We understand that rights holders
Speaker 2:  want to protect what they've created and even alleged
Speaker 2:  infringers, alleged counterfeiters, they do deserve due process, right? They
Speaker 2:  should have their day in court, they should have the opportunity to respond
Speaker 2:  to allegations because sometimes they didn't really infringe at all. So
Speaker 2:  what is the danger of sort of allowing schedule asus to proceed at the current
Speaker 2:  clip to proceed sort of how they're, they're working right now.
Speaker 22:  There are a lot of reasons to be concerned as a really
Speaker 22:  practical matter, right? We talked about how
Speaker 22:  individual defendants can be wrongfully caught up in these
Speaker 22:  dragnets. Now, I'm not totally sure how
Speaker 22:  different plaintiff's firms come up with these cases or who's vetting their
Speaker 22:  claims. And we can't know for sure what percentage of
Speaker 22:  these infringement claims have merit and which ones don't. But we
Speaker 22:  do know for sure that an alarming number of them
Speaker 22:  completely lack merit. And that's not something I say lightly.
Speaker 22:  I think as someone who is a, you know, a due process absolutist, a proceduralist,
Speaker 22:  I would be concerned, even if these were all perfect infringement, right?
Speaker 22:  They actually had merits, and you're actually an infringer, I would self
Speaker 22:  concerned about this litigation model just from a due process procedure
Speaker 22:  perspective. But when you add in the fact that a lot of these defendants
Speaker 22:  are very, very clearly not infringers, let alone counterfeiters.
Speaker 22:  And again, I can't quantify that as a percentage because of just the volume
Speaker 22:  plus the secrecy plus all these other problems we've talked about.
Speaker 22:  But I've seen enough to be very, very, very disturbed. And
Speaker 22:  again, this is a problem not only for the individual defendants, but also
Speaker 22:  for the integrity of the system. Right? What does this say about design
Speaker 22:  patents in particular, right? You know, that's my thing. In design patents,
Speaker 22:  it's maybe particularly concerning because you can get a design patent
Speaker 22:  really easily and really quickly for not
Speaker 22:  enough lot of money in the scheme of things. And so we've seen
Speaker 22:  allegations of people saying that this plaintiff went and got a design
Speaker 22:  patent on something that already exists on an Amazon that they didn't create,
Speaker 22:  and then they sued all all of us in a scheduled case. And
Speaker 22:  if that's true, that's incredibly disturbing, right? And the
Speaker 22:  part that is additionally disturbing to me is that it's plausible
Speaker 22:  design patent examiners at the PTO are really hardworking
Speaker 22:  people. Everyone I've met is really dedicated and smart and doing the best
Speaker 22:  they can, but they only get a couple of hours. You can't search all of Amazon
Speaker 22:  in the couple of hours, let alone do all the other work you need to do on
Speaker 22:  your file. And so we have a system where In theory, even If you have a design
Speaker 22:  patent, if the applicants are not being
Speaker 22:  scrupulous, there is room for additional exploitation, which again,
Speaker 22:  puts the entire system into disrepute. Not to mention being
Speaker 22:  enormously unfair to all the people who were being targeting. And then there's
Speaker 22:  the public, right? Let's say that I wanted to buy a purse hook,
Speaker 22:  but the best one out there was taken off the market because they got threatened
Speaker 22:  by a schedule a plaintiff, even though they didn't infringe. There's a harm
Speaker 22:  to competition in consumers because while online infringement
Speaker 22:  is a problem, online choice is a good,
Speaker 22:  right? And so I think there's a lot of people who get hurt here in a very
Speaker 22:  practical way. In addition to all these sort of more
Speaker 22:  maybe abstract sounding concerns about due process or procedure
Speaker 22:  or you know, law,
Speaker 2:  Is there any indication that judges are beginning to question this tactic?
Speaker 2:  I know there was an order coming down from a judge in the Northern District
Speaker 2:  of Illinois. Walk me through what he said.
Speaker 22:  So Judge Ness. So it looks like starting in about
Speaker 22:  March, judge Ness started
Speaker 22:  issuing these orders in all his Schedule A cases where
Speaker 22:  he said, look, I become concerned about this litigation
Speaker 22:  model and especially these certain parts where I'm being asked to use my
Speaker 22:  discretion in these certain ways. So I'm gonna hold all these cases in
Speaker 22:  abeyance for now while I figure it out, which is completely my,
Speaker 22:  I've never heard of a judge doing anything like this. Like this is wild,
Speaker 22:  just saying, we gotta shut this all down so we can figure out what's going
Speaker 22:  on, right? Judicial version and yeah, this is pretty
Speaker 22:  extraordinary. And that's added to a rising
Speaker 22:  number of cases where we've seen other judges on issues like
Speaker 22:  joinder say, Hey look, I know that other judges have accepted this, but
Speaker 22:  I don't, here's why. There was a case filed by Toyota where Judge
Speaker 22:  Daniel issued his decision. It's become very persuasive. I see that
Speaker 22:  cited by other judges. Even judges will say, Hey look, I used to do this,
Speaker 22:  but this has changed my mind. Hmm. We've seen
Speaker 22:  judges with those asset freezes. There's a case Judge
Speaker 22:  Seger issued involving the character Zoro. I love these cites. They're
Speaker 22:  all the most amazing. So in the Zorro case, he kind of
Speaker 22:  identified that sort of turnabout game that plaintiffs were playing with
Speaker 22:  the asset freezes where they say, I'm asking for this, but then I'm gonna
Speaker 22:  get that at the end of the case. And he said, I'm not freezing it, I'm not
Speaker 22:  doing it. I don't believe you anymore. Which again, is pretty extraordinary
Speaker 22:  for a federal judge to just be like, I don't believe you anymore. And we
Speaker 22:  have seen at least one judge start citing that Zoro case more frequently.
Speaker 22:  I believe that the plaintiff's lawyers have been fighting back. I'm not
Speaker 22:  sure exactly how successful they've been. So it does seem like
Speaker 22:  there again, and this is just in the northern district, that there has been
Speaker 22:  some pushback from newer judges,
Speaker 2:  and the email is vergecast at The Verge dot com. We love all your
Speaker 2:  questions and we try to answer at least one on the show every week. So keep
Speaker 2:  'em coming. And today I have Victoria song to help me answer a fun one about
Speaker 2:  AI translator apps.
Speaker 25:  Hey y'all, longtime listener, first time caller. My
Speaker 25:  name's tj. I'm an American currently living between Mexico and Columbia
Speaker 25:  because of my relationship. Shout out to love and Immigration law.
Speaker 25:  So here's my question slash rant slash cry
Speaker 25:  for health. I am a huge user and fan of ai, both
Speaker 25:  in my personal life and professionally, but I still don't
Speaker 25:  have a good real time natural feeling translation tool.
Speaker 25:  My partner's mom And I spend a lot of time together and she doesn't speak
Speaker 25:  English, so I've been relying on chat GPT voice mode, which is
Speaker 25:  genuinely amazing. But Google Translate and Apple
Speaker 25:  translates still feel like robot interns and voice mode, advanced
Speaker 25:  voice mode is pretty limited for like everyday use.
Speaker 25:  So I want something that can do live back and forth, translation reliably,
Speaker 25:  like subtitle, a real conversation, let us actually talk.
Speaker 25:  I've been searching everywhere and I'm almost ready to drop $500 on meta
Speaker 25:  raybans just for the translation feature. But like, do I trust
Speaker 25:  LAMA to handle emotional nuance with this Colombian mom? I do not.
Speaker 25:  So my question is, is there anything out there I'm missing? Are there tools
Speaker 25:  worth trying? Are we or are we still in the almost but
Speaker 25:  not quite territory for live AI translation? I
Speaker 25:  would love your take honestly. Thanks all. Love your pod.
Speaker 2:  Okay. I was thinking about this V And I think we both speak Japanese, so
Speaker 2:  maybe we should just do it in Japanese and have everyone AI translate. Oh
Speaker 2:  my god, just kidding.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, so this is a good duo to tackle this. I
Speaker 2:  personally think, I mean I just have a hard time with any
Speaker 2:  translator things because language is so dynamic. Yes. That it changes
Speaker 2:  day to day, week to week, month to month. And like I have
Speaker 2:  used translator tools for my entire life for various reasons. And
Speaker 2:  like it has never gotten to the point where it can keep up with
Speaker 2:  the way that people speak casually. Naturally. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 2:  Slang. Like just forget about it.
Speaker 26:  Yeah. And I have used a lot of translation tech just because
Speaker 26:  like I like my Japanese pretty decent, my Korean
Speaker 26:  not great. Even though those two languages are quite similar, like almost
Speaker 26:  grammatically, not almost, they are grammatically identical. And
Speaker 26:  a lot of the vocabulary is the same. It's just I'm not great at
Speaker 26:  speaking it, understanding it. I'm Korean Chewbacca in my family just because
Speaker 26:  I speak English, they speak Korean and we understand each other just fine.
Speaker 26:  So to that point, there are times where I have wanted these
Speaker 26:  kinds of tools and so I've tested a bunch of them with my family
Speaker 26:  and I regret to tell you listener, tj,
Speaker 26:  they're not you, you are coming up against what all of them
Speaker 26:  struggle with. Like
Speaker 26:  they just can't handle slang. Yeah. And if Colombian mothers
Speaker 26:  or anything like Korean mothers Yeah. And auntie figures, they
Speaker 26:  do be talking at the speed of light.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And like the precision is so important. Yeah. When you're
Speaker 2:  talking across languages and across cultures and like
Speaker 2:  one thing that I've always found very difficult is, so like
Speaker 2:  I grew up in Japan And I haven't
Speaker 2:  been like living full-time in Japan in a really long time.
Speaker 2:  And so a lot of like my vocabulary in Japanese is almost like
Speaker 2:  stuck in time with the slang or the way that people spoke at the time
Speaker 2:  I last lived there. And that is something that I think no
Speaker 2:  translator app ai or not could ever help me with like that. You
Speaker 2:  need to be actively speaking and engaging with people in
Speaker 2:  this moment to really pick up on the nuance like TJ was
Speaker 2:  asking about.
Speaker 26:  Yeah. There's like so many examples of that. Like my family immigrated from
Speaker 26:  Korea to the US a long ass time, like over 50 years ago at this point.
Speaker 26:  And one thing that I learned growing up with the word for bathroom we called
Speaker 26:  it, which is apparently like ancient colonial times,
Speaker 26:  still living under Japan Wow. Levels for the word
Speaker 26:  bathroom. Yeah. And I was just like, oh, I didn't know that. Yeah. And that
Speaker 26:  explains why when I went back to visit family And I was like, oh,
Speaker 26:  they were like, do you mean which is the actual
Speaker 2:  Oh, interesting. Like
Speaker 26:  The actual word for it. So you know is, is a
Speaker 26:  translator gonna be able to handle skippity toilet? That's my, that's my
Speaker 26:  example that I use all
Speaker 2:  The time. That's a litmus test. That's a
Speaker 26:  Litmus test because those are the things, and I remember when I
Speaker 26:  was in high school and taking Japanese, my Japanese teacher was losing her
Speaker 26:  mind because of the slang that the Japanese kids were using, which was
Speaker 26:  kuru because she's like, that means to turn. Mm.
Speaker 2:  Right,
Speaker 26:  Right. And and apparently no, it meant teens were saying we're going to
Speaker 26:  McDonald's.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That's so interesting. So
Speaker 26:  It's, it's, it's like these things where
Speaker 2:  It's really hard. But I do think TJ, that you maybe are in
Speaker 2:  the perfect situation in real life to get
Speaker 2:  over some of these shortcomings with like the tech
Speaker 2:  option. Like in my opinion, when you are trying to speak with, you
Speaker 2:  know, your partner's family, like that's a great time to
Speaker 2:  ask about the nuance. I assume that you probably have some language capabilities,
Speaker 2:  but you know, maybe you use that opportunity to be like, you said
Speaker 2:  this word and I'm not quite following. Like can you help me understand what
Speaker 2:  it means? I actually had a great time doing this with some friends from Japan
Speaker 2:  who were visiting the last couple years. Like they would teach me all of
Speaker 2:  the new things that the kids were saying, like even younger than we are.
Speaker 2:  And they're like, I don't really know where it comes from, but this is what
Speaker 2:  the kids are saying. Like the tech is never gonna keep up with that. No.
Speaker 2:  But If you have people around you who can explain that context and explain
Speaker 2:  the meaning, like that's golden. That's a great opportunity.
Speaker 26:  Also, If you are living between Mexico and Columbia, that's like a great
Speaker 26:  chance to be immersed in that and you can use the tech to kind of
Speaker 26:  help you learn certain things while you're getting up to speed.
Speaker 26:  I think at the level where the tech is now, it's very friendly
Speaker 26:  for people who are tourists. It's not really useful in family situations.
Speaker 26:  It's not necessarily useful in any situation other than, I
Speaker 26:  dunno how to read a menu. Yeah. But you kind of can't just
Speaker 26:  scan it to read a menu and then not learn what the words are
Speaker 26:  because y you know, I've used the translation feature
Speaker 26:  for Spanish actually on the meta ray bands and it
Speaker 26:  couldn't handle slang. One, it couldn't handle slang. And then
Speaker 26:  If you, we were, I was speaking with someone who was fluent in Spanish and
Speaker 26:  English and if we were switching back because it was just easier for them
Speaker 26:  to explain something in English. I had John Cena's voice because
Speaker 26:  you can, you can make the meta AI sound like John Cena and why not Life
Speaker 26:  is short.
Speaker 2:  That seems distracting, have
Speaker 26:  Fun. You do hear them in your ear at the same time and you're having that
Speaker 26:  problem. So
Speaker 26:  I think it's okay in a pinch if you're going around town and you just really
Speaker 26:  need help for, I don't know how much this costs, can you tell me how much
Speaker 26:  this costs? Like those things the translation can handle
Speaker 26:  every day, like bonding and getting to know someone. These
Speaker 26:  things can't really do it. And If you use it as a crutch, I think you're
Speaker 26:  arguably missing out on connecting with your partner's mother. So I
Speaker 2:  Think a lot of people who are speaking with a non-native speaker actually
Speaker 2:  love explaining Yeah. Words. Another thing I was just thinking about
Speaker 2:  here is like, there is a lot in Japan and Japanese that is
Speaker 2:  very reference heavy. Like If you watch Japanese television, like
Speaker 2:  late night shows or whatever, there are so many references that like, I
Speaker 2:  don't, even if I had a subtitle machine, I don't even think it would be helpful.
Speaker 26:  Yeah. It's like I almost, you know, in college I had a, I had a
Speaker 26:  two second dream that I was gonna be a translator. And
Speaker 2:  Then same, I think that's just like, yeah, canonical
Speaker 26:  A thing,
Speaker 2:  Weird idea that we have at some point,
Speaker 26:  For whatever reason I was like, yeah, I'm gonna be a translator. And then
Speaker 26:  it was like, oh my god, I don't, 'cause when you have the subtitles, you
Speaker 26:  actually have a character limit as to what you're gonna say. Right. So you
Speaker 26:  were gonna lose out on all the context and the nuance there. And you know,
Speaker 26:  Japanese and Korean are both, I think, high context languages. So to your
Speaker 26:  point, everything's referential and it's about what's not being said and
Speaker 26:  there's no AI that's gonna be able to like, you know, if someone
Speaker 26:  goes Mm,
Speaker 26:  they're saying no,
Speaker 2:  Like
Speaker 26:  There there's some like,
Speaker 2:  You know what I mean? It's like, it's not what it means really.
Speaker 26:  It's not, it's not what that means or it's just like, I, I think my favorite
Speaker 26:  video about how weird Japanese can be is like all the things that
Speaker 26:  dejavu can mean.
Speaker 2:  So true.
Speaker 26:  It's just like, oh
Speaker 26:  yeah.
Speaker 2:  Right, right.
Speaker 26:  It just like, it all means different things. Yeah. So like
Speaker 26:  Spanish is not the same and each language has its nuances. But
Speaker 26:  yeah, if, If you were gonna try something, there is something called Time
Speaker 26:  kettle there. I, I keep, I know all of this And I keep going, well maybe
Speaker 26:  this one will be different. So I got a pair of time kettle earbuds.
Speaker 26:  I'll try it. We'll see. But
Speaker 26:  don't rob yourself the, the chance of fumbling through all the
Speaker 26:  funny things that will happen. Yeah. Due in this translation
Speaker 26:  with your Colombian
Speaker 2:  Mom. Once you make some of these mistakes, you'll never forget it. You know
Speaker 2:  what I mean? You'll never forget what's right. Oh
Speaker 26:  God. There's so many things in language learning. Like I will never forget
Speaker 26:  Hmm.
Speaker 2:  Japanese
Speaker 26:  And because it was like a, an example that my very enthusiastic
Speaker 26:  Japanese teacher was like, how would you read this kanji to this advanced
Speaker 26:  group, group of Japanese leaders of readers and in college? And we were
Speaker 26:  like, KU beautiful person office. No,
Speaker 26:  it's, it's a badger game. And she's like, it's,
Speaker 26:  it's not read in any way. That makes sense. It's so weird. And it's a badger
Speaker 2:  Game. It's such a weird language.
Speaker 26:  It's, yeah. Yeah. Don't rob yourself of finding all the weird
Speaker 26:  crap. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Agree.
Speaker 26:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Thanks so much for your question TJ, and thanks V for helping me answer this
Speaker 2:  one. Okay. That's it for The Vergecast today. Thanks to
Speaker 2:  everyone on the show today, and thank you for listening. There is a whole
Speaker 2:  lot more stuff from this conversation at The Verge dot com. We'll put some
Speaker 2:  links in the show notes, but also read The Verge dot com. Maybe even subscribe,
Speaker 2:  you can find our bylines, how you find everything online.
Speaker 2:  As always, If you have thoughts, questions, feelings, you can always email
Speaker 2:  us at vergecast at The Verge dot com or keep calling the
Speaker 2:  hotline. 8 6 6 VERGE 11. We love hearing
Speaker 2:  from you. Send us all your thoughts and questions and ideas for what we should
Speaker 2:  do on the show. We do a hotline question every week, so keep 'em coming.
Speaker 2:  Call in This show is produced by Eric Gomez, Brandon Kiefer, Travis
Speaker 2:  EK and Andrew Marino. The Vergecast is The Verge production and part of the
Speaker 2:  Vox Media podcast network. Jake will be back on Friday to discuss all the
Speaker 2:  news from the week. Goodbye. See you next time.