# Transcript
ID: 253f98e9-880e-4288-83fd-993e7290be7f
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-2404514500561876621/7808890865273370307/s93290-US-3198s-1754823082.mp3
Description: In this bonus episode of The Vergecast, Senior Reviewer Victoria Song sits down with a bunch of Verge staffers to talk about how they use AI tools in their everyday lives. Not all of it went smoothly — we definitely get into the ways these tools fall short — but we explore how AI can be used to help bedtime go more smoothly for parents, plan big cross-country moves, supplement your internet searches (always double-check!), and even vibe code an app for your next tabletop role-playing game.
If you have any examples where AI was useful to you, we’d love to hear them. (For what it’s worth, we’d also love to hear stories where it spectacularly failed.) Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (10 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of testing
Speaker 2:  cursed technology. I'm your friend V song and I'm here
Speaker 2:  with a special Sunday bonus episode. Yay.
Speaker 2:  We're calling this AI for Normies. So
Speaker 2:  here's the concept. AI can be so open-ended, it's
Speaker 2:  really hard for the average person to know what it's good for.
Speaker 2:  And if you ask me, I don't think big tech is doing
Speaker 2:  such a great job at explaining that either. But
Speaker 2:  we here at The Verge dot com are a bunch of giant
Speaker 2:  nerds and we test all of this stuff for a living. So I've asked
Speaker 2:  a bunch of my colleagues to join me in talking about how they've used AI
Speaker 2:  in their everyday lives. And I'm not talking about the canned
Speaker 2:  demo examples that you hear at product launches that
Speaker 2:  don't actually seem all that useful in real life.
Speaker 2:  I wanted to know what they found to be actually helpful. And I
Speaker 2:  also wanted to know what doesn't work. We have a
Speaker 2:  mix of practical applications, some quirky ideas, and
Speaker 2:  personally I think my main use
Speaker 2:  is a little unhinged. So stick around for
Speaker 2:  The Vergecast and we'll see you after the break.
Speaker 2:  So Esther Cohen is our director of subscriptions at The Verge and she
Speaker 2:  recently used chat GT to help gather the information she needed before making
Speaker 2:  a really big decision.
Speaker 3:  So as of last week, our family of four made the really,
Speaker 3:  really big change of moving from New York City,
Speaker 3:  upper West side in New York City to Miami Beach
Speaker 3:  in Florida.
Speaker 2:  Moving is really tough. I moved not a couple of years
Speaker 2:  ago to New Jersey And I never wanna do it again.
Speaker 2:  I never wanna move ever again. I probably will, but you know, it's
Speaker 2:  really tough. It's really hard. And you said that
Speaker 2:  you were using AI to help you figure
Speaker 2:  out how to manage this logistical nightmare.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, so I use the, I found myself using AI
Speaker 3:  surprisingly a lot for my move in terms
Speaker 3:  of planning, finding out information, finding
Speaker 3:  out kind of how things work locally. 'cause when you're moving to a new state
Speaker 3:  and a new city, like the way things work are just totally different.
Speaker 3:  But I would say the most helpful and surprising way in which I used AI
Speaker 3:  for this move was actually for budgeting. Specifically when you
Speaker 3:  move from Manhattan, New York to Florida,
Speaker 3:  your taxes are extremely different.
Speaker 3:  And things like how much utilities cost,
Speaker 3:  how much gas costs, how much traffic there is
Speaker 3:  during the day in your commute. And so calculating how many miles
Speaker 3:  your car lease should have,
Speaker 3:  I was like hanging out with Chad GPT all day asking those questions.
Speaker 3:  So I was very surprised. I surprised myself
Speaker 3:  by how much I used it every
Speaker 2:  Day. So one of, one of the things was AI that you know, people
Speaker 2:  have trouble with is having to double check that information. Did you find
Speaker 2:  that it's so far, I know, I know you just moved, so some of this
Speaker 2:  will bear out over time. Did you find that those calculations were
Speaker 2:  realistic? Were you worried about double checking stuff? Yeah,
Speaker 3:  So I'll take an example. Like basically figuring
Speaker 3:  out what our new salaries and take home pay was gonna be given the new tax
Speaker 3:  situation. So I did a lot of Chad GPT prompting of
Speaker 3:  like, if I make this much before taxes
Speaker 3:  And I live in Bow Harbor, Miami,
Speaker 3:  Florida And I am withholding as a single
Speaker 3:  or whatever information, I input, what's my take home pay gonna be.
Speaker 3:  The first few times I did different versions of that. I did double check
Speaker 3:  just to make sure, but part of why I leaned into GGPT
Speaker 3:  was because
Speaker 3:  I find doing math that is like related to different facts
Speaker 3:  and like tax rules extremely, extremely daunting and overwhelming.
Speaker 3:  So I, before I even get to the math, I'm like, do I even have the setup right?
Speaker 3:  So I found JGPT super helpful 'cause all I did was feed it like my,
Speaker 3:  what I needed to know. And then it did all that math for me. It explained
Speaker 3:  all that math for me and I'm happy to report we just got our
Speaker 3:  first or second paycheck as a family with
Speaker 3:  based in Florida and the math pretty much
Speaker 3:  checked out down to the cent. So this is not a CHA
Speaker 3:  GPT endorsement, but for tax and budget and
Speaker 3:  salary planning, it was very accurate and helpful.
Speaker 2:  Would you say that this was basically kind of
Speaker 2:  making your life a lot easier as far as like pre-planning
Speaker 2:  the move, but also were there any things that you
Speaker 2:  tried to pre to like use chat GPT for your move that didn't
Speaker 2:  work out and you were like, Ooh, this is not what, what I should be using
Speaker 2:  AI for?
Speaker 3:  Yeah, so I would say great question. So it did make
Speaker 3:  my life a lot easier because I got to a couple dead ends where I would've
Speaker 3:  had to, to like hire an accountant for example, to figure things out for
Speaker 3:  me. And I was able to just like chat GP t it up and that was
Speaker 3:  like an expense saved and time saved and kind of like
Speaker 3:  having to hire one more service or one more person like that got taken off
Speaker 3:  the plate and that was really helpful. Where it was not helpful was
Speaker 3:  for, I found for shopping around or getting estimates of things.
Speaker 3:  So like I wanted to figure out, a thing that would've
Speaker 3:  been extremely helpful for me was like what's the the right car
Speaker 3:  for us given the kind of size that we need our budget. And
Speaker 3:  also thinking about what the cost to insure it is. So again,
Speaker 3:  this is moving and car rabbit hole, but sometimes even
Speaker 3:  if a car lease is cheaper, it'll be more expensive to insure it if it's not
Speaker 3:  as as safe of a car or if, or sometimes like crossovers are cheaper to insure
Speaker 3:  than sedans. So I would've loved for chat you to tell me, okay, get
Speaker 3:  this particular car model because even though the lease will be a little
Speaker 3:  more, the insurance will go down. So it sucked at that. It did not gimme
Speaker 3:  accurate like lease pricing. It did not gimme accurate insurance pricing.
Speaker 3:  I had to get on the phone with the insurance broker and like figure all that
Speaker 3:  out and call all different insurance comp companies before I got to the right
Speaker 3:  one. So it was really, really bad at that. Same with movers, like I wanted
Speaker 3:  to get a sense of like how much will it cost to move a family of four in
Speaker 3:  a three bedroom apartment from Manhattan to Florida. And
Speaker 3:  it did a lot of like basic Google answers. Like
Speaker 3:  it could be anywhere between $6,000 and $27,000 depending on the
Speaker 3:  following factors. So I did not find it
Speaker 3:  helpful when it came to shopping arounds. That would've been really nice
Speaker 3:  if I could have had more help with that.
Speaker 2:  Another question I had is like how long did it take you to kind of figure
Speaker 2:  out that, oh this is something like this is something that I can
Speaker 2:  do, here's how I ask the AI the appropriate
Speaker 2:  prompts to kind of get the answers that I need. 'cause I found that like
Speaker 2:  when I am experimenting or using with different AI models, like
Speaker 2:  the, the real key is learning how to ask the question
Speaker 2:  correctly. And I spend a, I spent a lot of time in the beginning while
Speaker 2:  testing, just learning how to ask the question. So I'm just curious
Speaker 2:  how long that took you to kind of get in the groove.
Speaker 3:  It took me a minute to figure out what the right way to approach this was
Speaker 3:  with chat GPTI did a lot of like explain to me how
Speaker 3:  taxes in Florida work kind of prompts in the beginning and those
Speaker 3:  were other failures and did not get me the info that I needed. I thought
Speaker 3:  I could get the tools to do the math myself. And then I finally realized,
Speaker 3:  oh, what if this, I really just treated like an accountant and
Speaker 3:  I'm like, here's how much I'm making. Here's my paperwork,
Speaker 3:  figure out how much I'm gonna take home every month. Once I did that And
Speaker 3:  I figured out I, I can literally redo my prompt. It was like, if I make x
Speaker 3:  amount of money and have this many dependents and live
Speaker 3:  in my neighborhood, how much take home pay? Will I
Speaker 3:  bring every paycheck or something? And it literally
Speaker 3:  was able to do the math, explain to me what all the different like
Speaker 3:  deductions and with sorry withholdings are, lay that all out
Speaker 3:  for me and then give me a yearly amount and a monthly amount. So that was
Speaker 3:  amazing, but it did take me a minute to get there. 'cause I, I think as someone
Speaker 3:  who is a collaborator and likes to figure things out on my own,
Speaker 3:  my first approach was like, okay, let me ask Chad GPT for the tools to figure
Speaker 3:  this out. And it took me a few steps before I was like, no, the
Speaker 3:  whole point is that I don't want the tools. I want Chad GPT to
Speaker 3:  do the figuring out for me. Once I did that, it was smooth sailing.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it's, it's, it's sort of like a, a catch
Speaker 2:  22 because you have to know what you want, but you're also trying to
Speaker 2:  go in without knowing what you want and figure these things out. So like
Speaker 2:  I find that I spin wheels a lot of times when I'm trying to, trying to really
Speaker 2:  get my answers. So then if you could do this move all over again,
Speaker 2:  or if you have, if we have listeners out there who are,
Speaker 2:  you know, on The Verge of a move, do you have any advice
Speaker 2:  for them?
Speaker 3:  If you need to lay something out very clearly
Speaker 3:  before making a decision to move, like whether it's your budget for moving,
Speaker 3:  what your new salary is gonna be, any kind of
Speaker 3:  logistical problem that you're trying to solve as your decision making, g
Speaker 3:  pcha, gp PT is your friend. I find sometimes when we're making a really,
Speaker 3:  really big,
Speaker 3:  daunting life decision, what I personally struggle with
Speaker 3:  is when there's so many moving pieces before you can even
Speaker 3:  make the decision. Like, so like I, I personally really
Speaker 3:  struggle with like the whole, there's so much to figure out before we even
Speaker 3:  do the thing of it all, that it's actually been really,
Speaker 3:  really nice to have a tool that like
Speaker 3:  got rid of I would say three quarters of that, right? Like
Speaker 3:  there isn't that much to figure out. We can figure it out with our computer
Speaker 3:  and like with a glass of wine in two hours. I can do a lot of that like
Speaker 3:  figuring out like the groundwork before actually having to
Speaker 3:  make a decision or do the big thing. And that was like personally
Speaker 3:  and like emotionally a huge, a huge crutch and a huge
Speaker 3:  help for me.
Speaker 2:  I love that. Thank you so much. I'm how, how far are you along? Are you on
Speaker 2:  unpacking? Are we, are we like 10% of the way there? 0%
Speaker 2:  of the way? There we're
Speaker 3:  Like 3% of the way there.
Speaker 2:  I mean, I, I moved over a year ago And
Speaker 2:  I think 18 months ago maybe. And I'm still somewhat
Speaker 2:  unpacking, so yeah. Yeah, that's just how it goes,
Speaker 2:  g Godspeed. Good luck and all right, thanks Esther.
Speaker 2:  Thanks
Speaker 3:  V Love talking to you. Bye.
Speaker 2:  Next up Allison Johnson is our senior smartphone
Speaker 2:  reviewer, which means she's had to test a lot of different AI
Speaker 2:  assistance over the last two years. Here's what she found most useful.
Speaker 2:  Definitely my favorite,
Speaker 4:  Like, and it's not even close, is using
Speaker 4:  AI to put stuff on calendars. I don't know how it's possible
Speaker 4:  to be bad at calendars, but I am bad at doing
Speaker 4:  calendars. If there's like a way to mess up putting something on a
Speaker 4:  calendar, I will do it. Like without fail, I'll put something on the wrong
Speaker 4:  day or
Speaker 4:  the wrong calendar. And my husband's like, what are you talking about? You
Speaker 4:  don't have an appointment this weekend? I'm like, actually I do. So the bar
Speaker 4:  is already really low. I think that's important that like AI
Speaker 4:  really can't mess this up more than I am already messing it up.
Speaker 4:  So it's the perfect candidate for like a
Speaker 4:  BAI can do this. This has been something that's been like in the
Speaker 4:  works with Gemini on Android phones for a while.
Speaker 4:  And
Speaker 4:  I like, to be honest, the first like
Speaker 4:  few weeks, maybe a month, I tried it, it like consistently
Speaker 4:  got stuff wrong and like would insist that I
Speaker 4:  was leaving. I had a flight out of the wrong airport And
Speaker 4:  I was like ready to give up on this whole concept, but it's, I don't know
Speaker 4:  what they did, they did something behind the scenes. It works, it like
Speaker 4:  works so well
Speaker 4:  that I am just like never gonna
Speaker 4:  do my own calendar again. I think on an Android
Speaker 4:  phone you'll like summon Gemini and you
Speaker 4:  tap something that says ask about this screen and then if
Speaker 4:  there's it, it'll kind of like take a screenshot and it looks for dates and
Speaker 4:  stuff. And if this sounds like
Speaker 4:  did we need AI to do that?
Speaker 4:  Yes and no. It'll, it, it's really smart actually.
Speaker 4:  It'll ask you like follow up questions about what's on the screen.
Speaker 4:  It can sort out like time zones,
Speaker 4:  like it will, will put something on my calendar
Speaker 4:  for the correct Eastern time time zone
Speaker 4:  and that that'll be reflected. So it's like, it's
Speaker 4:  the ideal kind of like AI tool I think where
Speaker 4:  it's, it's sort of low stakes. I wasn't doing it
Speaker 4:  great to begin with and it's pretty easy.
Speaker 4:  So I, that's like my first AI on
Speaker 4:  a phone thing where I'm like, yes, a hundred percent I want this and
Speaker 4:  I'm going to keep using it for the rest of time.
Speaker 2:  And so this is like android, Android phones only. There's
Speaker 2:  no hope for us on iOS yet.
Speaker 4:  There is Hope iOS has it. It is an Apple intelligence
Speaker 4:  feature. It's like pretty good.
Speaker 4:  I would say not as good as Gemini. It doesn't do the like follow
Speaker 4:  up questions. It did get tripped up on a time zone
Speaker 4:  thing once. But again, if the bar is
Speaker 4:  very low for you and it is for me, it's like
Speaker 4:  something to start with. And then you, you fix a couple things and
Speaker 4:  and you usually get there.
Speaker 2:  So like what's been most useful for you in terms of like these calendar
Speaker 2:  adding, is it like flights? Is it, I don't know, I
Speaker 2:  don't have kids, but I have been told by parents that
Speaker 2:  kids schedules are absolutely banana bonkers
Speaker 2:  appointments is everything, like is there a particular thing
Speaker 2:  that this calendar AI Magic is, is best for?
Speaker 4:  It is a hundred percent the kids stuff And I didn't fully
Speaker 4:  grasp it until you have a kid in school or like my kid's in
Speaker 4:  daycare. But it's like a preschool program and you'll get an email
Speaker 4:  with the most insane list of dates and
Speaker 4:  it's like crazy Hair day is Friday and it like, the
Speaker 4:  information will not be complete. You know, it's like Raptor
Speaker 4:  visit on such and such day, wear
Speaker 4:  your pajamas to school on this day and going through
Speaker 4:  all those things and adding on a calendar manually is a
Speaker 4:  nightmare. And also it sucks if you send your kid to pajama day and they're
Speaker 4:  not wearing pajamas. Like, it's so sad. But this is like
Speaker 4:  a thousand percent the best use case for it. 'cause you do the
Speaker 4:  screenshot, it scans the whole thing and it's like, I
Speaker 4:  added all this to your calendar and then, then your kid isn't like
Speaker 4:  sad when they show up on crazy hair day. But to be
Speaker 4:  fair, my kid has crazy hair day every day. So we're covered there,
Speaker 2:  But my immigrant parents would've been like, you're not doing that. Just
Speaker 2:  be sad. So like,
Speaker 4:  Yeah, maybe I'm depriving him of like a learning
Speaker 4:  experience where it's like, well sometimes you don't do crazy
Speaker 4:  hair day on the right day. But for the most part
Speaker 4:  I think it's been good for everybody.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Is there anything else that you found particularly useful?
Speaker 4:  We were having like the worst time with
Speaker 4:  kid bedtime. This is a thing that happens throughout like early
Speaker 4:  parenthood. Like kids sleeps great. You're like,
Speaker 4:  this is amazing. I can read a book and like relax at night and then
Speaker 4:  all of a sudden it goes completely off the rails and you're like
Speaker 4:  negotiating every little tiny thing and you're like, please, dear God,
Speaker 4:  I just, I need this hour to myself. So I was like
Speaker 4:  kind of desperate And I went to the, to the AI
Speaker 4:  And I was like, describe the situation we're having his age. And like,
Speaker 4:  I was like, get help me out. Like what can we do? And it goes and
Speaker 4:  finds whatever relevant like things on Reddit, there are like,
Speaker 4:  it's, it's always Reddit, like there's so many parenting things on
Speaker 4:  Reddit, but it kind of like brought it all back and was like, you
Speaker 4:  could try this, this, and this. And I was like, okay, I wanna
Speaker 4:  try this thing and this thing. Can you put this all together
Speaker 4:  in a a a I called it a playbook
Speaker 4:  'cause like I needed to communicate it to my husband and right.
Speaker 4:  He, he will get overwhelmed if I just kind of sit down.
Speaker 4:  I'm like, we're doing this thing. He has two passes, he can use the passes.
Speaker 4:  We sit for five minutes and the, you know, it's like so
Speaker 4:  convoluted, but it spit it all, it, it like
Speaker 4:  explained everything. There were subheads. It was very
Speaker 4:  like logical.
Speaker 4:  And the funniest thing is the thing it could not
Speaker 4:  do. I was like, great, can you put this in a Google doc for me? And
Speaker 4:  I was like, I'm sorry, I can't,
Speaker 4:  I don't
Speaker 2:  Understand. It's your Gemini though. I know.
Speaker 4:  I'm like, this is the Google
Speaker 2:  Platform.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like I have all the little like plugins for all the,
Speaker 4:  I don't know why it couldn't do a Google Doc, but it literally was like,
Speaker 4:  you can use command, you know, v or whatever, like
Speaker 4:  copy and paste it and it the, I was like, okay,
Speaker 4:  don't explain copying and pasting to me machine.
Speaker 4:  But the, the kicker is like, this honestly
Speaker 4:  did work. Like it's, it's probably a little more complicated
Speaker 4:  than it needs to be. And we've, we've like tweaked the system a little
Speaker 4:  bit. But like, I sent my husband the playbook, he
Speaker 4:  read it like we, we went into
Speaker 4:  bedtime, like just ready. We were like a united
Speaker 4:  front and, and it has worked. So
Speaker 4:  did, did Gemini just like read a bunch of Reddit
Speaker 4:  threads back to me and like format it probably.
Speaker 4:  Do I feel good about that? I don't, I'm not a hundred percent sure
Speaker 4:  but like I, I need that kid to go to sleep
Speaker 4:  and that has happened. So I, I'm like, well, alright,
Speaker 2:  My real life bedtime story AI thing was like, for a while
Speaker 2:  I was just like really struggling to fall asleep. So my
Speaker 2:  spouse actually was just asking AI to generate
Speaker 2:  bedtime stories for me. Like I was a child. That's
Speaker 2:  a adorable, just like based on our family.
Speaker 2:  So like, aw, they generated a story about
Speaker 2:  my cat Pete becoming a cult leader and how
Speaker 2:  Pablo our other cat brought upon his downfall.
Speaker 2:  And I don't know what prompt they used, but it was
Speaker 2:  like kind of good. And
Speaker 4:  Oh my God,
Speaker 2:  If I were to like try and publish the story, I wouldn't because it's just
Speaker 2:  so hyper specific. But if I just needed like a quick really
Speaker 2:  funny bedtime story to listen to for
Speaker 2:  myself to fall asleep,
Speaker 2:  we've actually kind of done that every once in a while and
Speaker 2:  just been like, oh my gosh. Absolutely shocked. So yeah,
Speaker 2:  it was like, forget the title of it, it, but it was just like, PD
Speaker 2:  starts a cult was the title And I was the number
Speaker 2:  one cult follower. I didn't use any critical thinking, oh my in this AI story.
Speaker 2:  And I was like, oh, that's actually quite accurate. Pablo, our other
Speaker 2:  cat would be the one to what? Like what is,
Speaker 4:  What is a cat if not a cult leader, where
Speaker 2:  They like, yeah. So you
Speaker 4:  Do their bidding, they're a little bit evil.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean like ideally it would, would it have meant more if my spouse
Speaker 2:  had actually written that story and, and like
Speaker 2:  presented it? Yes, but I needed, I am the child in this
Speaker 2:  scenario.
Speaker 4:  I needed oh gosh,
Speaker 2:  To go to bed right away. So they just like whipped it up
Speaker 2:  and that was like a good running saga for a week.
Speaker 2:  And I was like, yeah,
Speaker 4:  I love that.
Speaker 2:  This is actually kind of cute and adorable. So, you know, I wish just, I
Speaker 2:  would
Speaker 4:  A hundred percent read Pete the cult leader, by the way.
Speaker 2:  I'll see if I can get the transcript because that was please,
Speaker 2:  that was truly just fundamentally the most,
Speaker 2:  I, you know, I actually almost didn't go to bed. I was laughing so hard.
Speaker 2:  Right?
Speaker 4:  That's the danger. It was.
Speaker 2:  That is the danger. But we're just trying to help people go to bed,
Speaker 2:  help their kids go to bed. We just want some rest.
Speaker 4:  We all just want some rest.
Speaker 2:  That's, that's all we want. Thank you Allison. I I'm sure the
Speaker 2:  parents will now have some other tools in their arsenal.
Speaker 4:  Please. Yeah, message me on threads. We'll, we'll brainstorm, we'll bring
Speaker 4:  Gemini into it. Yeah, we, we'll get through it together.
Speaker 2:  So we're gonna go to break and when we come back, Jake will tell me his
Speaker 2:  tips for how to best use AI for search. 'cause you
Speaker 2:  know, AI sometimes do be lying. See you soon.
Speaker 2:  We are back. So it's pretty hard to search for anything on the web these
Speaker 2:  days without an AI large language model butting in and telling
Speaker 2:  you to put glue on pizza or something like that. Jake Kakis is our
Speaker 2:  executive editor and he's been figuring out how to use AI
Speaker 2:  to help him find actually accurate information.
Speaker 2:  A thing that I thought could not be done
Speaker 13:  Well for one, I it is actually changing how
Speaker 13:  I search online. You know, I think for good reason people are are very skeptical
Speaker 13:  of using Chachi, BT or Gemini as a search engine, right? Sometimes it's
Speaker 13:  wrong. It is. That is In fact very true. But one thing that's interesting
Speaker 13:  is that over the years I've heard Google executives saying like, oh, you
Speaker 13:  know, all all these kids, all these people who, who grew up smartphone first,
Speaker 13:  you know, they, they don't, they don't search the same way all of us do,
Speaker 13:  right? And I, I'm in my mid thirties, I think anybody, you know, my age,
Speaker 13:  anybody who's been using Google for, for decades, when, when you do a search,
Speaker 13:  right, you, you're very precise and specific, right? You, you enter a couple
Speaker 13:  keywords to get exactly what you want, right? If, if you want to figure
Speaker 13:  out how much RAM the iPhone 16 has you, you just type in iPhone
Speaker 13:  16 ram, you're not gonna type out that whole question. They's a bunch of
Speaker 13:  extra words, they're gonna get filtered out. They might, you know,
Speaker 13:  pull up search results you don't want with chat CB t it, you really do
Speaker 13:  just type in the question. And that allows you to get more specific
Speaker 13:  and get nuances that you wouldn't be able to get. And, and this might, okay,
Speaker 13:  my example right now is one that I use for work, but I think it, it, it
Speaker 13:  shows what these tools can do in a way that a normal search engine couldn't.
Speaker 13:  So recently we covered that Reddit says it wants to become a search engine,
Speaker 13:  right? That's like, that's really weird. That's a big idea. And so
Speaker 13:  I wanted to make sure, okay, has Reddit said before that it wants to become
Speaker 13:  a search engine? So I went to Google, right, typed in Reddit search
Speaker 13:  engine. Well that's not a very good search because
Speaker 13:  number one it it, first off you just get a ton of results of
Speaker 13:  of from Reddit, right? All the results are from Reddit about search engines.
Speaker 13:  Okay, well so now you gotta, you gotta know how to filter out Reddit searches.
Speaker 13:  That's easy. So I filter out Reddit searches. Now it's just a bunch of stories
Speaker 13:  about how everybody's using the Google hack where you just type in Reddit
Speaker 13:  to your search, right? Okay. So because the, the, the keyword
Speaker 13:  search is, is too messy, there's too many results, I
Speaker 13:  can't actually find what I need here. So I go to chat GBT to see, okay,
Speaker 13:  can it find this for me? So I type in, hey, I'm looking for examples of
Speaker 13:  Reddit, the company or its executives saying that they
Speaker 13:  want the company to be seen as or operate
Speaker 13:  like a search engine.
Speaker 13:  And that's like pretty specific, right? And it's able to sort through
Speaker 13:  all of that and it came back to me with a bunch of results and it says,
Speaker 13:  okay, Reddit hasn't said it wants to become a search engine,
Speaker 13:  but here are some similar quotes from
Speaker 13:  executives where they're saying things about how
Speaker 13:  Reddit's thinking about search or how search is a valuable opportunity.
Speaker 13:  And so it's able to, you know, sift through all these
Speaker 13:  other stories that are irrelevant, but have the right keywords and find
Speaker 13:  the specific things. Now here's the trick, right? Everybody's worried about
Speaker 13:  AI being wrong, right? And I think when it comes to quotations,
Speaker 13:  that's an area where AI is really likely to make stuff up. And so
Speaker 13:  particularly for our jobs, we have to make sure everything is correct. And
Speaker 13:  so fortunately, you know, now CH A BT does the thing where it
Speaker 13:  will give you web links. So I clicked through these and in this case they
Speaker 13:  were all right. And so that was fantastic, that was really useful. And I
Speaker 13:  was able to use this to help me suss out whether they had made claims like
Speaker 13:  this before. I will say as a counter example, I tried a very
Speaker 13:  similar thing when Apple said, okay, we're gonna make all
Speaker 13:  of the glass for the iPhones in the us. And I was
Speaker 13:  like, okay, Che GBT, how much of
Speaker 13:  the glass is already made in the us? And it just, it just
Speaker 13:  made up a quote, it just made up a quote for me. Yeah, right. So you gotta
Speaker 13:  check. You have to check. But I think it's the same thing with right, with
Speaker 13:  Google where you have to have the skillset.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, no, this is like a super interesting example because I have a much
Speaker 2:  sillier problem that really mirrors what you were saying. Like,
Speaker 2:  so I have been watching Law and Order SVU because I found
Speaker 2:  out my spouse had never seen an episode of Law and Order recently. And I
Speaker 2:  was like, what this is
Speaker 13:  Are there are like 900, there's
Speaker 2:  Like 20 thou, there's 24 or 25 seasons of
Speaker 2:  law and order. S-V-U-I-I actually wasn't aware that
Speaker 2:  it was still going, but we started watching it and you know,
Speaker 2:  he had seen clips before and he is like, I did ice, does ice tea
Speaker 2:  always have a ponytail in, in law and order
Speaker 2:  SVU. And I was like, well, you know, he changes up his, look, I don't recall
Speaker 2:  him wearing suits all the time either in the first season.
Speaker 2:  'cause I think normally he wears something more like a leather jacket. So
Speaker 2:  I went into Google And I was like, when does ice tea lose the ponytail in
Speaker 2:  SVU? I got nothing useful.
Speaker 2:  And then I was like, okay, let me try the Reddit thing. Let me see if there's
Speaker 2:  a Reddit community that talks about it. All I found were Reddit's voting
Speaker 2:  on whether they like bald ice tea or ponytail ice
Speaker 2:  tea better. And I could see that there was like some who's winning,
Speaker 2:  it was pretty even. There were like people just who were
Speaker 2:  pro ponytail iced tea, pro bald iced tea. But
Speaker 2:  you know, I wasn't getting a, when does he he change his look thing? So I
Speaker 2:  went to perplexity because, you know, I'm trying like, like you, I'm testing
Speaker 2:  all these things and perplexity calls itself an AI search engine first. And
Speaker 2:  it told me like the exact season And I was like, oh my God.
Speaker 2:  And there were like links saying the exact season. So I was like, oh, at
Speaker 2:  the end of season three, beginning in season four, that's when he changes
Speaker 2:  his look. That's early. It's very early considering there's 24
Speaker 2:  seasons of this show. But it, it gave
Speaker 2:  me the answer of like exactly when that, that like, I'll, I'll,
Speaker 2:  I'm in season three now, so we'll, we'll see if at the end, at when
Speaker 2:  we switch to season four, whether he becomes bald.
Speaker 2:  But it, it, it, it's a very silly example, but it's, it's kind of what you
Speaker 2:  were referring to.
Speaker 13:  No, I think that's so interesting and, And I think it really speaks to the
Speaker 13:  fact that the types of searches you can do are changing
Speaker 13:  and, And I think that is the big thing to tap into, right? And so
Speaker 13:  I do think there are people who are maybe missing out as a result of,
Speaker 13:  of being too skeptical that
Speaker 13:  AI can be useful. So I actually had another really interesting
Speaker 13:  chat BT use case literally just this past week.
Speaker 13:  Tell me about it. So I've been trying to get work done
Speaker 13:  in my apartment
Speaker 13:  and so I I, I have this big open room And I wanna kind of put up
Speaker 13:  a wall to, to turn it into a bedroom, right? Split it in half, it's a little
Speaker 13:  bedroom, little office. And so I started
Speaker 13:  thinking, okay, let's, let's just chat g PT for ideas.
Speaker 13:  And honestly it was not very helpful, right? I I, I described the
Speaker 13:  project. It, it didn't really, you know, I think it's, it's
Speaker 13:  not great at like giving me image generation that, that is consistent,
Speaker 13:  coherent and makes sense. I already had pretty clear ideas on
Speaker 13:  my own of like where to put this wall. So like it wasn't
Speaker 13:  too complicated. So that didn't really help me. But one thing I
Speaker 13:  did was that you can keep going back to the same chat GBT
Speaker 13:  thread over and over again. And so, you know, I've, I've been, this is something
Speaker 13:  I've been working on for like months at this point and you know,
Speaker 13:  every time I had an idea I would just go back to this thread and, and you
Speaker 13:  know, I don't have anybody to toss these ideas around with, right? Like,
Speaker 13:  I don't have like a professional I can, I can talk to because I need to
Speaker 13:  hire that person.
Speaker 13:  And so I, you know, I would like bounce things back And I, it would gimme
Speaker 13:  some, some ideas to think through. And anyway,
Speaker 13:  I finally got a contractor to work with me
Speaker 13:  about a week ago and the contractor sends over a,
Speaker 13:  a quote, right? And so I paste the quote into
Speaker 13:  chat GBT and it has like a breakdown of all the, all the work this person's
Speaker 13:  supposed to do for me. And I say, Hey, are there any questions I should
Speaker 13:  ask about this? And Chachi BT goes, well
Speaker 13:  it doesn't list the closet that you wanted to add. And that was a mind
Speaker 13:  blowing moment for me because I had told chat bt months ago
Speaker 13:  that I needed to put up a wall to add a closet And I had told the contractor
Speaker 13:  this in person, but in their estimate they, they had forgotten
Speaker 13:  to include that. And it had noticed that
Speaker 13:  they didn't include it And I had missed it. I had missed that the closet
Speaker 13:  wasn't there. And you know, that's like pretty important, right? It is important
Speaker 13:  that we, we have in writing ahead of time the, the work that this
Speaker 13:  person is gonna be doing. And the fact that I had missed it, I, I thought
Speaker 13:  it was like, yeah, that, that really, really sent me for a trip.
Speaker 2:  That gets to another thing that I've been thinking about, like in my testing,
Speaker 2:  which is like the best scenarios I found
Speaker 2:  for AI chatbots is just like
Speaker 2:  thinking of it as me talking to myself in the mirror, but the mirror version
Speaker 2:  of me has like a Google access. Yeah, yeah. And like a,
Speaker 2:  a running list of everything that I said I wanted. So like, I
Speaker 2:  don't know if I believe all of the hype where these
Speaker 2:  big tech companies are like, AI is gonna be your companion. It's gonna be
Speaker 2:  what, like, I I find it more useful when I think of it as like I'm talking
Speaker 2:  to myself because I don't have a sounding board And I need a
Speaker 2:  sounding board. And all the other people in my life who I would use as a
Speaker 2:  sounding board are one tired of hearing me talk about this
Speaker 2:  or too currently unavailable. So like, I
Speaker 2:  like you, I, I have these like different project things that I've been like
Speaker 2:  iterating on, brainstorming on where it's just like, ooh, I don't wanna
Speaker 2:  bother someone just yet 'cause I am going to take
Speaker 2:  something to someone and do a real in life meet person
Speaker 2:  hashing out of ideas. But I wanna go in prepared. I wanna like
Speaker 2:  have thought through the stuff already. I wanna know what questions
Speaker 2:  I should ask or like, have I missed something after like what I said
Speaker 2:  those things. And in that sense it's been pretty
Speaker 2:  useful. Still not useful at times,
Speaker 2:  like in the beginning, which gets to my other issue with AI is that you have
Speaker 2:  to do so much training for it to get to that like little nugget,
Speaker 2:  which is pretty labor intensive, but when it works you're just kind of like,
Speaker 2:  ah, look at that, look
Speaker 13:  At that. No, that's such a good way to think about it. Like I, I I think
Speaker 13:  you're right and it's, it's funny, like I think people get very concerned,
Speaker 13:  rightfully so about like where this is taking away
Speaker 13:  people's, people's jobs. And I think in these cases, like
Speaker 13:  it really is just talking to myself. It's, it in a lot of ways it's, it's
Speaker 13:  like talking to, yeah, it's, you're right. It's like talking to myself with
Speaker 13:  Google who's just able to spit stuff back at me. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I wish we talked about this kind of way to use AI more instead of like
Speaker 2:  the, I get why companies do the flashy marquee versions, but
Speaker 2:  this I feel like is more useful framing,
Speaker 13:  I will say there's a limit to this. There are also those stories of the
Speaker 13:  people who like go off the deep end and like, chat GBT
Speaker 13:  told me I can run through a wall. And you're like, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 13:  Yeah, no, no. Like, you still gotta still
Speaker 13:  have to like use all of your like, good judgment and instincts here
Speaker 13:  if you use it rationally. I think there are actually some like very
Speaker 13:  like simple ways it can kind of, you know,
Speaker 13:  just make you more productive or
Speaker 13:  able to think through things a little bit more clearly. It's not like I,
Speaker 13:  I would've not been able to accomplish these things without
Speaker 13:  ai, but you know, it, it was a lot easier and a lot more fun
Speaker 13:  than having to search through a million
Speaker 13:  forums on, you know, how walls are put up right
Speaker 13:  now. It it, it's true. That does lead to the downsides, right? It, you know,
Speaker 13:  we, we, we've been writing quite a bit about how Google
Speaker 13:  search traffic is declining And I think some of this is because of AI
Speaker 13:  and it's like, right, okay, so all these, you know, construction
Speaker 13:  forums that I probably would've read through, you know, are, are not getting
Speaker 13:  my traffic. And that absolutely leads to issues.
Speaker 13:  On the other hand, it, it's hard to argue that that
Speaker 13:  would've been a better experience for me than having a tool that can
Speaker 13:  just gimme a readout.
Speaker 2:  Totally. And you know, we'll see. Like, I don't think you
Speaker 2:  can put it back in the box at this point. So you might as well figure out
Speaker 2:  how to make it work for you in some ways,
Speaker 2:  some ways like find the practical because it's getting
Speaker 2:  shoved down your throat whether you like it or not. At least
Speaker 2:  with search, it's helping with the fact that Google
Speaker 2:  is no longer what it used to be.
Speaker 13:  There is this idea forever that Google could not be toppled. Right? Right.
Speaker 13:  Nobody could build a better search engine than Google. And it's true.
Speaker 13:  I I think like nobody has built a better search engine than Google.
Speaker 13:  However, it turns out that this other product is quite
Speaker 13:  competitive and it has challenges. It absolutely does.
Speaker 13:  But so does Google. And I think the, the key is
Speaker 13:  knowing what the difficulties are and knowing where you need to be careful
Speaker 13:  and apply your judgment in both cases.
Speaker 2:  That's so simple. But also the
Speaker 2:  rope, the applying, the applying your good judgment
Speaker 2:  I think is a thing that we're all so,
Speaker 13:  So much less fun if you just believe everything it says. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So much less fun. And also like you can have good judgment or believe
Speaker 2:  you have good judgment and then find, oh, I got fooled, I gotta
Speaker 2:  practice a little bit more. But to your point, the good judgment
Speaker 2:  part is key. Well that was enlightening. Thank you so
Speaker 2:  much for, you know, talking with me about how you're
Speaker 2:  evolving your search process. Like I think that was like really helpful
Speaker 2:  to just chat that out and also made me realize that I also am
Speaker 2:  kind of going through that same process myself. But yeah,
Speaker 2:  thank you so much.
Speaker 13:  Yeah, no problem. Good to talk with you. Thanks for having me. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  Last up, Travis produces The Vergecast and he's
Speaker 2:  actually been vibe coding. We found someone who actually has vibe coded
Speaker 2:  using Google Gemini to help him with admin for tabletop
Speaker 2:  role playing games.
Speaker 14:  I run an RPG online for some friends
Speaker 14:  over, what are we using now? I think we're using Discord
Speaker 14:  now. This is an original world. It is inspired by
Speaker 14:  Pokemon. And so what the players are doing is
Speaker 14:  they are these trainers, they're going around and
Speaker 14:  capturing these creatures or finding other trainers
Speaker 14:  who have their own creatures to battle against them. And this is
Speaker 14:  an original rule set that I created. And one of the
Speaker 14:  things that I wanted this world to have was that
Speaker 14:  the creatures would essentially be randomized, like, I don't
Speaker 14:  know if procedurally generated is the right term for this, but
Speaker 14:  basically like I wrote a rule set of like, here's everything that a
Speaker 14:  creature could be like here are the moves that it potentially could have.
Speaker 14:  Like here's how many bonuses it can have at this level.
Speaker 14:  But I didn't want to like have a bunch of lists printed out where
Speaker 14:  I just like rolled, diced, like see on each table, like each thing that
Speaker 14:  the creature would be. So I fed the rule
Speaker 14:  set into Gemini and told it
Speaker 14:  what I wanted it to vibe code for me. And so
Speaker 14:  I will now share with you and our video
Speaker 14:  audience the app, And I will do my best to describe it
Speaker 14:  for the audio audience here is
Speaker 14:  the Crystal Spirits generator. Oh, these are called crystal spirits, which
Speaker 14:  I think also sounds like a Boone's farm style. Pretty wild. Okay, so
Speaker 14:  crystal spirits Generator. Generator at the top of the page it
Speaker 14:  lets you select number of spirits you wanna generate from one to four.
Speaker 14:  The level of the spirits that you're generating from one to six,
Speaker 14:  which biome they're going to be generated in this world has
Speaker 14:  color coded biomes according to the visible white spectrum.
Speaker 14:  So I'm going to generate, let's see, two spirits,
Speaker 14:  let level three in the, the blue biome
Speaker 14:  Alright, would generate. And so we've got
Speaker 14:  it. It also automatically determines their initiative order for combat
Speaker 14:  as soon as they're generated
Speaker 14:  and gives them a name randomized from a list of I think
Speaker 14:  about 200 real animals and fictional creatures that
Speaker 14:  I also fed into Gemini. So we've got Octopus Crab
Speaker 14:  is the first creature that was generated. It is a water creature.
Speaker 2:  This is amazing.
Speaker 14:  It's two xt, it's Combat Die is a D eight. It, it's a drag. It's time strike
Speaker 14:  is too. So it's interesting, like the way that you do this, it's like
Speaker 14:  you ask Gemini for a cake and then it gives you a cake
Speaker 14:  and then you taste the cake and you're like, can you make me another cake?
Speaker 14:  But like, use less. It's just like you're getting all
Speaker 14:  of these like fully formed cakes, right? Right. So each time it'll
Speaker 14:  like create this thing and then, you know, you have to test it to make sure
Speaker 14:  that it's implemented the rules correctly and then you make a little tweak.
Speaker 14:  So, so yeah, this is what I've been doing with my time with Job And I
Speaker 2:  Oh my goodness. How long did this actually take you to make? Because
Speaker 2:  like, you know, I think we've heard the term vibe coding a bunch
Speaker 2:  recently in all of these, you know, developer conference
Speaker 2:  keynotes. Did you have like the basics of
Speaker 2:  programming in your head? Like did did that help inform how
Speaker 2:  you were gonna do this? Or did you just go like, here are the rules,
Speaker 2:  Gemini make a thing.
Speaker 14:  I went, here are the rules. Gemini make a thing. Like, I know very, very
Speaker 14:  basic coding. It was something that I was actually really good at
Speaker 14:  as a kid. And then my life, like, it was one of those moments where
Speaker 14:  two branching paths present to themselves And I went on the one that
Speaker 14:  didn't make me an insanely rich engineer.
Speaker 14:  But yeah, so I mean like I'm, I'm really into
Speaker 14:  like tabletop games in general, like board games and like what is a,
Speaker 14:  what are, what is a, what are instructions to a board game other than like
Speaker 14:  a extremely simple set of like rules and code, right? So
Speaker 14:  it's not like too far of a stretch to take that and then give that to
Speaker 14:  Gemini and ask it to create an interactive out of it.
Speaker 14:  The, the parts that take a lot of time, like it, it
Speaker 14:  basically like what you're seeing here are like, there are a bunch of it,
Speaker 14:  it's a very simple looking app, but there are buttons that have like different
Speaker 14:  colors associated with them. Like I didn't ask it to do any of that. Like
Speaker 14:  it picked all the fonts, it like picked the emoji that it uses when it's
Speaker 14:  showing that something is like a water element. All of that stuff like Gemini
Speaker 14:  came up with by itself. But the thing that
Speaker 14:  does take time is like you experiment using it, you realize that
Speaker 14:  it misinterpreted a rule that you gave it, and then you have
Speaker 14:  to convince it that it's wrong. Because sometimes
Speaker 14:  it'll be like, well I did that for you. And you're like, no, you did like,
Speaker 14:  please try again.
Speaker 2:  Was it just something that you were like, Hmm, I don't wanna have all
Speaker 2:  these sheets, let me see if AI can do the thing. Or was it something that
Speaker 2:  you found other game masters have been doing that you've heard of? Like,
Speaker 2:  is this a Travis original idea? Did you find it on Reddit? Like
Speaker 2:  what, what sparked this as like a reason to use ai?
Speaker 14:  So there are, there are a bunch of, of systems that work
Speaker 14:  for existing like games. Like for example, Dungeons and
Speaker 14:  Dragons. There are plenty of places online that you, you can
Speaker 14:  go to and your, your character sheets are already in there. Like, you know,
Speaker 14:  the, the Dungeon Master, basically all they have to worry about is coming
Speaker 14:  up with whatever challenges the players are going to have to face next.
Speaker 14:  Like all of the rules for the enemies are baked in, like
Speaker 14:  rolling the dice. That's all, all baked in because this is an original game
Speaker 14:  system that I came up with And I don't know
Speaker 14:  how to code something like that. For me, I figured I would just
Speaker 14:  see if it worked and yeah, I think
Speaker 14:  it worked a lot better than I expected it to.
Speaker 14:  I mean, in terms of ai, like I
Speaker 14:  wouldn't want to use it to ask it. Like, Hey,
Speaker 14:  so what should happen next in this story? I'm like, the entire
Speaker 14:  point of playing the game is that we are coming up with what happens next
Speaker 14:  in the story. So I wouldn't wanna use it for that, but I think
Speaker 14:  for sort of this admin use case,
Speaker 14:  I'm, I'm pretty happy with it. It, it does something that would be
Speaker 14:  a lot more complicated for me to do on the
Speaker 14:  fly. Like it would be possible, but I would just be like, hang on
Speaker 14:  everybody. And then I like, I gotta roll a D 100 right now.
Speaker 14:  Okay, the first part of the animal is fish. You know,
Speaker 14:  like, I could, I could do that, but instead I
Speaker 14:  basically wrote all of that down and then told Gemini like,
Speaker 14:  make a thing that does that for me. I
Speaker 2:  Feel like you just ex described what I think,
Speaker 2:  you know, the real use case of AI should be, which is
Speaker 2:  taking the tedium out because to your point, I can
Speaker 2:  just imagine all the various dice that you have clattering on
Speaker 2:  a table and then it falls off the table and then you're like, hang on guys,
Speaker 2:  I gotta figure this out. Oh, now I gotta find the dice. Oh, my cat is taking
Speaker 2:  the Dyson
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back time for me to confess the very, very
Speaker 2:  silly thing that I have been using AI for. So
Speaker 2:  to, to bring it back a bit, a couple of years ago,
Speaker 2:  I kind of fell into the astrology rabbit hole on
Speaker 2:  TikTok. And I'm not talking about, oh, you just look in your weekly horoscope
Speaker 2:  and you look at your sun sign, I'm an Aries, and you go, oh, this is what's
Speaker 2:  gonna happen for Aries. No, I got into the extremely
Speaker 2:  nerdy version of this, which is natal birth charts. Oh
Speaker 2:  yeah, it takes your time of birth where you were born,
Speaker 2:  and depending on the status of the stars in the sky at that
Speaker 2:  point in time, you can apparently learn a lot about yourself and
Speaker 2:  what's gonna happen. And it's absolutely, it's
Speaker 2:  absolutely crazy. I wanna preface this by saying that I don't really
Speaker 2:  believe in a lot of it, but there's been some batshit things happening over
Speaker 2:  the last couple of years, and when you feel that there's no hope, I don't
Speaker 2:  know, sometimes I feel a little better going and looking at my natal
Speaker 2:  chart and going, oh,
Speaker 2:  mercury is in retrograde and that's why everything is sucking
Speaker 2:  yay. You know, and just going on with my life because
Speaker 2:  that I, I don't know, that's there. So at the start of this journey,
Speaker 2:  I was using the AP CoStar, you may have heard of it. It's an
Speaker 2:  AI powered astrology app and it's pretty well
Speaker 2:  known for being very sassy in its horoscopes, but
Speaker 2:  also very surface level. Like, if you wanna go deep
Speaker 2:  into stuff and kind of get some really nitty gritty
Speaker 2:  insights, which, you know, it starts off being fine just getting roasted
Speaker 2:  by an AI saying like, girl, mercury
Speaker 2:  re me, mercury retrogrades happening. So get your shit
Speaker 2:  together, you sad sack. Like, you know, that kind of vibe of thing. You know,
Speaker 2:  after a while you get really into something, you wanna learn more, you
Speaker 2:  want something more direction in your life because the chaos
Speaker 2:  of the world is getting really un unmanageable.
Speaker 2:  So, you know, CoStar wasn't cutting it for me And I was trying all these
Speaker 2:  different apps inputting my birth time. Nothing seemed to be
Speaker 2:  answering the questions I had when I was in these
Speaker 2:  moments of like, dear God, I need, I need something to tell me
Speaker 2:  it's gonna be okay. So one day I was just on
Speaker 2:  the site astro seek.com, and then I scrolled down, I went, ah,
Speaker 2:  it has listed everything out so that you can copy
Speaker 2:  paste the entire details of your birth chat into
Speaker 2:  chat GPT, and then you can just have chat GPT, save your
Speaker 2:  birth chart as a memory and then you can ask it, whatever. So
Speaker 2:  basically I have been asking chat GPT stuff like, you know,
Speaker 2:  I am planning this project, what transits of planets
Speaker 2:  in the sky support me being successful? When am I supposed to manifest
Speaker 2:  certain things? And like I said, I don't actually believe in all of this
Speaker 2:  nonsense, but I am trying to make sense of a senseless
Speaker 2:  world and I've actually found it kind of useful to,
Speaker 2:  I don't know, just go to Chachi PT and ask my unhinged questions
Speaker 2:  when I'm feeling just a little out of my mind and
Speaker 2:  just need to be like brought down to earth a little bit. And you know, at
Speaker 2:  least I'm not using Chad GPT as a therapist. I have a real person for that.
Speaker 2:  But yeah, I go to it with a bunch of different timing and astrology questions
Speaker 2:  and go like, oh, thank you Chad. GPT. My Mercury is in the ninth house
Speaker 2:  and in Aries. And that does mean I am a direct communicator, thank you.
Speaker 2:  Some very silly placebo type things.
Speaker 2:  I probably just confess to all of you that I am neurotic as hell And I amm
Speaker 2:  using AI for a very, very silly purpose. But
Speaker 2:  hey, I've downloaded every AI powered
Speaker 2:  astrology app at some point during the past five years. Do I think
Speaker 2:  this is a particularly healthy coping mechanism? No, absolutely
Speaker 2:  not. But it is what it is and it's, I don't know, it's working for
Speaker 2:  me. So that's what I've been using AI for.
Speaker 2:  Don't at me that astrology is fake because I already know
Speaker 2:  and agree with you. Just let me have this, Ms. Cleo isn't
Speaker 2:  around anymore. Just let me have this. Okay, so that's it
Speaker 2:  for The Vergecast. Thanks to all of my colleagues who join me today.
Speaker 2:  As always, if you have thoughts, questions, feelings, examples of how
Speaker 2:  you use AI in your daily life, you can always email at us
Speaker 2:  at vergecast at The Verge dot com or keep calling the hotline.
Speaker 2:  8 6 6 VERGE one one. This show is produced by
Speaker 2:  Eric Gomez, Brandon Kiefer, Travis Uck and Andrew
Speaker 2:  Marino. The Vergecast is The Verge production and part of the Vox Media
Speaker 2:  podcast network. See you next time.