# Transcript
ID: 95fe9920-5596-49e5-ae14-537403b96ae1
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5695377549465740495/2692703682326949423/s93290-US-6322s-1750416907.mp3
Description: Starting a wireless carrier is easier than you might think. So is building a half-decent Android phone! But doing all the things Trump Mobile promises, at the price and on the schedule it says, seems awfully close to impossible. While Nilay's out, David and Jake chat with The Verge's Dominic Preston about what we know about Trump Mobile and the T1 Phone, why everyone wants to be a wireless carrier, and what it would actually take for this to work out. After that, David and Jake talk through some big news in the TV world, and the streaming takeover that appears to be happening faster all the time. Finally, in the lightning round, it's time for some brief FCC news, a check on the state of Siri, big questions about the ad-rich future of WhatsApp, a look at the new fediverse feed in Threads, and some thoughts on the Framework Laptop 12.
Speaker 4:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of phones. That
Speaker 4:  for sure definitely do not exist. It, it just doesn't exist.
Speaker 4:  I don't know what to say. It just does not exist. But we're gonna talk about
Speaker 4:  this. I'm m your friend David Pierce. Jake AKIs is here. Hi, Jake. Hey,
Speaker 5:  Good to be
Speaker 4:  Here. Your microphone works, your headphones work. The camera works.
Speaker 4:  People should know that this is a small miracle we've accomplished to make
Speaker 4:  this happen. It is. I
Speaker 5:  Have some fancy technical wizardry that I've just learned that
Speaker 5:  I, I can, can do in this room. So we'll see. We'll see if it comes up later.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's gonna get weird in here. Dom Preston's also here. Hi Dom.
Speaker 4:  Hey, happy to be here. We have brought you here late in the day
Speaker 4:  where you are. You're, you're in the uk. It's late, it's the evening,
Speaker 4:  but, but Trump mobile exists and we have to talk about it. Do you know what
Speaker 4:  I mean? Like, it's just that these are the rules. I don't make them, I just
Speaker 4:  abide by them. So we have a lot of news to talk about today. We're gonna
Speaker 4:  talk about, there's a bunch of interesting streaming stuff happening. I,
Speaker 4:  I think this is like a sort of moment in the history of the
Speaker 4:  television industry that we're gonna talk about some stuff on Siri,
Speaker 4:  some interesting politics news. Whatsapp got ads and
Speaker 4:  everybody's having a lot of feelings about it. But we gotta start with Trump
Speaker 4:  Mobile. We the, there, there is a phone, it's called
Speaker 4:  the Trump Mobile T one phone 8,002.
Speaker 4:  A fact that gives me a great number of questions. And then there
Speaker 4:  is Trump Mobile, the wireless carrier. Dom, you,
Speaker 4:  you wrote the original story for us when, when Trump mobile came up, kind
Speaker 4:  of out of nowhere. Do you wanna explain what this thing is? What did the
Speaker 4:  Trump organization actually launch this week?
Speaker 6:  So they've launched two things. It came almost out of nowhere. There'd been
Speaker 6:  some trademark applications a few days prior. So we kind of had an inkling,
Speaker 6:  maybe they're working on this, but in that like long term, maybe we'll see
Speaker 6:  something eventually. And then all of a sudden, an hour after we published
Speaker 6:  the story there. The other thing was, so there's two parts to this.
Speaker 6:  There's a network, Trump Mobile, which is offering a
Speaker 6:  single plan called the 47 plan. They
Speaker 6:  are an MVNO. They're just kind of piggybacking on T-Mobile coverage. But
Speaker 6:  that's just this kind of single plan you can get. You could bring any phone
Speaker 6:  you want to Trump mobile if for some reason you wanted to and, and
Speaker 6:  sign up. In theory, you can do that right now and switch to Trump mobile.
Speaker 6:  I, I think in practice that might not work entirely smoothly, but
Speaker 6:  supposedly you could. But then they also wanted to have a phone because,
Speaker 6:  you know, you can't have Trump mobile without the Trump mobile. And that
Speaker 6:  is the, the T one phone 8,002. This I feel
Speaker 6:  like we know less about in that we know a lot of things about it, but
Speaker 6:  don't believe very many of them. We have a big long spec sheet. We
Speaker 6:  kind of have a picture, but I'm pretty sure it's not actually a picture of
Speaker 6:  a real phone in the world. And this is a
Speaker 6:  phone they claim will be made in America or is being
Speaker 6:  made in America, or will eventually be made in America. Some combination
Speaker 6:  of the above. And it's coming out either in August or
Speaker 6:  in September, depending on which part of their website you believe. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  We should say Dom, you're not like making
Speaker 4:  different guesses here about possibilities. These are all things that people
Speaker 4:  associated with this project have said out loud in public. Like
Speaker 4:  it either will or won't or might be someday built in the United States is
Speaker 4:  a compilation of things that Eric Trump said. Like that's just
Speaker 4:  the, these are not educated guesses. That is what, that is what the person
Speaker 4:  responsible for. This has said out loud over and over and over again.
Speaker 4:  This is what we're doing here. This is
Speaker 6:  All we have to work with. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So I think, I think I like the way you set that up because like the
Speaker 4:  Trump mobile piece of it is just whatever,
Speaker 4:  right? Like Jake, you, you wrote about sort of the, the economics of Trump
Speaker 4:  mobile, but basically an NVO is not a complicated
Speaker 4:  thing to do. You can just have a wireless carrier if you
Speaker 4:  want, have a wireless carrier.
Speaker 5:  I mean, this is also such a funny week to have launched it because like less
Speaker 5:  than a week before this, the Smartlist Podcast
Speaker 5:  launched a mobile carrier and like, if, if Smartlist
Speaker 5:  can launch a wireless carrier, then first off stay tuned for wireless.
Speaker 5:  It's probably not happening, but it could, it could is the point. I will
Speaker 4:  Say, Mila is not here today. He's off doing fancy people things. I
Speaker 4:  pitched him on the idea of VERGE Mobile as an
Speaker 4:  MVNO and he immediately green lit it, and I'm saying it in public now so
Speaker 4:  that he can't take it back. This
Speaker 5:  Is happening. This, this is how he goes head to head with Brendan Carr. You
Speaker 5:  know who, who regulates VERGE Mobile.
Speaker 4:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  We're coming through, this is how we make it happen. But yeah, look like
Speaker 5:  Allison Johnson talked to a couple of analysts about, you know, why are
Speaker 5:  MVNOs like blowing up right now? And apparently it's, it's part of it is
Speaker 5:  five GII, I hate to say it, but I, there's just a bunch of
Speaker 5:  extra spectrum and bandwidth and capacity because of 5G. So
Speaker 5:  there, so these networks are like, how do we offload this?
Speaker 5:  Number two, eims make it really easy to just join whatever network
Speaker 5:  you want and try them out. And then I think everybody's looking at
Speaker 5:  Ryan Reynolds who let, let's be clear what Ryan Reynolds did. He
Speaker 5:  sold T-Mobile's own network back to T-Mobile
Speaker 5:  for over a billion dollars, which good for him. That rules
Speaker 4:  One of the great business cos of the century, honestly.
Speaker 4:  And, and it, it's actually like a perfect microcosm of the whole thing. And
Speaker 4:  I think Allison's gonna come on the show on Tuesday and we're, we're gonna
Speaker 4:  sort of dive deeper into the world of MVNOs, but Mint Mobile,
Speaker 4:  which was an MVNO, like you're talking about, perfect example of this, right?
Speaker 4:  Because all it is is you take Spectrum that exists from one of these
Speaker 4:  carriers. They give you capacity on their network, you then
Speaker 4:  build whatever brand you want to around it. And all you have to do is manage
Speaker 4:  like billing and customer service, right? Like the, the network piece of
Speaker 4:  it. It, it's kind of like standing up a company on AWS right? Like the,
Speaker 4:  the networking is no longer the problem. You just sort of solve everything
Speaker 4:  else around it. And that is all stuff you can increasingly like
Speaker 4:  offload to a bunch of other SaaS things. So you just, like, you sign up for
Speaker 4:  six pieces of enterprise software and like you have an MVNO and
Speaker 4:  you can just do it. And so it's becoming like a branding exercise
Speaker 4:  now. And I think Allison compared it to like the, the liquor
Speaker 4:  companies that used to just put, you know, George Clooney's name on a bottle
Speaker 4:  of liquor and call it a day. Now you can do it with a wireless carrier.
Speaker 5:  I mean that's what it is, right? It's it's a branding exercise, which is
Speaker 5:  like, that is what the Trump organization is. They just put their name on
Speaker 5:  things. It's Trump stakes.
Speaker 4:  Yes, I agree. And I think in a weird way, I actually think with Trump this
Speaker 4:  makes more sense than with some other things. Yes. But like it's weirdly
Speaker 4:  it's the smartless one that I have not been able to get my brain around.
Speaker 4:  Like what is there, is there any
Speaker 4:  celebrity or brand in the world that would make either of you immediately
Speaker 4:  switch wireless carriers to be on that mobile carrier Dom? Like who,
Speaker 4:  who, who would do it for you?
Speaker 6:  The only name that is for some reason immediately coming into my mind is
Speaker 6:  Kyle McLachlan of, of of Twin Peaks and so on.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 4:  That's it. Twin Peaks mobile. You're in.
Speaker 6:  I'm, I'm in. Yeah. And in loving memory of David Lynch, let's launch a
Speaker 6:  mobile network and, and we'll go from there.
Speaker 4:  Twin Peaks also ironically have pretty good name for a wireless game. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Jake, what about you? Who would, who would it be for you?
Speaker 5:  You, oh, we're going with, with the Rock Wireless, right? This
Speaker 5:  between
Speaker 4:  The Rock
Speaker 5:  Wireless, like it's gonna be an every single movie contract that he has to
Speaker 5:  be like, hello, I'm speaking you, you from Rock, rock Wireless.
Speaker 4:  Can you hear me now? Yes. Terrific.
Speaker 5:  Of course you can.
Speaker 4:  Of course you can.
Speaker 5:  With the best connection across the 50 states.
Speaker 4:  See that's
Speaker 5:  Very good free international calling. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  The thing that's really upsetting is that would 100% Oh it would crush. He
Speaker 4:  would do it and it would work.
Speaker 5:  Like you need somebody who can sell it.
Speaker 4:  Yes. This is very good. But wait, I, we will come back to the MV and O stuff.
Speaker 4:  'cause I think like we're talking about, that's actually the more straightforward
Speaker 4:  part of this. And Jake, you mentioned Trump stakes, like this is just, it's
Speaker 4:  just Trump stakes. Like it really is just a pure
Speaker 4:  brand licensing exercise. And fine, if you wanna overpay
Speaker 4:  to say that you have Trump Mobile, knock yourself out. The service will be
Speaker 4:  fine. It's too expensive. It's $47 and 45 cents because he was the
Speaker 4:  45th and 47th president.
Speaker 4:  My favorite part of that, by the way, is it would've made way more chronological
Speaker 4:  sense if it was $45 and 47 cents and they did it backwards just to scam
Speaker 4:  you out of more money. Yes.
Speaker 5:  You know, that's true.
Speaker 4:  Hate that. But we should talk about the phone.
Speaker 4:  And one of the amazing VERGE things that
Speaker 4:  happened to this week, which doesn't happen a lot, but is one of my favorite
Speaker 4:  things that happens is a, a piece of news drops and like
Speaker 4:  a huge percentage of VERGE employees all
Speaker 4:  begin the same quest at the same time. And this time it was,
Speaker 4:  what the hell is that phone? Because we all made the same
Speaker 4:  assumption and, and Dom you got to do this before anybody, which was, we
Speaker 4:  saw the Photoshop of this phone on the website
Speaker 4:  and we all sort of immediately assumed, okay, it's like a, it's a re badged
Speaker 4:  something. And then the Internet's favorite question for several days has
Speaker 4:  been, what is that something Dom,
Speaker 4:  you see more weird phones than Jake And I do. By virtue of not being in the
Speaker 4:  United States, how has, how has this exploration gone for you?
Speaker 6:  More challenging than I expected. I think though, the strangest thing about
Speaker 6:  this was, I did think the moment this dropped, I thought, I can find out
Speaker 6:  what this is. I can absolutely go track down what phone this is. I,
Speaker 6:  you know, it was like rolling through my head all the names of the brands
Speaker 6:  that I know work as ODMs and that and that, that do these off the shelf things.
Speaker 6:  That's like I can find a phone that has been re reskinned. The weird thing
Speaker 6:  is we can't, we can find a lot of phones that are very similar,
Speaker 6:  a lot of phones that match everything on the spec list except
Speaker 6:  one bit. So it doesn't look like this
Speaker 6:  is an exact version of another phone on the market that's just been given
Speaker 6:  like a gold spray paint and a, and a, you know, us flag on the back.
Speaker 6:  Whatever they've done, you know, they are working with, well to whatever
Speaker 6:  extent, you know, this is real, they are working with some sort of ODM
Speaker 6:  in, in most likely in China to customize something a bit to make this
Speaker 6:  from what we can tell. Because if there is an exact version of this phone
Speaker 6:  out there, we, we can't find it. So far
Speaker 4:  What's the closest you've found? Like if you, if you had to pick one, where
Speaker 4:  do you land?
Speaker 6:  Oh, I think some of the, I've never actually known how you're meant to say
Speaker 6:  it, but ePhone is always what I've gone for. I think some of
Speaker 6:  the ePhone models look very, very close. They have that perfect
Speaker 6:  iPhone pro knockoff triangular camera module
Speaker 6:  and they do have some models in, in basically the same size and, and with
Speaker 6:  a headphone jack, which is that weird element that narrows everything down
Speaker 6:  a lot, including a 3.5 mil headphone Jack actually suddenly removes a lot
Speaker 6:  of the phones that this could be because that's obviously a part of the chassis
Speaker 6:  and part of the design that I I imagine is baked in fairly early in the design
Speaker 6:  of these things. So I I I can't say that with total confidence.
Speaker 5:  Oh, that's interesting because I, I think, and David you pointed this out
Speaker 5:  on the site, but the, the things that is most incongruous here is
Speaker 5:  they say it runs Android 15, which is not true of, of a,
Speaker 5:  you know, a cheapo knockoff Android phone and that it has a headphone jack,
Speaker 5:  which is true of a very old
Speaker 5:  cheapo Android phone. And So I like, I also have been poking around
Speaker 5:  Dom and you can find a bunch of iPhone lookalikes on Ali
Speaker 5:  Express and the headphone jack is the thing that I think is particularly
Speaker 5:  hard to come by.
Speaker 4:  Jake, you sent me a screenshot when you say poking around you I believe went
Speaker 4:  to Amazon and Googled big Android phone and that was the great
Speaker 4:  journalism that Jake did mobile. I thought that was
Speaker 5:  Was about the right starting point. And I have now, lemme tell you, it was
Speaker 5:  so successful. I have repeated that everywhere you just type in big Android
Speaker 5:  phone and it gets you exactly what you want. 'cause it turns out that
Speaker 5:  people actually just want a thing that looks like an iPhone and you know
Speaker 5:  what? That, that search result gets you there. I do think like what we have
Speaker 5:  been finding is telling
Speaker 5:  these things cost what dom like $150.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean one of the closer comparisons, like actually
Speaker 6:  a phone that did get a real release in the us well almost did it got recalled,
Speaker 6:  but the, the T-Mobile Revel seven Pro 5G
Speaker 6:  is a pretty close match. I think the camera layout is wrong. It, it's not
Speaker 6:  the exact same thing, but that did, you know, have a proper price announced
Speaker 6:  by a major American company and that was $250 and it is a
Speaker 6:  very close spec match for this. If you go for ones direct from the likes
Speaker 6:  of ePhone or, or Doogie or OMI Digi,
Speaker 6:  then yeah, maybe you're more in the 200, 1 50 range.
Speaker 4:  True kudos for saying all of those names with a straight face. The, the most
Speaker 4:  enlightening thing about this whole process to me has been how
Speaker 4:  truly deep the like Amazon alphabet soup
Speaker 4:  of phone brands goes. I mean it's wild
Speaker 4:  and every imaginable variation of
Speaker 4:  specs you can just, you can just have, and it's, this is like a thing I like
Speaker 4:  intuitively sort of new, right? That like intellectually I understand
Speaker 4:  that phones are mass manufactured unlike almost anything
Speaker 4:  we've ever seen. And they're everywhere and you can have any kind of spec
Speaker 4:  that you want and they're just pulling parts out of a bin and, and putting
Speaker 4:  them together and sending you the phone. But oh my God, can you just have
Speaker 4:  whatever phone you want on Alibaba tomorrow? And like Jake you said
Speaker 4:  98% of them will look alarmingly like an iPhone.
Speaker 4:  It's just nuts. How many of these are out there and they're so cheap. Hmm.
Speaker 4:  Like a bunch of the specs, right? It was like a 5,000 million battery, 12
Speaker 4:  gigs of ram, I think 256 gigs of storage.
Speaker 4:  All this like relatively fine
Speaker 4:  Android specs, right? Like slightly better than the pixel nine. A way to
Speaker 4:  go Google
Speaker 4:  120 bucks in many cases. Like you, I'm gonna,
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna start buying phones just for fun. Like I, I need to own more phones
Speaker 4:  is the thing that I have learned at the end of this process.
Speaker 5:  Dom, how much have you gotten a chance to try some of these like random cheapo
Speaker 5:  phones? Because again, like the specs, are they, they sound delightful and
Speaker 5:  then in practice I get the impression that they do not perform like what
Speaker 5:  you would expect from those numbers.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it can be a mixed bag. I've tried a few, especially the
Speaker 6:  ruggedized ones.
Speaker 6:  They, they tend to, I think performance is usually okay in
Speaker 6:  terms of them being reasonably fast to use depending on what chip set you're
Speaker 6:  gonna find in there. But you know, once you've got the chip set and the ram
Speaker 6:  that's pretty much baked in, the software will probably be ropey
Speaker 6:  the closer it is to being stock Android, the better a time you're likely
Speaker 6:  to have, the more they've bothered to put some spin on it. The worse of a
Speaker 6:  time you're gonna have, you will probably be lucky to get
Speaker 6:  an OS upgrade, you know, or a
Speaker 6:  couple of security patches. I I would never trust these things for any sort
Speaker 6:  of long-term use that kind of, almost like disposable phones.
Speaker 6:  The big thing you're not gonna get is camera performance. None of them have
Speaker 6:  cameras worth of Damn at all. And that was the giveaway for me looking at,
Speaker 6:  at the T one is going through and being like, yeah, a lot of these specs
Speaker 6:  sound fine. It's 120 hertz OLA display, it's got a decent sized
Speaker 6:  battery, 12 gigs of ram is more generous than a lot of these funds would
Speaker 6:  ship with. Yeah. But then you get to that camera and it's a 50 megapixel
Speaker 6:  main camera with two megapixel depth and macro sensors. No information
Speaker 6:  about what those sensors in any of this are. So that 50 megapixel is probably
Speaker 6:  absolutely dreadful. There's gonna be no software
Speaker 6:  doing its own camera processing functionally, you know, it's, it's gonna
Speaker 6:  be doing very little to improve the image you get. Those macro and depth
Speaker 6:  sensor are just dead space. The, the cheap end of the Android market has
Speaker 6:  been throwing them on phones for years as a way to goose up camera counts.
Speaker 6:  It's a three camera phone. Interesting. It looks like an iPhone with three
Speaker 6:  cameras, you know, at a glance that's a triple camera. You open the camera
Speaker 6:  app up, there's only one camera mode to use. There's no ultra wide, there's
Speaker 6:  no zoom. You just have the camera. The macro in depth sensor might kick
Speaker 6:  in at certain points. They might just not, and if they do,
Speaker 6:  they're not gonna do anything you care about.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Two megapixel macro sensor is not an exciting piece
Speaker 4:  of camera hardware, I would say. No. Yeah. I I'm so struck by
Speaker 4:  like how many of the sort of specs
Speaker 4:  that we have thought of as important for a long time and like we talk about
Speaker 4:  them in reviews are actually like, not not just table
Speaker 4:  stakes but almost kind of irrelevant to a lot of this stuff now. Like
Speaker 4:  you, you should be worried about a phone that ships with less than this
Speaker 4:  amount of storage, right? And like yeah, any, anything below a certain number
Speaker 4:  you should take as like a huge red flag. Everything else is like, that's,
Speaker 4:  it's just, it's just a phone. You just made a phone. And I think we've
Speaker 4:  come to an interesting space where I remember, like, I wrote this big story
Speaker 4:  a bunch of years ago about this company Blue Products, which is a, a Miami
Speaker 4:  based, they're essentially an importer of phones,
Speaker 4:  but they were very early to this game of like essentially drop shipping phones
Speaker 4:  on Amazon and would would bring them in and tweak them a little bit. And
Speaker 4:  they started to do more and more over time. But they had like real honest
Speaker 4:  to god performance issues because they were, they were not using
Speaker 4:  mid-range specs. And this is like in 2012 when mid-range specs were
Speaker 4:  sort of a problem. Now you can get probably,
Speaker 4:  we don't know what processor this T one phone has, which is a very notable
Speaker 4:  emission, but assuming it's like a middle of the road processor, you can
Speaker 4:  sort of brute force into reasonable performance
Speaker 4:  on Android, right? Like most things work
Speaker 4:  fine because there is just enough performance headroom in even like a half
Speaker 4:  decent processor that I think the, the like overall quality of a
Speaker 4:  crappy phone has gone way up over time.
Speaker 4:  Which is fascinating
Speaker 6:  To get a phone that actively feels slow and laggy
Speaker 6:  in that day-to-day usage. You know, I'm not gonna talk about gaming performance,
Speaker 6:  that's a different thing. But if you want something that really feels like
Speaker 6:  slow and you open Instagram up, you would have to go below a hundred dollars
Speaker 6:  I think to find something that's still in, in feels slow like that. Anything
Speaker 6:  above a hundred bucks and it's gonna feel fine just for social media and
Speaker 6:  email and, and your average app,
Speaker 4:  Right? Unless you decide to just
Speaker 4:  absolutely ruin the phone with bloatware and spyware and all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 4:  And if I'm being completely honest with you, I think the
Speaker 4:  Trump organization might do that. Like I just, can you
Speaker 4:  imagine the, the like windows style
Speaker 4:  crap that's gonna get built into this and it's, it's gonna come with like
Speaker 4:  a hundred apps, none of which you want. Most of which you've never heard
Speaker 4:  of, all of which are like allowed to run in the background and cause all
Speaker 4:  kinds of problems for like I think we've been on a good path away
Speaker 4:  from junkie software coming on phones for a very long time. Even Samsung,
Speaker 4:  which can barely help itself has kind of learned how to help itself and here
Speaker 4:  comes Trump mobile and they're just like, what if we just bundled every app
Speaker 4:  that would give us a dollar onto your phone? Would that be fun? Would you
Speaker 4:  like that?
Speaker 6:  I'm fascinated to see where they land here because
Speaker 6:  I still review a lot of Chinese phones and, and all of Chinese flagships
Speaker 6:  and you know, phones that don't launch in the US but would be in the like
Speaker 6:  grand and a half price range if they did. And
Speaker 6:  you can turn those on and they are filled with apps from minute
Speaker 6:  one and not, not opera apps, not Xmi apps. They have
Speaker 6:  every social media network come to the sun, every Chinese food delivery app,
Speaker 6:  every different browser and search engine, all this stuff. There's so much
Speaker 6:  stuff loaded on even a very high-end device in China that is still the way
Speaker 6:  that market operates.
Speaker 4:  That's so interesting.
Speaker 6:  And you're right, like in in the west, like the funds we that you can buy
Speaker 6:  in in Europe and, and the states like that just doesn't happen anymore.
Speaker 6:  But it is still a money spinner if you're willing to make that compromise
Speaker 6:  and Yeah, I I really bet the Trump organization is willing to make that
Speaker 6:  compromise.
Speaker 4:  I know I've been trying to decide like what what apps do I think are gonna
Speaker 4:  get built in. I think the the funniest one that I've been able to come up
Speaker 4:  with is signal. Like, I think Signal should reach out to the Trump organization
Speaker 4:  and be like, just, just build us into the T one. We'll we'll we'll give you
Speaker 4:  some money just for a bit. I think I would enjoy that very much,
Speaker 4:  but I suspect that will not be it and it will be much uglier. So Jake,
Speaker 4:  here's my question. Is there any chance any of this is real, like
Speaker 4:  the the $500 T one phone launching on Trump mobile in
Speaker 4:  September? Is there any chance that's a real thing that's gonna
Speaker 4:  happen
Speaker 5:  Made in the US No. I I think like can they have a
Speaker 5:  phone available to send us by September? Yeah. Why not? Like I think we
Speaker 5:  could get a phone available to, to send to people by September.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. One Alibaba order away from having a bunch of phones that we Right.
Speaker 5:  And like, you know, like if you look at the Trump
Speaker 5:  mobile website, like it does not look like
Speaker 5:  a thing. They put a lot of effort into it. It it like right,
Speaker 5:  this looks like it was, it was put together in about a day. And
Speaker 5:  So I I'm not expecting this phone to be particularly great. I'm not
Speaker 5:  expecting 'em to put a ton of work into making this
Speaker 5:  wireless service all that exciting and appealing. I
Speaker 5:  suspect they will get a phone out the door. Surely they have the
Speaker 5:  resources to put in an ALI Express order. I I I think that is
Speaker 5:  manageable on that one podcast we saw
Speaker 5:  E Eric Trump holding up two versions of what like
Speaker 5:  supposedly was the, the T one phone
Speaker 5:  8,002. He
Speaker 4:  Didn't say it was the T one phone, but he sure wanted you to think that it
Speaker 4:  was the T one phone
Speaker 5:  They keep showing. Here's the thing, there are two versions of this phone
Speaker 5:  that we have seen. There's the one on the website, which is just an egregiously
Speaker 5:  bad Photoshop. And then they keep having the, there's the ones that, that
Speaker 5:  Eric has held up as well as the ones that they've posted on social media,
Speaker 5:  which are either just iPhones with stamps on the back
Speaker 5:  Or they are, you know, the first versions of what they've imported from
Speaker 5:  from China. I, and seriously I've been like pixel
Speaker 5:  peeping on these things. They have the antenna lines in the same spots as
Speaker 5:  an iPhone. They have the buttons in the same spots as the iPhone. The
Speaker 5:  one thing that I have seen is that
Speaker 5:  iPhones are, are really the only phones that have the volume buttons on the
Speaker 5:  left hand side. And that's kind true. I I could be wrong, but
Speaker 5:  all all of the, the Android knockoffs I've seen,
Speaker 5:  even they, the ones that are trying to be exactly like an iPhone have the,
Speaker 5:  the volume buttons on the right and these ones. So I don't know, I I'm not
Speaker 5:  sure if that's actually the key one that he's holding up, but you know,
Speaker 5:  maybe they'll just wave around some more iPhones. I listen, I think they're
Speaker 5:  probably gonna ship something. Do I think this phone is going to
Speaker 5:  revolutionize the phone industry? No. Do I think this phone is going to convince
Speaker 5:  Americans and Congress that you can in fact
Speaker 5:  build great phones in the United States? I do not think so
Speaker 5:  particularly 'cause I do not think this is going to be built in the United States.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I would agree with all of that. The, the Trump organization has said
Speaker 4:  to a couple of folks that their plan is to build
Speaker 4:  it in Alabama, California and Florida. Make of that
Speaker 4:  what you will, and again, we we should say there, there is a
Speaker 4:  technicality by which
Speaker 4:  you can get away with something like this, right? Like the, the rules for
Speaker 4:  what it requires to be able to say something was made in x, y,
Speaker 4:  Z place are not as straightforward as you would like
Speaker 4:  them to be. Like it's, it's, it's all of this sort of
Speaker 4:  vague language about like meaningfully changing something. So like you could
Speaker 4:  bring it here and take a thing that's facing like this and turn it like this
Speaker 4:  and kind of get away with calling it built
Speaker 4:  in America. It's nonsense. But it's,
Speaker 4:  it's true enough that I, I can see how
Speaker 4:  someone in the organization will get up and say with a straight face,
Speaker 4:  this thing was made in America like TM
Speaker 4:  by the, by a very specific letter of a very specific law.
Speaker 4:  This thing was made in America. And that's just, that just feels like where
Speaker 4:  we're headed and it's gonna drive me insane. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I mean there's basically kind of two versions you can, the FTC has a full
Speaker 6:  made in the USA
Speaker 6:  kind of system which is quite
Speaker 6:  comprehensive and challenging And I don't think there's a realistic world
Speaker 6:  in which this phone meets that because it requires you not
Speaker 6:  only prove that you've built it here, but that like that a lot of the parts
Speaker 6:  were built in the US as well. And that is just clearly beyond what this phone
Speaker 6:  could be. But there is also basically this just kind of like, I can't remember
Speaker 6:  the actual term of it is, but it's functionally made in the SA asterisk
Speaker 6:  and you know, wink. Yeah. It just gives all this leeway for, for
Speaker 6:  exactly what you might have done. And it's kind of partially made in the
Speaker 6:  SA functionally, but you know, you can blur the lines a bit on where you
Speaker 6:  use that and, And I imagine that's the space we're gonna see them in Whethers,
Speaker 6:  there's some sort of final assembly happening in in the US
Speaker 6:  even if that's as little as, you know, putting the SSID
Speaker 6:  stickers on them and shoving them in a box and, and calling that assembly.
Speaker 5:  I mean, Dom that's fascinating. This also gets at one of the other problems
Speaker 5:  with the Trump organization running a mobile phone business, which is
Speaker 5:  who runs the FTC,
Speaker 4:  Right?
Speaker 5:  Is the FTC going to go after Trump mobile for
Speaker 5:  Mismarketing? Their phone is the FCC is Brendan Carr
Speaker 5:  gonna go after Trump mobile because they're, you know,
Speaker 5:  mishandling your data? Like I don't, it does,
Speaker 5:  doesn't seem like it, it doesn't seem like that's gonna happen. Doesn't seem
Speaker 5:  like I I I I'm pretty sure they can say it's made in America as much as they
Speaker 5:  want. I do not see a way in which they could possibly get in trouble
Speaker 5:  under the current administration.
Speaker 6:  Well that's, 'cause that's one of the other little wrinkles around the question
Speaker 6:  of whether this thing is real is something I was pointed out to me today
Speaker 6:  is that no one's been able to find an FCC ID for
Speaker 6:  this phone.
Speaker 4:  Oh,
Speaker 6:  Interesting. And you do need one, like if you want to launch a phone, you've
Speaker 6:  gotta have that so that that could mean this really is a full reskin. They've
Speaker 6:  changed nothing of an existing phone, in which case you could get away with
Speaker 6:  using that FFC F-C-C-I-D. But as we said earlier, we kind of looked
Speaker 6:  and we just can't find that phone. It doesn't seem to exist the exact carbon
Speaker 6:  copy. So then you've gotta say, well either they don't have an
Speaker 6:  F-C-C-I-D and they really need one and they should have it by now for a September
Speaker 6:  launch and that's gonna mean there is no phone. Or you just say, well, you
Speaker 6:  know, Brendan will fix it and you know, they'll, they'll escape by and
Speaker 6:  it'll be fine.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, we are, we are forever watching tests of there
Speaker 4:  not being any rules and just seeing what happens. I will say
Speaker 4:  the optimistic part of me thinks all of this Trump
Speaker 4:  stuff is a grift because it is obviously a grift to get you to pay too much
Speaker 4:  money for a phone and too much money for a mobile carrier just to say
Speaker 4:  Trump and sure if you would like to do that,
Speaker 4:  do it eyes wide open, know what you're doing, knock yourself out. I think
Speaker 4:  the, the like grand thesis of this
Speaker 4:  thing and that they're trying to do, I think is sort of fascinating. Like
Speaker 4:  a, a thing we talk about a lot is how bad
Speaker 4:  the US phone market is because it is so controlled by a couple of
Speaker 4:  companies, right? Like most people buy their phones in carrier
Speaker 4:  stores. There are effectively three carriers. There are
Speaker 4:  not that many places in those stores. And so the, the US market is
Speaker 4:  so incredibly small and controlled and like Dom,
Speaker 4:  I'm forever jealous of you because you, you have access to just like a vast
Speaker 4:  ocean of cool smartphones that for a whole variety of reasons just do not
Speaker 4:  come to the United States. Part of that is like politics with China, but
Speaker 4:  a huge amount of it is just the way that the wireless business works here,
Speaker 4:  which is that it's completely and utterly carrier dominated. And
Speaker 4:  I think if we're, if we're heading to a point where what happens at the end
Speaker 4:  of all of this MVNO stuff is that everything is
Speaker 4:  sort of pulled out of basically Verizon, at and t
Speaker 4:  and T-Mobile. Those companies become like infrastructure companies,
Speaker 4:  right? In the way that like Google Cloud and AWS and Azure are infrastructure.
Speaker 4:  You have on top of that lots of new ideas about how this stuff can work.
Speaker 4:  We get real competition in terms of like how you manage your
Speaker 4:  wireless account and the perks that come with it and all the stuff that you
Speaker 4:  get by having a wireless carrier there because there's real competition on
Speaker 4:  top of this network. They can also start to make new kinds of phones. It's
Speaker 4:  actually really easy to make phones. This is what we've been talking about.
Speaker 4:  Like more companies should try to make phones but they don't because
Speaker 4:  the pipeline has just been destroyed in the United States because Samsung
Speaker 4:  and Apple own it. They've just bought the wireless industry in every
Speaker 4:  meaningful way in the United States. Google is like around and that's it.
Speaker 4:  And So I think if, if there is a world at the end of all of this,
Speaker 4:  hopefully a, a much less thrifty one than the one that we appear to be in
Speaker 4:  right now that is actually like we, because all of this stuff is so
Speaker 4:  commoditized, we're gonna be able to get more of it from more directions.
Speaker 4:  I think that could be really interesting. I don't think that's where we're
Speaker 4:  headed because I think Apple and Samsung and the carriers remain way too
Speaker 4:  powerful. But there is like a glimmer of a thing here that is like,
Speaker 4:  I can get access to wireless networking
Speaker 4:  for a small amount of money and make it accessible in whatever way I want
Speaker 4:  to other people that I think is like potentially a very powerful
Speaker 4:  idea Right now it's Ryan Reynolds and Smartlist and Donald Trump. Yeah. But
Speaker 4:  there's, we're starting to see other stuff and, And I think like Klarna,
Speaker 4:  the, the buy now pay later company launched an MVNO this week and it's like
Speaker 4:  weird again. But like, I don't know, you can just start to see
Speaker 4:  stuff happening when it's not like my entire life on my phone is not
Speaker 4:  mediated through Verizon anymore. Interesting stuff could start to happen
Speaker 6:  And it's just a very straightforward shift from the consumer perspective
Speaker 6:  because you,
Speaker 6:  if you're on Verizon, you kind of need to get your phone from Verizon nine
Speaker 6:  times outta 10 or at least that makes it a lot easier. They make it very
Speaker 6:  appealing for you to do that. When you're on an MVNO, it's a lot easier to
Speaker 6:  just buy your phone from Amazon and put the SIM in
Speaker 6:  or, or, or activate the eim or whatever it is. And I think that is a shift
Speaker 6:  basically the UK market went through a few years ago. I know for me that's
Speaker 6:  when I moved from, you know, getting my phones on contract from one of the
Speaker 6:  big networks. I then switched to an MVNO about a decade ago and
Speaker 6:  then was like, wait, I can just buy my, like buy a Nexus phone on
Speaker 6:  Amazon and that's cheaper than doing it on the contract. And then I just
Speaker 6:  put the sim in and that works and oh wow, I've saved so much money by doing
Speaker 6:  this. And I think that's basically the sole shift we've had. And then as
Speaker 6:  soon as Amazon can be the big phone player, it completely changes who's putting
Speaker 6:  phones on the market.
Speaker 4:  I remember I bought my wife an unlocked Pixel eight relatively recently.
Speaker 4:  It was on this like giant sale at Best Buy And I bought her one and she
Speaker 4:  was like blown away that I could just take her sim card out and
Speaker 4:  put it in her new phone and it would work. Like, this is gonna sound
Speaker 4:  insane to anyone who doesn't live in the United States, but we, we have been
Speaker 4:  so convinced by these companies that this is like a
Speaker 4:  tightly controlled thing that only a couple of companies can manage for
Speaker 4:  us. And that probably takes a professional to manage. No, and
Speaker 4:  especially with eims, like you were saying, Jake, all this stuff can just
Speaker 4:  move around again now I see like there's so much potential here.
Speaker 5:  I a hundred percent agree with you. Like even when I do this with my own
Speaker 5:  phones, I'm like, are they gonna let me get, get away with it? Like,
Speaker 5:  it, it feels like open in a revolutionary way when
Speaker 5:  it's actually just like, no, like this is just, this is just my data, this
Speaker 5:  is my connectivity, this is my number. Of course I should be able to move
Speaker 5:  it from here to here. And it is kind of a marvel that we're still able
Speaker 5:  to do that. And you know, EIM does make it a little bit
Speaker 5:  trickier, but in some ways, but it also makes it a
Speaker 5:  lot more accessible in others. 'cause now you can just pop over to whatever
Speaker 5:  network you feel like. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  There is, again, I I suspect this ends closer
Speaker 4:  to Trump and Smartlist than it does to full democratization of wireless
Speaker 4:  networks. But like, I gotta have something to hope for here. You know what
Speaker 4:  I mean? All right Dom, we need to let you go here in a minute 'cause it is
Speaker 4:  late and you need to go. But before we do, what is the coolest phone you've
Speaker 4:  seen recently that Jake And I are never gonna get to touch in the United States?
Speaker 6:  Oh, the Vivo X 200 Ultra, which I wrote about on
Speaker 4:  got, we got so much more stuff to talk about. Tom, thank you for being here.
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back Jake, it's just you and me. Let's do
Speaker 5:  It.
Speaker 4:  Can I make a potentially insane sounding argument to you that I don't
Speaker 4:  actually think is that insane? Okay, you're gonna think I'm crazy, but then
Speaker 4:  at the end you're gonna think I'm not crazy. I just
Speaker 5:  Have to clarify for the audience. This is our daily work. This is just how
Speaker 5:  it goes is true. This is like, let's go,
Speaker 4:  Let's do it. Jake edits most of my stories and every once in a while I just
Speaker 4:  appear and I'm like, I said something absurd. Can you make sure it's obs
Speaker 4:  as not absurd as I'm hoping it might be? I would like to argue
Speaker 4:  that this week is a, is the end of
Speaker 4:  television, okay? That, that like in, in a bunch of ways, you
Speaker 4:  can mark some studies and data that came out this week as
Speaker 4:  the moment old school TV
Speaker 4:  died.
Speaker 5:  I wanna hear, I wanna hear your numbers, I wanna hear your argument. Okay.
Speaker 5:  This is one of those things where if it,
Speaker 5:  you're not saying it died with one grand strike,
Speaker 5:  right? This is still, it's a long arc and you're saying we've crested
Speaker 5:  and traditional TV is now its moment has passed.
Speaker 4:  I i it's more apocalyptic than that. So I, what I actually think is happening,
Speaker 4:  so the way I've come to understand this business is that for a long time,
Speaker 4:  TV made just earth shatteringly huge amounts of money, right? Like
Speaker 4:  that that's just true. It was an unbelievable business for a really long
Speaker 4:  time. And then streaming came up and a lot of these companies
Speaker 4:  made the bet that streaming is going to rise and cable is going to
Speaker 4:  fall. And by cable, I mean cable and broadcast, which is a, an an important
Speaker 4:  distinction that I, I will make a couple of times here that
Speaker 4:  that is going to fall, but it is going to throw off so much money while it
Speaker 4:  slowly dies because a lot of people who have cable are gonna keep having
Speaker 4:  cable and there's a lot of money in cable and it's a very sticky thing that
Speaker 4:  like eventually everyone who has cable will die and the cable business will
Speaker 4:  die with it. But until then cable will be around and it'll throw off lots
Speaker 4:  of money. So we're gonna keep investing in cable that, as we've talked about
Speaker 4:  a bunch on this show, has been slowly shifting faster
Speaker 4:  and faster and faster, right? I think there was a sense that maybe this was
Speaker 4:  like a multiple decade change into like maybe
Speaker 4:  it's a one decade change. And what we've learned is that this
Speaker 4:  is, it's a momentum business, right? Because so much of it is about where
Speaker 4:  do you put ad dollars that in theory everybody could
Speaker 4:  just move it tomorrow because if, if all the ad money goes away,
Speaker 4:  none of it works anymore because for, for a variety of
Speaker 4:  reasons that we can get into. And so what I think there is a thing that happened
Speaker 4:  this week, which is the Nielsen gauge. Nielsen is the company that
Speaker 4:  has done TV ratings for forever. The gauge is the thing they've been doing
Speaker 4:  since 2021, I believe, to also try and measure
Speaker 4:  streaming. And basically everybody says it's an imperfect measurement, but
Speaker 4:  it is sort of directionally useful over time. And what
Speaker 4:  happened, this most recent version of the gauge was that
Speaker 4:  streaming was bigger than cable and broadcast TV
Speaker 4:  For the first time ever.
Speaker 4:  This is like a hugely meaningful moment, right? So the, the number was that
Speaker 4:  streaming accounted for 44% of viewership
Speaker 4:  broadcasting cable accounted for 44.2%.
Speaker 4:  So 44.8 versus 44.2. If you were to say, David,
Speaker 4:  where's the other 11%? I don't have a good answer for you. That's, there's
Speaker 4:  like an other category that I,
Speaker 5:  The TV is just off digress. You're just, where it's frame TVs, you're just
Speaker 5:  looking at the art. Yeah. Like, yeah,
Speaker 4:  Something like that. But anyway, so that, that's a big change and
Speaker 4:  the momentum is just nuts. Can I just read you a bunch of numbers from your
Speaker 4:  support? Yeah, I'd
Speaker 5:  Love, love.
Speaker 4:  So YouTube, Maine, which is sort of the, the industry term for like
Speaker 4:  regular YouTube, not YouTube tv, not YouTube shorts, just YouTube, the, the
Speaker 4:  proper YouTube app. Google as always very good at branding.
Speaker 4:  YouTube main accounts for 12.5% of all streaming,
Speaker 4:  which is as big as Netflix and Disney plus combined.
Speaker 4:  It is it, it has been just dominant in this space for the last couple of
Speaker 4:  years. It's up 120% in four years. Like, well,
Speaker 5:  And we've, we've talked about it, how, how YouTube's biggest platform is
Speaker 5:  now the tv. Yeah. Which I, I like still feels
Speaker 5:  bewildering to me. Like YouTube, I, my own YouTube usage
Speaker 5:  has increased dramatically over the past like five years even,
Speaker 5:  which is honestly on a personal level, bad. It's not good. I should spend
Speaker 5:  less time on YouTube, but like for me it's still very much a, a, a
Speaker 5:  laptop thing. But you look at the numbers and, and you look at where
Speaker 5:  their product efforts are going and it is to the tv and these numbers very
Speaker 5:  much show you why. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I remember for years I would meet with people at YouTube and they would say
Speaker 4:  The living room is our fastest growing screen. But it was for a long time
Speaker 4:  it was like, it went from very small to still very small but bigger, right?
Speaker 4:  And like fastest growing is a relative term, but then kind of in the last
Speaker 4:  18 months it started to turn to like, no, this is actually our biggest platform.
Speaker 4:  And now they're starting to redesign YouTube around the
Speaker 4:  tv. Like we're seeing real TV first parts of
Speaker 4:  YouTube in a way that I think is really fascinating. But I, I wrote
Speaker 4:  a thing earlier this year for YouTube's 20th anniversary that was basically
Speaker 4:  like YouTube is just winning the entertainment industry. And that is,
Speaker 4:  that continues to be true. But the fact that it was up 120%
Speaker 4:  in the last four years just blew my mind. Like think about how dominant YouTube
Speaker 4:  was in 2021 and it has more than doubled
Speaker 4:  in, in as on television since then. Insane.
Speaker 5:  Seems impossible.
Speaker 4:  So that's just one in like regular streaming
Speaker 4:  services. I think we, we think of YouTube as kind of its own thing, but in
Speaker 4:  the realm of like traditional streaming services. Netflix has been in first
Speaker 4:  place for four years running, it's up 27% over the
Speaker 4:  four years that the gauge has been running. And it accounts for like seven,
Speaker 4:  I think seven and a half percent of streaming. So like huge
Speaker 4:  Netflix is like the winner of the streaming war in like every
Speaker 4:  meaningful way and is still getting its as kicked by YouTube. But anyway,
Speaker 4:  so Netflix growing like crazy, YouTube growing like crazy
Speaker 4:  in that same period of time, broadcast according to
Speaker 4:  Nielsen's Gauge has been down 21% and cable has been down
Speaker 4:  39%.
Speaker 5:  That is falling much faster than I would expect. Yes. And like,
Speaker 5:  that's just absent the, the ad dollars problem, right? This is just people
Speaker 5:  are shifting their behaviors
Speaker 5:  And I, I really expected this, this industry to sort of
Speaker 5:  just like chug along pretty indefinitely. And
Speaker 5:  those are some dramatic devastating
Speaker 5:  declines that are really going to imperil the ability to operate those businesses.
Speaker 5:  And I think I, I mean I suspect for a lot of our listeners, and certainly
Speaker 5:  for me, it's like yeah, of course. Right? Like I, I
Speaker 5:  have never had a cable subscription of my own, right?
Speaker 5:  Because, you know, by the time I was out of college, right, like
Speaker 5:  streaming was available, why would I not just stream everything
Speaker 5:  that I, that I need on the rare occasions, right? I went to, I went
Speaker 5:  to a bar to watch the finale of Breaking Bad.
Speaker 5:  I think that was, that was the, the like the one where I was like, okay,
Speaker 5:  I do need cable for this. But that just like, doesn't even, that doesn't
Speaker 5:  happen anymore, right? Like that's scenario doesn't come up where the thing
Speaker 5:  you want to watch,
Speaker 5:  you can't get access to at home. Like one way or another.
Speaker 5:  You can find a way to stream it, even if you have to sign up for an entire
Speaker 5:  service that you don't want, or even if you have to sign up for like a, a
Speaker 5:  bundled cable streaming service for a month. But it's all,
Speaker 5:  it's all doable and it's, and it's like, you know, there's much
Speaker 5:  to complain about in terms of, oh, okay, we've just recreated the cable bundle
Speaker 5:  in a million different ways. Yep, sure. Great. It turns out that streaming
Speaker 5:  did not exactly save us a ton of money, and it is in fact wildly
Speaker 5:  complicated. But these things are all
Speaker 5:  available. It's all possible. You have those options in front of you.
Speaker 5:  And I, I think like that has actually accelerated pretty
Speaker 5:  dramatically probably just over the, the recent, like five years maybe during
Speaker 5:  the time that we've seen that big decline, right? I think
Speaker 5:  a lot of these stragglers were the traditional
Speaker 5:  broadcast networks, and now you're finally going to be able to get those
Speaker 5:  like major live events that traditionally you still
Speaker 5:  would've had to have a cable subscription to get access to. Now
Speaker 5:  that's all streaming. There's very little that you need to have cable
Speaker 5:  for. You need to have cable if you just wanna like, have that experience
Speaker 5:  of being able to flip through the channels and not really worry about it
Speaker 5:  too much.
Speaker 4:  And this becomes like a self-fulfilling thing over time, right? Like, I'm
Speaker 4:  thinking a lot about sports rights And I remember not that many years ago,
Speaker 4:  all of the leagues made a point to stick with the broadcast networks
Speaker 4:  because what they kept saying was, it's important to us that we have a product
Speaker 4:  that is accessible to everybody and, and in a few spots would leave money
Speaker 4:  on the table in order to do so. Right? Like it's, it matters to the NFL that
Speaker 4:  it is essentially accessible to everyone, even if
Speaker 4:  that means not letting Amazon give you all of the money in the known
Speaker 4:  universe to do so. But the thing that has changed, right, is that you, you
Speaker 4:  can make an increasing case that actually if you wanna reach everybody all
Speaker 4:  at once, the move is to do it on Netflix. That, like, I
Speaker 4:  I think if you just took a poll of people that, you know,
Speaker 4:  more of them are likely to have Netflix than to have like a quick way
Speaker 4:  to watch Fox. And that is a, a
Speaker 4:  giant cultural shift that I think we're only starting to see the money follow.
Speaker 4:  But that's the thing, like when I see numbers like this, it's like every,
Speaker 4:  everybody in this page watches the Nielsen cage. Like say what you want about
Speaker 4:  the numbers. It is, it is the gold standard of how the
Speaker 4:  advertisers in particular look at this stuff and they're going to look at
Speaker 4:  this and they're gonna say, oh, it moved, not it's moving, but like it moved.
Speaker 4:  We have this, this thing that we have been thinking was going to eventually
Speaker 4:  changed has now changed.
Speaker 5:  Well, it's funny, we, we were talking about
Speaker 5:  Warner Brothers discovery splitting in half last week,
Speaker 5:  and one of the re I mean, part of it is because Z Love has done a disastrous
Speaker 5:  job, but another part of it is like they're splitting it into
Speaker 5:  the thing that streams really well and the stuff that is cable tv and that's
Speaker 5:  just their good luck,
Speaker 4:  Right? It does make a bunch of that stuff make sense. And we should, like,
Speaker 4:  Comcast, Comcast, by the way, disclosure an investor in Vox Media,
Speaker 4:  giant fans of ours did the same thing. They, they were like, okay, we're
Speaker 4:  gonna take the thing that's kind of working, which is peacock, which is
Speaker 4:  by the way, WAMP, wamp like at the, at the very bottom, it's like the lowest
Speaker 4:  one that the Nielsen gauge even ranks. There's like, Hey,
Speaker 5:  That's success.
Speaker 4:  It's peacock. And then it's other like, you did
Speaker 5:  It, they were popping champagne bottles when they made that list.
Speaker 5:  Okay,
Speaker 4:  Yeah. They're like with the, we have the logo on there now. That's all, that's
Speaker 4:  all we need. But they did the same thing. They, they took the thing that
Speaker 4:  works and then split off all of the cable companies. And it was like
Speaker 4:  those companies now are just being essentially put out to pasture. Like
Speaker 4:  there is this sense that not that long ago, there was
Speaker 4:  this belief that like, oh, we, we should keep ESPN because
Speaker 4:  it funds the rest of Disney and it will for a long time. And
Speaker 4:  that idea is just quickly going away everywhere. And, and this is what
Speaker 4:  I mean by I think like we we're going to look at this as the moment
Speaker 4:  it died because like everybody has been waiting for this sort of moment
Speaker 4:  of confirmation that the change has happened. And this
Speaker 4:  is not young people stream more. This is not like cable nevers
Speaker 4:  or grow. This is, this is people in America are streaming
Speaker 4:  more than they're watching cable. And, and even Nielsen's thing I think was
Speaker 4:  like the, these numbers are very close, so they're like, it'll probably shift
Speaker 4:  and you know, sports will start and it'll jump up again. But they were like,
Speaker 4:  the, the trend is, is unchanging and it very soon
Speaker 4:  will be permanent that the streaming number is higher. And once that happens,
Speaker 4:  it's, it's gonna get, it's gonna get weirder and like the money
Speaker 4:  is going to move even faster.
Speaker 5:  I do wonder if there is a floor, right? Like you still hear about like
Speaker 5:  there's somehow, there's still some a OL dial up customers. Sure. And they're
Speaker 5:  just like, they're like, I, it works. I'm not changing. I, I'm sure there's
Speaker 5:  a lot of people who just have cable and they're just never gonna unsubscribe.
Speaker 5:  I could see it like falling to a point and just staying there steadily
Speaker 5:  for a while. But honestly, I, it, it sounds
Speaker 5:  crazy. It really does sound crazy to be like, actually TV's TV's dead. It's
Speaker 5:  done. But, but I think you might be right like this, this actually is
Speaker 5:  a really momentous case. You have sold me on this. Did it, it does mean that
Speaker 5:  I think we're gonna probably continue to see some, some big changes in the
Speaker 5:  streaming space too as everybody races to take advantage of that growth,
Speaker 5:  right? Because this means there is more opportunity there. Now it also means
Speaker 5:  they just by necessity have to go over there. One of the big things that
Speaker 5:  we haven't talked about yet that I'm curious how much it is contributing
Speaker 5:  to this is the fast channels, because that feels like
Speaker 5:  a relatively new trend to me, and it seems like they
Speaker 5:  are are, you know, there, there are new ones launching
Speaker 5:  every single week somehow,
Speaker 5:  and that, that seemed to be very popular. So I'm, I'm really curious if that
Speaker 5:  is contributing to this. If part of this is that people are going, oh,
Speaker 5:  I can, I can actually just watch stuff for free. Like there are maybe even
Speaker 5:  fewer ads on these free streaming TV channels.
Speaker 5:  Like what, what am I doing with cable still? Like, I'm paying a hundred dollars
Speaker 5:  or more a month for this giant bundle of channels. I don't even know what's
Speaker 5:  on half of them.
Speaker 5:  And I, you know, the fast channels feel like one of those things
Speaker 5:  that's like, if, if you had started that, you know,
Speaker 5:  at the origin of streaming services, that business model wouldn't have made
Speaker 5:  sense because the ad dollars wouldn't have been there. But now the ad dollars
Speaker 5:  are shifting there. There's all kinds of new things you can do with streaming.
Speaker 5:  And So I think we are gonna continue to see number one more of these things
Speaker 5:  launch, but probably some new models pop up And I, I mean we,
Speaker 5:  we also already see this with like Netflix and basically every other premium
Speaker 5:  streaming service shifting to this. Like actually just, just watch the ads
Speaker 4:  Approach. Totally. And I think that, yeah, the fast channels are fascinating
Speaker 4:  because they're just so easy in a way that I think
Speaker 4:  we, we, I, we talked about this for years, right? That like the biggest problem
Speaker 4:  with streaming services is it's a hell of a lot of work to figure out what
Speaker 4:  you wanna watch. And what I, what I miss about cable
Speaker 4:  is I could just turn on my TV and it, it was just showing me television
Speaker 4:  And I would just like leave it on a channel and it would play things
Speaker 4:  like that. That sounds different now, but that's what it was and it was great.
Speaker 4:  But now, like the Roku channel is the fifth most popular
Speaker 4:  streaming service.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's
Speaker 4:  Incredible. The Roku channel like insane and the Roku channel
Speaker 4:  is, is just, it's Pure a fast channel and the only reason it's popular
Speaker 4:  is because it's there because lots and lots and lots of people have Rokus
Speaker 4:  and the Roku channel just has a lot of free stuff just sitting there
Speaker 4:  for you to watch. And Tubi is also on this list to
Speaker 4:  be more popular than Peacock. Tough day for
Speaker 4:  Peacock. But, but you're totally right. And, and these two things
Speaker 4:  are starting to sit side by side, right? Where you, like you have Netflix
Speaker 4:  for like the the high end premium stuff that I sort of
Speaker 4:  go watch on purpose. And then you have Tub be in the Roku channel for just
Speaker 4:  like, I just, just show me something and like
Speaker 5:  I'm consistently surprised at, at how much good programming
Speaker 5:  is available on the fast channels,
Speaker 5:  the frequency with which I will look up where I can watch a movie or TV show
Speaker 5:  and they're like, oh, it's available with ads on this free thing. And I'm
Speaker 5:  like, oh, with ads. And then it is like, not even that many ads like it,
Speaker 5:  it's it, they are what the best value in streaming. It is really incredible.
Speaker 4:  No question. I do think it's a lot of ads And I think the problem is
Speaker 4:  we are being sort of re desensitized
Speaker 5:  A ad may be true, that may be true.
Speaker 4:  Like do you remember when they first started showing ads on some of these
Speaker 4:  streaming services again? And it would be like one 32nd ad two
Speaker 4:  times a show and you'd be like, ah, I'm gonna watch an ad.
Speaker 5:  How dare you.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And now we're back to like, there was news last week that Amazon doubled
Speaker 4:  its ad inventory and like, I'm not gonna notice it's just Right. We're just
Speaker 4:  back to having too many ads all the time. And so the one that kills
Speaker 4:  me on the Fast services, And I don't know if they fixed this because
Speaker 4:  I, I either just stopped noticing it or they got better at it, but
Speaker 4:  they are just trash at knowing when to insert ads.
Speaker 4:  It's just like something in their system is just like every seven minutes
Speaker 4:  just due two ads no matter what is going on. And so it'll be in the middle
Speaker 4:  of a person's
Speaker 5:  Sentence that's
Speaker 4:  Not good and it'll just be like, buy Charmin toilet paper and then it'll
Speaker 4:  go back to the person's sentence in the middle. And I'm just like, this is
Speaker 4:  not a good user experience. I'm fine with the ads, but like, can we put them
Speaker 4:  where they go?
Speaker 5:  I, I've still may, I've just been lucky. I've still had the, like the other
Speaker 5:  side of the experience where someone s like, I can't, I can't believe this
Speaker 5:  ads on this thing. And then they'll show again. It's like they'll show me
Speaker 5:  32nd spot at the, the beginning of something and then I just watch a two
Speaker 5:  hour movie And I'm like, like I think you guys messed up here. Like, there
Speaker 5:  you needed to make me pay for this. It is the
Speaker 4:  Greatest scam in television when they're like, we're gonna show you three
Speaker 4:  minutes of ads and then you get the whole movie ad free and I'm just like,
Speaker 4:  tight, I'm gonna leave for three minutes. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I'm like, you guys just,
Speaker 4:  What are we accomplishing here?
Speaker 5:  Didn't know you had this in your catalog. Like you, you, you just forgot
Speaker 5:  to sell ads against this. Yep,
Speaker 4:  Yep. Yeah. I'm just like, I'm gonna go make popcorn and then I'm gonna come
Speaker 4:  back and I'm gonna watch an ad free movie. Like you can play an ad on my
Speaker 4:  television while I'm not here. Right. This
Speaker 5:  This is part of the thing. Like it is true, you are not always getting the
Speaker 5:  best program. Sometimes it's great, but sometimes it is. In fact it's like
Speaker 5:  that it is the c tier of movies that are on these things
Speaker 5:  sometimes. But you know what, there are
Speaker 4:  A lot of good bad movies out there. Well, you know what I mean?
Speaker 5:  This is the thing like Netflix, you look through Netflix sometimes and you're
Speaker 5:  like, I've seen all of these I've seen like, and I'm like, I I need
Speaker 5:  that like weird tier of movies that you don't feel like paying for
Speaker 5:  Netflix because not a lot of people are gonna watch them. But I've, I've
Speaker 5:  seen, you know, I know you've got
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I'm, I'm completely with you. I've,
Speaker 5:  I've watched Hot Frosty five times now. Like, let's like what's next?
Speaker 4:  Okay, first of all, hot Frosty is great justice
Speaker 4:  for hot Frosty.
Speaker 5:  I, I said nothing to to suggest otherwise.
Speaker 4:  There are very few things in my life that I enjoy as much as that period
Speaker 4:  between Thanksgiving and like December 23rd where there's just
Speaker 4:  an infinite supply of bad new Christmas movies. If
Speaker 4:  you're ever like, who are these for? The answers me. I watch them. I am the
Speaker 4:  reason they keep getting made,
Speaker 5:  Lemme tell you. And I'm not sad tell this is why streaming is winning.
Speaker 4:  'cause now there's more crappy stuff for me to watch. It's great times. Okay,
Speaker 4:  wait on the TV is dying. Can I, can I offer you one more quick
Speaker 4:  study on, I'm telling you this is like an interesting week for, oh no,
Speaker 4:  TV's dead. So there was, there's this group at,
Speaker 4:  at Oxford called the Reuters Institute for the Study of Journalism
Speaker 4:  and every year they do a big report on sort of the state of journalism
Speaker 4:  in the world. It's, it's real bleak. It's,
Speaker 4:  it's just what I'll say about that. It's not great to be a journalist.
Speaker 4:  There's a lot of stuff going on. The PE misinformation is everywhere, but
Speaker 4:  there are, there were a couple of interesting shifts, particularly
Speaker 4:  in the United States that I thought were very interesting and also
Speaker 4:  very bad news for television. So lemme just read you from this report.
Speaker 4:  It says the proportion accessing news via social media and video networks
Speaker 4:  in the United States is sharply up at 54%. So
Speaker 4:  54% of people are getting news via social media and video networks. Video
Speaker 4:  networks being like TikTok and stuff like that. That number is actually lower
Speaker 4:  than I would've guessed, but is is high.
Speaker 4:  And I think probably the younger the audience, the higher that number is
Speaker 4:  gonna be. That number 54% overtook
Speaker 4:  both TV news, which is 50% and news
Speaker 4:  websites slash apps 48% For the first time. So
Speaker 4:  now For the first time ever, social media and video networks
Speaker 4:  are the dominant place by which people in the United States
Speaker 4:  access their news. And again, the the trends suggest
Speaker 4:  that number is only going to get even further away. TV is down
Speaker 4:  22% online news sites are down 21% print is down
Speaker 4:  33%. Like there's only one number
Speaker 4:  going up. And it's, it's social media and social networks
Speaker 4:  and everything else. Podcasts interestingly
Speaker 4:  hanging in there, doing fairly well and are like more popular in the US
Speaker 4:  than almost anywhere else as a news source. But again, like TV news
Speaker 4:  dying.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean this, this makes a lot of sense, right? Like the, the in the
Speaker 5:  old days. In the old days, right, but
Speaker 4:  Old
Speaker 5:  Days, couple days of in the old days,
Speaker 4:  Eight years ago in the
Speaker 5:  Late years, no, but like right, it was a real thing. Like the evening news
Speaker 5:  was on, you had to have it on if you wanted to know what, right. That was
Speaker 5:  also when they showed the weather, if you wanted to know what the weather.
Speaker 5:  Right. These things become increasingly less essential.
Speaker 5:  It's funny, like, you know, I don't know at what point in time
Speaker 5:  I would've been like, like goodness. Like
Speaker 5:  you're, you're Ewing the great television news
Speaker 5:  in favor of some, for sure. Right, right. Like
Speaker 4:  I don I don know this is a commentary on quality, by
Speaker 5:  The way, but it, it is certainly, you know,
Speaker 5:  I, the the rise of, I I think like social video
Speaker 5:  news, like that kind of maybe spells out where some of this viewership is
Speaker 5:  going, right? Like Yep.
Speaker 4:  And a lot of it is, it's super, super creator based in a way that is,
Speaker 4:  is very different from the sort of like giant networks that were
Speaker 4:  around for the last generation. Like the whole way people experience
Speaker 4:  this stuff has just changed. Well
Speaker 5:  That's, I actually, I have so many questions And I would love to know when
Speaker 5:  somebody says yes, I get most of my news from TikTok, like, what does that
Speaker 5:  mean to them? Right? Like, does that mean that they caught a, a
Speaker 5:  ten second snippet of a podcast where somebody goes, you know, they just
Speaker 5:  passed the Genius Act and that's gonna regulate stable
Speaker 5:  coins and then they just like swipe up. Like is that, is that the thing?
Speaker 5:  Is it somebody,
Speaker 4:  Can I tell you a fact that's gonna really bum you out?
Speaker 5:  Oh no. Would
Speaker 4:  You like to hear a list of some of the podcasts that people said
Speaker 4:  they turned to for news? Yeah. Would you like to know the most popular?
Speaker 4:  Is it us? No, it's the Joe Rogan experience, not, which I think
Speaker 4:  fairly neatly answers your question. Right? Okay. Like,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, we, there is
Speaker 4:  Also this giant change in what people perceive to be news.
Speaker 4:  That's, news used to be like a a a sort of put
Speaker 4:  together report of some kind and you would watch it at
Speaker 4:  6:00 PM and that's what the news was. And then the news was like,
Speaker 4:  I don't know, stuff on Twitter and New York times.com and now news
Speaker 4:  is something else. And I feel like I can't even exactly
Speaker 4:  describe what it is, but it is very clear that like, if you think, if you're
Speaker 4:  sitting there being like, I get most of my news from the Joe Rogan experience
Speaker 4:  that is like a fundamentally different understanding of how to move through
Speaker 4:  the world than I am like fully capable of recording
Speaker 5:  With it. It's so interesting. It's like, I mean, I, going to the
Speaker 5:  New York Times in some ways feels like the same audience who like likes to
Speaker 5:  play chess and like, like, don't get me wrong, like that's me, right? But
Speaker 5:  it's like, yeah, sure. Like, yo, you could play sellers ofan, like the,
Speaker 5:  you could play Fortnite. Those would be more fun.
Speaker 4:  I get all my news from Fortnite, Jake, I should say
Speaker 5:  That, right? And it's like, like, you know, sure you could go to the New York
Speaker 5:  Times and, and it will have great reporting and you'll get things in a
Speaker 5:  timely manner and it'll be accurate. Or you
Speaker 5:  can hear a version of it. And I'm putting version in like
Speaker 5:  very serious like air quotes there on Joe Rogan like
Speaker 5:  some amount of time later. And I think that that makes a lot of sense to
Speaker 5:  me, right? Like news just becomes entertainment, right? You, you, you are
Speaker 5:  not seeking out news, you are seeking out entertainment
Speaker 5:  and you happen to find out things about what is happening as a result.
Speaker 5:  The problem with it being entertainment is that it is not always accurate.
Speaker 5:  You know, listen, this is like a podcast we're chatting, but we also, like,
Speaker 5:  we uphold the same like rigorous standards as, as we do on the
Speaker 5:  verges website. Every single thing we're saying we are making sure is
Speaker 5:  accurate
Speaker 4:  Here. I have never been wrong on The Vergecast before ever.
Speaker 5:  Listen, our takes our takes no promises there.
Speaker 5:  But you know, this makes a lot of sense, right? And I think like, to to,
Speaker 5:  to go back to your arguing about tv, it's like yeah, people are looking for
Speaker 5:  the more entertaining and engaging experiences and TV
Speaker 5:  in a lot of like, number one it's, it's, it's old, it's inconvenient.
Speaker 5:  It is also just like, it is work in a way that flipping
Speaker 5:  through TikTok is actually like pretty fun. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  No, it just, it makes me think of like, do you remember that phase
Speaker 4:  when Facebook went from like a, a thing that
Speaker 4:  young people did and then all of a sudden it felt like in, in the span
Speaker 4:  of a week everybody's parents joined Facebook. Yeah. Like, do, do you remember
Speaker 4:  that moment where all of a sudden everyone was on, you could just assume
Speaker 4:  other people had Facebook. That's kind of what it feels like we're going
Speaker 4:  through right now with a lot of this stuff where it's like none of these
Speaker 4:  trends are surprising. Like you're saying, like, this has been happening.
Speaker 4:  We've been talking about it, but the speed at which it happened
Speaker 4:  and then this sort of immediate flip to like,
Speaker 4:  just everybody's on TikTok now. It's not like every
Speaker 4:  your, your parents are on TikTok now. God, I hope my parents are not
Speaker 4:  on TikTok now, but like many people's parents are on TikTok now. And
Speaker 4:  the, that, that thing has just happened. Like the shift
Speaker 4:  is done and it, it will keep growing. But whatever inflection point
Speaker 4:  we have been looking for
Speaker 4:  happened, like, it, it, it, it inflected. Yes. And I think
Speaker 4:  now we're just gonna have to like, there's going to be so many downstream
Speaker 4:  effects of all of that. Even like the, the way that these
Speaker 4:  giant news organizations that are used to vast amounts of
Speaker 4:  money being thrown off by their cable news networks, that's gonna change.
Speaker 4:  They're gonna start thinking differently about how these platforms work.
Speaker 4:  That's already been happening, but it's only gonna accelerate. Like all of
Speaker 4:  this stuff is gonna change.
Speaker 5:  I mean, it's interesting, like news was the flagship program on a
Speaker 5:  lot of these big broadcast networks, right? Yeah. Like this was the primetime
Speaker 5:  show. It happened like around dinnertime or right after dinnertime, so you
Speaker 5:  could all watch it together, said it was there when you got home from work.
Speaker 4:  Well, and then the next generation was 24 hour cable news was like the killer
Speaker 4:  app of cable news, right? It was cable.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And you look at Netflix, how many news shows do they have?
Speaker 4:  There's like John Lenney's show is like the closest thing
Speaker 5:  They have. Yeah, yeah. Right. Like it it is just so interesting that news
Speaker 5:  is just not a programming category that, that people are bothering with.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. It's, I I don't know what to make of any of this. And I think
Speaker 4:  I, like you said earlier, none of this is a statement of quality. There's
Speaker 4:  a lot of trash on tv, there's a lot of bad news on tv,
Speaker 4:  but it is like, it is different now. And it, and it, and it, it happened
Speaker 4:  more quickly I think than anybody expected it to. Yeah. And we're like,
Speaker 4:  it's all gonna get faster from here. I think like I just, I I remember talking
Speaker 4:  to folks for this YouTube story that I was writing and one of the things
Speaker 4:  they said was that when YouTube hit the top of the
Speaker 4:  Nielsen gauge when it first was on the Nielsen gauge, and it was like sort
Speaker 4:  of apples to apples how big it was as a TV streaming platform,
Speaker 4:  YouTube's entire business shifted because all of a sudden everybody saw it
Speaker 4:  differently. Right? And that is like, it, it can happen that fast. These
Speaker 4:  people look at these things and they go, oh, this one is winning and this
Speaker 4:  one is losing, we're gonna go on the winning team. And it just, that's how
Speaker 4:  it spirals.
Speaker 5:  It's also really funny how much this, all this, like we, this whole
Speaker 5:  streaming thing started as a way to get away from ads and commercials
Speaker 5:  and actually it's all just looped back around. And the thing that is driving
Speaker 5:  it is that the ad dollars are now in streaming. Yeah. Everybody's
Speaker 5:  rushing their 'cause that's where it is.
Speaker 5:  Can't escape it.
Speaker 4:  No, this is just what we do here. Okay, wait, a couple more streaming things
Speaker 4:  and then we should take a break. One, I think we just need to take
Speaker 4:  like a very brief victory lap because Max or
Speaker 4:  Warner Brothers Discovery announced this week that when you go into
Speaker 4:  the Max app, which is not yet called HBO Max again, but will be soon.
Speaker 4:  Every time I open the app on my tv, I'm like waiting for it to change. And
Speaker 4:  it's gonna be such a joyful moment when it switches to HBO Max. I'm gonna
Speaker 4:  laugh hysterically. But anyway, now they're, they're
Speaker 4:  doing AI video previews and they're actually going to be
Speaker 4:  mining platform data to figure out which parts of a show or
Speaker 4:  movie they should show you in the preview in order to make you more likely
Speaker 4:  to watch it. And this is an idea that we had on The Verge. We, we
Speaker 4:  invented this on The Vergecast and no one can convince me otherwise. I
Speaker 4:  don't remember what it was, but I'll find it because
Speaker 5:  We did. I cannot wait until they start showing the twist at the
Speaker 5:  climax of movies. And people, you know, are just
Speaker 5:  like, what the heck you guys,
Speaker 4:  Do you ever do the thing on YouTube where like it has the, it has the little
Speaker 4:  graph of how much people play it and you tell, and you just skip right to
Speaker 4:  the most replayed bit.
Speaker 5:  I only do that on YouTube that like, why would you click anywhere else? Of
Speaker 5:  course,
Speaker 4:  It's just, you go to the sixth sense, you just, I'm,
Speaker 5:  It was, it's
Speaker 4:  He was dead the time.
Speaker 5:  This is what I needed. Yeah, like that. Of course. It's why like, oh, this
Speaker 5:  sounded intriguing.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The the AI is going to be both right and horribly, horribly wrong.
Speaker 4:  And then the other one is the, the, we're gonna talk
Speaker 4:  a bunch about meta in the lightning round. 'cause a really fascinating set
Speaker 4:  of meta news this week. But the, the streaming thing that it did this week
Speaker 4:  was basically rename and rebrand
Speaker 4:  all of the video on all of Meta's products, particularly on Facebook
Speaker 4:  as reels. Okay. And so,
Speaker 5:  Oh my god, me and Barbara Krasnoff on our team tried
Speaker 5:  to get to the bottom of this a few months ago. We were trying to figure out
Speaker 5:  like the different video products and what happened. You put, and
Speaker 5:  Facebook had at least three different video products. Oh my God. And I
Speaker 5:  wanna be clear, they looked the same, they worked the same, they
Speaker 5:  were accessible through the same apps. They were just in different places.
Speaker 5:  And we emailed them And I believe they were like, yeah,
Speaker 5:  some of them will play content from the others and others won't play content
Speaker 5:  from the others. And so there's sort of different silos, but they're not
Speaker 5:  different silo.
Speaker 4:  Jake, are you saying we deserve credit for this too? Did we do this when
Speaker 4:  you emailed Meta? Were somebody sent that to Mark and he was like, that's
Speaker 4:  a good idea, Jake, I should do that.
Speaker 5:  I, I'm not sure, I'm not sure what was ever happening over there. I
Speaker 5:  don't know how they were operating this, it, it,
Speaker 5:  it was the most confusing way to operate three video
Speaker 5:  services. Yes. I guess, I don't know. I don't know how this emerged. And
Speaker 5:  so yes, finally here's the thing. It like
Speaker 5:  on one level Facebook says all video is now reels. It's like,
Speaker 5:  oh man. But on the other it's like, no. Like, actually, actually
Speaker 5:  this is like so much more sensible Yes. Than what they were doing
Speaker 5:  beforehand. That I'm actually like, thank goodness, like
Speaker 5:  EE even if this means the real situation might be worse because it's gonna
Speaker 5:  be flooded with more stuff. It's like it was way too complicated beforehand.
Speaker 4:  Oh yeah. I think, I think the, the most
Speaker 4:  problematic outcome of this is I think it makes very clear that
Speaker 4:  Facebook's future is just as a video player
Speaker 4:  that seriously, like I think Facebook is going to be, it's gonna be
Speaker 4:  groups, it's gonna be Marketplace, and it's gonna be a video player. And,
Speaker 4:  And I think the idea of Facebook as like the
Speaker 4:  repository for all of the video created elsewhere on Meta
Speaker 4:  properties is their best idea about how to bring people
Speaker 4:  back to Facebook.
Speaker 4:  Will it work? I don't know, but I think, I think that is pretty clearly where
Speaker 4:  we're headed. And this gives them a way to just like pour everything back
Speaker 4:  into Facebook. Because again, Facebook is very important to
Speaker 4:  Mark Zuckerberg in a way that I don't think any of the other products are.
Speaker 4:  And they will do everything they can to get people opening the Facebook app
Speaker 4:  as often as possible. Just one other thought on this is I think it's
Speaker 4:  very important to Facebook and to meta
Speaker 4:  at large to be competitive as a video platform. And
Speaker 4:  I've, I've written about this a bunch, but like anything you can do
Speaker 4:  to juice view counts, you will do. And so for meta
Speaker 4:  to take all of these disparate video platforms and just roll them into one
Speaker 4:  is going to make all of the numbers look bigger and is gonna make it a much
Speaker 4:  more compelling appearing creator platform, it's gonna make it seem like
Speaker 4:  reach is much bigger. And so, like one of the things Mark Zuckerberg has
Speaker 4:  been saying is he wants Facebook to be culturally relevant. Again, I
Speaker 4:  think that might be impossible, but I think you can juice video numbers
Speaker 4:  in a such a way that will suggest cultural relevance and that might be
Speaker 4:  all you need. If the goal is to just make a lot of money.
Speaker 5:  Thi this tracks me. I think I'm, maybe I'm underestimating them. I'm
Speaker 5:  not convinced this will necessarily work in a, at least in a good quality
Speaker 5:  way. But I I I think this actually loops all the way
Speaker 5:  back to the YouTube TV stuff that we were talking about.
Speaker 5:  Do you want to juice engagement? Do you wanna juice time
Speaker 5:  spent? Have people watch videos all day, right?
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent. YouTube, they change their algorithm to promote longer
Speaker 5:  videos. Okay, great. Now the videos are longer, now they're
Speaker 5:  better on tv now people are watching more YouTube on tv. You should make
Speaker 5:  your videos even longer 'cause people are sitting back
Speaker 4:  All right, we're back. It's time for the lightning round.
Speaker 4:  Alright, so since NE's not here, we're going to, we're going to
Speaker 4:  skip Brendan Carr as a dummy for a week. We're gonna give Brendan two weeks
Speaker 4:  to be a dummy. But there is one tiny bit of news that is
Speaker 4:  related to our man, man, Brendan, that we should just, we should just
Speaker 4:  mention very briefly, which is that the Senate confirmed Olivia Trusty
Speaker 4:  who was Trump's pick to be the new commissioner of the
Speaker 4:  FCC. The vote was, let's see, 53 to 45.
Speaker 4:  And now this means there are three people on the FCC
Speaker 4:  instead of two and kind of just one because Anna Gomez is just like
Speaker 4:  running around telling everybody that Brendan Carr is a monster and waiting
Speaker 4:  to get fired.
Speaker 4:  Hooray, great job everybody. Good government. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  This actually has a big impact, right? There is now a quorum again, right,
Speaker 5:  because before they fired too many people and So there just
Speaker 5:  weren't enough people for the FCC to actually officially legally get things
Speaker 5:  done. Right now there's three of them. Now they can, this
Speaker 5:  is sort of, this is like a slightly weird process.
Speaker 5:  FCC commissioners are usually nominated and confirmed
Speaker 5:  in pairs. There's usually one Democrat and one Republican at the same time.
Speaker 5:  Interesting. Now maybe you can make the argument that, okay, there already
Speaker 5:  is Anna Gomez and, and there's an odd number. So
Speaker 5:  may maybe that's why I think some people are definitely a little worried
Speaker 5:  about the fact that they only did a Republican this time.
Speaker 5:  The the, this is actually like very strange to me, but the
Speaker 5:  communications act, which which established FCC, it's a legal
Speaker 5:  requirement that there can only be three people
Speaker 5:  out of the five commissioners. Only three of them can be of the same party.
Speaker 5:  So that there is some limit to your ability to
Speaker 5:  stack the commission. That being said, could the other
Speaker 5:  two people be like the wig party? And I don't think anybody's tested that
Speaker 5:  yet. So we'll find out. But yes, now the FCC
Speaker 5:  back at it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I mean can can I just, can I just read you a quote
Speaker 4:  from our story, which I feel like just perfectly, it says all the things
Speaker 4:  that I would like to say much better than I would say them. So
Speaker 4:  Lauren Finer wrote a story for us about Olivia Trusty and the
Speaker 4:  the nomination process. The confirmation process. And
Speaker 4:  she got a quote from a guy named Matt Wood, who is the VP of policy and general
Speaker 4:  counsel of a nonpartisan group called Free Press Action. I'm just gonna read
Speaker 4:  you the whole quote and then we're gonna move on. He says, in normal times
Speaker 4:  there would be little reason to oppose the confirmation of a candidate as
Speaker 4:  qualified as trustee, but these are not normal times Trustee's confirmation
Speaker 4:  gives Carr the majority. He needs to radically reshape the media sector in
Speaker 4:  Trump's image, including offering policy favors to large broadcasters in
Speaker 4:  exchange for their unwavering loyalty to the president. I agree
Speaker 4:  with every single word of that and that seems
Speaker 4:  to be what is going on. Let's move on. We'll, we'll come back to this, you
Speaker 4:  know, we'll just
Speaker 5:  Just end on that light
Speaker 4:  Note. I just, yeah, Brenda Carr remains a dummy. We'll get back to this next
Speaker 4:  week and now an
Speaker 5:  Empowered one
Speaker 4:  Now, now a dummy with
Speaker 5:  Feel good about
Speaker 4:  That. Yeah. Someone else who can sign the papers for him.
Speaker 4:  Next up we got a little tiny nugget
Speaker 4:  of maybe kind of new news about Siri.
Speaker 4:  Everybody is, everybody is doing the, the
Speaker 4:  developer beta stuff, liquid glass is bad.
Speaker 4:  They're out there doing more interviews about iPad os and we continue
Speaker 4:  to hear spring 2026 for better. Siri,
Speaker 4:  I just, I just wanna put that out there.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Do you buy
Speaker 4:  It? No,
Speaker 5:  I thought there'd be some equivocation there. Yeah, I don I don't either.
Speaker 5:  Right? Like se 2 20 26. That sounds like maybe an internal target.
Speaker 5:  It, it just, it also just seems very weird to me the idea that they would
Speaker 5:  drop such a major feature so late in operating systems
Speaker 5:  release cycle.
Speaker 4:  I, I think if, if you were to say, would I bet on
Speaker 4:  fall 2026 with like the next round of software, I would
Speaker 4:  say more likely because it seems
Speaker 4:  possible to me that there's going to have, they will have had a lot of time
Speaker 4:  to do the work. They, they are going to ship some of the features, but not
Speaker 4:  all of them. Like, I think, I think it's possible developers will have
Speaker 4:  had another full year to do the app intent stuff that I think is gonna make
Speaker 4:  a lot of this stuff work. Like we talked about last week
Speaker 4:  maybe, maybe I would believe that. But I, I think you're right, the idea
Speaker 4:  that they would just like ship this thing in March
Speaker 4:  as a like 0.4 update does not, I don know just
Speaker 4:  doesn't pass the test for me. I don't buy
Speaker 5:  It. Neither do I. One thing that I think is also gonna be really tricky
Speaker 5:  for Apple going forward is, you know, they, they have been
Speaker 5:  breaking from this a little bit, but traditionally they, they release software
Speaker 5:  once a year, right? And they have some small updates here and there and,
Speaker 5:  and that, that has been breaking, that has been breaking a little bit where
Speaker 5:  they'll, they'll do like, you know, a little bit of an update in the fall,
Speaker 5:  maybe a little bit in the spring. But basically it all comes once a year.
Speaker 5:  And I think for the AI world in particular, which is
Speaker 5:  moving so fast and which is seeing like some really
Speaker 5:  material leaps from release to release where it's like, it, something can
Speaker 5:  go from like, oh, AI can never do that. It's so broken to like, oh, it can
Speaker 5:  like kind of do that. Which to be clear is, is meaningful
Speaker 5:  in a, in a couple months time. Like Apple really puts itself at
Speaker 5:  a pretty big disa like set aside that they
Speaker 5:  have to just make Siri work, which apparently is a, a monumental task,
Speaker 5:  right? Just being able to keep up with all the other, you know,
Speaker 5:  AI players. They, they're putting themselves at a really big disadvantage
Speaker 5:  with the way that they make their products and ship so infrequently.
Speaker 5:  So I, I look forward to seeing if they can meet this, you
Speaker 5:  know, reported internal date. I suspect, I suspect later in
Speaker 5:  2026 feels more likely to me just given how much they've been
Speaker 5:  struggling so far.
Speaker 4:  I was talking to somebody the other day about all of this and
Speaker 4:  people have been throwing out the, you know, they, they should just kill
Speaker 4:  the Siri brand thing for a while And I
Speaker 4:  just asked somebody, I was like, well would you know you're a product person,
Speaker 4:  would you get rid of the Siri brand and what would you rebrand it to? And
Speaker 4:  they were like, dude, spotlight, it's sitting right there. People like Spotlight.
Speaker 4:  People know what it is. People understand how it works. It's not trying to
Speaker 4:  do everything, but it is trying to do all the things that people actually
Speaker 4:  want. Just call it Spotlight. Like you don't even have to retire Siri, just
Speaker 4:  keep adding features to Spotlight. Yes. And I was like, oh my God, that's
Speaker 4:  it. Like I, I I don't think that's gonna happen, but I kind of think that
Speaker 4:  is a brilliant idea that I wish I had had. I love it on my own. Alright,
Speaker 4:  next up. Some news that caused some
Speaker 4:  surprising amount of both consternation and funny jokes on the
Speaker 4:  internet this week. WhatsApp is officially getting
Speaker 4:  ads, ads, ads are coming to, let's see if I
Speaker 4:  remember this correctly. There are gonna be ads in the, the status sort of
Speaker 4:  story screens that I sincerely believe no one ever looks at.
Speaker 4:  There are gonna be promoted channels in the channels interface, which
Speaker 4:  I think is actually growing pretty fast from what I hear. Channels have actually
Speaker 4:  been a pretty big hit, especially globally. So notably the place
Speaker 4:  that ads are not is in your chats,
Speaker 4:  but this feels to me like maybe not the beginning of the end
Speaker 4:  of WhatsApp, but the beginning of a very different Whatsapp.
Speaker 5:  Well this is also right, like the, the founders famously
Speaker 5:  never wanted ads in the app and like look like
Speaker 5:  they had just watched Fight Club. They were like, kind of like on one and
Speaker 5:  they were like, ads are the death of humanity. Like, it was like a little
Speaker 5:  dramatic and like it's, it's, you know, ads bring us a lot of free stuff.
Speaker 5:  It's all right. But it is true, right? I I think they did like,
Speaker 5:  they did have a pretty singular point, which is that like that a a
Speaker 5:  a chat app is really intimate and personal. These are all of your friends,
Speaker 5:  they're people, you know and care about. Having ads
Speaker 5:  inserted between that is actually pretty disruptive. It's jarring,
Speaker 5:  it changes the experience in a material way. And while Meta has
Speaker 5:  not yet, you know, gone and done that, you know, it's
Speaker 5:  starting, it's happening. They went, Hey, we need to make some more money
Speaker 5:  off Whatsapp. How are we gonna juice it? The obvious answer, it's ads,
Speaker 4:  Right? Yeah. I mean there was the business chat thing that I think has, has
Speaker 4:  turned into some of a business for Meta, but this is also like,
Speaker 4:  clearly this is the thing that Meta does best is ads at massive
Speaker 4:  scale. And this is also the thing that Meta is
Speaker 4:  best equipped to do from an advertising perspective, which is advertised
Speaker 4:  for businesses next to other businesses. Like that's, that's what Facebook
Speaker 4:  ads are. Yeah. Like this makes perfect sense to me from a
Speaker 4:  meta business perspective. Like of course this is what you would do and it
Speaker 4:  is probably the least intrusive thing they could have done
Speaker 4:  in Whatsapp, but that's a really
Speaker 4:  high bar, right? Like it's all pretty intrusive. And I think
Speaker 4:  there was an interesting thing that it, it had to note
Speaker 4:  explicitly, which is that it won't use your
Speaker 4:  messages or your information to inform and
Speaker 4:  and tune the ads. And this, this is the like perception
Speaker 4:  change that I think is so hard to do after the fact, which is come in and
Speaker 4:  say, yes, of course we've been reading all of your messages, but we're
Speaker 4:  not gonna do anything with them. And even though, like I actually, I have
Speaker 4:  no reason not to believe Meta's lines about encryption.
Speaker 4:  There are a million conspiracy theories out there, but if, if, if there has
Speaker 4:  been a proof that Whatsapp messages are not encrypted, I
Speaker 4:  I I have not seen it. So I will assume that they are, but you
Speaker 4:  don't, that that perception goes away quickly. This sense of like,
Speaker 4:  I am in an actually private place, which already became
Speaker 4:  harder for Whatsapp to do when it was bought by Meta A company that is not
Speaker 4:  famous for being a good citizen of your privacy
Speaker 4:  to then say there's ads here. But we
Speaker 4:  still don't, we we're not looking, we're just putting ads. It's just a constant
Speaker 4:  reminder of who is here with me in this place where I'm supposed to be able
Speaker 4:  to be by myself.
Speaker 5:  No, that's so real. Like e everybody thinks Facebook is like tapping their
Speaker 5:  microphone and it's, it's like they just know everything
Speaker 5:  else about you. Right? Right. They, they they don't need to reach. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That probably
Speaker 4:  Doesn't have to read your Whatsapp.
Speaker 5:  Right? Right. They don't have to, they already, they already know this stuff
Speaker 5:  and, and now it's going to be very like abundantly clear how much they
Speaker 5:  know about you.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Yeah. I think it's, it's, it's pushing in this very
Speaker 4:  interesting like snapchatty kind of direction, which is very funny because
Speaker 4:  it just absolutely decimated Snapchat as a product, but they're trying to
Speaker 4:  do some Snapchat stuff. But the, the last thing
Speaker 4:  I wanna say on this before we move on is, is just genuine kudos
Speaker 4:  to Signal for immediately after this happened,
Speaker 4:  screenshotting the, the, an announcement of it and saying
Speaker 4:  this was Meredith Whitaker, the, the president of Signal who said,
Speaker 4:  use Signal. We promise no AI clutter, no surveillance ads, whatever the rest
Speaker 4:  of the industry does, we lead, we don't follow heart emoji.
Speaker 4:  Nailed it. No. Like it is very funny how,
Speaker 4:  how much signals marketing is just written for
Speaker 4:  itself and they just, every time they're like, oh look, somebody did a bad
Speaker 4:  thing, we won't do that Use signal. That's their whole marketing message
Speaker 4:  and it, it just keeps working and it's very funny And I enjoy it very much.
Speaker 4:  It's good. All right, couple more and then we should get out of here. There
Speaker 4:  was this interesting change while we're talking about ads to
Speaker 4:  Reddit this week that I found really fascinating. Did you, did you track
Speaker 4:  this at all?
Speaker 5:  What do you mean by track this?
Speaker 4:  Did you, did you pay attention to what Reddit is doing at all? Reddit ads
Speaker 4:  are not required to be interesting to you, but I I am happy to explain it
Speaker 4:  to you if you'd like to
Speaker 5:  Not No, tell tell me, tell me. Yeah, whatever. So
Speaker 4:  Reddit basically forever trying to grow as a business and has realized
Speaker 4:  that the best thing it has going for it is all of the posts and comments
Speaker 4:  on Reddit. So Reddit announced two things for advertisers this week.
Speaker 4:  One of them is that it will basically let you take
Speaker 4:  all of the insights and all of the information from all of Reddit and use
Speaker 4:  it to inform your ads, which is the sort of thing that is like, true on
Speaker 4:  lots of platforms. But is is again the kind of thing that Reddit went
Speaker 4:  out of its way to be like we are a user friendly and moderation friendly
Speaker 4:  platform. When in like Facebook was like, screw you, we sell ads based on
Speaker 4:  all your stuff. Reddit is just fully doing that. But the thing that I find
Speaker 4:  even wilder is that now if you're an advertiser, you
Speaker 4:  can have an ad on Reddit and then right underneath it
Speaker 4:  Reddit will, will dynamically the AI driven e
Speaker 4:  place positive Reddit posts about your product that
Speaker 4:  you're trying to advertise. So they will just find people who said nice things
Speaker 4:  about you on Reddit and just dump it right underneath your ad all over Reddit.
Speaker 5:  That feels, that feels weird. I I it's bad. It's interesting when, when I
Speaker 5:  saw the headline for this, I, I part of this feels genius
Speaker 5:  and part of this feels, feels really not good. Like
Speaker 5:  it makes sense to me if, if you know
Speaker 5:  your Mercedes and somebody's like, check on my sick Mercedes,
Speaker 5:  great. Like go promote that. That seems cool. And, and like, you know, maybe
Speaker 5:  that's a little weird if you're the guy who gets promoted, but just like
Speaker 5:  streaming a bunch of random comments from out of context that feels a, that
Speaker 5:  feels off and, And I feel like users are going
Speaker 5:  to feel betrayed. 'cause you don't, you do not believe that your comment
Speaker 5:  is going to be used in that way. Right? It is meant to be in a
Speaker 5:  specific spot for a specific community. And I think once you start moving
Speaker 5:  that around, and particularly once you start putting dollars behind it that
Speaker 5:  you, the user are not seeing that starts to get really uncomfortable really
Speaker 5:  fast. So I understand why Reddit is doing this. There, there's like
Speaker 5:  something I think very smart about, Hey, there's
Speaker 5:  people saying nice things about you and like having fun with your stuff.
Speaker 5:  Why don't like just promote that instead of putting a boring ad that nobody
Speaker 5:  wants to read. I like that. But yeah, they have to be really careful.
Speaker 5:  Like these, you know, community is everything for Reddit
Speaker 5:  and this is a thing that is disruptive of that in a, in a very real way.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I would just encourage everybody to go look at the screenshot in Jay's
Speaker 4:  story, which we'll put in the show notes. It's a lucid air ad that just looks
Speaker 4:  like a normal ad. It has a picture of the, the car, it looks like a Reddit
Speaker 4:  ad. And then right below it there's an AI summary that says
Speaker 4:  Redditers show excitement for Lucid Air's performance, quality and innovation.
Speaker 4:  They also appreciate the company's service and delivery. And then it has
Speaker 4:  a, a side scrolling list of presumably positive
Speaker 4:  posts about Lucid. This
Speaker 5:  Is, I'm looking at this gif this is the worst possible version of this feature.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like I just, I don't understand this at all. It,
Speaker 4:  It feels so disingenuous and like not representative of what is actually
Speaker 4:  great about Reddit.
Speaker 5:  No, no. This is, this doesn't make sense at all. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  I, I'm,
Speaker 5:  And this feels terrible if you're one of these users too. Like, it looks
Speaker 5:  like you made an ad.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. That's alright. Two more things that we should get outta here. First
Speaker 4:  thing, the Senate passed the Genius Bill, a terrific,
Speaker 4:  terrific acronym to get to Genius. I, I'm very proud of this for everybody.
Speaker 4:  And basically what it does is it establishes a regulatory framework for stable
Speaker 4:  coins and crypto tokens, basically so that private companies can
Speaker 4:  now launch digital coins pegged to the value of the US dollar.
Speaker 4:  As far as I can tell Jake, this is a huge win for crypto people, right? Like
Speaker 4:  every, every, as far everybody seems very excited that this is
Speaker 5:  Happening. Yeah. I I think the idea is that it legitimizes stable coins.
Speaker 5:  It also, it also means that the US is not going to, you know, alternatively
Speaker 5:  crack down on them. Right? True. I think that's the bigger fear. And and
Speaker 5:  this is saying, Nope, go ahead, go do your thing. I read through some of
Speaker 5:  the bill and it, it does put some like, I think, you know,
Speaker 5:  useful requirements to place, right? It, it requires that you
Speaker 5:  actually back your crypto token with, with,
Speaker 5:  you know, real assets. It requires that once a month you publish what those
Speaker 5:  assets are. So there is some transparency and there is some requirements
Speaker 5:  here.
Speaker 5:  I have to say this still feels like a, you know,
Speaker 5:  product in need of a market to me.
Speaker 5:  But yeah, this is just a win for the crypto industry. It it is an
Speaker 5:  allowance for them to make these tokens.
Speaker 5:  Theoretically. It will make them less scammy, theoretically.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I I would encourage anyone who wants to know how this stuff works to
Speaker 4:  read about Tether, which is a really fascinating, stable coin and probably
Speaker 4:  the most successful one we've had so far has also had a just
Speaker 4:  long running series of shenanigans around it. And I think
Speaker 4:  it's a good, it's a good place to understand like how this works
Speaker 4:  and where it can both go really well and get really weird.
Speaker 4:  But yeah, the, the incursion of crypto people into the government
Speaker 4:  continues a pace. And one of the interesting things about this was a lot
Speaker 4:  of the Democrat opposition to this bill has been
Speaker 4:  about essentially like Trump coin exists and now this makes
Speaker 4:  Donald Trump, it just lets him regulate his own money now. And that's
Speaker 4:  a strange thing. And so we will, we will have to see how all of that shakes
Speaker 4:  out, but let's end on some better news, which I am
Speaker 4:  much more unabashedly excited about, which is
Speaker 4:  new fedi verse stuff for threads. And
Speaker 4:  normally this is where Neli And I just like gas each other up about how great
Speaker 4:  the Fedi verse is. My question for you, Jake, is, are you excited about this
Speaker 4:  at
Speaker 5:  All? That's so funny. I I was gonna flip this back around because I, I'm
Speaker 5:  the person who's, I, I'm a little more skeptical. I was gonna ask you,
Speaker 5:  it seems to me that some of the Fedi verse momentum
Speaker 5:  has maybe slowed down. And admittedly this is a, this is a pretty big
Speaker 5:  announcement because I think when Threads launched, I think it was at Peak
Speaker 5:  fedi verse hype, and they're like, we're gonna be won the same with the Fedi
Speaker 5:  verse. Yeah. And then last year they're like, there's some fedi verse if
Speaker 5:  you want it. And now maybe there's finally a little bit
Speaker 5:  more fedi verse, but it does feel like in some
Speaker 5:  ways it now feels like things are even more fragmented to me. Right? Like
Speaker 5:  nowadays we're like, blue Sky has a personality. You know, what you get
Speaker 5:  on Blue Sky Threads is a personality, you know, what you get on on, on threads.
Speaker 5:  I don't know what's happening on Mastodon, but it is, it is there,
Speaker 4:  It very much has its own personality. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So I I
Speaker 4:  Very much So
Speaker 5:  I think like, honestly thi this is, it is encouraging to me to
Speaker 5:  see that Threads is still pushing forward on this. 'cause I, I,
Speaker 5:  I could very easily have seen them just being like, hmm. And, and letting
Speaker 5:  it drop. But I am curious from your perspective, somebody who is following
Speaker 5:  the Fed averse stuff much more closely. How, how you feel
Speaker 5:  about the momentum for, for the Fedi verse right now,
Speaker 4:  I'm torn. So the, the news we should say it was essentially now there
Speaker 4:  is a, a semi dedicated feed
Speaker 4:  in the Threads app for Fedi verse posts. And I say semi dedicate
Speaker 4:  because it's, it's a feed within the following feed. So if you
Speaker 4:  want to get there, you have to open the app, go to your following feed, and
Speaker 4:  then there's a little menu at the top that shows you fedi verse post and
Speaker 4:  you tap that and you go to the fedi verse feed. So it's, it's there and it
Speaker 4:  is like front ish and center ish, but it's not like
Speaker 4:  full fedi verse integration with the, for you feed on threats.
Speaker 4:  But it is a meaningful integration of like, now you can see fedi verse
Speaker 4:  posts inside of threats. And that's a, that's a real thing.
Speaker 4:  What I find more, maybe not alarming, but
Speaker 4:  potentially worrisome is talking to Peter
Speaker 4:  Coddle, who's a, a software engineer at Meta working on a lot of this stuff
Speaker 4:  and seems to be kind of the, the spokesperson for a lot of meta's
Speaker 4:  threads work and Fedi verse work.
Speaker 4:  Meta doesn't seem to know exactly what it wants to do here, which I think
Speaker 4:  is really interesting. There's, there's one vision of the Fedi verse that
Speaker 4:  is like
Speaker 4:  perfectly interoperable, interconnected, everything, right? Like
Speaker 4:  I can post from one place to another place, you can like it and I'll see
Speaker 4:  it and we can have a sort of cross platform conversation
Speaker 4:  and like what if Facebook was, the internet is like that way of thinking
Speaker 4:  about it, right? And that is
Speaker 4:  exciting but also complicated. And then there's another version of the Fedi
Speaker 4:  verse that is basically like, there are just a million
Speaker 4:  things in a bucket, right? Everything is content and, and
Speaker 4:  newsletters are a type of post and images are a type of post and videos are
Speaker 4:  a type of post and podcasts are a type of post. And all those posts go into
Speaker 4:  one giant database of posts. And then the cool thing
Speaker 4:  about the Fedi verse is you can build any kind of app you want to both create
Speaker 4:  and, and consume those posts. That's a very different idea
Speaker 4:  than the sort of completely interoperable social network, right? It's just
Speaker 4:  an, it's a like content machine that is not run by one company.
Speaker 4:  Both very cool, very different. And meta does not seem
Speaker 4:  to know which of those it wants threads to be. So right now it's much
Speaker 4:  more like you, it it, the fedi verse feed in threads is basically like an
Speaker 4:  RSS reader for Fedi verse posts. And that's not nothing, but it's not a
Speaker 4:  completely interoperable social network. And then
Speaker 4:  on the flip side, they're starting to do some of this work where like if
Speaker 4:  I, if I post and you like something in a fedi verse app that comes back to
Speaker 4:  threads, but that continues to be kind of messy and
Speaker 4:  weird. And So I I just, we're at this point now where
Speaker 4:  somebody needs to decide what we're doing here. And I think, I have thought
Speaker 4:  for the last year it would be threads that just by virtue
Speaker 4:  of its size and by virtue of meta's importance to the internet
Speaker 4:  threads would dictate a lot of things. And from what I've heard from Fedi
Speaker 4:  verse people, the threads folks have actually been pretty good citizens of
Speaker 4:  this. They have worked with the protocol, they have played by the rules,
Speaker 4:  they have been, you know, useful members of different systems
Speaker 4:  and, and actually part of meetings rather than just like coming
Speaker 4:  and dictating how all this is gonna work because platform's huge. But at
Speaker 4:  some point somebody has to just look at it and be like, here's what this
Speaker 4:  is for. And I still don't see that. And I worry
Speaker 4:  even talking to them that they don't know what it is and until they, until
Speaker 4:  someone decides what it is, it's gonna keep kind of being nothing.
Speaker 4:  And, and part of me is it like at this point now we're two
Speaker 4:  and a half years into the sort of post
Speaker 4:  Twitter era and it doesn't feel like we've made
Speaker 4:  progress. And I'm sort of like, what if we just had an answer?
Speaker 4:  Like I don't even, I don't even care what it is, just pick one of the things
Speaker 4:  and start doing it in a like, powerful, mainstream way
Speaker 4:  and instead we're we're kind of like, we're we're half answering a hundred
Speaker 4:  different questions.
Speaker 5:  No, I I think that makes a lot of sense. And and this is what I think is,
Speaker 5:  is so strange about this, the current state of the Fedi verse,
Speaker 5:  in some ways it feels like there are more fedi verse
Speaker 5:  products and in some ways they feel more siloed to me,
Speaker 5:  right? Somehow we've ended up in a universe where I
Speaker 5:  can go on these different networks that accomplish the same thing that are
Speaker 5:  all allegedly interoperable, but most of which
Speaker 5:  are basically just the one network. And
Speaker 5:  you know, I think with threads it's like, just do it, right?
Speaker 5:  Like why like you have this technology, you have a giant team, just do it.
Speaker 5:  Right?
Speaker 5:  And I don't quite know why they haven't. And I think maybe this is because
Speaker 5:  they haven't quite figured out how they want to interact with the Fedi verse,
Speaker 5:  what they want their fed averse input to be. And
Speaker 5:  you know, this is the thing, right? It, it comes from a very big company
Speaker 5:  that has its own interests and there's a a, a lot that
Speaker 5:  they have at stake there. And so it makes sense that they're taking a slow
Speaker 5:  approach. But I think that also just makes it so much more complicated for
Speaker 5:  every other player in the space. 'cause you just don't know what they're
Speaker 5:  gonna do when they're gonna do it. And I think, you know, this, this does
Speaker 5:  feel meaningful to me. It feels really meaningful to me that they are continuing
Speaker 5:  to build this, that you actually will be able to get fed stuff. And it's
Speaker 5:  just one of those things where it's like, oh, it's in a sub menu, right?
Speaker 5:  Like
Speaker 4:  It just feels like it's very hard for me to imagine Mark
Speaker 4:  Zuckerberg who is desperately committed to get people back on
Speaker 4:  Facebook and integrate ads everywhere. Also being
Speaker 4:  super enthusiastic about the idea of more interoperability
Speaker 4:  with other platforms. Right? And I just, I've hit this point now where like,
Speaker 4:  as far as I can tell, which is frankly not very far
Speaker 4:  the to do the fedi verse inside of meta is like one of those things you're
Speaker 4:  doing and kind of hoping Mark doesn't notice and
Speaker 4:  that's just never where you wanna be Yeah. With this kind of thing. And So
Speaker 4:  I think I, I sincerely hope I'm wrong And I sincerely hope there's a lot
Speaker 4:  more coming, but it was, this was one of those things that like, I'm, I'm
Speaker 4:  psyched this is as far as it has gone, but it, it doesn't feel like,
Speaker 4:  it doesn't feel like enough to me yet. Yep. Alright,
Speaker 4:  one more and then we're gonna go. Alright. And this one more is, is a thing
Speaker 4:  we just published today. We should say we're, we're recording this on Wednesday
Speaker 4:  because it's Juneteenth on Thursday and today
Speaker 4:  Antonio de Benedetto posted his review of the Framework
Speaker 4:  Laptop 12
Speaker 4:  device that I have been personally very excited about. And boy,
Speaker 4:  is it exactly what I expected it to be. It's so the, this
Speaker 4:  thing is like the, the Framework Laptop, it's $800,
Speaker 4:  it's cool and pink and colorful and pastelly. It's
Speaker 4:  very repairable and upgradeable, which is framework's whole thing.
Speaker 4:  This was designed to be the like, fun, approachable
Speaker 4:  version of what so far has been like a very nerdy brand of
Speaker 4:  computers. And it's like, it's awesome but
Speaker 4:  it's not very good all at the same time. And that is like exactly
Speaker 4:  what I assumed it would be and kind of a bummer,
Speaker 5:  Honestly, this is exactly what I expected And I think like what it needs
Speaker 5:  to be, right? Like if, if, if you haven't seen what the Framework
Speaker 5:  Laptop 12 looks like, like please Google it, it is the most delightful looking
Speaker 5:  laptop. It really is. It's like these pastel like pinks and aquas, it,
Speaker 5:  it is like one of the most fun pieces of tech that has come out in a
Speaker 5:  long time. It's great. And I think if you would just replace this with like
Speaker 5:  a normal, beige, boring thing, you'd be like, okay, but the
Speaker 5:  a hundred percent I, I, I think so much of this thing is the ethos, right?
Speaker 5:  Like it is repairable. It is upgradable, and it is fun. And
Speaker 5:  you know, what, is it a perfect laptop? Absolutely not. Right?
Speaker 5:  But I don like, it couldn't have been, it was not going
Speaker 5:  to be. No, but it, but it, I think you can buy this thing and feel good
Speaker 5:  about it. And, And I love that. Like, I love that they, they
Speaker 5:  delivered on, I think what they were promising here.
Speaker 4:  And there were a lot of things that framework
Speaker 4:  didn't do well here that are actually pretty easy to do well,
Speaker 4:  which I find sort of encouraging, right? Like the webcam is pretty bad
Speaker 4:  and the, the speakers are extremely whatever, and
Speaker 4:  it needs more ram and a better processor, right? Like a, the beauty of this
Speaker 4:  thing is you can upgrade some of those things yourself over time, but B,
Speaker 4:  those are things that a company like framework can
Speaker 4:  just go do better next time. Yeah. So I think to me, I, I look at this
Speaker 4:  and I'm like, okay, this is not the thing that I wanted it to be.
Speaker 4:  The performance isn't amazing. The keyboard isn't amazing. There's just like
Speaker 4:  a lot of sort of near misses, but they all feel
Speaker 4:  correctable. And I think a Antonio's takeaway was very much like, this
Speaker 4:  is a great idea. This is a thing that should exist. This will appeal to lots
Speaker 4:  of people. It just a, we need framework to deliver
Speaker 4:  on the upgrade path here and like, make this thing last a long time, which
Speaker 4:  the company's done a pretty good job of so far. But also like, stay at this
Speaker 4:  one, right? Like keep making adorable laptops and a couple of them from
Speaker 4:  now you'll have one that's awesome. Like, you know, you know what this is
Speaker 4:  making me think of actually is, do you remember the Google Pixel
Speaker 4:  book that was the very thin, like
Speaker 5:  Yes. Oh my gosh,
Speaker 4:  Yes. White and gray laptop that Google made. Yeah, I loved that thing to
Speaker 4:  bits
Speaker 5:  That it was thing had some fans,
Speaker 4:  One of my absolute favorite laptops of all time. And the only downside of
Speaker 4:  it was it had a just big giant
Speaker 4:  monster bezel and looked sort
Speaker 5:  I'm excited, I like I framework has been like, kind of on a roll putting
Speaker 5:  out some cool hardware and yeah, if they can keep at this and like keep doing
Speaker 5:  this on a
Speaker 4:  anybody who's been in a long time. And I would, I would very much like it
Speaker 4:  work in the right market to work. I just want a pink laptop. Like, I don't
Speaker 4:  think I knew I wanted a pink laptop until I read Antonio's review And I was
Speaker 4:  like, this, this color scheme like really works for me. It really works.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. All right. We have gone way over, Jake, it's been a delight to do this
Speaker 4:  with you. This is good. I'm now like nearing the end of
Speaker 4:  my time on The Vergecast before I go on parental leave and I'm starting to
Speaker 4:  have real like graduation sadness. It's like I'm never gonna see my friends
Speaker 4:  again. This is, this is, this is terrible, but
Speaker 5:  We're taking your keys away. It's been, you're not gonna be allowed back
Speaker 5:  in the Zoom.
Speaker 4:  I honestly think it's possible that I'm just never gonna be allowed to do
Speaker 4:  The Vergecast again. Everybody's gonna realize it's much better once I'm
Speaker 4:  gone and it's just gonna be four hours of Brenda Carr as a dummy every week.
Speaker 4:  And that's just what we're doing here. But as always,
Speaker 4:  thank you for doing this. We'll have lots more next week, more stuff on
Speaker 4:  MVNOs. There's some Tesla stuff potentially happening this weekend that we
Speaker 4:  will cover in one way or another next week. But until then,
Speaker 2:  Keep it locked. Rock and roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 1:  you. Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one. The
Speaker 1:  Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network.
Speaker 1:  Our show's produced by Will Por, Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer.
Speaker 1:  And that's it. We'll see you next week.