# Transcript
ID: d219e7b1-dcb3-4e4b-abf4-0de24cd2b483
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7452273277104489538/-2313000298435047577/s93290-US-5146s-1759830948.mp3
Description: Oh, you thought AI was just in your browser and on your phone? Well, the AI is coming from inside the house. The Verge's Jen Pattison Tuohy and Google's Anish Kattukaran both join the show to discuss last week's Google smart home news, including the company's big bet on the Gemini assistant. Anish explains why Google cares about the smart home in the first place, why things haven't exactly gone great so far, and why he's so convinced the new generation of AI can make it work. After that, The Verge's Vee Song joins the show to talk about Peloton's newest gear, including a $6,695 treadmill and a huge new push into personalized AI training features. Vee then sticks around to help David answer a question from the Vergecast Hotline (call 866-VERGE11 or email vergecast@theverge.com!) about how many smartwatches is too many smartwatches. Spoiler alert: the answer is two. But it's not quite as simple as that.
Speaker 1:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of treadmills that
Speaker 1:  don't fit anywhere in my house. So I'm moving and we have this
Speaker 1:  new room in our new house that is basically, it's like a big
Speaker 1:  closet, but my wife looked at it and was like, oh, wouldn't it be cool if
Speaker 1:  we use that as like an exercise room? It's, it has no windows.
Speaker 1:  It's just like a seven foot by five foot cave. And
Speaker 1:  she's like, what if we put a treadmill in there? So we've been shopping for
Speaker 1:  treadmills and it turns out that treadmills are either horrible or
Speaker 1:  $7,000 and in many cases are both of those things. So if you
Speaker 1:  have an idea of a treadmill that isn't gigantic,
Speaker 1:  isn't horrible and isn't $7,000, please tell me
Speaker 1:  my family is dying. We need this. Thank you. Anyway, that is not what
Speaker 1:  we're here to talk about. Actually, we are here a little bit to talk about
Speaker 1:  treadmills, but we're gonna get to that later. We're gonna do two things
Speaker 1:  on The Vergecast today. First, we're gonna talk more about the smart Home.
Speaker 1:  We talked a lot about Amazon and Alexa and Echo devices last week.
Speaker 1:  This week we're gonna dig in to what Google is really up
Speaker 1:  to. I think Google is maybe the company best set up
Speaker 1:  to figure out the smart home, but it's been trying as long as anybody and
Speaker 1:  hasn't really made any progress. So we're gonna talk to Anish Karran, who
Speaker 1:  runs a lot of that stuff at Google and try to figure out whether
Speaker 1:  Google or anybody is actually set up to do this well and do
Speaker 1:  it now. After that, we're gonna talk to V Song about what is going on with
Speaker 1:  Peloton, because Peloton, a company I hadn't thought about in a long time,
Speaker 1:  announced a bunch of really interesting and really expensive stuff
Speaker 1:  last week. So we're gonna get into what it all means and whether the
Speaker 1:  Peloton people are gonna be into it. We also have a really fun question on
Speaker 1:  the Vergecast Hotline that may or may not lead you to buy many more gadgets
Speaker 1:  and put them all over your body. All of that is coming up in just a second.
Speaker 1:  But first, I just found this treadmill that is $200. My wife sent me a link.
Speaker 1:  I'm confident it's horrible, but I have to go read reviews.
Speaker 1:  Please send help. This is The Vergecast, we'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Rinse takes your
Speaker 4:  State Farm help you create a competitive price when you choose to bundle
Speaker 4:  home and auto bundling. Just another way to save with a personal
Speaker 4:  price plan like a good neighbor State Farm is there. Prices are based on
Speaker 4:  rating plans that vary by state coverage. Options are selected by the customer.
Speaker 4:  Availability. Amount of discounts and savings and eligibility vary by state.
Speaker 1:  Alright, we're back. Jen Tui's here. Hi Jen.
Speaker 6:  Hi David. Long time noi,
Speaker 1:  I just can't stop talking to you about Smart Home. Thanks. You have a guest
Speaker 1:  for us today. You, you have, you've brought someone you think would be fun
Speaker 1:  for us to talk to. So just set this up for us a little bit before we get
Speaker 1:  into it. Who, who are we about to talk to?
Speaker 6:  Yes. So we have Anish Cran who is the head of
Speaker 6:  Google Home and Nest. And he is basically the guy that
Speaker 6:  has been leading the sort of resurgence,
Speaker 6:  should we put it that way, or of Google Home o Over the last few years
Speaker 6:  and last week there were a lot of announcements from Google Home about
Speaker 6:  completely rearchitecturing, the Google Home app,
Speaker 6:  new hardware, new software for Google Home, all of which
Speaker 6:  has been sort of developed under his leadership over the last few years.
Speaker 6:  So he's, and he's the guy that I've spoken to several times over the last
Speaker 6:  few years about this big shift that we're seeing from this command
Speaker 6:  and control infrastructure in our home to these LLMs coming,
Speaker 6:  you know, generative AI powered voice assistance that he
Speaker 6:  believes. And I, I guess I'm drinking the Kool-Aid
Speaker 6:  a little bit. It's gonna be a huge change for the smart home.
Speaker 6:  This is what Amazon's doing with Alexa plus. So yeah, he, I'm
Speaker 6:  hope hopeful he'll be able to give us some interesting insights into what's
Speaker 6:  going on, why it's been so difficult, why Google Home has been so
Speaker 6:  bad for so long and what's coming in the future.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So on the Google Home being so bad for so long, I just like, I'm curious
Speaker 1:  if you And I are kind of coming into this interview in the same headspace,
Speaker 1:  because just to lay my own cards on the table, I would say the way I think
Speaker 1:  of Google's smart home efforts is that when we talk about sort of the
Speaker 1:  smart assistant 1.0 revolution, such as it was,
Speaker 1:  it was basically Alexa and Google Assistant. Yeah. Like Siri is kind of off
Speaker 1:  on the side doing its own thing, largely very badly. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  But Alexa and Google Assistant are largely trying to do the same thing the
Speaker 1:  same way. And I think my impression is that Google
Speaker 1:  Assistant became a very good thing to do on your phone and that it seemed
Speaker 1:  like Google sort of forgot it, had a smart home project,
Speaker 1:  but I pay less attention to it than you do. So how, where's your head kind
Speaker 1:  of coming into this conversation?
Speaker 6:  So yeah, Google Home and Amazon Alexa have kind of grown up together in the
Speaker 6:  Smart home. It's been interesting to watch their different approaches.
Speaker 6:  They've, you know, kind of copied each other. They've been moving, you know,
Speaker 6:  at the same speed. But some, sometimes we'll get better features on one
Speaker 6:  than the other. And then all of a sudden, a few years ago, Google Home just
Speaker 6:  started to sort of seem to stop to innovate and everyone was like, well,
Speaker 6:  Google has checked out on the smart home, just like they've checked out
Speaker 6:  on previous projects and hardware in the past. Yep.
Speaker 6:  But I'd always, during this period, I've been talking to the team there and
Speaker 6:  it's, there's this sort of passionate small team that seems to be doing a
Speaker 6:  lot of really interesting things. And one of the core
Speaker 6:  differences here, I think for Google Home has been
Speaker 6:  the way it was built. And I think they've spent the last several
Speaker 6:  years fixing that because they brought together Nest.
Speaker 6:  And we've talked about Nest before, and Nest is a great smart home
Speaker 6:  hardware ecosystem and they brought it together with Google and its
Speaker 6:  software ecosystem and Chromecast. So basically they
Speaker 6:  built a smart home system on three separate pillars.
Speaker 6:  And it, you know, I think there have been, this was an interesting space
Speaker 6:  that everyone was trying to understand as they built it. And
Speaker 6:  now what they've done is rearchitect everything from the
Speaker 6:  ground up. And that's what's they've been doing the last few years. And this
Speaker 6:  is why we've been seeing sort of not last few years, maybe last couple years,
Speaker 6:  we've been seeing this a bit of a degradation, which has been frustrating
Speaker 6:  users understandably. Because when you have a product that doesn't do what
Speaker 6:  you expected it to do anymore, you get very unhappy. But
Speaker 6:  I think I'm quite excited by what their show, what
Speaker 6:  they showed me last week, what they're working towards. Because I
Speaker 6:  do believe, And I think you agree with me here, that David, that Google
Speaker 6:  Home with the infrastructure that Google can provide
Speaker 6:  has one of is PO is positioned really well to
Speaker 6:  make the smart home work. So I'm excited to see
Speaker 6:  whether they can take this where they want to go, and most
Speaker 6:  importantly, whether Google slash Alphabet is gonna really continue
Speaker 6:  to push and invest in this space. I mean, I think they're paying attention
Speaker 6:  to it now because Gemini, you know, that's everything.
Speaker 6:  That's all Google seems to care about right now. But I'm just hoping we can
Speaker 6:  keep the focus and attention here for a bit longer so that this team can
Speaker 6:  actually do something to make the smart home more exciting, more
Speaker 6:  useful, and more reliable.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I like it. Alright, that's, that's good context. Let's just get
Speaker 1:  into it with Anish. Anish, Welcome to The Vergecast.
Speaker 7:  Thank you. I'm excited to be here.
Speaker 1:  Very glad to have you here. We have a lot to talk about. Jen has lots of
Speaker 1:  questions for you. I have lots of questions for you, but I think I wanna
Speaker 1:  start with the most like annoyingly philosophical question I can
Speaker 1:  think of to start with. Okay. Which is, why does
Speaker 1:  Google care about the smart home at all? I, I guess a, does
Speaker 1:  Google care about the smart home? Because there have been times in the last
Speaker 1:  decade, I have debated the answer to that question, but like
Speaker 1:  for a, for a company that is as, as big and broad and
Speaker 1:  into as many things as Google is, what's in the smart home for Google at
Speaker 1:  this point?
Speaker 7:  Yeah,
Speaker 7:  probably a fair question.
Speaker 7:  And I, you know, I I I think we've also been on a, on a journey. So at a
Speaker 7:  different points, I, I can see how we've had some sort of high highs and
Speaker 7:  some challenging, challenging lows. But like, listen, in
Speaker 7:  20 15, 20 16 when we rolled out the first assistant, for us,
Speaker 7:  getting into the smart home was a means for people to have this sort of fundamentally
Speaker 7:  new interaction with, with the way they access
Speaker 7:  information and, and sort of how they control things in their home. I
Speaker 7:  think that was sort of a step function change for us at the time.
Speaker 7:  And then while, you know, the subsequent years have been, have been challenging,
Speaker 7:  the vision for us has always been can we build a home that's
Speaker 7:  truly helpful and, and and proactive and kids have to take care of
Speaker 7:  the people inside of it. That, that mission has been unchanged. I think for
Speaker 7:  us, as we looked at what has made it complicated over
Speaker 7:  the last few years, like we haven't always sort of lived up
Speaker 7:  to like the, the, the, the delta between expectations And I and reality I
Speaker 7:  think has been, there's been a gap. And I was telling Jen last week when
Speaker 7:  we were chatting, but in, in a lot of ways the biggest limiting
Speaker 7:  function was the last generation of, of AI and ml. And so for us now at
Speaker 7:  this inflection point with the Gemini as sort of this core asset,
Speaker 7:  we think we are best positioned to realize that initial vision of
Speaker 7:  ours and then Gemini is this like incredible, powerful sort of
Speaker 7:  technology that can help us do that. And so, so yeah. So I,
Speaker 7:  I I think for us, this is realizing our, our existing vision, but
Speaker 7:  with Gemini at its core. And, and that's gonna help us sort of have a, a,
Speaker 7:  a step function change and what we can do there.
Speaker 1:  But just, lemme lemme just poke at that strategy a little bit. 'cause I think
Speaker 1:  you, you said, you said two things that I, that are I think
Speaker 1:  different that actually get conflated a lot. And I, I wanna see if we can
Speaker 1:  separate them out a little bit. 'cause there's, on the one side, there's
Speaker 1:  the, we have this thing called Google Assistant. We want people to use it
Speaker 1:  as much as possible. In order to do that, one of the things we need is probably
Speaker 1:  something for them to yell at in their living room that isn't their phone,
Speaker 1:  right? So like, smart home is a means to an end and the end is, lots of people
Speaker 1:  use Google Assistant seems like a perfectly
Speaker 1:  rational Google strategy, right? Like sure. What we want is people to use
Speaker 1:  Google. This is a speaker through which they will use Google. That I completely
Speaker 1:  get that the, the idea of like, oh, we need to help
Speaker 1:  people turn their lights on and off. Yeah. Doesn't necessarily have to
Speaker 1:  follow from that, But it seems like to some extent it did that you're like,
Speaker 1:  okay, well we, well now we have this thing in people's living rooms, what
Speaker 1:  can we do with it? Like, is that, are those two different things? Am I,
Speaker 1:  am I wrong in parceling those two things out?
Speaker 7:  I think they're related, right? Like, I, I, in my mind it's, that's almost
Speaker 7:  sort of like a slightly internal way of looking at it. Okay. Like if you're,
Speaker 7:  if you take a, if you sort of take a consumer or a user lens, if you're talking
Speaker 7:  to this thing, let, let's call it, if you're talking to something in your
Speaker 7:  home, there's, there's a question that we ask often, which is like, what
Speaker 7:  are our expectations of what they can do with that? And I think in that
Speaker 7:  mental model, users expect to be able to have
Speaker 7:  at least sort of a, a partner where they can get access to information, which
Speaker 7:  is sort of the first thing you talked about. But they also wanna be able
Speaker 7:  to take a lot of sort of like fundamental actions, right? Things that can
Speaker 7:  actually help, like, I've got three kids, things that can help me make my
Speaker 7:  life a little bit easier so that I can go back to spending time with the
Speaker 7:  kids, to me is incredibly powerful. And I think a lot of people, people
Speaker 7:  say that, So if you can make it a little bit easier to, you know, do stuff
Speaker 7:  in the home, like listening to your media, consuming your media, things like
Speaker 7:  household coordination, like setting timers, getting recipes, like,
Speaker 7:  you know, adding to lists, coordinating your, you know, your groceries and
Speaker 7:  maybe in the future, sort of ordering them, having them show up at your door
Speaker 7:  and then like all the smartphone controls. I think those are all sort of
Speaker 7:  like things that are related if you put it through the lens of what do
Speaker 7:  users expect when they're having this sort of conversation with Google
Speaker 7:  and or Gemini in the home. And so maybe that that's the way that I would,
Speaker 7:  I would sort of reframe what you asked. Yeah. Okay.
Speaker 6:  I I think one of the reasons that the, perhaps,
Speaker 6:  you know, the, a reason behind these questions are that
Speaker 6:  Google as a company has sort of had a history of, of
Speaker 6:  paying attention to things and then not paying attention to things and where,
Speaker 6:  but you know, the smart home has been part of Google for, as you say, over
Speaker 6:  a decade, But it has gone through, as you mentioned, some peaks and troughs.
Speaker 6:  And so I, one of the things, and I've heard from my readers,
Speaker 6:  And I think you've heard from your users, is a fear that
Speaker 6:  Google's just going to say, ah, we're done with the smart home.
Speaker 6:  You know, especially with the shift away from the Nest hardware,
Speaker 6:  the, the Nest protect, the Nest secure security system,
Speaker 6:  the Nest Yale door lock, you know, you, you sort of moved
Speaker 6:  those to, to new partners and there was, and over the last few
Speaker 6:  months and years, it felt like maybe to some
Speaker 6:  users, the smart home wasn't a priority. So I guess one of the things that
Speaker 6:  would be interesting to sort of understand from Google's perspective is
Speaker 6:  what is that value to the company? And
Speaker 6:  that we can see and understand so that we think, okay, I don't
Speaker 6:  worry that they're just gonna pull the rug out from under me.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Listen, I, I, I think it's a probably fair
Speaker 7:  criticism for what it's worth. I have read all of those comments
Speaker 7:  in your, in your comment threads. I, I spent a lot of time on Reddit in our
Speaker 7:  communities, reading all that stuff. And I have a, I have a deep empathy
Speaker 7:  for this. Like, I, I started building out my ecosystem well before I was
Speaker 7:  here in this role. Like, I've got, you know, Jen, we talk about this often.
Speaker 7:  I've got like 150, 200 devices in my home that I accrued,
Speaker 7:  you know, well before that. But yeah, so maybe going back to your question
Speaker 7:  around should people or should our users sort of trust our
Speaker 7:  commitment and our focus?
Speaker 7:  And that's, is that a fair summary of of what you're Yes. You're,
Speaker 7:  you're asking me. Okay. The thing that I would say to
Speaker 7:  that is our, and, and this is what we talk about internally as well,
Speaker 7:  like our mission has not changed once over
Speaker 7:  the last decade. I think what people feel sometimes is how we
Speaker 7:  have tried to realize that has evolved, right? Yeah. So
Speaker 7:  when we start, like when we started over a decade ago and sort of like the
Speaker 7:  nascent phase of smart home, not all of your devices
Speaker 7:  were connected, right? There weren't a ton of smart home
Speaker 7:  OEMs making every device under the sun. And so yeah, there was an initial
Speaker 7:  hypothesis that, yeah, you know, we'll go and build every device in every
Speaker 7:  category at every price point. And you have this sort of like, price ladder
Speaker 7:  and people can choose everything. And I think what we saw over
Speaker 7:  time was that a, a few different things, but people just,
Speaker 7:  you know, there was a sort of massive explosion. You had a whole bunch of,
Speaker 7:  of OEMs and manufacturers come into the ecosystem. Suddenly everything was
Speaker 7:  quote unquote connected or smart. And then we had to sort of
Speaker 7:  look at, are we actually going to build every device in the home? Like, am
Speaker 7:  I going to go and build like vacuum cleaners and robo
Speaker 7:  vacuums and blinds and washers and dryers and
Speaker 7:  stuff like that? Because the reality was, users were very clear, they wanted
Speaker 7:  a lot of those devices and they didn't necessarily tell
Speaker 7:  us that they wanted all of it from one partner or one
Speaker 7:  brand. Yeah. It was very clear from the early days of, of assistant, they
Speaker 7:  were like, Hey, I wanna be able to connect to everything, right? I wanna
Speaker 7:  connect to all of sort of the partners in the ecosystem. So we did have to
Speaker 7:  like, take a step back and say, where do we lean into our
Speaker 7:  strengths? And, and sort of like, how do we evolve our hardware
Speaker 7:  strategy as a function of that? And it has evolved. Like you'll, you know,
Speaker 7:  I I, when I was sharing with you last week was the way that I think
Speaker 7:  about our hardware strategy is that we will conti, we, we love
Speaker 7:  building hardware. We will continue to build awesome hardware. We think of
Speaker 7:  it as a two-pronged strategy. We're gonna build sort of
Speaker 7:  flagship devices in a few categories where we can showcase innovation,
Speaker 7:  where we can sort of push the boundaries of what Gemini can do, and then
Speaker 7:  we'll compliment that with partners that can sort of expand choice
Speaker 7:  for users, give you choice of form factor and price points and stuff like
Speaker 7:  that. And you saw a little bit of that, you know, this week, certainly in
Speaker 7:  cameras and doorbells, we announced Walmart and stuff like that. So there's
Speaker 7:  gonna be a lot more of that. But that's how I think about how our hardware
Speaker 7:  strategies evolved. But our broader mission remains like pretty
Speaker 7:  unchanged. Is
Speaker 1:  It obvious to you where that line is now in, in the sort of what is and isn't
Speaker 1:  your job in the smart home?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah. I, I, I think so. And maybe just
Speaker 7:  to, to sort of put a finer point on the last
Speaker 7:  question of people trusting us. We've made some hard calls for sure,
Speaker 7:  but we've also, we've also sort of done a lot of hard work. Like
Speaker 7:  you think about two things that have happened this week. We said
Speaker 7:  we're gonna replace the Google assistant on every speaker
Speaker 7:  and smart display that we've built in a decade. There was an easier path
Speaker 7:  for us, by the way, which is to say just the new ones, right?
Speaker 7:  Sure. But not for a second did we say that we were gonna take that path?
Speaker 7:  Like for us, obviously like that, that was a, that that is like one sign
Speaker 7:  of commitment to our ecosystem. I think the other way, the other one that
Speaker 7:  I would point to is on the devices in the Nest app, right? We finally
Speaker 7:  finished this, this migration and we've said like, Hey, now all those
Speaker 7:  old Nest devices, some as old as like, you know, over a decade old, you can
Speaker 7:  use all of those in the Google Home app. Like also not an easy
Speaker 7:  undertaking. I know most people don't care about the, the behind the scenes,
Speaker 7:  but between those two things, those were like millions of lines of
Speaker 7:  code that we rewrote to support devices a
Speaker 7:  decade old. And for me, that's a sign of commitment Yeah. Where we could
Speaker 7:  have taken that easier path. So maybe that's the, that's a perfect question,
Speaker 7:  but David, sorry, you, you were asking a follow on.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. How would you describe sort of where your job begins and ends as
Speaker 1:  Google? Because like, I, I think the,
Speaker 1:  everybody in this industry has at various times tried to do the, actually
Speaker 1:  yes, we're going to become a washing machine manufacturer strategy, and
Speaker 1:  most companies, including Manu washing machine manufacturers, have realized
Speaker 1:  that's the wrong strategy. So like, how, how do you paint the sort of
Speaker 1:  clear lines about like, this is actually not what we do in this space?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I, I, I think we play a couple different roles
Speaker 7:  in this space. So I think one key place that
Speaker 7:  we play is, you know, we think it's really critical to build a
Speaker 7:  platform layer to enable partners to sort of innovate. We're
Speaker 7:  deeply committed. You know, I, Jen And I talk often about matter. We're
Speaker 7:  very committed to that as sort of an open standard as one of the early
Speaker 7:  supporters. And we have to, like matter's, got a way to go and
Speaker 7:  we'll sort of spend time there and we'll, we'll continue to invest. It's
Speaker 7:  not sort of a, something that's done in, in a week or a month or a year.
Speaker 7:  But yeah, so we think that platform layer is really, really important. So
Speaker 7:  what you saw with the sort of Walmart on camera announcement, we spent a
Speaker 7:  lot of time building software tools, right? Like SDKs, APIs,
Speaker 7:  things like that, where you could have a partner like Walmart whose core
Speaker 7:  competencies building hardware in this contech in
Speaker 7:  this context, there's a lot of partners there that, that don't wanna build
Speaker 7:  the software layers, the intelligence layers. And so we think that
Speaker 7:  that's a, that's an important role. And the, the user ultimately is the net
Speaker 7:  beneficiary of it, right? You get devices at a whole bunch of different price
Speaker 7:  points. Other partners will do stuff that I don't think
Speaker 7:  necessarily is in Google's best interest to do. Like, you know, if you
Speaker 7:  want a pee hole camera or a bird bath camera and stuff like that. Like,
Speaker 7:  I think there's a bit, there's a markets for all these things I like, it's
Speaker 7:  just, I don't think it's, we are well positioned to do that, but if I can
Speaker 7:  give you the tools to do that, I definitely want to. And Gemini, I think
Speaker 7:  can be sort of a massive unlock in that capacity. So, so one role I think
Speaker 7:  we play is can we help support the ecosystem in that context by giving you
Speaker 7:  tools. I think the second layer is this, this
Speaker 7:  intelligence layer. Like this is, you know, for us, Gemini for home we think
Speaker 7:  is gonna be a big unlock. And so that's a major investment.
Speaker 7:  Gemini as a whole is, is a major investment for, for Google. And so I think
Speaker 7:  there, there will play a, a massive role and to showcase that
Speaker 7:  second part, we'll build devices where it makes sense. That's why we're doing
Speaker 7:  cameras and doorbells because we think, you know, multimodal
Speaker 7:  semantic scene understanding type stuff is pretty unique. We think we can
Speaker 7:  showcase what the market can do. You know, speakers, smart
Speaker 7:  displays like hub, hub devices, those are other areas where
Speaker 7:  we think, you know, we should invest to showcase the market. Will we
Speaker 7:  build it at every price point, every screen size, et cetera? No, probably
Speaker 7:  not. But again, similarly you'll see that us plus partner
Speaker 7:  approach there.
Speaker 6:  Before we move on to what you announced and what you're doing going forward,
Speaker 6:  I just wanna address what we were talking about, a little bit about the kind
Speaker 6:  of frustration that maybe some Google Home and Nest users had had over the
Speaker 6:  past. And one of the things we talked about when we spoke last week was that
Speaker 6:  you basically had to rebuild Google Home with this launch, right? You
Speaker 6:  said there had been a number of different infrastructures
Speaker 6:  under there. You had Nest, you had Chromecast, you had a number of
Speaker 6:  pieces and parts that you kind of had to pull together. And I know that
Speaker 6:  some of the problems specifically in the last few months, I
Speaker 6:  think a lot of users have been talking about things not working anymore with
Speaker 6:  Google Assistant features that had been taken away from Google Assistant
Speaker 6:  that we've reported on over the last year or so. And there was this sort
Speaker 6:  of feeling of like it was dropping off a cliff, but you're sort of saying
Speaker 6:  we've, we've caught it and we are bringing it back up. But I guess I would
Speaker 6:  just love to for you to explain a little bit about what's happened and
Speaker 6:  what's, what happened in to the existing infrastructure of Google
Speaker 6:  Home and now what, what you've built that in that hopefully
Speaker 6:  will be a more solid foundation to go forward.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, you're right, right. But
Speaker 7:  yeah, we've taken on a lot of different infrastructures over time and,
Speaker 7:  and techno tech companies often, often do that,
Speaker 7:  though. There was sort of definitely an inflection point or sort of a moment
Speaker 7:  in time where we had to look at, I'm, I'm gonna sort of focus on the assistant
Speaker 7:  piece for a quick second, where we had to say,
Speaker 7:  okay, we, we see the limitations of
Speaker 7:  the last generation of AI and ml. And as we sort of did that
Speaker 7:  audit, it became very, very clear that we could put a bunch of
Speaker 7:  band-aids on that old technology and it would be pretty brittle
Speaker 7:  and probably not take us into the future. So then we had to make this hard
Speaker 7:  call of like, okay, well listen, like we've gotta go over to this mo more
Speaker 7:  modern infrastructure and more modern architecture. That's, that was the
Speaker 7:  call to move to, to Gemini. But even that wasn't a silver bullet,
Speaker 7:  because if you do that, you get all the stuff that LLMs do
Speaker 7:  really, really well, that creativity, sort of the conversationality,
Speaker 7:  but as an industry, LLMs weren't built to solve
Speaker 7:  like the predictable action type problem, right?
Speaker 7:  And so that's why we had to take some time to say, okay, we have to re-architect
Speaker 7:  Google Home for this world, which with both LLMs, but then also when I
Speaker 7:  say turn off my lights, it does it 10 time outta 10. So, so we had to do
Speaker 7:  that. Like that was a big, big undertaking. Now we feel like we're in a better
Speaker 7:  place. We'll start off, like I said, with early access,
Speaker 7:  there'll be learning, right? So it, it won't be perfect on, on
Speaker 7:  day one, but, but that's, that's, that is what we, we had to do there. And
Speaker 7:  it was a tough call because it meant for the users that had the assistant.
Speaker 7:  Things work great for a while and it will take them some time to get to a
Speaker 7:  better place. But that's where we wanted to compliment it with, okay, listen,
Speaker 7:  if you had our devices for a decade, I,
Speaker 7:  I, I feel deep empathy for, for sort of the, the challenges because I was
Speaker 7:  one of those users. I still am, but I promise like the solution is coming
Speaker 7:  to you as well. It's not gonna require you to buy a new thing.
Speaker 6:  Right? And that's all starting to roll out this month. Is that right? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  So when are people gonna be seen, because I know this whole thing with the
Speaker 6:  early access. Yes. I mean, Amazon's been doing this. It's like, yes,
Speaker 6:  some people can get it. So when can people who've been having problems
Speaker 6:  with Google Assistant feel comfort, you know, when, when are they
Speaker 6:  gonna see improvements with Gemini and is it gonna be improvement or is there
Speaker 6:  still issues there? Because I know I've seen this with Alexa plus
Speaker 6:  that disconnect between what the LLM can do and what the, the
Speaker 6:  deterministic systems that we had before are able to do is still there.
Speaker 6:  Have you solved that problem? That's two questions. I know.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I think a lot of questions about this since we rolled out.
Speaker 7:  Yes. Early access is starting this month, I'll be super clear on our
Speaker 7:  Gemini for home is the thing that's going into early access for cameras
Speaker 7:  and doorbells that has already started to ramp up. So people who
Speaker 7:  have, have raised their hands to get into the early access should be
Speaker 6:  Seen. Just got one of them today. I am very excited. Hey,
Speaker 7:  There you go.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And the beautiful red one too, I'm holding up then the new camera,
Speaker 6:  it just arrived today, the very pretty red angle camera.
Speaker 7:  It very is what we call it. Yeah. So, so for early access for cameras
Speaker 7:  and doorbells in the home app that's already started to roll out and, and
Speaker 7:  it is a rollout, so you know, it's not day and date for everyone.
Speaker 7:  So, and then on speakers and displays, we'll start ramping that up in the
Speaker 7:  last week of, of this month. Okay. So yeah,
Speaker 6:  So like next month for the speakers and displays
Speaker 6:  for most people
Speaker 7:  Last week of this month, so, okay, sure. Yeah. I mean, yeah.
Speaker 7:  So Google
Speaker 6:  Assistant is gone. RIP it's dead. Yeah. When you get
Speaker 6:  Gemini, can you, can you bring back Google Assistant if you don't like Gemini?
Speaker 6:  Or are you just, it's just Gemini?
Speaker 7:  No, it is, it's just, it's just Gemini. Yeah. So you'll get
Speaker 7:  in the home app when you are sort of get off the early access
Speaker 7:  list, you'll get a, a notification in there, you know, you'll go through
Speaker 7:  a couple screens, you know, to select your voices and do a bunch of things.
Speaker 7:  But yeah, when you do that, you switch over from the assistant tona.
Speaker 7:  So when you say, Hey, G, and I'm saying that so I don't trigger everybody's
Speaker 7:  speakers, all your listeners, but yeah, when you say, Hey G, you are at that
Speaker 7:  point, you are now talking to Gemini and that
Speaker 7:  that is not a reversible change,
Speaker 6:  Will it be able to do everything that Google assistant can do today?
Speaker 7:  And, and, and hopefully more and more so, so yes. Yeah, yeah,
Speaker 7:  yeah. The, the intent is very much, yeah, whatever you've got with the assistant.
Speaker 7:  So all of your media stuff, everything you do with household coordination,
Speaker 7:  you know, people care about setting their timers and, and their lists
Speaker 7:  and all of those things. Yes. You, you'll absolutely be able to do that.
Speaker 7:  All of your smart home controls. Then I think the, the, the big thing though
Speaker 7:  is that with Gemini, it sort of unlocks this
Speaker 7:  more natural conversation, right? Yeah. And so we, Jen, we, we often talk
Speaker 7:  about how controlling the smart home has become like this, I have to speak
Speaker 7:  in a very specific syntax, right? Like, if I say the words in this
Speaker 7:  exact order, then something will happen. So that's where I think
Speaker 7:  Gemini will be the upgrade here is it's gonna be far more conversational.
Speaker 7:  You're not, you don't have to like remember the formulas to, to get it right.
Speaker 7:  So pretty excited about that.
Speaker 6:  Well, and you talked about the cameras as being key there with the multimodality.
Speaker 6:  Not everyone wants cameras in their homes, but people want smart homes and
Speaker 6:  there's so many more parts and pieces to creating
Speaker 6:  a, a more a home that understands what you do than just
Speaker 6:  visual. So I guess can you speak a little bit to how you've, what
Speaker 6:  your vision is for how that, that ambient home kind of all comes together
Speaker 6:  outside of just the cameras? Because obviously the cameras are what you launched
Speaker 6:  last week, but I wanna know more about the future.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, and, And I, in, in some ways I, I think
Speaker 7:  we've taken,
Speaker 7:  as an industry, we've taken this view that a, a camera is sort of a predominantly
Speaker 7:  security device, right? Like you put cameras to like, that's, that's probably
Speaker 7:  the primary thing that people use it for.
Speaker 7:  One way that I think about it is that
Speaker 7:  the camera in so many ways will become kind of this
Speaker 7:  general purpose sensor in a way, right? Right.
Speaker 7:  Whereas, you know, today you've got like motion sensors and they do a very
Speaker 7:  specific thing. You've got water leak sensors and do do a specific thing
Speaker 7:  and, and you've got all these different sensors, right? And those I think
Speaker 7:  all have a, have a tremendous role. But I think the role of a camera evolves
Speaker 7:  from just like, you know, I see a thing, I tell you the thing, and it's
Speaker 7:  predominantly security to, it could be this incredibly powerful like
Speaker 7:  general purpose sensor. Yeah. That sort of makes the, the
Speaker 7:  home smarter. Now, of course there, there's like different layers
Speaker 7:  of comfort that have to come with that for, for people to adopt it in different
Speaker 7:  contexts, right? Like, you're probably reasonably comfortable with it outdoors
Speaker 7:  in your backyard and your front yard to bring something inside the house.
Speaker 7:  You've gotta do it in a way that you trust it and you feel like it's
Speaker 7:  secure and, and stuff like that. So, And I think there the biggest
Speaker 7:  unlock will be if users start to see that there's value that it's giving
Speaker 7:  them, then, then they might be willing to make that, that
Speaker 7:  trade. Yeah. But so, so that's my sort of view on, on cameras.
Speaker 7:  I think the, the notion of Gemini being this proactive, like helper in
Speaker 7:  the home absolutely has to encompass all of the devices in your smart
Speaker 7:  home. And, And I think this is like the, this has been in my mind that the
Speaker 7:  gap in the smart home has been, and you, we've talked about this before,
Speaker 7:  the journey has never, the promise has been if you invest in a smart home
Speaker 7:  and you add more devices in the home gets smarter,
Speaker 6:  Right?
Speaker 7:  That is not the case today, right? Yeah. Every device, every incremental
Speaker 7:  device I add to my home, it gets an order of magnitude worse.
Speaker 7:  It's more set up, they don't work together. Automations
Speaker 7:  is like this thing I've gotta do if this, then that. And like, it's, it's
Speaker 7:  so complex. And so this is where, for me, it's not about
Speaker 7:  automations, but it's about Gemini. Just being able to say, okay, bring all
Speaker 7:  of your devices in, we'll figure it out for you. That to me is the unlock.
Speaker 7:  And it has to, at its core be bring in any device, right?
Speaker 7:  Any sensor, any compatible, like smart home device and can I figure it out
Speaker 7:  and can I make it smarter?
Speaker 6:  So we haven't had a new Nest hub smart display for a while. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  There was the Google Pixel tablet, which wasn't really, but kind of, and
Speaker 6:  ev yeah.
Speaker 6:  So, and there was, you know, this, you've talked a lot about
Speaker 6:  cameras being key and vision. Yeah. And that, so a, a smart
Speaker 6:  display really does sort of tie a lot of what
Speaker 6:  you've talked about together. Yeah. In theory, unless you have an entirely
Speaker 6:  new form factor for this that we don't, that you can share now, but is this
Speaker 6:  something that is part of what you see as
Speaker 6:  integral to that sort of core hardware where you said, you said at
Speaker 6:  the beginning that you're gonna focus on producing the, the core hardware
Speaker 6:  and, and if it is key, why, what's, what's important about the smart display?
Speaker 7:  I guess the preempt, given that we're not sharing any explicit news
Speaker 7:  about smart displays, the way that I'll just say it is we are
Speaker 7:  definitely committed to smart displays while we're not announcing anything.
Speaker 7:  Now, you should definitely expect that we'll have news to share there
Speaker 7:  soon. And I think the reason that I'm excited about this category is if you
Speaker 7:  think about, you know, how all these LLM technologies are
Speaker 7:  sort of converging, it does present itself as a
Speaker 7:  like, incredible form factor to interact with something like Gemini for home,
Speaker 7:  right? Yeah. Like you think about the properties of a smart display microphone,
Speaker 7:  which means audio in speaker, audio out. So it's great
Speaker 7:  for audio and audio out. It's got a screen, which means to
Speaker 7:  compliment sort of a voice modality. You can sort of interact with it,
Speaker 7:  you can sort of visualize information, you know, we've got cameras in them.
Speaker 7:  So you get that, that's a vision piece to it as well. So I think, you know,
Speaker 7:  as I see where Gemini for home is going, and Gemini more broadly is going
Speaker 7:  all of the things that Google is investing in building, for me, it feels
Speaker 7:  like the almost at a ultimate form factor to be able to deliver like
Speaker 7:  a really great home experience. So that's, that's why we are gonna
Speaker 7:  continue to invest in that category. So I'm, I I I think it's gonna be awesome.
Speaker 1:  A lot of people I think have correctly identified a lot of the same problems
Speaker 1:  that you have with the smart home, right? And I think a lot of people also
Speaker 1:  think LLMs are gonna help fix it. But you work for Google, which
Speaker 1:  also has this unbelievably gigantic trove of
Speaker 1:  information in real time and not about every
Speaker 1:  person on earth. And as you talk about like multimodal,
Speaker 1:  you know, multimodal input and understanding more about people's context,
Speaker 1:  like it's all just sitting there for you if you want it. So like,
Speaker 1:  is is the, is the end of this road that like my smart home
Speaker 1:  not only knows where I am, but has like read my email and my
Speaker 1:  Google Maps history and knows what I shopped for and actually can like
Speaker 1:  preheat the oven for me without even me having to ask. And that I just live
Speaker 1:  my life. And because Google knows everything about me, it starts to solve
Speaker 1:  my life for me. Is that, is that the end of this road
Speaker 7:  On the point around having access to all
Speaker 7:  this information? I think what we build with it is going to start
Speaker 7:  and end with like with trust, right? So you've gotta
Speaker 7:  be able to trust the sort of assistant that you're
Speaker 7:  bringing into your home. And so I think, you know, we've got like as broader
Speaker 7:  Google and certainly in the context of the home, we definitely have to earn
Speaker 7:  that trust. We, we thought so deeply about what it
Speaker 7:  meant to bring Gemini into the home, which is why we started with, hey, this
Speaker 7:  is going to be a communal experience first because we don't
Speaker 7:  want to skirt around the ideas that you might
Speaker 7:  accidentally have access. Like my, like my partner might accidentally have
Speaker 7:  access to my personal interactions with Gemini and stuff like that. Now I
Speaker 7:  can see definitely like us continuing to invest there with the right,
Speaker 7:  you know, maybe Jen, to your point with the right sort of sensors and ability
Speaker 7:  to authenticate that it's actually a niche alone in the room
Speaker 7:  talking to Gemini, then in that case, yes, I, I should have
Speaker 7:  access, but if there's other people in the room, I probably don't, right?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I don't want my credit card details or a personal interaction about
Speaker 7:  what cough medicine I might have wanted to use last week when I had a sore
Speaker 7:  throat to be sort of like displayed out to everyone. So, so I think we we're
Speaker 7:  approaching it in a way that we wanna be very thoughtful, especially in a
Speaker 7:  communal environment. Like how do you utilize the right set
Speaker 7:  of contexts and history about the person and do that in a
Speaker 7:  thoughtful way, in a way that sort of preserves trust long term? Because
Speaker 7:  I don't think, David, we get to, I, I, I think the, the thing you
Speaker 7:  described is definitely a place that we would love to get to, but
Speaker 7:  we have to do it methodically and thoughtfully that, that maintains trust
Speaker 7:  along that journey the entire way.
Speaker 1:  I just think it's interesting because you, you, that's a different problem
Speaker 1:  than everybody else has, right? Everybody else has that problem and also
Speaker 1:  doesn't know what's in my email. And so I think you're, you're just in this
Speaker 1:  position of like, you have to solve the creepy
Speaker 1:  problem, not the where is David problem,
Speaker 1:  right? Like, knowing where I am is not hard for Google. It's, it just isn't
Speaker 1:  hard for Google in a way that is hard for almost every company. You have
Speaker 1:  to reflect back to me where I am without freaking me out about it. And I
Speaker 1:  think in a lot of ways that might actually be the harder problem to solve.
Speaker 7:  I I I think that's true, not just for us though. I think it with any sort
Speaker 7:  of like new technology, right? The, not with any new
Speaker 7:  technology, but with a lot of new technologies, the line between, between
Speaker 7:  cool and creepy can be a very fine line, right? Oh, and it like
Speaker 1:  Dances all over the place all the time. Yes.
Speaker 7:  Or, or it constantly evolves, right? Yeah. And I think the onus is on us
Speaker 7:  as product builders, which to say
Speaker 7:  people are comfortable moving the line if they can
Speaker 7:  crisply understand what it does for them and whether or
Speaker 7:  not it adds, actually adds value to their life. Yeah. And then do they trust
Speaker 7:  the person building them and giving them that thing, right? Yeah. So, so
Speaker 7:  that's why I think there's, there's two big parts we have to get right, which
Speaker 7:  is one, you've gotta enough, like you've gotta deliver enough value
Speaker 7:  to the user to their lives that says, okay, this is cool
Speaker 7:  enough that I'm willing to, to give you permission to do these things.
Speaker 7:  And then do they trust you as sort of an entity or a company
Speaker 7:  or a product builder to do that? And so I think if we can, if we can, you
Speaker 7:  know, do those two things really well, then I think we
Speaker 7:  could actually make people's lives in their home a lot easier.
Speaker 1:  All right. That's a good place for us to end, I think.
Speaker 8:  big business idea into reality, which Shopify on your side. Sign
Speaker 11:  That's linkedin.com/track to post your job for free terms
Speaker 11:  and conditions apply.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. V song is here. Hi, ve
Speaker 12:  Hi.
Speaker 1:  I mean, fine. We can talk about the glasses. You wanna talk about the glasses?
Speaker 1:  Let's talk about the glasses. We're, we're, we're here to talk about Peloton,
Speaker 1:  but you can't just show up on camera with me and wearing these glasses and
Speaker 1:  we're not gonna talk about it for two minutes. So you, you are wearing
Speaker 1:  the, let me hold on. I'm gonna try and get the name right. I, the, the
Speaker 1:  Ray band meta display,
Speaker 12:  The meta ray band
Speaker 1:  Display, the, god damn it. Okay.
Speaker 12:  I know whatever
Speaker 1:  You're wearing, I know Meta's new smart glasses with a screen. We're gonna
Speaker 1:  talk much more about this in a, in a future episode sometime in the next
Speaker 1:  couple of weeks when you finish your review, but you've now been wearing
Speaker 1:  these things for a little while. Gimme, gimme 60 seconds. How are you feeling
Speaker 1:  so far?
Speaker 12:  It's very genuine. The hardware is impressive,
Speaker 12:  but the software, they really need to get this
Speaker 12:  API that they just opened up to third parties going, the
Speaker 12:  neural band is surprisingly good. I actually think
Speaker 12:  the neural band is kind of the most interesting thing about this.
Speaker 1:  That's the thing you, it's like a, you wear it on your wrist and use it to
Speaker 1:  control the
Speaker 12:  Yes, it's this little guy and you do, oh, it looks like a
Speaker 1:  Whoop it, it just looks
Speaker 12:  Like a whoop. It does look like a whoop, it just looks, it's very unobtrusive.
Speaker 12:  Interesting. It does work if you have to wear another smart watch, which
Speaker 12:  I have taken off because it is embargoed, but like it does work if you
Speaker 12:  have another smartwatch on there, which I was like, oh, thank God I'm running
Speaker 12:  out of body parts. Like I have to test all of these things and yeah, I can't
Speaker 12:  just give up real estate on this wrist without, you know,
Speaker 12:  so that was a relief to me personally.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, it's, it's interesting, I literally had to listen to
Speaker 12:  a lecture from my spouse this morning about why they think these look
Speaker 12:  terrible on me. So we'll get into that. Maybe
Speaker 12:  the style section of my review is just a video of them going off
Speaker 12:  for 30 minutes and you can choose to listen to it or not.
Speaker 12:  It's, it's, it's a very intriguing product. Do I think
Speaker 12:  the rollout was botched? Yes, absolutely. And
Speaker 12:  I think people are gonna be talking about it and for good reason. There's
Speaker 12:  a lot of meaty stuff to dig into, but is it
Speaker 12:  the future? We'll see, we'll see.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Well, we're gonna come back to it. My, my read so far is that
Speaker 1:  they look both like vastly better than almost
Speaker 1:  anything we've seen and still kind of bad. They're, they're in a like
Speaker 1:  uncanny valley kind of situation of like, I look at those glasses And
Speaker 1:  I don't clock them as glasses, I clock them as something else. Do you
Speaker 1:  know what I mean? But it but you don't look at it like it's not, it's obviously
Speaker 1:  not like a vision pro, right? It's not like, oh my God, what is that gadget
Speaker 1:  on your face? But it's like you look at those and there's something just
Speaker 1:  like slightly wrong with the pair of glasses V is wearing and yeah,
Speaker 1:  it's throwing me,
Speaker 12:  I think if you, if you look at me in person, like one-on-one like this,
Speaker 12:  you might feel that way. But if I, you know, I was walking throughout New York
Speaker 12:  City yesterday, commuting to the office, nobody looked at me twice.
Speaker 1:  I I believe that. So, which is a huge deal. Yeah. Like that is, that is more
Speaker 1:  the bar than almost anything else. Yeah. With, with a lot of these things.
Speaker 1:  But all right. That's not what we're here to talk about. No, again, we're
Speaker 1:  gonna come back and talk about this because I have, I have a thousand things
Speaker 1:  I wanna talk about about these, but that's for another time I wanna talk
Speaker 1:  about Peloton because there was a lot of gadget news
Speaker 1:  this fall. I, I found this big swing
Speaker 1:  from Peloton as interesting as anything else that has come out
Speaker 1:  And I just, I just wanna talk through it. So I kind of left
Speaker 1:  Peloton behind in my brain as like an interesting company, right? This
Speaker 1:  is like, if you rewind five years, the, the pandemic happens.
Speaker 1:  Peloton spikes like crazy because lots of people suddenly want and need what
Speaker 1:  it provides. Pelotons doing great, it becomes like culturally relevant because
Speaker 1:  its instructors start to become famous. So Peloton like has a moment and
Speaker 1:  then fades, right? And goes through a bunch of leadership changes and has
Speaker 1:  huge hardware issues and pivots and pivots and changes and
Speaker 1:  everything. And I just kind of like relegated Peloton to like
Speaker 1:  a thing that will probably keep being around for a while but has maybe
Speaker 1:  jumped the shark and will never quite get it back.
Speaker 1:  Then Peloton just comes out absolutely swinging for the
Speaker 1:  fences with a bunch of new stuff and new ideas.
Speaker 1:  So just sort of walk me through this like new generation of Peloton stuff
Speaker 1:  that just launched before we get into what it all means. Like what, what
Speaker 1:  is all of this stuff?
Speaker 12:  So basically for the first time in Pelotons history, they have refreshed
Speaker 12:  their entire product lineup. So there is an, there are two new bikes,
Speaker 12:  two new treadmills and a new rower. And they basically were
Speaker 12:  like, they got a little syringe, put a bunch of AI into that syringe and
Speaker 12:  injected it into these products. There's something called Peloton iq
Speaker 12:  and so the there, oh God, okay, so there's two tiers of products.
Speaker 12:  There's the regular bike and the regular treadmill. Those do not
Speaker 12:  have a camera in them, but everything else now has a
Speaker 12:  handy dandy little swivel camera. You can like plus
Speaker 1:  Means camera, right? Is like essentially way I think about
Speaker 12:  It Camera. Okay. Yeah. Plus means camera. And this camera is basically like
Speaker 12:  if you took the Peloton guide, which is what I would call their first
Speaker 12:  bonafide hardware flop, it was a little, it kind of
Speaker 12:  reminded me of the Microsoft Connect. You stuck it on your TV and it looked
Speaker 12:  like a little webcam and you did strength training exercises with it and
Speaker 12:  it would kind of analyze your form, not give you very much feedback. And
Speaker 12:  so it was just like, all right, this is a thing. But now they've stuck that
Speaker 12:  and they squished it into their existing products and now it does give you
Speaker 12:  feedback. The AI will look at you doing strength training exercises and
Speaker 12:  be like, Hey girl, I think you need to go up in weights. Or man, your form
Speaker 12:  is really bad, so why don't you go down and wait so that you do that exercise
Speaker 12:  better. So those are in those devices now all of the devices plus and
Speaker 12:  Nonplus have swivel screens. So you can just
Speaker 12:  whip that screen around. So if you're not in a tiny space, you can
Speaker 12:  just like fold out the screen and do your strength exercises, your yoga
Speaker 12:  exercises, oozy, whaty, whatever. The plus
Speaker 12:  models, again, sorry to jump around, but the plus models also now have a
Speaker 12:  fan in them because Peloton fans are like, man, it sure does get hot
Speaker 12:  when you're doing cardio. Like
Speaker 1:  A fan for your face. Yes, I hear, I hear fan in like a gadget context. I'm
Speaker 1:  like, oh, it's inside to keep the thing from overheating. It's to keep you
Speaker 1:  from overheating.
Speaker 12:  It's to keep you from overheating. Yeah. It's like on top of the display
Speaker 12:  there's like this, this cam that where the camera's also built in,
Speaker 12:  like there's just this fan, it's adjustable speed.
Speaker 12:  So when you're working out you, you can cool down,
Speaker 12:  there's a phone tray. Now the bikes have a sier
Speaker 12:  seat, so it's more cushy for your tushy, which is what I wanted to write
Speaker 12:  in my hands on. But I was like, that's a little much,
Speaker 1:  That's a headline. I don't know, I don't, we missed opportunity with the
Speaker 1:  headline
Speaker 12:  Missed. Yeah. So you know, they, they've done a bunch of hardware updates.
Speaker 12:  Oh, Sonos had a hand with the new speakers. The plus models
Speaker 12:  have a a wolfer now. So when the base drops,
Speaker 12:  Sonos has done the tuning and the equalizing for those. So I guess to
Speaker 12:  ensure that the base drop really hits when you're in your workout.
Speaker 12:  Sure. The entire interface has been changed around,
Speaker 12:  you know, you can better integrate with your third party devices and
Speaker 12:  services so that you can import all of your exercise data and the AI
Speaker 12:  will be like, hmm, let me give you insights. So
Speaker 12:  it's, it's a lot. It's a, it's a pretty much a total revamp of
Speaker 12:  the everything. Yeah. From
Speaker 1:  A pure hardware perspective there. Do you look at that and
Speaker 1:  say, okay, Peloton is like trying hard to get
Speaker 1:  all the people who bought a bike eight years ago
Speaker 1:  or a treadmill five years ago and trying to get those people to buy
Speaker 1:  a new one or is this like a swing at people who have never bought a Peloton
Speaker 1:  before?
Speaker 12:  I think it's both. Okay. I definitely, it
Speaker 12:  confuses me a little bit though because you would expect that if they want
Speaker 12:  their existing customers to upgrade that there would be
Speaker 12:  some sort of trade-in program. But from what I've seen, sure. And from what
Speaker 12:  Peloton diehards have been DMing me, that does not look to be the case.
Speaker 12:  You can't just trade in your bike plus and get a new bike plus,
Speaker 12:  which I, that's a bummer. Think is, that's a bummer. Yeah. So
Speaker 12:  that's kind of surprising I think because, you know, is Peloton,
Speaker 12:  these do not come cheap.
Speaker 12:  So that's strange. But I really feel, and like I went to
Speaker 12:  this little keynote event that they had in New York City same day as the
Speaker 12:  Amazon event. So we're a lot of really tired tech journalists at this event.
Speaker 12:  But you know, they were saying this is a new era for Peloton.
Speaker 12:  This is gonna bust everything wide open. And you
Speaker 12:  know, I am a fitness AI
Speaker 12:  hater, I'm just gonna say it, I'm a hater. Sure. I've tested, I've tested
Speaker 12:  the whoops ai. Whereas ai, all of these AI Garmin
Speaker 12:  Strava fucking sucks. It's
Speaker 12:  regurgitated book reports. Yes. They're not
Speaker 12:  particularly useful. The only ones that I've been
Speaker 12:  mildly intrigued by are what Google's working on and is gonna be rolling
Speaker 12:  out sometime later this month for the for on Fitbit,
Speaker 12:  which is the AI coach that they have on there. And Pelotons is
Speaker 12:  surprisingly like, I got to see a demo of a fictional
Speaker 12:  Peloton user named Amy and like the insights that she was getting from
Speaker 12:  Peloton IQ And I was like, okay, maybe
Speaker 12:  we'll see. 'cause you know, demos are such, they're
Speaker 12:  guardrails so you can't really get a real, I mean I got a demo
Speaker 12:  of these glasses And I was like, whoa. And now that I'm using them in real
Speaker 12:  life, I'm like, ah, now I find some problems and some issues. So,
Speaker 12:  you know, I saw the the demo And I was like, okay, these are
Speaker 12:  the types of insights that athletes would want. Like if you're doing a strengths
Speaker 12:  training program and you're new to strengths training and you're
Speaker 12:  not really sure when you should go up in weights, this will tell you like
Speaker 12:  Hey, you've been doing chest presses at 25 pounds for two weeks
Speaker 12:  next week you should really be either upping the reps or upping
Speaker 12:  your weight just so that you maintain progressive overload that's
Speaker 12:  genuinely useful. Versus an AI going like, you ran 35
Speaker 12:  miles and it was slightly slower than your average. Jesus
Speaker 12:  Christ. Thank you. I I can also read my own metrics and come to that conclusion.
Speaker 12:  Right.
Speaker 1:  Well, but that's the thing. So this, this is, I think the trick and the
Speaker 1:  challenge we've run into with a lot of these things is that what they
Speaker 1:  give you is this incredibly basic feedback
Speaker 1:  on an incredibly advanced device, right? Yes. And I think like
Speaker 1:  the stuff with Peloton for me, and, and the thing I've been trying to figure
Speaker 1:  out for years is whether Peloton is eventually going
Speaker 1:  to go like way down market and start to be like, okay, actually
Speaker 1:  the bike is free and all you have to pay for is a subscription. And that,
Speaker 1:  that's how Peloton gets like a whole new type of person
Speaker 1:  to be a Peloton person. Or if it's gonna go the other way and do the, the
Speaker 1:  sort of like, you know, go after the, the Garmin people
Speaker 1:  in the world who are like, no, I'm serious about this And I want tools
Speaker 1:  that help me get more serious. And that gets more expensive. It does more
Speaker 1:  stuff. And so my, my read of a lot of this announcement is it is like ramping
Speaker 1:  up the seriousness for people who are already serious, right? And these
Speaker 1:  things got more expensive. They, the, the subscription went up,
Speaker 1:  there's more stuff. And so for me it's like you, you got this demo of
Speaker 1:  someone basically like doing bad form. I think you said they were doing overhead
Speaker 1:  dumbbell presses. And it will, like, if you do comically bad
Speaker 1:  form, it will, it will tell you you're doing a bad job and do better
Speaker 1:  fine. That, that to me is like the equivalent of an
Speaker 1:  AR device that looks at a bag of nuts that says nuts in big
Speaker 1:  letters and can tell me it's a bag of nuts. Like that's not nothing, but
Speaker 1:  it's not much. What I need is the stuff that is
Speaker 1:  vastly more nuanced and subtle and it's like, you're doing
Speaker 1:  a pretty good job. Here's how you could be doing a really good job. Like
Speaker 1:  that's what the people who are buying these things want and need, and that's
Speaker 1:  the level that they're at. And I think it's just a much harder
Speaker 1:  technology problem. And so I think, I think you're, you're right to be skeptical
Speaker 1:  even of the demos because it's like, it's one thing to see me going like
Speaker 1:  this and be like, that's not right. But if I'm like, almost right,
Speaker 1:  and it tells me how to do it exactly right. Like that's the actual stuff
Speaker 1:  and that's a way harder thing to do.
Speaker 12:  It's very hard. And it's like that's, it's, it's hard even if you have a
Speaker 12:  in-person personal trainer. So that's, it's a right,
Speaker 1:  That's what people pay a lot of money for. That's
Speaker 12:  What people pay a lot of money for. It's, it's an access thing because it's
Speaker 12:  so, it is so much easier to do fitness if it's in your home that that's
Speaker 12:  just true if you are a beginner, I can see this
Speaker 12:  being helpful in a lot of different ways. But again, the people who would
Speaker 12:  be most interested in those features are not the beginners. So
Speaker 12:  it's, it's, they call it the cross training series because
Speaker 12:  on the one hand you have your cardio device and your preferred method of
Speaker 12:  indoor cardio. And so now you can cross train and do other things and
Speaker 12:  get this form feedback, which, you know, form feedback.
Speaker 12:  I will say of all the
Speaker 12:  exercise modality strength training is the thing that stumps all
Speaker 12:  the technology companies the most. It's really like Ladder is
Speaker 12:  the only strength training app that I really resonated with. And did
Speaker 12:  Peloton steal everything for its strength training app from Ladder?
Speaker 12:  Yeah. Well, I don't know. Go to Reddit. People are having that conversation
Speaker 12:  there.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, the general vibe on Pelotons strength app is, oh, they just did Ladder.
Speaker 1:  That's which is not Yeah. Not the wrong
Speaker 12:  Choice. No ladder's great
Speaker 1:  Choice. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  Ladder actually has helped me get into lifting a little bit more consistently
Speaker 12:  than previous iterations have. That's great. But you
Speaker 12:  know, exercise is just such a weird thing because it's individual.
Speaker 12:  What works for one person is absolutely not gonna work for another person.
Speaker 12:  There's no blanket prescription that you can give people. So, but that's
Speaker 12:  so funny.
Speaker 1:  That is like, that exact reason is why it makes perfect sense to me
Speaker 1:  that this is a thing Peloton is doing, right? Because the, the first move
Speaker 1:  is like, okay, how do we take the experience of a class and bring it home?
Speaker 1:  And that worked super well, But it does have limitations, right? Whereas
Speaker 1:  it's like that by definition can't be responsive to me
Speaker 1:  and what I need. And especially with strength training, that is really important,
Speaker 1:  right? Like I always think about, I, I would do the, the like Peloton
Speaker 1:  yoga stuff on the ground next to the Peloton, like,
Speaker 1:  And I, I would fall behind and just fall apart, right? Because like I suck
Speaker 1:  at yoga, they're good at it and they're doing this class for people who
Speaker 1:  are good at it. And like what I need is something that actually is
Speaker 1:  engaging with me in some sort of meaningful way. And so it's like, of course
Speaker 1:  that's the pitch here, right? Like I can absolutely see why
Speaker 1:  Peloton is after this. And there are a bunch of reasons. It actually seems
Speaker 1:  like if anybody can do it, well it ought to be Peloton. It does have access
Speaker 1:  to the hardware, all the stuff you're talking about. Like I think the camera
Speaker 1:  is really fascinating. The swivel screen is really interesting. There's just,
Speaker 1:  it has all this historical data on people and me specifically, but
Speaker 1:  also just like people in the aggregate. Like there are a lot of reasons
Speaker 1:  if someone can pull this off that it might be Peloton. Am I crazy? Like am
Speaker 1:  I giving Peloton way too much credit here?
Speaker 12:  No, no. Like I talked to their chief product officer, Nick
Speaker 12:  Caldwell at the event and you know, he said a couple of really interesting
Speaker 12:  things. Just, you know, their AI is built on chat,
Speaker 12:  GPT and llama in part, but also it's trained on their
Speaker 12:  thousands of classes, like a lot of thousands of data points. And
Speaker 12:  the AI is integrated in ways beyond just what, how you're
Speaker 12:  like interacting with it. Because it's also in the sense of how they
Speaker 12:  surface classes to you. So based on what you need, they're like,
Speaker 12:  well how do we help you find a class that actually helps you in our library
Speaker 12:  of thousands of classes? That's a pain point too, because it's great that
Speaker 12:  they have thousands of classes. But if, you know pe, if you're on Peloton
Speaker 12:  and you're just trying to find something that'll work for you, a instructor
Speaker 12:  that you like, because instructor personalities can be,
Speaker 12:  you know, not every instructor's you're gonna jive with. I really can't
Speaker 12:  stand the ones that are just like, Hey girl, you got this and, and all that.
Speaker 12:  And I'm just like, no, I'm suffering. Please don't try and encourage me.
Speaker 12:  But so, you know, like the AI is also supposed to help you surface a
Speaker 12:  class that you might actually resonate with and might, you know,
Speaker 12:  there's a new thing that pops up that tells you if you current
Speaker 12:  effort levels are matched with that class. Like this class might be harder
Speaker 12:  for you than normal is, is what'll pop up when you're browsing.
Speaker 12:  So there's that. I actually think that's way more interesting than the form
Speaker 12:  correction, but that's just me. Fair. There's new stuff where you can generate
Speaker 12:  your own workouts that are sans instructors that you can take
Speaker 12:  at your own pace and oh, I like that and moves that you want. So like
Speaker 12:  they're doing a bunch of different things to appeal to a bunch of different
Speaker 12:  people. So they're kind of very thoughtful
Speaker 12:  and smart about how they're going about it in a way that it doesn't feel
Speaker 12:  fully just like, here's ai, let's staple it onto the product. Which is
Speaker 12:  what most fitness AI has felt like. So I do think if anyone's
Speaker 12:  gonna do it, it is probably them because they are
Speaker 12:  very clued in to their diehard fan base. Like a lot of the
Speaker 12:  new hardware upgrades are things that people have been yelling at them to
Speaker 12:  fix for a long time. So they are listening to their, to their
Speaker 12:  core constituency.
Speaker 1:  Do you think their core constituency was also like spending a lot of time
Speaker 1:  saying, God, I wish this was all way more expensive. You know, do you feel
Speaker 1:  like that was a bunch of Peloton people being like, you don't have enough
Speaker 1:  of my money. Do you want more of my money? Peloton.
Speaker 12:  So I find Peloton diehard like a
Speaker 12:  fascinating group of people. So, you know, I know RIP
Speaker 12:  Jane Goodall, but I consider myself the Jane Goodall of Peloton
Speaker 12:  diehards. I love this for like, I spent some time, I spent some time just
Speaker 12:  in like their official groups and on Reddit just reading what they have
Speaker 12:  to say about stuff. Because I did a feature last year where I talked to
Speaker 12:  like a dozen Peloton diehards and you know what, the vast
Speaker 12:  majority of them told me that the hardware was
Speaker 12:  integral to their experienceing. And I was just shocked by that because
Speaker 12:  most people I talk to are like, oh my God, it's so expensive. Why not
Speaker 12:  just buy a $500 version and with a tablet holder,
Speaker 12:  right? Bad a bang bad a boom. Well
Speaker 1:  There was, there was a really sort of obvious future for Peloton after this
Speaker 1:  like post pandemic slump that was like, stop being a hardware company.
Speaker 1:  You have a software and you like you're, you're a media company. Like
Speaker 1:  go be an exercise class company and let me run that on any
Speaker 1:  treadmill that exists. Like make a, make an API that plugs into every other
Speaker 1:  treadmill, go to the gym. Like the, it becomes like a
Speaker 1:  exercise as a service company. And I have actually been surprised to not
Speaker 1:  see Peloton go more in that direction. But it sounds like that's just because
Speaker 1:  I'm not talking to enough Peloton people that maybe the hardware there's
Speaker 1:  is
Speaker 12:  More the thing's a specific there. So there's like grades of Peloton people,
Speaker 12:  there's like the people who are like, I've heard of it. Sure. That's the
Speaker 12:  one where the guy died in sex in the city. And you're like, yes. That, yes.
Speaker 12:  So that's that level of Peloton awareness. And there's the people who, who
Speaker 12:  are like the spouses of Peloton diehards who are just like, yeah,
Speaker 12:  person I live with, they do Peloton And I
Speaker 12:  don't get it, but sometimes I use their equipment and yeah, I guess it's
Speaker 12:  nice. And then you have the Peloton diehards and like they are a
Speaker 12:  unique group of people. I find them fascinating and you know,
Speaker 12:  when I talk to them, they're like, they're talking in such tones where
Speaker 12:  I don't wanna call them culty, but it's not, not
Speaker 12:  culty where they're like, and you know, they also will
Speaker 12:  positively call themselves cult members. So I'm not trying to be derogative
Speaker 12:  here, but they are like,
Speaker 12:  Jess King helped me get through a really tough period of my life. Mm. And
Speaker 12:  I'm just like, okay, cool. Yes, you who,
Speaker 12:  who are the instructors you like? And it's very interesting to see who they
Speaker 12:  pick and why and how it relates to their personality. And those people
Speaker 12:  for sure are always like, yeah, I'm thinking about how I can upgrade
Speaker 12:  and it doesn't matter to me how much it costs because it's just so
Speaker 12:  high quality. And so, you know, to us Normies
Speaker 12:  just looking at them going, you're really gonna pay $6,700
Speaker 12:  for a fucking treadmill to them, they're just like, this
Speaker 12:  tool fits into my life, right? It is my life.
Speaker 12:  And I don't see this as a ridiculous cost because
Speaker 12:  I use this treadmill every day and you know,
Speaker 12:  it's, my life has changed this, this, this thing.
Speaker 12:  I used to be depressed and sad and now look at me, I'm running 46
Speaker 12:  marathons and I'm like, that's just a different kind of depressed and sad
Speaker 12:  to me personally.
Speaker 12:  No, I love that. For you it's
Speaker 1:  Physically healthier, so go for it. Yeah,
Speaker 12:  It's physically healthier. I am concerned because marathons
Speaker 12:  are so tired. I know, I have talked to people who have trained for whole
Speaker 12:  marathons on a treadmill, on a Peloton treadmill and I'm like, how
Speaker 12:  whoa, I can't do two more than three miles on a treadmill. 'cause I lose
Speaker 12:  my mind. It's so boring. Yeah, I can do, I can run hours
Speaker 12:  outside. I love that. But like the, the treadmill three hours of
Speaker 12:  running, I'm like, how? And you know, one of the people
Speaker 12:  I interviewed, she was just like this bubbly, enthusiastic,
Speaker 12:  lovely lady and she was like, yeah, when I ran my marathon,
Speaker 12:  I had the Peloton app and the outdoor classes
Speaker 12:  just going on on a loop. And that's what got me through my marathon outdoors.
Speaker 12:  And I was like, you brought Peloton to S Marathon. Holy crap.
Speaker 1:  That is such a telling thing in so many directions that that
Speaker 1:  is the response. That's so interesting. So, okay, so that must mean you
Speaker 1:  look at these prices. 'cause like I look at these prices and see them
Speaker 1:  as sort of shocking. Like Travis, our producer went
Speaker 1:  through and did the shockingly difficult work of figuring out
Speaker 1:  how these prices have changed over time and it's kind of nuts. So like,
Speaker 1:  just to give you one example, the the Tread Plus, which is the, the like
Speaker 1:  high end treadmill launched in 2018 and it was
Speaker 1:  $4,295, which was a ton. And we talked a lot
Speaker 1:  about how expensive it was. And then in 2023 it jumped to
Speaker 1:  $5,995, which is more just in case
Speaker 1:  you're wondering and then now is
Speaker 1:  $6,695. And that is, that is just what
Speaker 1:  the Tread plus costs. The tread has gone up. It,
Speaker 1:  it went down a little bit then up again, it's more expensive than ever. The
Speaker 1:  Row plus is more expensive than ever. The subscription continues to go
Speaker 1:  up. It's not like everything else is getting cheaper, but like maybe it just
Speaker 1:  is true that this is a group of people who are not super price conscious
Speaker 1:  and the idea of, you know, I'm pitting this against an
Speaker 1:  Equinox membership or like two sessions a week with a personal trainer. And
Speaker 1:  so it's actually not expensive in that context, but like when
Speaker 1:  you look at these prices, what does it make you think Peloton is
Speaker 1:  doing here?
Speaker 12:  I'm just like, Baha six, $7,000
Speaker 12:  for for a treadmill. Yeah, running outside is free.
Speaker 12:  That's me though, right? Like I,
Speaker 1:  To be fair, running outside is awful and you can't watch the office while
Speaker 1:  you run outside. So like I would pay a lot to be able to watch the office
Speaker 1:  while I run indoors.
Speaker 12:  But again, this is like different people
Speaker 1:  But not 6,700.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, this is different people, different preferences, right? I cannot,
Speaker 12:  I've tried watching KDRs and my straight kids videos
Speaker 12:  on treadmills. I can't do it. I can't do it for more than 20 minutes. I
Speaker 12:  thought I was a terrible runner for years ing because of I just could not
Speaker 12:  do it outside. I can run for three hours and it's just me, my thoughts and
Speaker 12:  K-pop for like three hours. That's so funny.
Speaker 1:  I the exact opposite. I, yeah. So the best gym trick I ever
Speaker 1:  discovered, and everyone should try this if you have trouble making yourself
Speaker 1:  go to the gym, was I found a TV show that I loved And I was only
Speaker 1:  allowed to watch it at the gym.
Speaker 12:  I tried that. And so
Speaker 1:  For me, I through like seasons upon seasons running on the
Speaker 1:  treadmill at the Y because that was just, I was just like, I wanna watch
Speaker 1:  the show so I'm gonna go and watch it on the treadmill. And then literally
Speaker 1:  it's, it's a like third of a mile from here to the gym
Speaker 1:  and that run is so boring that I didn't, I,
Speaker 1:  I didn't wanna do it. I would drive to the gym and run on the treadmill Like
Speaker 1:  what? Like a true maniac stuff. But yeah, it's just
Speaker 1:  people are different.
Speaker 12:  I tried doing that. It does not work for me. So that, that's, that's such
Speaker 12:  the challenge that they have is
Speaker 1:  That you're like my dad who ran a marathon with no headphones And I still
Speaker 1:  think he's no, that's like true psychotic behavior
Speaker 12:  That's the most psychotic. But I still need the headphones, I still need
Speaker 12:  my beats. Okay. I I need my little k-pop boys singing,
Speaker 12:  whatever I, I need that. But you know, I've listened in
Speaker 12:  to Peloton earnings dutifully every quarter and when they
Speaker 12:  upped the price to about $6,000, I was like, ha.
Speaker 12:  And then the next quarter they're like, oh yeah, and we sold out of every,
Speaker 12:  out of all of the stock that we had for $6,000. And I was like, how
Speaker 12:  so every, every earnings, they're like tread plus the most expensive
Speaker 12:  product in their portfolio. It sells like gangbusters. And
Speaker 12:  I'm like, how that's the one where the kids died. How do you
Speaker 12:  do this? And and the people who love them love them.
Speaker 12:  I believe it was Business Insider back when like the height of
Speaker 12:  that controversy was happening. They were like interviewing people who were
Speaker 12:  like, yeah, I fell down and it threw me through a wall, never giving
Speaker 12:  it up. And it's just like these people, it resonates
Speaker 12:  with them in such a way and it creates such a degree of loyalty
Speaker 12:  that I'm just like, oh my god. And you know, historic, their churn
Speaker 12:  is a little higher than it used to be, but it's still not that much higher
Speaker 12:  than like one, 1.5%. So these
Speaker 12:  people really stick with
Speaker 1:  It, which is like crazy low.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, it's crazy low for a churn rate of, of subscribers. And
Speaker 12:  we talk about Peloton churn subscribers being high, it's like 2%. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  Which is so low if you really think about it in the scale of things.
Speaker 12:  But you know, whether or not this opens a new chapter for them, I don't
Speaker 12:  know because their previous CEO Barry McCarthy, who I
Speaker 12:  absolutely loved because he always had unhinged quotes in the, in
Speaker 12:  the investor shareholder letter the one time he's like, this, this is a
Speaker 12:  cargo ship and we are halfway through the Mediterranean. I was like, what
Speaker 12:  is happening here? But sure, he very much, he very
Speaker 12:  much went, the reason why the prices are like so hard to track
Speaker 12:  over time was because he was doing a lot of experimenting with the prices
Speaker 12:  and with the theory that this is a media company and we are
Speaker 12:  gonna be futzing around with hardware prices, we're gonna see what sticks,
Speaker 12:  we're gonna introduce a rental program, what's happening. He
Speaker 12:  did a lot of that and the numbers went up like
Speaker 12:  actually, you know, I tune into these things and the numbers have been going
Speaker 12:  up for some time, even though it's not pandemic levels of high, in which
Speaker 12:  case I go, you know, investors, does everything have to be on a constant
Speaker 12:  state of growth trajectory? Like what if, what if it's just fine being
Speaker 12:  a mid-size company? Totally. What if, what if? And the investors are always
Speaker 12:  like, no, you must go to pandemic levels again. And it's like, we don't
Speaker 12:  do that. I don't
Speaker 1:  In this country. So last question on this and then, and then we should take
Speaker 1:  a break. I think thinking about these Peloton people, like the the stuff
Speaker 1:  that you hear them talk about all the time is a, you like, you're like, we've
Speaker 1:  been talking about the hardware is, is a hugely important part of it. People
Speaker 1:  love the classes, people love the instructors, people love the sort of real
Speaker 1:  time competition of it. There is this sense that you're like part of a
Speaker 1:  community even though you're inside of your house. Can you, if you're a
Speaker 1:  Peloton, can you do the AI thing in a way that doesn't
Speaker 1:  ruin that? Like thinking about what you know about all of these Peloton people
Speaker 1:  is this idea of everything being super individualized and
Speaker 1:  personalized, but also in a certain way sort of depersonalized that it's
Speaker 1:  not gonna feel as though you're in a live class full of
Speaker 1:  people. It's gonna feel like an AI is coaching you on how to do things.
Speaker 1:  Is that gonna be compelling to those people?
Speaker 12:  So I think they've been very thoughtful about that because when I went
Speaker 12:  to this event, and this is just gonna be another
Speaker 12:  description of the Peloton energy, I go into this event and what do
Speaker 12:  they do? First of all, they don't introduce the CEO first and no, no, no.
Speaker 12:  He's, he's an afterthought. They go,
Speaker 1:  We
Speaker 12:  Have Tunde, we have Adrian Williams and I'm sorry I forgot the third name
Speaker 12:  of the, the instructor that was there. The instructors come out and
Speaker 12:  they are like clapping people's hands in the audience and like they're,
Speaker 12:  you know, and I'm just like, I don't know who most of these people are,
Speaker 12:  but every single time I've gone to a Peloton event, they have brought out
Speaker 12:  an instructor and the instructor is there and they have actually
Speaker 12:  put a big hand into how this Peloton IQ has been
Speaker 12:  crafted. So, you know, I had my demo and my demo was with Tunde who
Speaker 12:  is a cycling instructor I believe. And she was just like, it's
Speaker 12:  like it's my assistant. The AI is my assistant. I have helped
Speaker 12:  craft these recommendations. We have
Speaker 12:  had a huge say in like what it tells you so
Speaker 12:  you know, you're gonna listen to me, you're coming from me and this is just
Speaker 12:  gonna help you out. It's gonna be my little helper. It's like a, she's like,
Speaker 12:  I'm the professor and this is my teaching assistant. And I was like, that's
Speaker 12:  a very interesting distinction that they're making there. And I think
Speaker 12:  that could work because if they're messaging that correctly,
Speaker 12:  you know, I think the diehards will be like, oh yeah, Tene is my professor
Speaker 12:  and this is my teaching assistant at Right. Love you Peloton iq. But we'll,
Speaker 12:  we'll have to see. I'm, I'm in, I'm in the communities, I do be lurking
Speaker 12:  and some of them are like, AI slop get this shit
Speaker 12:  outta here. So, you know, we'll see how it shakes out over
Speaker 12:  time. I think they kind of stepped in it by not having an
Speaker 12:  upgrade program for those people because you know, if you're a really
Speaker 12:  loyal diehard, you wanna be rewarded for that loyalty. So I think some of
Speaker 12:  them feel a little betrayed by that to be honest, but
Speaker 12:  we'll see. We'll see how it goes. Sure. I I remain an AI
Speaker 12:  and fitness hater and skeptic until proven otherwise.
Speaker 1:  It's gonna be again, like if, if anybody gets it, I think there's a solid
Speaker 1:  chance that it's Peloton. But also everything you just said about the relationship
Speaker 1:  between person and AI is the thing every company says
Speaker 1:  six months before being like, we've created a new AI instructor,
Speaker 1:  her name is Kim and she is the only instructor on the platform
Speaker 1:  forever. And everything just immediately goes to help.
Speaker 1:  Right? Like you, you can just see the path towards here is a new con
Speaker 1:  here as a new instructor, this is the future of Peloton.
Speaker 1:  It's blobby. It's like, I actually think you missed it's Peloton. Yeah,
Speaker 12:  It's bl bbo which is my name for all ai. Yeah. Friends
Speaker 12:  and companions and whatever. It's, But it,
Speaker 1:  But if they can not do that and actually make this thing like a tool and
Speaker 1:  not a character, I think there's something really powerful there.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. It's just, are the insights good? That's gonna
Speaker 12:  be the number one, that is the question. That's the number one question.
Speaker 12:  If they can't nail that, I'm just gonna add it to my AI fitness
Speaker 12:  wall of shame. So if
Speaker 1:  You need somebody to really earnestly be bad at exercise, I'm here for
Speaker 1:  you. So just lemme know I got your
Speaker 12:  Back. I can't test five of these equipment. My house is not big enough
Speaker 12:  for that. So this might have to be a team effort. Anyway,
Speaker 1:  I'm, I'm in, I'm here for you. This is, I got, I got, I got room in the basement.
Speaker 1:  I'll get rid of the couch. There you go. I'll put in three treadmills and
Speaker 1:  we'll we'll go to
Speaker 13:  Work. They're really big treadmills, like they're
Speaker 1:  Really big one treadmill.
Speaker 13:  One treadmill. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  All right, we need to take a break but will you stick around? I have a hotline
Speaker 1:  question for you. Yeah. Alright, cool. We'll be right back.
Speaker 14:  Right now at the Home Depot shop fall savings and get up to
Speaker 14:  40% off select appliances like Samsung.
Speaker 14:  Upgrade your kitchen this fall with the Samsung Bespoke four door
Speaker 14:  refrigerator. Now featuring the dual auto ice maker with Sphere Ice
Speaker 14:  only at the Home Depot you'll have perfectly chilled drinks for
Speaker 14:  every gathering. Don't miss fall appliance savings at the Home Depot.
Speaker 14:  Offer valid October 2nd through October 22nd. US only C-store online for
Speaker 14:  details.
Speaker 15:  Experience a membership that backs your business journey with American Express
Speaker 15:  Business Platinum. Earn five times membership rewards points on flights
Speaker 15:  and prepaid hotels booked on Amex travel.com. Plus
Speaker 15:  enjoy a welcome offer of 200,000 points after you spend
Speaker 15:  $20,000 on purchases on the card within your first three months of
Speaker 15:  membership. American Express Business Platinum, there's nothing like
Speaker 15:  it. Terms apply. Learn more at american
Speaker 15:  express.com/business-platinum.
Speaker 13:  Imagine fast hydration
Speaker 13:  combined with balanced energy, perfectly flavored with zero
Speaker 13:  artificial sweeteners. Introducing liquid Ivy's new energy
Speaker 13:  multiplier sugar free.
Speaker 13:  Unlike other energy drinks, you know the ones that make you feel like you're
Speaker 13:  glitching. It's made with natural caffeine and electrolytes so you get the
Speaker 13:  boost without the burnout. Liquid IVs, new energy
Speaker 13:  multiplier, sugar-free hydrating energy. Tap the banner to learn more.
Speaker 5:  Alright,
Speaker 1:  We're back V song still here. Hi V. Hey. So let's do a
Speaker 1:  question for the Vergecast Hotline. We get lots of them that are like specifically
Speaker 1:  directed to a specific person and we have one for you today. Oh I love it.
Speaker 1:  As always you can call 8 6 6 VERGE one one. You can email Vergecast to The
Speaker 1:  Verge dot com. There's been like a million gadgets so send us s Gadget questions.
Speaker 1:  I think we're also gonna do a smart home hotline episode here at some point
Speaker 1:  in the near future. So send us all of your questions for now. The
Speaker 1:  let's get at it. This one's for you.
Speaker 16:  Hi Vergecast crew, this is Power Lister and
Speaker 16:  a new runner. This is a question probably best answered by V
Speaker 16:  Song. For the longest time I've been using my Apple Watch in
Speaker 16:  combination with the strong app to track my lifts. I've been a power lifter
Speaker 16:  for many years and would focus on big compound lifts with some accessories.
Speaker 16:  Recently I've picked up running and mostly track it with Strava. A lot of
Speaker 16:  my running friends have repeatedly told me to get a Garmin for the better
Speaker 16:  battery life and overall better smart tracking for running.
Speaker 16:  I've been using an Apple Watch series six since release and replaced the
Speaker 16:  battery last year and it's already draining fast. My dilemma is I've
Speaker 16:  adopted a hybrid plan that incorporates running with my main traditional
Speaker 16:  strength training lifts that I track with the strong app. And nothing online
Speaker 16:  shows that that app is compatible with Garmin watches. I was
Speaker 16:  wondering if you had any advice on maybe potentially repping two smart
Speaker 16:  watches, one for lifts and one for runs or if I should just
Speaker 16:  commit to one if so, which appreciate any
Speaker 16:  help and rock on
Speaker 1:  V You can see why I picked this for you, right? Like our caller didn't give
Speaker 1:  their name, but if ever there is someone who feels our caller's pan, it's
Speaker 1:  it's you. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  Wow. Welcome to my world caller
Speaker 12:  because, 'cause I've lived both of those lives. What I will say is that
Speaker 12:  the double wristing life is difficult because
Speaker 12:  so, so the crux of the problem here is the fact
Speaker 12:  that fitness data is messy, right? Lots of people use
Speaker 12:  Strava because it is a def facto hub where you can
Speaker 12:  import your data from disparate devices and it lives in one place
Speaker 12:  because
Speaker 12:  that's just how it goes. It integrates with everything everyone
Speaker 12:  uses. Strava love it. So bad news,
Speaker 12:  Strava sued garment last week, so Oh no.
Speaker 12:  And is asking Garmin to stop selling all of its devices.
Speaker 12:  So there's beef between these two companies As a
Speaker 12:  new runner, what I'm gonna say is that Garmin, I
Speaker 12:  love Garmin. Garmin, Garmin fans are really die hard, so don't comfort me.
Speaker 12:  Garmin is overwhelming in terms of the running data for a beginner
Speaker 12:  because when you are a beginner and you are just running for the first time,
Speaker 12:  it's about good form. It's about
Speaker 12:  just kind of increasing your time on the road, doing it safely,
Speaker 12:  making sure you're cross training and all of that sort of stuff and just
Speaker 12:  really kind of finding your rhythm for, for running
Speaker 12:  and you know, is vertical oscillation data
Speaker 12:  gonna help you do that or is it gonna confe like confuse you further?
Speaker 12:  That's, that's what I would say. I do enjoy Garmin. I think
Speaker 12:  it, it's, it's very complicated to kind of get into the
Speaker 12:  Garmin in depth data. It's not knocking them at all.
Speaker 12:  I find it very useful, but Apple has made some updates that are for
Speaker 12:  beginners I think are pretty compelling. Like they've added training load,
Speaker 12:  so it kind of helps you visualize whether you're doing too much
Speaker 12:  or how, how your levels are doing.
Speaker 12:  So what I would say is since you're a beginner, just find out if you like
Speaker 12:  running first and if you really love running, eventually you will
Speaker 12:  naturally gravitate towards the Garmin just because the
Speaker 12:  features there really are catered towards runners.
Speaker 12:  They're really great. I, you know, if, if it were up to me
Speaker 12:  And I was just using a watch for running, I would pick a
Speaker 12:  Garmin, I would probably pick one of the foreign runner garments because
Speaker 12:  they're not gigantic and they fit well and
Speaker 12:  they're like really suited towards that. But
Speaker 12:  just like, hold hold for a second because
Speaker 12:  that's a lot of gear that we're talking about you having in one Yeah, one
Speaker 12:  space. And as much as possible, I do recommend
Speaker 12:  streamlining your data streams just because look, I'm, I'm psycho. I have
Speaker 12:  this notebook and this notebook literally is where I log
Speaker 12:  all of my disparate fitness data and baselines because
Speaker 12:  I have not found a good digital way of doing it for testing. I, I,
Speaker 12:  I spend like 40 minutes after each workout just comparing data points.
Speaker 12:  Like you don't wanna be me and doing that. So
Speaker 12:  like, this is reviewer problems though because I am testing multiple products.
Speaker 12:  Yes, I do have to live this multiple life. And so why would you, why would
Speaker 12:  you do this to yourself friend? If you are gonna go the Garmin
Speaker 12:  route, you can track reps and
Speaker 12:  workouts within Garmin. Is it gonna be
Speaker 12:  as good as strong? I'm not sure because you know,
Speaker 12:  all of my power lifter friends are very into strong and that
Speaker 12:  app, so you are running into the problem of how you know
Speaker 12:  much like the smart home, there's all these different silos of of data
Speaker 12:  that people have. The main thing is to find what works best for
Speaker 12:  you that you will stick with. If strong is something that you really love
Speaker 12:  and has really helped you in your power lifting life, don't
Speaker 12:  ditch it Just because you're running friends are saying that you should
Speaker 12:  go into Garmin.
Speaker 12:  I personally do not like the Garmin strength training tracking
Speaker 12:  because it does not give me enough time to edit my, my, my
Speaker 12:  weights and my reps and it, I like it throws me out. Mm
Speaker 1:  Yeah, it sounds like our color didn't like it either. Yeah,
Speaker 12:  I don't, I don't love it. I'll be quite frank about that.
Speaker 12:  So if, if you find that you love strong on the Apple watch, I don't
Speaker 12:  know, maybe you upgrade to an ultra and see how that does for you. This
Speaker 1:  Is what I was just about to say. Why is the watch ultra not the perfect,
Speaker 1:  like jack of all trades version of the answer here?
Speaker 12:  Okay, so you know the outdoor running crowd and garment and they have a
Speaker 12:  lot of really valid points here is battery life.
Speaker 12:  A Garmin is measured in weeks, it's measured in months.
Speaker 12:  The, I have the ultra three here, I'm still reviewing it. That'll be out
Speaker 12:  soon, but you know, I've got 72 hours out of it, which is great.
Speaker 12:  Not if you are running lots of marathons,
Speaker 12:  doing a lot of hikes, doing a lot of cross training. Sure. It's still a
Speaker 12:  lot of charging management that you have to do and that's, that's not for
Speaker 12:  the garment crowd, that that's not what they want.
Speaker 12:  There are certain like metrics that I think the longer you go into
Speaker 12:  endurance sports, it's the longer you are in outdoor sports. They are useful.
Speaker 12:  I like the hill endurance, the hill endurance score. When I was training
Speaker 12:  for a half marathon, I found, I think it's called the endurance score.
Speaker 12:  It just basically tracks like how tired you are throughout a run and
Speaker 12:  whether you're exerting a certain amount of energy. I did find that helpful.
Speaker 12:  It, it did kind of visualize for me whether or not
Speaker 12:  I was gonna make it to the end of my first half marathon. I did, it was
Speaker 12:  great. It was not, I suffered immensely, but you know, I,
Speaker 12:  I trained for my half marathons with garments And I found some of the
Speaker 12:  more in depth metrics at that point in time once I learned how to read them.
Speaker 12:  Because you do have to sit there and you do have to like digest that
Speaker 12:  information.
Speaker 12:  I did find it helpful for me, But that was when I had kind of gotten to
Speaker 12:  a level where I was running half marathons and we're talking about thinking
Speaker 12:  about fueling and what those, you can get fueling reminders on
Speaker 12:  your garin, you know, like when you're at that level that can be really
Speaker 12:  useful and helpful and it helps you pair down what you're using. There's
Speaker 12:  a reason why so many high level runners use
Speaker 12:  Garmins, but if powerlifting
Speaker 12:  is your main focus and running is cross training for you,
Speaker 12:  do what your main
Speaker 12:  modality of exercise do prioritize that
Speaker 12:  because Right, the Apple watch, it's decent at run running for a casual
Speaker 12:  runner. Like if you are just doing 10 Ks or less,
Speaker 12:  you don't really need, you don't need everything that a Garmin is
Speaker 12:  gonna give you. Okay. If you are a through hiker, if you, if you decide
Speaker 12:  that you are gonna make like Liz Lipato and Ruck and, and do
Speaker 12:  all that sort of stuff. Yeah, no, Garmin makes way more sense for you. It's
Speaker 12:  just, yeah, do don't live the double
Speaker 12:  wrist life. It's expensive. You get double watch tans.
Speaker 12:  I do it because I'm paid to do this. I don't think you should do, I don't
Speaker 12:  think any normal person should live this life. I may be biased saying that,
Speaker 12:  But it
Speaker 1:  Does sound like largely unfortunately as a function of the way that
Speaker 1:  these devices platforms work, if this person is going to
Speaker 1:  get into running at the same level, it sounds like they're currently into
Speaker 1:  power lifting. They, they are going to end up with two devices that like,
Speaker 1:  I I think your advice to like do the casual thing on the Apple watch
Speaker 1:  as long as you can is really good advice. But it does sound like if if
Speaker 1:  you're gonna get to like, you know, a nine or 10 out of 10 on the commitment
Speaker 1:  scale, you're gonna end up with two devices.
Speaker 12:  You're gonna end up living my life, in which case welcome friend and also,
Speaker 12:  I'm sorry,
Speaker 12:  but yeah, stay, stay on a single device as long as you possibly can
Speaker 12:  because managing the data streams becomes a second full-time
Speaker 12:  unpaid job.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I think that's good advice. And then After that, then you get a smart
Speaker 1:  ring and then you start wearing stuff around your neck and then you come
Speaker 1:  work at The Verge. I think it's like literally that's essentially, there's
Speaker 1:  just a certain number of devices that happens and then Eli shows up at your
Speaker 1:  house and offers you a job, I think is like basically
Speaker 12:  How it works. Yeah. That, that's honestly my career trajectory. I was, that's
Speaker 12:  what happened. I was just living my, my life as a fricking cyborg
Speaker 12:  and then I got a knock on the door and The Verge was like, Hey, we need
Speaker 12:  a wearables person. And I was like, Yolo, let's go.
Speaker 1:  I have all of them. Let's
Speaker 12:  Do this. And now look at me. Now look at me. Live your dream. Do you wanna
Speaker 12:  be like me? Call her? No. No, you don't. I
Speaker 12:  only have one face and so many smart classes that need to, yeah,
Speaker 1:  Yeah. This is what we do here. It's, it's, no one should live our pain, but
Speaker 1:  too many people are forced to is I think we, what
Speaker 12:  We're, I mean like is this, is this optimal? I don't think so.
Speaker 1:  All right. If you're wearing more gadgets than ve send us an email.
Speaker 1:  I want, I want pictures of people who are wearing more gadgets than ve.
Speaker 12:  These aren't all the ones I even wear. Some are embargoed and some
Speaker 12:  are on parts of the body that, you know, that's not gonna fit in this camera
Speaker 12:  view. Don't live my life.
Speaker 1:  That's good advice. All right, ve thank you as always. We'll see you next
Speaker 1:  time. Alright,
Speaker 12:  See you next time.
Speaker 1:  Alright, that is it for the show this week. Thank you to everybody who came
Speaker 1:  on and thank you as always for listening. Thank you. By the way, to everybody
Speaker 1:  who reached out about version history, I hope you enjoyed the first episode
Speaker 1:  about Hoverboards that was on The Verge YouTube channel, on the version History
Speaker 1:  Feed and on The Vergecast Feed. So hopefully you encountered it somewhere.
Speaker 1:  We're really proud of the show. It's been really fun to make. But please
Speaker 1:  keep sending us ideas. I want episode ideas, I want ideas about the version
Speaker 1:  history questions and how we can do those better. We have some ideas for
Speaker 1:  the next series of these episodes. Please keep all your ideas coming. I wanna
Speaker 1:  make lots of this show. I think it's gonna be great And I want to keep hearing
Speaker 1:  all of your thoughts about everything that we're up to. For now,
Speaker 1:  we're gonna get outta here. The Vergecast is The Verge production and part
Speaker 1:  of the Vox Media podcast network. The show is produced by Eric Gomez, Brandon
Speaker 1:  Keefer, and Travis Uck. We will be back on Friday to talk about
Speaker 1:  more news. We may or may not have a very fun person
Speaker 1:  who's coming back on the show. I'm not a hundred percent sure, but I'm like
Speaker 1:  pretty sure and I'm, I'm very excited about it. We got a lot to do. We'll
Speaker 1:  see you then. Rock and roll,
Speaker 17:  Adobe Acrobat Studio. So brand new. Show me all the things PDFs can do.
Speaker 17:  Do your work with ease and speed. PDF spaces is all you need. Do hours of
Speaker 17:  research in an instant with key insights from an AI assistant. Pick a
Speaker 17:  template with a click. Now your preza looks super slick. Close that deal.
Speaker 17:  Yeah, you won. Do that. Doing that. Did that done? Now you can do
Speaker 17:  that. Do that with Acrobat now you can do that.
Speaker 17:  Do that with the all new Acrobat. It's time to do your best work with the
Speaker 17:  all new Adobe Acrobat Studio limo
Speaker 18:  And Doug. Here we have the LIMU IMU in its natural
Speaker 18:  habitat, helping people customize their car insurance and save
Speaker 18:  hundreds with Liberty Mutual.
Speaker 18:  Fascinating. It's accompanied by his natural ally. Doug
Speaker 1:  LIMU is that guy with the
Speaker 17:  Binoculars watching us
Speaker 18:  Cut the camera. They see us. Only
Speaker 19:  Pay for what you need@libertymutual.com. Liberty,
Speaker 17:  Liberty, Liberty.
Speaker 18:  Liberty
Speaker 19:  Savings very underwritten by Liberty Mutual Insurance Company and affiliates
Speaker 19:  excludes Massachusetts.