# Transcript
ID: b4109e3b-4a29-4066-94c4-490e623a90e0
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/2443249629892064772/-6898166201993161420/s93290-US-6282s-1757901445.mp3
Description: One thing you should know about the iPhone launch is that there’s... not usually a lot of other tech news around the iPhone launch. So David and Jake start this episode with some more information about the iPhone launch, including some controversial details we missed about the AirPods Pro 3 and the argument in favor of the crossbody strap. After that, with David back on the mic, it’s time for a round of AI-focused hot takes with The Verge’s Hayden Field. The gang talks ChatGPT, Claude, money, more money, and what counts as a real friend. (And money.) Finally, in the lightning round — yes, once again the LIGHTNING ROUND — the three co-hosts talk about Canon’s confusing new camera, the future of Reddit, Claude’s spreadsheet-y future, and much more.
Speaker 5:  with our lives. I'm your friend, David Pierce. Jake Kakis is here. Hi, Jake.
Speaker 6:  Hello. Good to see you again.
Speaker 5:  It's been a couple months. I, I feel weird being back. I have to be
Speaker 5:  honest with you. This is, this is strange. I'm, I'm not like
Speaker 5:  used to sitting here and looking into cameras anymore. I've forgotten how
Speaker 5:  tiring it is to like sit on video meetings all day. We all just do
Speaker 5:  this. It's, it's a lot.
Speaker 6:  It isn't fun just staring at, at zoom all day long
Speaker 6:  hoping that your meeting shows up on time and
Speaker 6:  ends on time and somebody's taking notes. And the AI isn't saying the wrong
Speaker 6:  thing.
Speaker 5:  I think we've all like forgotten how weird it is to stare at our own
Speaker 5:  faces as much as we stare at our own faces in the era of video chat. And
Speaker 5:  when you don't do it for a long time, it is glorious.
Speaker 5:  And then you start staring at your own face again and you're like, oh God,
Speaker 5:  is that what I look like? Like it's not, it's not great. I don't recommend
Speaker 5:  it. You have done a terrific job this summer. I just wanna say this now in
Speaker 5:  front of God and everybody, you did a great job. It was very fun to listen
Speaker 5:  to this show all summer and have absolutely no input over any of
Speaker 5:  it. You did a really good job. So we have a lot to get to today. We're
Speaker 5:  gonna do some gadget news up top here. We have a lightning round
Speaker 5:  at the end,
Speaker 5:  just yes, you heard it correctly. What? We'll come back to that, David.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna have a lightning round in which we fight about the lightning
Speaker 5:  round, and then we're gonna have a lightning round. And I'm very excited
Speaker 5:  about it. And in the middle we have, we have a segment I'm calling
Speaker 5:  Summer Takes, which is just, I have a lot of things I need to get off my
Speaker 5:  chest And I need to know if I'm insane. So we're gonna talk about all of
Speaker 5:  that. But first, it's still Apple Week. Like this is, this is
Speaker 5:  the week where nobody else does anything because it's mostly Apple News.
Speaker 5:  So let's cover off on some of the Apple stuff we didn't really touch on on
Speaker 5:  Wednesday show. We talked about all the gadgets. If you haven't listened
Speaker 5:  to Wednesday show, we, we talked about all the iPhones, the watches, the
Speaker 5:  AirPods, the cross body straps, everything. We ran through all of that.
Speaker 5:  Go listen to that episode. But there are a few details we should touch on
Speaker 5:  before we get outta here. And the first one is the charging
Speaker 5:  cable. This, this has been like a, a, a mild kerfuffle on the
Speaker 5:  internet since it became revealed that the AirPods Pro three
Speaker 5:  do not ship with a charging cable.
Speaker 6:  Are people upset about this? People
Speaker 5:  Are upset about this.
Speaker 6:  Okay, so back a few years ago when this, when I think
Speaker 6:  every company stopped, including the charging brick, I was like, this is
Speaker 6:  cheap. You're all cheapen out on us. The cables
Speaker 6:  I have so many cables are, so I had to get a
Speaker 6:  new laptop at work recently 'cause my old one broke. And our IT
Speaker 6:  team was like, here's the laptop and here's the charger and here's the cable.
Speaker 6:  And I'm like, please keep this. And they're like, no, no, no. We insist it's
Speaker 6:  great cable, it's a great charger. And I'm like, please do not burden me
Speaker 6:  with this chart. I have so many, I have so many of
Speaker 6:  them. The other thing,
Speaker 6:  there's just, we all, we're all we're, we're full up. We're full up.
Speaker 6:  We don't need this. Do you feel the same way?
Speaker 5:  I do. So I'm, I'm torn. I think the, I
Speaker 5:  honestly, I, I swear to God, if you gave me five minutes, I could find you
Speaker 5:  a hundred USBC cables in, in like within arm's reach of me. I'm not
Speaker 5:  like, like
Speaker 5:  that just right there. I just, that's, I
Speaker 6:  Can confirm that's my arms. David is holding like 19 cables.
Speaker 5:  Like it's, that was one reach into one drawer like this. Most people are
Speaker 5:  not like us, right? Like this is not a normal situation
Speaker 5:  for humanity. And I think there is something to,
Speaker 5:  like, you should have a charging cable with your phone, right? Like that
Speaker 5:  is, that is the device that I think if you own nothing else, you probably
Speaker 5:  own that. And if you own nothing else, that's the one that should come with
Speaker 5:  a charger. So I think I, I'm actually, I have more feelings about it on that
Speaker 5:  one. If you're paying $250 for a pair of AirPods pros,
Speaker 5:  the, the overlap of the Venn diagram between those people and people who
Speaker 5:  don't have USBC cables to spare is non-existent. So like, this to me is
Speaker 5:  such a non-issue. Except if you're like a person who cares about the
Speaker 5:  principle of I should have charging cables. I
Speaker 6:  Also distinctly think of wireless
Speaker 6:  earbuds as devices that should be wirelessly charged.
Speaker 6:  I have never plugged any of my pairs of wireless
Speaker 6:  earbuds into a charging cable. Now, that's particularly true for the AirPods
Speaker 6:  that I have. 'cause I have the lightning port AirPods, and I'm not
Speaker 6:  messing with that. I, somebody recently asked me for an
Speaker 6:  iPhone charger. I'm like, which one you mean man in the middle
Speaker 6:  lightning cord? Ugh, I, I had to tear my house apart.
Speaker 6:  'cause I've done everything I can to rid myself of lightning cables. And
Speaker 6:  it's like, I've got a, a nest of them somewhere. But it's like in some
Speaker 6:  old cabinet, the, the, the AirPods,
Speaker 6:  these new ones, they ha they have wireless charging. You don't need it. It's
Speaker 6:  fine. That's not the device I'm, I'm plugging in all the time.
Speaker 6:  And surely if you're gonna charge them, just use the same cord you're using
Speaker 6:  for your, for your, for your iPhone, it's fine. Yeah. You're gonna
Speaker 5:  Be all right. On this note, can I tell you about a gadget upgrade I made
Speaker 5:  this summer that I so incredibly highly recommend to everybody? Oh yeah.
Speaker 5:  So every company now that makes accessories, makes a version of this. But
Speaker 5:  it's basically the like all in one
Speaker 5:  wireless charger, right? So like, mine is maybe this company called 12 South.
Speaker 5:  And basically it's, it's, it's a little stand and on the sort
Speaker 5:  of sloping front, it's a mag safe charger for a phone, usually an
Speaker 5:  iPhone. But also the, the Pixel 10, which I have upstairs also fits on it.
Speaker 5:  There's a little thing on the back where you put the Apple watch and there's
Speaker 5:  a little pad down on the bottom where you can charge AirPods.
Speaker 5:  I bought one of those And I used to have it here sitting at my desk. But
Speaker 5:  where I actually put it this summer was next to the place.
Speaker 5:  Everybody has the place. They put their things when they walk inside, right?
Speaker 5:  Like it's where you put your keys or whatever. I put it there
Speaker 5:  and it has been incredible. That is now just like, it's the place
Speaker 5:  my devices live. And especially to your point about the AirPods, I now
Speaker 5:  never, ever think about charging my AirPods because when I come inside,
Speaker 5:  that's just where I put them down. Oh,
Speaker 6:  That's pretty good.
Speaker 5:  Is on the wire. I cannot recommend this enough. It's been the best. Okay.
Speaker 6:  I, I see photos of these things all the time. They look amazing online, but
Speaker 6:  I've always thought that in practice they're like the equivalent of putting
Speaker 6:  all of your spices into the same jar. Or like, and I'm like it,
Speaker 6:  like it looks very pretty on the internet. Does this really make sense? Is
Speaker 6:  it really gonna make my life better? Am I really use this thing is
Speaker 5:  Very slow when I'm trying to charge all of them simultaneously. Mm. But again,
Speaker 5:  this is like not a, oh no, I need to charge my AirPods thing. It's a I am
Speaker 5:  home. Where do my AirPods go? Yes. I just stick it on the thing. Yeah, I
Speaker 5:  charge my phone there less because I usually just like have my phone in my
Speaker 5:  pocket all day. But where, and it's like you come home and you like empty
Speaker 5:  the bag or empty your pockets having a charger
Speaker 5:  be a couple of those spots.
Speaker 6:  Fabulous. Yeah, I mean at, at, at home I just have a wireless charger on,
Speaker 6:  on my work desk. My AirPods just live there. Like,
Speaker 6:  yes. Does that probably hurt their battery over time? Doesn't matter. They
Speaker 6:  live on the charger. They're gonna have power.
Speaker 5:  This might be a messed up place to have landed, but I have, I have fully
Speaker 5:  landed on, I am going to lose or destroy these things long before their parts
Speaker 5:  start to fall apart. Oh. So I'm just, yeah. I'm so brutal
Speaker 5:  on AirPods for
Speaker 6:  That. It's going down a sewer great one day. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like it's a, it's a, I've had these, I still have the, the last regular
Speaker 5:  lightning AirPods that they made. And it is a full miracle that I still have
Speaker 5:  these anyway, charging cables.
Speaker 5:  If you need one, just call me. I have thousands of them. It'll be fine. The
Speaker 5:  next Apple thing mostly. I just wanna shout out a piece that Jess
Speaker 5:  weathered wrote for us about the cross body strap. You And I talked
Speaker 5:  about this on Wednesday's show, and we got a couple of emails from people
Speaker 5:  who were like, you know that thing Jake said about 30 something men being
Speaker 5:  the wrong people to talk about this? You are exactly correct. You guys are
Speaker 5:  idiots. Shut up. I'm paraphrasing. But that was more or less the
Speaker 5:  vibe. And that's also more or less the vibe of Jess's piece, which makes
Speaker 5:  a series of very good points about how people, particularly women's
Speaker 5:  clothes that don't typically have pockets or people in other countries, these
Speaker 5:  are already a thing. And that actually what Apple is doing here is leaning
Speaker 5:  into a very useful trend. I still would argue that just having
Speaker 5:  your phone sort of banging around on your hip is a weird choice.
Speaker 6:  It's funny because, you know, when I take my camera out,
Speaker 6:  it's on a strap, it's around my body, right? It's just banging
Speaker 6:  around. There's a very functional purpose for that, right? It, it's, I don't
Speaker 6:  need it all the time. I wanna be able to quickly pull it up. You can, you
Speaker 6:  can make that argument about a phone, I guess, which you also do use for
Speaker 6:  photos. Maybe the thing that feels off about it to me
Speaker 6:  is, you know, a camera, it sort of has like a, a very specific
Speaker 6:  purpose, right? It's either off or I'm taking a photo. If I'm taking a photo,
Speaker 6:  I'm, I'm doing some sort of socially constructed,
Speaker 6:  you know, action, right? Hmm. People know I'm taking the photo, I'm taking
Speaker 6:  a photo of an object. There's a limited period of time with the phone.
Speaker 6:  I think having it banging around all the time sort of indicates like, Hey
Speaker 6:  man, I could whip this out at any second. I'm gonna be on this thing a lot.
Speaker 6:  Might be watching TikTok videos. I'm gonna be in line. I'm gonna be talking
Speaker 6:  to you. And it might, right? And I think, you know, the
Speaker 6:  norms are a little different there for some
Speaker 6:  folks than others.
Speaker 6:  I, I think, like for me, you know, I want to have
Speaker 6:  my phone away and out of sight. If somebody else's phone was like right
Speaker 6:  beside them, buzzing up, lighting up all the time, I, I think that would,
Speaker 6:  would feel a little weird in conversation with me. But
Speaker 6:  I see it, right? Phones are a little big. People like them to be
Speaker 6:  a little too big. That's convenient. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And I think I, I sort of love this because, and, and Jess's piece is very
Speaker 5:  good molding to it in the show notes, but she, she argues that
Speaker 5:  this is sort of a perfectly appley product in that like, if this is
Speaker 5:  for you, apple really thought it all the way through, right? It has, it has
Speaker 5:  magnets for easy attaching, you can, you can color coordinate it to your
Speaker 5:  clothes because it's easy to take the, the lanyard on and off. You can
Speaker 5:  just quickly adjust the size of the strap so that you can use it more
Speaker 5:  easily and ha attach it to things like, if you're gonna
Speaker 5:  make a cross body strap, this is the way to do it. And I just think,
Speaker 5:  to me, the whole existence of this is a trend. It, it gets at
Speaker 5:  exactly what you're talking about. Where it's like, this is a tool you
Speaker 5:  use to do stuff all the time. And I think especially in places like
Speaker 5:  Europe and Asia where things like transit tickets are like
Speaker 5:  all done on mobile and, and the sort of NFC culture is just
Speaker 5:  absolutely everywhere. This idea of like having a thing that I can just reach
Speaker 5:  out and tap all the time instead of actually, even for me having to dig it
Speaker 5:  outta my pocket over and over makes a lot of sense. And it's just like, I
Speaker 5:  just so don't use my phone this way. Right. Where it is like constantly sort
Speaker 5:  of up and down. I'm actually trying to do that less with my phone. Yes, yes.
Speaker 5:  And I want my phone to be less near me. But it,
Speaker 5:  it's just an interesting way to like think about your phone in the world.
Speaker 5:  So I am suitably wrong and as penance, I will wear one of these around
Speaker 5:  for a week And I will tell everybody about it. And I'm very much looking
Speaker 5:  forward to that.
Speaker 6:  What color are you gonna choose?
Speaker 5:  I, I don't know. That's,
Speaker 6:  That's what matters
Speaker 5:  Most. Every, every hour that goes by, I get a little closer to
Speaker 5:  throwing away this blue iPhone 16 that I love dearly and absolutely do not
Speaker 5:  need to upgrade. And just going full orange, just, just
Speaker 5:  orange iPhone, orange case, orange, cross body strap.
Speaker 5:  Just, just be that guy. I do. You can't do both at once. Lifestyle
Speaker 6:  Blue on one side, orange on the other.
Speaker 5:  I like that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Now you're talking do Carey.
Speaker 5:  So yeah, go read that piece. It's good stuff. Couple more little things.
Speaker 5:  There was a really interesting paper slash
Speaker 5:  press release that Apple put out around the iPhone 17 that we didn't really
Speaker 5:  talk about, about a security upgrade that it comes with, which Apple calls
Speaker 5:  memory integrity enforcement. And basically
Speaker 5:  this is a very complicated system designed to stop one specific kind of
Speaker 5:  intrusion on iPhones, which is the thing that we hear about
Speaker 5:  and talk about usually during criminal activity of one kind or
Speaker 5:  another. When like law enforcement wants to get into an iPhone,
Speaker 5:  apple typically does not help. And there are an
Speaker 5:  increasingly large number of tools for getting into iPhones.
Speaker 5:  And there's also like, there, there's a whole sort of
Speaker 5:  spyware industry around this. There's, there's like a lot of way, and Apple
Speaker 5:  went way out of its way to be like, we are, we have spent,
Speaker 5:  I think they said a half a decade trying to stop this. And we have figured
Speaker 5:  out how to stop this. And I just think this is fascinating. Like this,
Speaker 5:  this ongoing privacy versus
Speaker 5:  openness versus who is actually responsible for the data
Speaker 5:  on your device and who owns it and who gets to have it. Apple
Speaker 5:  continues to make it stance there. Very clear. And I just think that's really
Speaker 5:  interesting.
Speaker 6:  I mean this is so fascinating, particularly because it's not like they went,
Speaker 6:  Hey, we fixed some really common issue with
Speaker 6:  Java that could have destroyed millions of iPhones. Right?
Speaker 6:  Right. This is the kind of thing that a specific
Speaker 6:  spyware developer is going to sell to one, you know,
Speaker 6:  state sponsored hacker for millions of dollars Yep. With the
Speaker 6:  goal of invading a single target's phone
Speaker 6:  and tracking them. Right? Yeah. But it's gonna be really, really, really
Speaker 6:  bad when that happens. Yeah. Like that's the kind of stuff that Apple is
Speaker 6:  dealing with now. And you know, to their credit, they, they do go
Speaker 6:  out of their way to lock that stuff down and to notify people when they figure
Speaker 6:  out that somebody's been targeted. And so I will confess
Speaker 6:  I do not understand what they did here at all, but
Speaker 6:  I do appreciate, like this is the kind of thing that we see from them pretty
Speaker 6:  regularly.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Apple calls this kind of software mercenary spyware, which is just
Speaker 5:  a truly terrific phrase. Like mercenary spyware is like
Speaker 5:  a, a series of Netflix spy thrillers that I would watch without one second
Speaker 5:  of thought. Like Mr. Robot, two mercenary spyware is like, I'm in, oh yeah,
Speaker 5:  let's do this. I love this very much. All right, a couple more things.
Speaker 5:  In, in all of the headphone stuff,
Speaker 5:  there are, there was a, a Beats earbuds leak
Speaker 5:  that I just wanna briefly mention because whenever we talk about Apple headphones,
Speaker 5:  I hear from people who are like, you're talking about the wrong Apple headphones
Speaker 5:  because the beat stuff is all better and they
Speaker 5:  haven't been officially announced yet, but the, the new
Speaker 5:  version of the Powerbeats fit may be coming soon. So if you're somebody who
Speaker 5:  likes the Wing Tips, I like the Wing tips. Maybe hold off in the AirPods
Speaker 5:  Pro three.
Speaker 6:  It's funny, beats even beat them to the heart rate sensor. Right.
Speaker 6:  Beats had a pair of earbuds earlier this year that, that did that. I
Speaker 6:  I do not understand the relationship between Apple and Beats at this point
Speaker 6:  in time. And I'm not convinced that Apple does either. But
Speaker 6:  Beats is putting out some nice looking headphones like they, they look good.
Speaker 6:  People still like 'em, the colors are nice. They know about colors.
Speaker 6:  That's good stuff.
Speaker 5:  They do. Beets also looks like they're gonna be an orange. Just
Speaker 5:  saying like, if you're going full aesthetic this year,
Speaker 5:  you want the beets.
Speaker 6:  It's the way this, oh this orange I'm, we'll we'll see. This feels like it's
Speaker 6:  gonna be hot for Halloween. And then everybody's gonna be like, I
Speaker 6:  I have regrets. That's, that's my early prediction on Orange.
Speaker 5:  Interesting. Speaking of the colors, by the way, I don't know if you've noticed
Speaker 5:  this, but in addition to the excitement about the orange, there has been
Speaker 5:  some consternation that there is no black option on the iPhone pros this
Speaker 5:  year, which I had, I didn't even really process until people started being
Speaker 5:  mad about it. Like there kind of isn't a default,
Speaker 5:  like no excitement choice for the iPhone
Speaker 5:  17 pro this year.
Speaker 6:  The the dark blue is good if you're, if you're a dark phone person, like
Speaker 6:  the dark blue is is very nice. Yes, it is a color, but it's nice. It's nice.
Speaker 6:  There's also, what is it white or is it like kind of cream? I can't remember
Speaker 6:  because there's like a creamy one for the the iPhone air. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  The, the pro, again, I haven't seen it in person. You have, but it's, it's
Speaker 5:  more, it's like silver, pretty straight silver. It's like, it kind of looks
Speaker 5:  like MacBook silver to
Speaker 6:  Right, right, right. Yeah. I've, I've never loved the Silvers.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But yeah, I, it, I think that's weird, right?
Speaker 6:  I i it has there been a year before where there hasn't, sorry, maybe since.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Has there ever not been a black iPhone? I
Speaker 5:  Would not swear to it, but I certainly cannot recall there not being a black
Speaker 5:  iPhone or something very like it. Like they'll call it, you know, space gray
Speaker 5:  or whatever, but something that is functionally a black phone.
Speaker 5:  I don't remember the last time.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Me, me either.
Speaker 5:  If you do Vergecast of The Verge dot com tell us when it was and tell us
Speaker 5:  what color you bought. I wanna know. But yeah, I think, I think you're
Speaker 5:  probably right that the blue becomes that thing, but it is
Speaker 5:  the, the sort of ongoing thesis of a lot of
Speaker 5:  this year's phones is that they're sort of more different than
Speaker 5:  ever. And that actually what Apple is doing is pushing more and more people
Speaker 5:  toward the 17. Like I think the, the
Speaker 5:  base pro and the base iPhone
Speaker 5:  have always been the ones that like regular people would decide to buy. And
Speaker 5:  it was always like, do you want the slightly better camera and the slightly
Speaker 5:  better battery life and like you might upgrade even if you don't want the
Speaker 5:  sort of highest of the high end features. I don't see that this time. I think
Speaker 5:  if you don't want the the if, if you don't know what pro
Speaker 5:  res is, you probably don't need an iPhone pro.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I'll say the air maybe complicates things a bit, but
Speaker 6:  I feel
Speaker 5:  It's easy 'cause it's the pretty one. It's like the iPad maybe is Yeah. You
Speaker 5:  either want it or you don't.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that's, I think that's fair.
Speaker 5:  And I think we, we try to sort of ham fist it into the lineup, but it is,
Speaker 5:  it's gonna be such a visceral thing for people where like either you want
Speaker 5:  the air or you don't. Yeah. And I think most people already know the answer
Speaker 5:  to that.
Speaker 6:  That tracks that tracks. Yeah. You're you're looking for something
Speaker 5:  Flashy, which is also really upsetting because I increasingly want the air.
Speaker 6:  Oh, I hate that
Speaker 5:  I am this person. It's, but I like,
Speaker 6:  It's cool. It's cool. It looks nice. I know. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  I'm, I'm trying to stop upgrading my phone every year like I do in part because
Speaker 5:  we do this for a living and in part because I'm like a lunatic in this specific
Speaker 5:  way, but I'm, I'm trying to be more
Speaker 5:  responsible in my gadget
Speaker 6:  Purchases. Now is this really the year to give it up, David?
Speaker 5:  No, it's not. I've decided this is, this is where I've landed.
Speaker 6:  I'm sorry. I'm I'm sorry to do it. You. Yeah, it's
Speaker 5:  Fraternal.
Speaker 6:  That blue is just so old. I, I can't believe you're still
Speaker 6:  still using that thing.
Speaker 5:  Alright, let's, let's talk about some other gadget news before we need to
Speaker 5:  take a break here. Yes.
Speaker 5:  This is like a half a gadget news so far. So nothing, which I think
Speaker 5:  is like one of the most interesting hardware companies still.
Speaker 5:  They have a new set of their own earbuds coming out the year three
Speaker 5:  coming out next week. So we're gonna get all the details next week.
Speaker 5:  But what we've learned this week is that in
Speaker 5:  the, the headphones look roughly the same as they have before. They have
Speaker 5:  that kind of transparent design. They look very cool. Nothing is very good
Speaker 5:  at designing these kinds of gadgets. I really like the way that it looks.
Speaker 5:  But there's a, there's a microphone and a talk button on the
Speaker 5:  charging case itself. We don't know what it's for. We don't know how
Speaker 5:  it's gonna work. We just know that it's there.
Speaker 6:  You know, I don't understand what it is, but it's cool. I think it's cool
Speaker 6:  that there's a button and it says talk I nothing loves a gimmick, but like
Speaker 6:  this might, it's maybe this is a good gimmick, right? Because I think that
Speaker 6:  the conspiracy theory, tell me if I'm wrong here. I think the conspiracy
Speaker 6:  theory is that this is going to actually double as a wireless microphone.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's the only thing I can think of is that, that that ha that it
Speaker 5:  is, it will, if you press the button take over as
Speaker 5:  the microphone,
Speaker 6:  It is weird because obviously the headphones have mics built in,
Speaker 6:  But that doesn't matter 'cause you're on TikTok and you wanna be holding
Speaker 6:  something, you wanna be holding like a, a thing that is a microphone but
Speaker 6:  doesn't look like a microphone.
Speaker 5:  Right? That is true. So my, my initial take for this
Speaker 5:  was like, okay, the, the sort of handheld microphones are everywhere now
Speaker 5:  and people love the little lavaliers in DJI is selling stuff. And so the
Speaker 5:  idea of like, let's let's repurpose the case into something that A
Speaker 5:  is usable and b puts our brand in front of everybody
Speaker 5:  every time you make a video makes a lot of sense to me.
Speaker 5:  But it, it might just look stupid. It might just
Speaker 5:  look like you're talking into your headphones case.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. But it's, it's a cool looking headphones case, right? Like,
Speaker 6:  you know, I'll give him that. I mean, is it, is it stupider than a very,
Speaker 6:  very, very, very tiny microphone?
Speaker 6:  Like I I don't think that, I don't know what cool is anymore. I
Speaker 6:  like everyone has lost the plot here. Oh,
Speaker 5:  That's so true.
Speaker 6:  You just need to be holding an object that looks slightly wrong. I
Speaker 6:  think that's what the goal is here. And so I I I actually think this works.
Speaker 5:  I that's a phenomenal argument. I actually have no comeback for that. It
Speaker 5:  is going to look slightly stupid in the way it is probably supposed to look
Speaker 5:  slightly stupid. I think is is probably exactly right. One
Speaker 5:  other theory I will give you is that so nothing has been doing
Speaker 5:  some really interesting AI stuff. They have this thing on their newest phones
Speaker 5:  called Essential Space, which is sort of like the pixel
Speaker 5:  screenshots feature, like blown out. You, you put a bunch of notes in, you
Speaker 5:  take screenshots, you add files, whatever else, and then it sort of,
Speaker 5:  AI is its way into trying to organize it for you and make it accessible.
Speaker 5:  Great idea. I think it's super useful.
Speaker 5:  The idea of this as like a dedicated voice input to that
Speaker 5:  strikes me as kind of interesting I think because if
Speaker 5:  you're, if you're nothing, what you don't have access to is
Speaker 5:  the like built in assistant stuff in the same way. So for nothing to just
Speaker 5:  be like, oh well we'll we're also shipping a little voice recorder that just
Speaker 5:  pipes stuff into your phone.
Speaker 5:  Some wonky bluetoothy stuff that would have to do to make that work. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But I think there is potentially, it's, it's just an input device that I
Speaker 5:  think could be interesting. We're seeing these like AI voice recorders
Speaker 5:  everywhere and they're not hard to build. They're pretty easy to like
Speaker 5:  make semi-functional. And so I, I could totally see a world in
Speaker 5:  which that's what this thing also is.
Speaker 6:  And it's also every single product designer is trying to figure
Speaker 6:  out how they can add AI to their spec sheet. So like it's it's there's
Speaker 6:  a real chance. There's a real chance it goes that direction.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The nothing ear three AI headphones is like a thing I Oh yeah. I hate
Speaker 6:  Already,
Speaker 5:  But it's is definitely coming. Speaking of ai,
Speaker 5:  Google, you may have heard of it, released this thing called the Daily
Speaker 5:  Hub with the Pixel 10. One of the like big features
Speaker 5:  of the new Pixel supposed to do AI to like bring all of your stuff together.
Speaker 5:  Calendar events. Like it's basically like the just Google Discover feed
Speaker 5:  times 10, I would say. Except it turns out it didn't work and Google pulled
Speaker 5:  it already.
Speaker 6:  Okay. On one hand I think this is, this feature
Speaker 6:  is totally inconsequential and doesn't matter. And on the other hand I think
Speaker 6:  this is completely galling, right? This is a
Speaker 6:  brand new feature that they sold the phone with, right.
Speaker 6:  A feature of your brand new phone was just removed. Yep.
Speaker 6:  And I think particularly for the pixel line where, and it's
Speaker 6:  particularly this year, the software is really all that's new.
Speaker 6:  The That's wild. That's what now listen, zero people bought the phone
Speaker 6:  for Daily Hub. Sure. Did Google even advertise this thing? I was trying to
Speaker 6:  find more information on this and it's, it just isn't available 'cause no
Speaker 6:  one cares about it.
Speaker 5:  But there is the, the, it's part of a bigger pitch to me, which is like,
Speaker 5:  I I, to me I think we need to hold Google's feet to the fire for this because
Speaker 5:  we held Apple's feet to the fire fort, right? Oh yeah. And what Google is
Speaker 5:  doing here is not as egregious as what Apple did, which is promise a
Speaker 5:  version of Siri that not only doesn't exist but like actively sucks.
Speaker 5:  This is just Google being like, actually what we're gonna do with AI is we
Speaker 5:  are going to fundamentally transform the way that you interact with your
Speaker 5:  phone. And instead of just having like a, a sequence of apps that
Speaker 5:  you open in order to do different kinds of things, you wanna look at your
Speaker 5:  calendar, you open the calendar, you wanna look at your email, you open your
Speaker 5:  email. Like it actually doesn't have to be that way. And the idea that you
Speaker 5:  could use AI to just be like, here's what matters to you. We have done the
Speaker 5:  work of going into your apps and making sense of your phone for you. Like
Speaker 5:  that's the pitch. That is what everyone is trying to do. And for
Speaker 5:  Google to be like, we did it. Here it is, it's a cool feature of this new
Speaker 5:  phone that you should totally buy and then just mothball it outta nowhere
Speaker 5:  is like, I don't think it's like consumer hostile for basically the
Speaker 5:  reason you're describing. Like, I don't know that anybody bought this phone
Speaker 5:  for that reason anyway, but it's a bad look and this suggests that Google
Speaker 5:  is not just
Speaker 5:  able to get this stuff right.
Speaker 6:  Well I agree. And it's like a feature of your phone that you potentially
Speaker 6:  bought the phone for has now been removed. That, that feels just
Speaker 6:  fundamentally wrong to me. Right. You still paid the same amount of money
Speaker 6:  for the phone, you just can't use some of it anymore. Yeah. Now
Speaker 6:  I I I am very curious to know what was going so horrendously wrong
Speaker 6:  with this feature that was basically just a glorified calendar
Speaker 6:  that that had been LL md like what, what happened
Speaker 6:  that they had to pull this entire thing?
Speaker 5:  So Alison Johnson who, who reviewed the phone and got to use it, lemme just
Speaker 5:  read you a little bit of the, the thing that she
Speaker 5:  described with Daily Hub. So she, she basically,
Speaker 5:  she used it, she got the calendar, she compared it to the now brief
Speaker 5:  on Samsung's S 25 phones, which is just like, pull some information about
Speaker 5:  your day. And then she says, but it also misconstrued some of my recent Google
Speaker 5:  search history in puzzling in hilarious ways. I looked up the schedule for
Speaker 5:  our recycling service provided by Waste Management. And it took that to mean
Speaker 5:  I'm interested in learning more about waste management generally. Not quite
Speaker 5:  this. If you, if you want a perfect microcosm of the ways
Speaker 5:  AI could be great and fall spectacularly short there, it's right. Like
Speaker 5:  Google's ability to be like, oh, here are all the things you Googled yesterday.
Speaker 5:  Here's some new information about that. Why don't we put it into your feed?
Speaker 5:  Oh, you wanted to see who won the Warriors game? Well the Warriors game is
Speaker 5:  over. We'll we'll we'll give you the score 'cause we know you
Speaker 5:  feelings about the news and tech industry and the world,
Speaker 5:  And I have brought you both here basically to tell me how wrong
Speaker 5:  I am about everything. So I don't know, do, do you guys know Subway takes?
Speaker 11:  Yes.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So Subway takes basically the, the shtick is they're sitting on the
Speaker 5:  subway. He sits down, he says, so what's your take? The person delivers the
Speaker 5:  take and, and Kareem the host, either a hundred percent agrees or a hundred
Speaker 5:  percent disagrees. So this is, I'm, we're just gonna rip that
Speaker 5:  format entirely. I'm going to offer you a take and you are going to either
Speaker 5:  there, there, there are no middle grounds here. You are either in or you
Speaker 5:  are out. But I will offer you a a third option, which is
Speaker 5:  essentially like David is just annihilating his own career in front of me
Speaker 5:  right now. So I'm just going to abstain from this and be quiet. That's allowed,
Speaker 5:  if you listen to see
Speaker 6:  That. Oh boy, I'm have a lot of questions about where
Speaker 6:  these takes are going. Yeah,
Speaker 11:  I can't wait to hear these.
Speaker 5:  We're either in a word out and, and, and this is just what we're doing here.
Speaker 5:  Can
Speaker 6:  I say something? I'm a hundred percent in. I have five
Speaker 5:  Takes for you. We, we can discuss as much as you would like. These are all
Speaker 5:  about ai. Hayden, I've brought you here because it turns out most of my takes
Speaker 5:  are about ai.
Speaker 11:  We're gonna talk. That's common. So I love it.
Speaker 5:  Does this sound good? Everybody? Everybody feel good? Any questions? Would
Speaker 5:  you like to leave before we even start?
Speaker 11:  We're all at, we're 100% in and as you said, so,
Speaker 5:  Okay, take number one. Open AI
Speaker 5:  is a total house of cards and it is all going to collapse like any minute
Speaker 5:  now. And it might just bring America down with it.
Speaker 11:  Man,
Speaker 6:  That's a, that's a lot for a quick reaction.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, this is one I would definitely love to have a middle ground on, but
Speaker 11:  okay, if I have to choose, you're
Speaker 5:  In or you're out.
Speaker 11:  If I have to choose one or the other to the dismay of some, I'll say
Speaker 11:  I will disagree. I think that, you know,
Speaker 11:  valuation is crazy. We won't even talk about profit. But you know,
Speaker 11:  they have a product that a lot of people are using every single day and
Speaker 11:  it's coming up when I go to the bar, it's coming up when I go to the club,
Speaker 11:  when I'm walking my dog, my super is talking to me about it. So I mean,
Speaker 11:  it is a consumer tool that everyone is using, it seems like, and they're
Speaker 11:  using it a lot for a ton of different things in their life. And
Speaker 11:  now they have government partnerships and they're working with like, you
Speaker 11:  know, companies all through the Fortune 500. So I think for better or
Speaker 11:  worse, I'll say that for better or worse, I disagree. And I don't think
Speaker 11:  it's a house of cards that's gonna fall anytime soon.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I'm, I'm, I'm with Hayden here. Damn. I disagree. Listen, they're a
Speaker 6:  product. It's a, it's a reasonably good product. Listen, there's a lot we
Speaker 6:  can argue about there, but every, it is a product that I think
Speaker 6:  any tech company would, would trade most of what they sell to have that product.
Speaker 6:  There is a lot of money tied up in it, questionable amounts of money tied
Speaker 6:  up in it. Right? If there's one thing I've learned about Silicon Valley and
Speaker 6:  listen, I I'll admit that, that this may not be an expert opinion, but
Speaker 6:  there's one thing I've learned, money is a little bit fake over there. Right?
Speaker 6:  They, they're gonna figure this out if they have to and they have to because
Speaker 6:  way too many people have way too much money on the line.
Speaker 5:  So you, you just said the thing that is the hardest for me to
Speaker 5:  combat, which is that there is now so much riding on it working
Speaker 5:  that like OpenAI might be Bitcoin in the sense that it, it it is
Speaker 5:  just, it is, there's too much money in it and the people who are in it
Speaker 5:  have too much invested in it to let it fall apart.
Speaker 11:  I actually think that's a great analogy.
Speaker 6:  Wait, can I a hundred percent disagree on the Bitcoin analogy?
Speaker 5:  You don't like the Bitcoin analogy? No,
Speaker 11:  Because we're doing a meta disagreement
Speaker 6:  Bi Bitcoin if I can. Okay. Bitcoin has a bunch of
Speaker 6:  nonsense investors, right? Like there, there are real
Speaker 6:  companies, they're like institutions that are invested in
Speaker 6:  open ai, Bitcoin. I think that one can fall apart.
Speaker 6:  So, but
Speaker 5:  Much
Speaker 6:  Bunch of internet randos. We just
Speaker 5:  Had some crazy bunch violent,
Speaker 6:  I'm really, I'm really like sidetracking us here in, in New York. One metaphor.
Speaker 6:  But so
Speaker 11:  You saw the violent crimes tied to Bitcoin recently, like people will do
Speaker 11:  a lot to make it succeed or get it.
Speaker 5:  I that is, that is fair. And I think yeah, we'll we'll leave the
Speaker 5:  Bitcoin thing to the side. That's a whole nother take. That I Fair enough,
Speaker 5:  fair enough. I'm not even ready for that. I'm
Speaker 11:  Time. We'll do that next time. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Allow me to just briefly make the case that OpenAI is a total disaster and
Speaker 5:  about to fall apart. Let's hear it. Thing number one, OpenAI. The,
Speaker 5:  according to the, the reporting from the information last week is going to
Speaker 5:  burn through $115 billion between now and
Speaker 5:  2029. Yes. Money is fake. Yes. Sam Altman appears to be
Speaker 5:  able to raise as much money as he wants at any given time.
Speaker 5:  $115 billion is a lot of
Speaker 5:  money. And, and at some point it actually doesn't take all that
Speaker 5:  much for somebody to say, oh, all that money we're giving to you we're just
Speaker 5:  gonna put over there. And it like, when it goes, it goes quickly. And
Speaker 5:  $115 billion until
Speaker 5:  2029 is, is a lot to ask of people, especially in a moment where some
Speaker 5:  of the hype on this is starting to die. Like the only way you get there is
Speaker 5:  to convince everybody that by 2029 you will have invented God. And
Speaker 5:  I think we're getting away from that pretty quickly. And so the idea of why
Speaker 5:  am I going to let you lose $115 billion by 2029
Speaker 5:  just gets a little harder. That's one Think number two,
Speaker 5:  Claude is a better product than chat GPT And I think people are starting
Speaker 5:  to realize it. I think Anthropic is shipping circles
Speaker 5:  around OpenAI and OpenAI had a very good big
Speaker 5:  first mover advantage that I think it is losing really, really, really fast.
Speaker 5:  And, and Anthropic also just raised money at a crazy valuation. Google is
Speaker 5:  out here doing stuff like I think OpenAI is still in the lead, but I think
Speaker 5:  it deserves that lead a little bit less every single day. And I think, again,
Speaker 5:  this is what I mean by a house of cards. Like all this stuff only works if
Speaker 5:  it's all working in tandem and as soon as one leg of it comes out, the whole
Speaker 5:  thing collapses because it's $115 billion. You have
Speaker 5:  to be willing to stomach. And I just don't know why people would be,
Speaker 6:  You know, I don't think they have to have invented God though. Right? What
Speaker 6:  if they have just merely invented Google, right? That is still a
Speaker 6:  very big company. I'm not sure that OpenAI is going to be the winner necessarily
Speaker 6:  after all of this. But they have a product they can compete on it.
Speaker 5:  You know, what Google's product makes is money.
Speaker 6:  That is true. But you know, what open I can do is start shoving a bunch of
Speaker 6:  ads into this thing, right?
Speaker 11:  Which they haven't ruled out,
Speaker 6:  Right? There are ways in which they can start making money, they can turn
Speaker 6:  that funnel on. I don't know how easily, I dunno if people will like it as
Speaker 6:  much. I don't know if they'll accomplish the, the crazy dreams of
Speaker 6:  automating the entire workforce of the world. But
Speaker 6:  they've, they've made, they've made a search engine, they've made a, a tool
Speaker 6:  that can code for people, right? It can do some things reasonably well.
Speaker 6:  They have a product, I, I'm not sure you are right,
Speaker 6:  it it is a high wire act that they are on. Right. That
Speaker 6:  there is so much money and they're spending it very,
Speaker 6:  very quickly.
Speaker 11:  Yes. And you know, like you said about product, they also are making a LinkedIn
Speaker 11:  competitor of sorts, you know, they're doing a lot. I think you're right
Speaker 11:  about the amount of money. It's crazy. Like, I won't even speak to that
Speaker 11:  because it's all fake and it's just like a hype bubble that's definitely
Speaker 11:  gonna burst, I don't think. But when I think about a house of cards, it's
Speaker 11:  something that's gonna like fail crazily and go out of
Speaker 11:  business. Like some of the companies we've reported on in the past, like,
Speaker 11:  you know, 10 years. And I don't think that's gonna happen to
Speaker 11:  open ai. I think that maybe they'll get less of a lead. We're gonna see
Speaker 11:  a lot more m and a in the space. We're gonna see, you know,
Speaker 11:  lots more aqua hires and like shell companies. But I don't think open
Speaker 11:  AI is just gonna fall apart. I think they'll make a lot of people mad and
Speaker 11:  investors mad probably. But you know, I don't see them like collapsing
Speaker 11:  entirely because a lot of their talent is, you know,
Speaker 11:  what's kind of pushing the space forward right now for better or worse.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I, I have debated many times on like, is the,
Speaker 5:  is the extent of the disaster that I'm predicting like
Speaker 5:  Theranos and like no, it's not. I'm, I'm not, I'm not, I don't see that coming.
Speaker 5:  I don't think anyone goes to prison at the end of the open AI story.
Speaker 5:  Or is it like, you know, the, the cosmos and web
Speaker 5:  vans of like the.com bust of 25 years ago that are like the ideas
Speaker 5:  that were ahead of their time and spent like crazy and just couldn't do it
Speaker 5:  and it all fell apart? Or is it like, I don't know who's a good example,
Speaker 5:  like Cisco is a company that like was huge
Speaker 5:  and then collapsed during the.com bubble and is now like
Speaker 5:  still around, still doing stuff, still doing fine, but is I think still
Speaker 5:  not as valuable as it was 25 years ago. Right? So it's like, I, I don't know
Speaker 5:  the extent to which I even think this is all gonna fall apart. I think you're
Speaker 5:  right that like at this point, the existence of open AI and chat
Speaker 5:  GBT in particular
Speaker 5:  is sort of self perpetuating. But I just, I can't
Speaker 5:  shake the idea that the only thing they have going for them now is
Speaker 5:  that they were first and they are famous and that is like, there is a, that
Speaker 5:  that's valuable and Sam Altman being like, the face of all of this is really
Speaker 5:  valuable, but also Sam Altman is going through perpetually weird stuff
Speaker 5:  all the time and is involved in 10 million different projects and
Speaker 6:  Totally fast. It's not clear how much he wants to be there.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. And he is, yeah. He's not good at faking it if
Speaker 11:  he does Yeah, sure isn't. So you, but yeah, I could see a
Speaker 11:  Cisco thing happening. I'll say that I could see a Cisco thing happening
Speaker 11:  in the future. We'll see. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Alright. That's take number one. Take number two
Speaker 5:  is, is less feisty, but is is a, a feeling I have had many times And I
Speaker 5:  just need to get this off my chest. Take number two is I officially
Speaker 5:  and forever do not care how much money your company has raised or what you
Speaker 5:  are valued at. It has no bearing on anything. And I don't care. I'm out.
Speaker 5:  I'm not interested. That is not a piece of information that is relevant to
Speaker 5:  me in my life personally or professionally anymore.
Speaker 11:  I 100% agree with that. Yes. Like utterly and
Speaker 11:  wholly with my whole soul. I,
Speaker 11:  it's funny because I was, you know, writing a lot of those stories
Speaker 11:  at my last job and it was very important that I get it first and like,
Speaker 11:  you know, you know, call and confirm and get the valuation
Speaker 11:  right and whether it was post money or pre and all of those details. And
Speaker 11:  I have to say that in the past few months, it's gotten so out of hand
Speaker 11:  that I now could not care less. And I often have to like, you know, even
Speaker 11:  as an AI reporter who like references very often what these companies are
Speaker 11:  valued at. I have to Google it every time because I, it's all fake to me
Speaker 11:  now. Like I don't, it's all just paper money and it doesn't
Speaker 11:  really mean anything. And yes, philanthropic is catching up to open AI's
Speaker 11:  valuation And I think in context, yeah, that's important for seeing
Speaker 11:  what the industry's doing and where it's heading, but the numbers like
Speaker 11:  I could be just making those up. I, I totally agree. I couldn't agree more,
Speaker 5:  Jake.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah, strong agree strongly. Let's go. They're, they're entertaining
Speaker 6:  at times if only to see how outrageous they are. But like they, they're meaningless,
Speaker 6:  right? They, this is just how much some random people decided to bet on a
Speaker 6:  certain company. I, I like look back, I don't
Speaker 6:  know, in some ways fondly on like 2010
Speaker 6:  tech crunch when there are all of these mobile app, like
Speaker 6:  anybody with a mobile app, just automatically, you'd be handed several million
Speaker 6:  dollars to build it out. Yep. And there was one in particular that
Speaker 6:  got a lot of buzz, I think it was color that got like
Speaker 6:  $40 million and it was supposed to like reinvent
Speaker 6:  social photo sharing and nobody used
Speaker 6:  it. But again, these things don't mean anything, right? Like, great, somebody
Speaker 6:  thought you had a good idea, they gave you way too much money. That does
Speaker 6:  not tell me if your idea is actually good or if you can actually execute
Speaker 6:  on it.
Speaker 11:  And the fact that, you know, I don't know, it's just, it's just crazy
Speaker 11:  because I feel like we've gone through so many periods of
Speaker 11:  fundraising too, where one word just gets you all the money with no questions
Speaker 11:  asked. Yes. Like first we had, you know, what you were talking about then
Speaker 11:  we had just ai, if you had AI in your pitch deck, great, we'll give, we'll
Speaker 11:  give you all the money now. It's AI agents, not just AI but agents.
Speaker 11:  And then, you know, there's gonna be something else. So it's just crazy
Speaker 11:  to me that like, you know, we just keep going through these cycles where
Speaker 11:  one word gets you as much money as you want or one person. So
Speaker 11:  a lot of these companies are pre idea, pre-product
Speaker 11:  and pre profit. So it's just you're investing in the person, which I guess
Speaker 11:  has always been the case, but you know, at what cost literally.
Speaker 5:  Right. And that's the thing. And it's like, if, if you're also a venture
Speaker 5:  capitalist, sure these numbers matter. But in terms of like,
Speaker 5:  if, if your job is just to understand like what companies and
Speaker 5:  products and people in this space matter company valuations and amount
Speaker 5:  raised literally have nothing to do with it. It's like, it, it is just completely
Speaker 5:  divorced from reality. And I am deeply tired of pretending any of it means
Speaker 5:  anything. And this is like, I, the one work thing I did this summer was like
Speaker 5:  occasionally check my email because coming back to thousands of emails just
Speaker 5:  sucks. So I would just occasionally go through and clear out my inbox and
Speaker 5:  the number of them where the whole pitch is, well we just raised x, y, z
Speaker 5:  money from x, y, z investor, thus you're gonna be interested in it. I'm like,
Speaker 5:  actually those are two completely unrelated facts. I
Speaker 5:  just, I don't care that you raised money, not interested,
Speaker 5:  but good. I'm glad we're on the same page. Okay. I think we're gonna all
Speaker 5:  agree on this one too. And this one might be the one I feel most strongly
Speaker 5:  about having spent too much time alone on the internet for the last two months.
Speaker 5:  If you find yourself starting a sentence with here's what chat
Speaker 5:  GPT said, or I asked Claude, or according to
Speaker 5:  Gemini y you are the worst And I don't like you and
Speaker 5:  you what the end of your sentence is not going to be interesting to me. I
Speaker 5:  asked chat. GPT is not the beginning of a good story and
Speaker 5:  everybody should stop doing it, please, on the internet and in real life,
Speaker 11:  I 100% agree. I think Jake will too. I'm like, I,
Speaker 11:  it doesn't matter at all. It, it has no bearing on anything. If I feel
Speaker 11:  crazy when people say that to me as like an evidence of something because
Speaker 11:  I'm like, it's just a large scale pattern generator. I think a lot of people
Speaker 11:  don't understand how these models work. It's like, it's a large scale pattern
Speaker 11:  generator. It's like you're at a campfire at summer camp and you're
Speaker 11:  doing one of those like games where each of you is telling a story, but
Speaker 11:  you're each saying one word and like trying to make a story together. That's
Speaker 11:  it, that's how it works. So I'm like, okay. Like I,
Speaker 11:  I don't even use it that much honestly, because I try not to like overuse
Speaker 11:  it in my personal life or in life at all. But whenever I do,
Speaker 11:  there are so many hallucinations that I'm like, okay, I'm not even like
Speaker 11:  a power user. So I can't even imagine how much it makes up for like other
Speaker 11:  people. Plus I've seen a lot of like TikTok trends lately where people are
Speaker 11:  holding up, you know, Chachi, bt or Claude, and they're like,
Speaker 11:  oh, see, like, yeah, this is what Claude said, see as evidence,
Speaker 11:  which is just, has no bearing on anything. It makes me feel crazy.
Speaker 11:  So yeah, I totally agree. And
Speaker 5:  Not only that, it's boring. It's like a really, it's just a boring way to
Speaker 5:  say something like, I don't, I don't care.
Speaker 5:  Jake, what do you think?
Speaker 6:  Listen, if there were degrees,
Speaker 5:  Nope. You're in or you're out, Jake,
Speaker 6:  I might take advantage, but no, I, I think I'm gonna agree here. I,
Speaker 6:  it's tricky because there are sometimes when I
Speaker 6:  have wanted to to, there, there's a number of things that I will look up
Speaker 6:  using Chassy, BT or Claude or whatever, where it's like,
Speaker 6:  I wanna know this. I don't really wanna know it that badly and it's not
Speaker 6:  that important to my life. Right? Like recently,
Speaker 6:  I wanted to know how chess engines work. And
Speaker 6:  so I was asking, I was like brushing my teeth and I'm like, like asking
Speaker 6:  Claude, how's chess engines? Like, figure out what the best move is. And,
Speaker 6:  you know, it goes through, it breaks it down for me. It like gives me all
Speaker 6:  this information. It seemed reasonably accurate. I don't know, I
Speaker 6:  didn't confirm it. There have been times when
Speaker 6:  I will do this and then I later wanna tell somebody like, oh, you know, I
Speaker 6:  learned this thing. And I'm just like, you're gonna need to take that with
Speaker 6:  a caveat. Right?
Speaker 5:  Interesting.
Speaker 11:  It's the new, I read it in the New Yorker or I read it online
Speaker 11:  when you saw TikTok. It's, it's that,
Speaker 6:  Yes. Yeah, yeah, yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But it's like the opposite, right? Because what what it is is like,
Speaker 5:  it, it's like, it, it's, it's the equivalent of like, I heard somebody saying
Speaker 5:  it to somebody else on the street. Yes, yes. Do do it. That which you will,
Speaker 5:  I think I actually, I am much more into it if we're gonna treat it as
Speaker 5:  shorthand for this is probably not correct, but
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But that, that is very fun. That's not how people use it. People
Speaker 5:  use it as like evidence for some, like if, if we are in an argument,
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna ask chat GPT and then I'm gonna report back to you what chat GPT
Speaker 5:  said is if it is a useful contributor to our argument and it is not, and
Speaker 5:  it drives me insane. That's
Speaker 11:  What exactly what I like. If I am telling someone else like
Speaker 11:  what Chacha BT told me or any chat bot,
Speaker 11:  I'm not gonna be like, well, like exactly the quote that you said at the
Speaker 11:  beginning of this. It was like, you know, well according to Claude, or like,
Speaker 11:  well Chacha be told me X, Y, z, I'm gonna look it up like you said Jake,
Speaker 11:  and make sure. And then I'll just be like, well yeah, when I looked, you
Speaker 11:  know, I'm not gonna use it as evidence. That's what bothers me. Like I look
Speaker 11:  up things on chatbots when it's like a lot of like
Speaker 11:  red tape or gray areas or like weird situations. Like for example, recently
Speaker 11:  I was looking up where can you get citizenship elsewhere?
Speaker 11:  And I have to say it made it a lot, a lot easier to
Speaker 11:  understand did I take it all with a grain of salt? Of course. But like,
Speaker 11:  it was like laid out in a nice chart instead of me going to like 50
Speaker 11:  websites. You know?
Speaker 6:  I mean, this is funny though, like I do the same thing where it's like, yeah,
Speaker 6:  yeah, WebMD told me all these symptoms mean I probably
Speaker 6:  have like this disorder. And it's like, it, there might
Speaker 6:  like listen, WebMD is correct ish. Like
Speaker 6:  my interpretation of it is not, and and like, you
Speaker 6:  know, this happens a lot with a lot of, I agree with you fundamentally David,
Speaker 6:  like Chatt PT as an expert. Absolutely not
Speaker 6:  Chachi, BT as, you know, a source of
Speaker 6:  general guidance. Okay. You
Speaker 6:  know, it, it maybe, but even when, even when I have had
Speaker 6:  to tell another person I learned this thing chat
Speaker 6:  is a source, I'm like, ugh. Like I, I'm not sure I wanna
Speaker 6:  convey this 'cause I have not checked that this is actually true.
Speaker 11:  I think that's the key. It's like doing it with a grain of salt or not being
Speaker 11:  like, you know, it just annoys me when people are so confident about it
Speaker 11:  or being like, well basically acting like they asked, you know, like a
Speaker 11:  legal expert about something. Yes. And they're like, well this, you know,
Speaker 11:  this is proof basically
Speaker 6:  That is concerning right
Speaker 5:  Here is the authority on the subject. And it's like, no, it's, it's the opposite
Speaker 5:  of that. Yes. To me it's like the people who, who say that are the people
Speaker 5:  who like, you know, will go to comment on
Speaker 5:  you, go to a Reddit thread that's like about an article and then you get
Speaker 5:  somebody who comments and is like, oh, well I didn't read the article, but
Speaker 5:  seems probably stupid. And it's like, what was the point of this? Like why,
Speaker 5:  why did you do this and why am I here reading it and why is any of this,
Speaker 5:  it just, no one needs this. Just the next time that you're like, I asked
Speaker 5:  Chad GPT, just congratulations, please keep that to yourself.
Speaker 6:  I did learn a fascinating thing about how chess engines work though, And
Speaker 6:  I, we can go into it later.
Speaker 11:  I can't wait to
Speaker 5:  Hear and it's like 60% maybe true. Who knows?
Speaker 5:  Okay, take number four. And this is, this is the one we could spend the
Speaker 5:  longest on and we're going to talk about many times in the future,
Speaker 5:  so we don't have to do too much of it now, but this is actually, I think
Speaker 5:  the one I feel the most strongly about. Take number four, a
Speaker 5:  AI friends are a societal disaster and must be stopped at all costs.
Speaker 5:  Thi this is the thing I have come, so I've, I've been reading, I, I had a
Speaker 5:  day randomly a couple of weeks ago where I like read a slew
Speaker 5:  of those stories and there's been like one a week all summer of like
Speaker 5:  such and such person became like super obsessed with their chat bot,
Speaker 5:  which told them to do all of these horrible things and you know, confirmed
Speaker 5:  all of their beliefs and they fell in love and it was this whole thing and,
Speaker 5:  and it, they became like totally crazed by their relationship with their
Speaker 5:  chat bot. And I'm starting to hear this from people like in the tech world
Speaker 5:  who are like deep down this road of I drive to work every morning And I talk
Speaker 5:  to my chat bot and it is the only one that really understands me and it's
Speaker 5:  always there for me. And I think this is such an incredibly
Speaker 5:  horrifying road to be going down that like I just
Speaker 5:  burn it all down. AI is not your friend and we have to stop
Speaker 5:  anything that makes it feel like your friend.
Speaker 6:  That's a lot of intensity,
Speaker 6:  man. That's really tricky. I think like directionally I agree with that.
Speaker 6:  It's just very, it's, it's hard to imagine because like, listen, this is
Speaker 6:  the
Speaker 5:  One you can abstain from. If you're gonna abstain from one, this is probably
Speaker 5:  the one to abstain from
Speaker 6:  The actual functional thing of like friend products that
Speaker 6:  are going to absorb you and you're gonna spend your social
Speaker 6:  energy talking to ai. That does seem bad, right?
Speaker 6:  Mo in most cases that, that does seem bad. Are there situations where I
Speaker 6:  can see this being useful for people? Like Absolutely. Are there also
Speaker 6:  like fundamental portions of this that I don't think you can divorce
Speaker 6:  from making an AI helpful? Oh, that gets tricky, right? Like, is there a
Speaker 6:  world where you open up your, your, your computer every morning
Speaker 6:  and there's a little AI agent that's just like, Hey, what's up David? Like
Speaker 6:  I know you were trying to get this done and somebody emailed you, right?
Speaker 6:  Like can it be friendly? Does it have to be all business all the time?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Okay. As I'm saying this, I'm like, yeah, it should just not, it shouldn't
Speaker 6:  flirt with you. That's actually pretty easy. They can just like turn flirting
Speaker 6:  off. So
Speaker 5:  I agree, this is complicated, but if you like, if we have to choose,
Speaker 5:  I think we have to run the other way. Like that's where I'm at And I think
Speaker 5:  because it's so gray, the only way to do it
Speaker 5:  is just to just burn all the boats. I dunno. Hayden, what do you think? I
Speaker 5:  know you've, you spent a lot more time talking to people about this than
Speaker 5:  I do. Where's your head?
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I would say, I mean like, I just spent an hour
Speaker 11:  talking to someone about the intricacies of this, so it's, it's gonna be
Speaker 11:  hard for me to not abstain, but I would say if I have to directionally agree,
Speaker 11:  I would say the same thing as you and Jake. It's like
Speaker 11:  I think that we as humans have a, you know,
Speaker 11:  propensity to assign like personhood to things and we even do it with
Speaker 11:  like stuffed animals, dogs, cars. I'm not saying dogs
Speaker 11:  don't have personality, but you know, we're like, oh, I know what they're
Speaker 11:  thinking. So it's like, of course if something's acting like a human back
Speaker 11:  to us or like a friend back to us, we will
Speaker 11:  kind of, it's hard to divorce that, you know? And
Speaker 11:  so I think in by nature of what like an AI
Speaker 11:  companion is, it's really hard to not go
Speaker 11:  down like a weird spiral or rabbit hole or like
Speaker 11:  psychologically it is like almost designed to draw you in so
Speaker 11:  directionally. Yeah, I agree. I mean it's like these products are
Speaker 11:  irresponsible and it's very difficult to see like a
Speaker 11:  world in which they help people more than they hurt people,
Speaker 11:  but also there's like a loneliness epidemic and I've seen stories
Speaker 11:  of people, you know, like that lost their spouse finding some
Speaker 11:  companionship in AI without going too far down the line
Speaker 11:  yet. So I don't know. I mean it's like, to me, if I had to
Speaker 11:  agree or or disagree, I'd say I agree for sure. But
Speaker 11:  especially because the thing that worries me the most about this is
Speaker 11:  honestly how these chatbots turn sinister
Speaker 11:  when you talk to them over long periods of time and the safeguards all fall
Speaker 11:  away. Like they say, you know, hey, you know, I know you better
Speaker 11:  than anyone else. I know you better than your brother. You know, I've seen
Speaker 11:  the all the parts of you and I'm the one who knows you the best. Like I
Speaker 11:  think it's sinister that they always seem to go that route. So yeah, if
Speaker 11:  I had to choose, of course they're bad and burn it all down.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Yeah, I, I I I grant that actually I think this one
Speaker 5:  is largely complicated And I think I just wanna recommend a story I
Speaker 5:  read last week that I've been thinking about ever since it's in rest of world,
Speaker 5:  which is generally very good and it's, it's this woman's story about her
Speaker 5:  mother who lives in rural China and goes to the
Speaker 5:  doctor, I think it's like once every quarter and it's like a two day
Speaker 5:  trip to go to the doctor and she goes and sees a doctor that spends like
Speaker 5:  two minutes with her and then leaves. And what she found instead of that
Speaker 5:  is deep seek, which is this, this chat bot that she can put her
Speaker 5:  symptoms into that is always there and always talks to her and is always
Speaker 5:  kind and is always sympathetic and always feels like it's helping. And she's
Speaker 5:  gone through this thing where she's getting worse medical
Speaker 5:  information, but she's actually okay with that because the experience of
Speaker 5:  it is so compelling and so soothing and so good
Speaker 5:  and it's like, okay, I actually fully understand how we get to
Speaker 5:  that point And I find it incredibly sympathetic that somebody would go down
Speaker 5:  that road. We have to fix all of the problems that got
Speaker 5:  us there, not assume that better AI is the solution to any of those
Speaker 5:  problems, right? It's like people pointed at the loneliness epidemic thing,
Speaker 5:  which is super real and and scary and there are lots of things we need to
Speaker 5:  do as a society to solve that stuff. Give everybody an AI best
Speaker 5:  friend is not one of those things. It just isn't.
Speaker 11:  I couldn't agree more. The
Speaker 5:  Solution to loneliness is not chatbots, it is other people and we have to
Speaker 5:  figure out how to do that without it being ai
Speaker 11:  AI is rarely the solution to one of these large societal problems. I totally
Speaker 11:  agree. It's like, you know, I feel like it's a bandaid outta
Speaker 11:  wound that sometimes like has bacteria on it and gets the wound
Speaker 11:  more infected, you know, it's like, not to be gross, but
Speaker 11:  yeah, I mean I think it's rough too because it's the same thing with like
Speaker 11:  AI therapy. You know, some people bring up, oh well it makes their therapy
Speaker 11:  more accessible. Well it's not therapy and it's so sick of fantic that,
Speaker 11:  you know, it can, especially if you're being vulnerable with your emotions,
Speaker 11:  it can send you down a spiral even if you have no previous history
Speaker 11:  of issues with mental health. So I think, yeah, I mean it's just,
Speaker 11:  it's hard when companies are kind of presenting this as a
Speaker 11:  cure all or a thing to, you know, fix a lot of societal problems that we've
Speaker 11:  had for like many years that have been worsening and they think this is
Speaker 11:  the solution when it is decidedly not
Speaker 6:  Well and they're sort of inherently built to suck you in and take up all
Speaker 6:  your time and maybe make that problem of loneliness worse because now
Speaker 6:  you're just talking to AI even more because that is what is,
Speaker 11:  You know, and then when they change, build your
Speaker 6:  Relationship. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  And then when they, when they change the model, you get really upset.
Speaker 11:  Mm. Just like we saw with open AI and 4.0
Speaker 5:  Yeah, totally. Yeah. That, that was one of the things that following that
Speaker 5:  story was, was really eyeopening for me that it's like when when you have
Speaker 5:  this little tiny product change that has this unbelievable like
Speaker 5:  interpersonal like life experience change
Speaker 5:  for people, we've gone down a bad road. This is not opening eyes should not
Speaker 5:  have that control over your relationships. Right. Like, it, it just shouldn't
Speaker 5:  and
Speaker 11:  And it shouldn't have the data either. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Take number five. We're gonna end on a happy note. It's gonna be better.
Speaker 5:  I, over the course of the summer, believe I have found two things that
Speaker 5:  surprised me that these generative AI systems are very good at.
Speaker 5:  And I wanna tell you the two of them and see if you both agree. So this,
Speaker 5:  this is technically a two-parter. I think AI
Speaker 5:  bots and AI as a, as a technology, these, these LLMs
Speaker 5:  actually are going to be better search engines than search engines. And,
Speaker 5:  and I'm all in on AI as the Google replacement. I think it's, it's a
Speaker 5:  disaster for the web. It's a, it's a huge mess for lots of reasons, but as
Speaker 5:  a pure like product user experience, AI search is rapidly
Speaker 5:  becoming my favorite version of search. So sub
Speaker 5:  agree or disagree? Whatcha guys saying?
Speaker 6:  I mean, yeah, I, no, I agree with that. Right? Really? Oh wow. Okay. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  no, that's easy. That's that's an easy one. Okay. For me, I I think if
Speaker 6:  you have not tried this yet, you, you need to try it, right? It's,
Speaker 6:  there are things that you find on the internet via Google that you know
Speaker 6:  are not reliable sources. And I think you need to go into using chat GT as
Speaker 6:  a chat engine or call as a chat engine or whatever knowing that there are
Speaker 6:  things that's gonna mess up. If you, if you are able to go into it a critical
Speaker 6:  lie, you will find what is often better than Google,
Speaker 6:  right? Yeah. It, it, it is the, there are certain types of questions that
Speaker 6:  it can answer and answer very easily and very
Speaker 5:  Naturally. Can I tell you the one that really did it for me? Yeah. So I have,
Speaker 5:  I have, I have a patio right here next to where I record in my basement
Speaker 5:  and we have these outdoor cushions on just like outdoor patio
Speaker 5:  furniture. The cushions are disgusting because I keep forgetting to put them
Speaker 5:  away when it rains. So I need new cushions. So
Speaker 5:  what I did for like days was just go on like Wayfair and browse
Speaker 5:  for couch cushions and you go through the filters and all this stuff And
Speaker 5:  I spent forever trying to find like pretty good couch cushions and then I
Speaker 5:  realized, oh I can just, I can do this backwards with, I think I used a claw
Speaker 5:  to do it. So I went outside, I measured the cushions And
Speaker 5:  I put into Claude, I need, I need outdoor patio furniture
Speaker 5:  cushions. I want things with good reviews that are exactly this dimension
Speaker 5:  that will ship to me in Virginia. And it, it
Speaker 5:  found me better options than I had found in
Speaker 5:  many hours of Googling in 90 seconds. And I was like, this is
Speaker 5:  the thing, I'm not, I'm not here looking for like, you know,
Speaker 5:  really important historically accurate information about World
Speaker 5:  War ii. I'm looking for couch cushions and this is much better at it than
Speaker 5:  Google is. And that was just a moment where I was like, oh this is, this
Speaker 5:  is it. There's something here
Speaker 6:  That's surprising that's like surprisingly detailed too. It's for, for me
Speaker 6:  it's just like the very nuanced questions. It, it's like
Speaker 6:  which year did this phone get this specific feature? And
Speaker 6:  it's like, normally what I would have to do is Google each phone model,
Speaker 6:  go to the Wikipedia page, see if it has the spec or not and
Speaker 6:  look, I'm gonna double check I'm gonna do it in Chatt BT, it's
Speaker 6:  gonna tell me, oh it was the iPhone 12, then I'm gonna check the 11 and then
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna check the 12 and I'm gonna see if that's where the change happened.
Speaker 6:  But that's still gonna save me a ton of time.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I completely agree also, mostly because search
Speaker 11:  has gotten so bad. You know, it's like I I
Speaker 11:  I'm thinking also about what your example about the
Speaker 11:  couch cushions for me. You know, I did a lot of testing
Speaker 11:  of AI agents lately and a lot of the selling points
Speaker 11:  were that they could do that and then order it for you. So
Speaker 11:  they're pretty bad at ordering it for you and all of it. Things
Speaker 11:  all fell apart when you got to that stage or filling out the form or doing
Speaker 11:  anything. But they were good I will say, at pulling up options and you know,
Speaker 11:  fitting those requirements. So I think, yeah,
Speaker 11:  AI is 100% the new search but not the new agent.
Speaker 11:  So I Oh co or not the new personal assistant. So I think I agree completely
Speaker 11:  with that. And also it's just, yeah, I mean search has just gotten really,
Speaker 11:  really bad. The one thing I will say though is
Speaker 11:  my friend's brother who's like a dad and like lives in a
Speaker 11:  rural area and like you wouldn't expect to be like maybe on
Speaker 11:  the cutting edge of the new technology. 'cause he is super busy with
Speaker 11:  like three kids right now. Sure. Was she googled something the other day
Speaker 11:  and he was like, what are you 80 put it into Chachi. So I
Speaker 11:  thought that was like indicative of a larger thing. But I will say I do
Speaker 11:  get annoyed when people put things into a chatbot that they could
Speaker 11:  easily Google that aren't, you know, varied or complex
Speaker 11:  because it uses so much more energy I think.
Speaker 11:  Totally. So it's like, you know, if you're googling what you just said,
Speaker 11:  Jake, like the, you know, time when a feature appeared in
Speaker 11:  a phone, great. But if you're just saying, oh what year did the phone come
Speaker 11:  out? I get so annoyed if people put that into a chat bot. 'cause I'm like,
Speaker 11:  you could use less energy. Does it still use a lot of energy? Are there
Speaker 11:  AI overviews? Yes, obviously, but I think it's less so that's what I always
Speaker 11:  tell people
Speaker 5:  And that's actually the kind of thing that Google is still unusually well
Speaker 5:  equipped to do, right? Like I think all the time about the, the fact that
Speaker 5:  on Google, most of the top searches are just for website names.
Speaker 5:  Like people go to Google and type Facebook to get to facebook.com and the
Speaker 5:  idea that that's going to be replaced by a chat bot that then has to go and
Speaker 5:  like burn a bunch of trees down just to find you the link to facebook.com
Speaker 5:  is bad. But yeah, for all of this more
Speaker 5:  intense, more specific stuff, I have been amazed by how much I've enjoyed
Speaker 5:  using some of these search products. The other one, and you
Speaker 5:  guys have talked a little bit about this this summer, I am increasingly
Speaker 5:  radicalized toward the belief that vibe coding is the future.
Speaker 5:  I think building little bespoke software for yourself
Speaker 5:  is very cool and very powerful and is going
Speaker 5:  to work. Like it's, it's clear already that coding is the first like true
Speaker 5:  killer app for these models. We hear these companies
Speaker 5:  all the time who are already saying like, oh, 90% of our code is being written
Speaker 5:  by ai And I feel like they think that's a brag and it sounds like a self
Speaker 5:  own, but
Speaker 5:  I did a bunch of it myself this summer, was just playing around with stuff,
Speaker 5:  learning how to build some of these things and like it really works. And
Speaker 5:  the idea that you can just build a thing for yourself
Speaker 5:  I think is a bigger behavioral switch than we're realizing
Speaker 5:  like, it, it's, you just have to think about technology differently to say,
Speaker 5:  here is the goal I need to accomplish and have it go make that the thing
Speaker 5:  that can accomplish it for you. But I'm, I'm increasingly convinced
Speaker 5:  that's going to be a huge deal and we're only just scratching the surface
Speaker 5:  of it. Agree or disagree.
Speaker 11:  I mean, I will say Jake v And I tested this and
Speaker 11:  we were very disappointed, so yeah,
Speaker 5:  You guys did not have a great
Speaker 11:  Time. I guess, I mean, you know what I'll like, if I have to agree or disagree,
Speaker 11:  like I feel like most people are gonna agree with you honestly, but if I
Speaker 11:  personally from my own experience have to agree or disagree, I have to say
Speaker 11:  100% disagree because I think like at companies, yeah, like if you're a
Speaker 11:  software engineer, absolutely. If you have any coding experience, absolutely.
Speaker 11:  But as someone who has no coding experience besides like
Speaker 11:  my like Neopets shop where I was like adding like a new song by
Speaker 11:  ABBA to be my shop, so which
Speaker 6:  Totally counts
Speaker 5:  To be, that is absolutely coding experience
Speaker 11:  I like truly had the worst experience. I mean it just, it didn't work and
Speaker 11:  even when it did work, it didn't follow through or things would break immediately
Speaker 11:  even when I did something pretty simple. So I mean, I need to try it more,
Speaker 11:  but right now I've gotta say based on my own experience. Disagree. Okay.
Speaker 5:  So
Speaker 6:  I agree with Hayden Damn would just say I disagree with you
Speaker 6:  David. Okay.
Speaker 5:  Do
Speaker 6:  Listen. I I I'm sure these tools will get better. I'm sure they'll get more
Speaker 6:  functional, right? I, there are tons of developers who are using
Speaker 6:  AI a lot to write their own code. Yes. I think that is very distinct from
Speaker 6:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  I mean vibe coding specifically. I actually don't think developers are going
Speaker 5:  to use AI to write code is even a hot take. That's just true.
Speaker 6:  Oh no, that's happening. We're there. Yeah, I think these things are functionally
Speaker 6:  good And I think they'll probably get better at vibe coding. Do I think everyone
Speaker 6:  is going to be vibe coding all the time or on a regular basis that I
Speaker 6:  I I'm gonna say no. Okay. I that is think think you're both gonna be
Speaker 6:  kind of niche. It, it's, that's a really hard thing
Speaker 6:  to, that's a really tricky behavioral change to create,
Speaker 6:  right? Even when I was trying to figure out ways to, you
Speaker 6:  know, bring that into my life, it was hard, it's hard for me to start thinking
Speaker 6:  that way of like, oh, can you generate a way for me to interact with this?
Speaker 6:  Can you, can you create an interactive for me? Can you make this into a game?
Speaker 6:  Can you make this into like some all all I can say is interactive. Like,
Speaker 6:  I, I don't, I don't know what to do And I don't know, maybe there'll be a
Speaker 6:  new generation where vibe coding is native Tim, they'll be like, well obviously
Speaker 6:  obviously you, you should turn this into like, you know, this set of
Speaker 6:  flashcards or we should turn this into a VR experience.
Speaker 6:  I don't really know. But mostly what I just
Speaker 6:  want is information, like plain old information given to me very quickly
Speaker 6:  and plainly. And you know, I think
Speaker 6:  having people come up with these specific use cases is tricky.
Speaker 6:  And having people come up with them in ways that are going to actually be
Speaker 6:  helpful and useful. Right. Okay. Maybe, you know, oh, I need an app
Speaker 6:  that will be perfect for doing this One thing around the house. We're tracking
Speaker 6:  chores. Okay, great. There's, there's probably a developer who's put a
Speaker 6:  ton of thought into making a really great chore tracker,
Speaker 6:  you know, and it
Speaker 5:  Probably costs $50 a year and steals all of your personal data. Yes.
Speaker 6:  But, but it works. They'll probably fix the
Speaker 6:  bugs when they come up and it, it probably has a logical flow
Speaker 6:  to it that makes sense because they put a lot of thought into it. You know,
Speaker 6:  does every person who wants a chore tracker and is ready to prompt Claude
Speaker 6:  to make them one know how it should work?
Speaker 6:  Is Claude smart enough to make it work in a logical way? I'm not sure.
Speaker 6:  So I, I'm disagreeing with you on this one. I, I do think that these tools
Speaker 6:  will get better, but I think even if they're good enough that they work on
Speaker 6:  try one, I'm not sure we're gonna get a change where everyone is prompting
Speaker 6:  all the time.
Speaker 11:  I do think that's a really good point that you made about like how people's
Speaker 11:  minds work here because you know, when we were testing it, I
Speaker 11:  had to use your examples. Like I couldn't think of something to do, you
Speaker 11:  know, and I'm a tech journalist, so it's like I feel like others
Speaker 11:  may feel the same. And the other thing is, yeah, I
Speaker 11:  mean just kind of getting over the idea of, I think it's hard to create,
Speaker 11:  like see change with people's, like how people think and how,
Speaker 11:  you know, it's the same way as like in college when I was making my website,
Speaker 11:  like my portfolio, I paid someone to do it for me, even though I
Speaker 11:  actually could have just gone on Wix and done it, right? Because I kind
Speaker 11:  of felt overwhelmed by the idea of figuring out what it should look like
Speaker 11:  and how to do it And I would've saved me money, but I just was like,
Speaker 11:  I don't know, I don't know. Let me just outsource this. So yeah, I kind
Speaker 11:  of agree. I think, you know, maybe if there's a new generation that it's
Speaker 11:  native to them, but otherwise, I don't know.
Speaker 5:  I've just been wanting to say, okay, boomer, like every four seconds this
Speaker 5:  entire time you guys have been talking. No, I, I think, I think you're both
Speaker 5:  right And I think the, the thing that has been so much fun for me
Speaker 5:  going through this process has been like learning how to
Speaker 5:  reorient my brain that way because like, it, it is a
Speaker 5:  completely different way of thinking about how we interact with technology,
Speaker 5:  right? Where you're like, when I need to do something, I don't go find the
Speaker 5:  thing that best accomplishes it. I can just ask it
Speaker 5:  to exist and, and like most of the time it doesn't work. But like the,
Speaker 5:  the simplest example I can offer you is the, when you, when you have a baby,
Speaker 5:  one of the first things they make you do is like religiously track how much
Speaker 5:  they eat and how much they pee and poop. And
Speaker 5:  the first time we had a kid, we just did this with a, with a shared Google
Speaker 5:  sheet spreadsheet. And that was very annoying because you're sitting there
Speaker 5:  with like kid in one arm and you're like scrolling on your phone through
Speaker 5:  rows and columns trying to find the right one. And so this time I was just
Speaker 5:  like, Hey, can you build me a tracker that I can
Speaker 5:  just open up and it will automatically time and date stamp it and it will
Speaker 5:  give me four radial buttons so I can just check poop, pee food or other.
Speaker 5:  And if, if I do other, it opens up a notes field. I literally, I wrote that
Speaker 5:  essentially into Claude and it built me an activity tracker. I
Speaker 5:  then spent a day and a half trying to figure out how to get that out of
Speaker 5:  Claude artifacts, which is the thing I was not going to be able to convince
Speaker 5:  my wife to use and onto like an actual website that I own and control
Speaker 5:  that it backs up to Google Sheets. But now I have a thing where I just go
Speaker 5:  to a website and it pops up this tracker, I click a button and it goes into
Speaker 5:  the Google spreadsheet And I didn't write one single
Speaker 5:  letter of code. And the process of that is more work
Speaker 5:  than most people should have to go through. But that moment of just like,
Speaker 5:  oh, I can just ask and we, it can
Speaker 5:  build some facsimile of this thing and then we can, we can refine it together
Speaker 5:  and build something. And I don't have to know the code. I just have to know
Speaker 5:  what I want is very powerful. But Hayden, to your exact point, trying
Speaker 5:  to sit down and come up with a list of things that I want my device to do
Speaker 5:  for me that it doesn't already is bizarrely difficult. And it's been, I have
Speaker 5:  like actively worked on trying to retrain my brain on how to do it.
Speaker 5:  And it's, it's been very weird but very fun. And I encourage everyone to
Speaker 5:  just like try to make up things for your phone to do for you because it is,
Speaker 5:  it is a good time.
Speaker 11:  Okay. I'm a little inspired now to actually like get my brain working that
Speaker 11:  way. But I will say I think you have like a new side hustle that would make
Speaker 11:  you a lot of money because it sounds like everyone needs this And I don't
Speaker 11:  know, I'm like, yeah, in a few years if I ever have kids I'll be getting
Speaker 11:  this website from you. So, oh
Speaker 5:  My god, anybody needs anybody who needs my poop tracker? Get at me. I got
Speaker 5:  you. David already gave him the prompt. It has dark mode now. I, Claude And
Speaker 5:  I worked on the colors together. I didn't like the way it was doing the buttons
Speaker 5:  for a while. Like the, I should, the transcript of our conversation about
Speaker 5:  this is very funny 'cause I'm like, can you put the poop emoji on the left
Speaker 5:  side of the word poop instead of the right side? Because when I'm on mobile,
Speaker 5:  it's not showing Correct. It's fabulous. This is just the weirdest of times
Speaker 5:  that we live in right now. Alright, those are all of my, those are all of
Speaker 5:  my takes. I feel better having said these to you. Thank you both for, for
Speaker 5:  going down this truly absurd
Speaker 5:  should we just do this now? Should we just, should we just fight about this
Speaker 6:  David? We've got some issues. Have you seen
Speaker 6:  The Vergecast inbox? Have you seen how many
Speaker 6:  hashtags saved the thunder rounds? We received The
Speaker 5:  People. The people do like the thunder. Listen,
Speaker 6:  Listen. I know how you feel and so I'm gonna make my strongest argument here.
Speaker 6:  Just imagine for a second the ability to announce
Speaker 6:  the, the title of this segment. Stick up your hand and have
Speaker 6:  thunder come roaring down. Feels good.
Speaker 5:  Hey, that
Speaker 6:  Could be you David. That could be
Speaker 5:  You. First of all, Hayden from now on is the only person who gets to do that
Speaker 5:  because she just signed that perfectly. Very well done by Hayden. Thank you.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 6:  Just felt it in me. You know, I have have,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that was actually not a sound effect. We played, Hayden did that herself
Speaker 5:  naturally. Just now
Speaker 5:  two things. One, thunder is slower than lightning. This,
Speaker 5:  this makes the whole conceit of this doesn't make any sense. It doesn't make
Speaker 5:  any sense. You can't have thunder if you don't have lightning. And also lightning
Speaker 5:  is the thing that goes fast and then thunder rolls forever. Like it doesn't
Speaker 5:  make any sense.
Speaker 6:  And yet, and yet thunder it, it feels powerful.
Speaker 6:  Powerful.
Speaker 11:  The the gravitas. The gravitas.
Speaker 6:  Thank you Hayden.
Speaker 5:  This is not the gravitas round. If you wanna do the gravitas round, you can
Speaker 5:  talk about that. That's
Speaker 6:  The after show.
Speaker 5:  This is, that's where we put on tuxedos and talk about tech news that
Speaker 5:  I'm into. We can, we can do that all day. No, it's okay. Here's
Speaker 5:  what we're gonna do. It's the lightning round again. But
Speaker 5:  in the spirit of the thunder round, we're going to actually
Speaker 5:  do all of the stories that we try to do. 'cause that I think was a very good
Speaker 5:  idea. And I would like to hold to at least we're gonna
Speaker 5:  do that until Neela comes back and starts yelling about Brendan Carr for
Speaker 5:  45 minutes every episode again. But until we do that, we are
Speaker 5:  going to actively go through all of the stories that we have. But it
Speaker 5:  is going to be called the lightning round because the thunder round doesn't
Speaker 5:  make any sense. This
Speaker 6:  Is not
Speaker 5:  All
Speaker 6:  It, it's personally devastating to me. And I wanna
Speaker 6:  say on behalf of all thunder round supporters, you're dead to us.
Speaker 6:  But we'll continue to listen.
Speaker 11:  I talked to David's new baby and he said that he preferred the
Speaker 11:  thunder round, so Wow.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Was he not
Speaker 6:  Give it 18 years? We'll employ him and overtake you.
Speaker 5:  All he does is poop his pants and listen to me yell about ai. He doesn't
Speaker 5:  know anything. All right, let's do this.
Speaker 5:  Jake, since you're heartbroken, I will allow you to go first.
Speaker 5:  What's, what's your first story of the week?
Speaker 6:  I am heartbroken, however, oh, it brings me great joy, great
Speaker 6:  joy to start this with. Spotify has
Speaker 6:  finally added lossless streaming.
Speaker 6:  Oh my God, what? 45
Speaker 5:  Years later.
Speaker 6:  They, they literally announced the feature four years ago.
Speaker 6:  They said they were doing it.
Speaker 5:  Wait, did they really? Yeah, I thought this was like rumors and speculation
Speaker 5:  this whole time.
Speaker 6:  It, it was rumored in speculation for eight years because they started like
Speaker 6:  trialing it and putting out surveys. Four years. I'm like, like
Speaker 6:  90% sure that they had Billie Eilish announce it in, in
Speaker 6:  like a promo video. Wow. Like they did a promotional video for Spotify
Speaker 6:  Hi-Fi. They were like, it's coming this year. And then they never
Speaker 6:  said another word about it. They just, just nothing I
Speaker 6:  want, you know, every time a Spotify PR
Speaker 6:  person has contacted me over the last four years, I've been like, and
Speaker 6:  by the way, whenever Hi-Fi comes down, you let me know. And they're sick
Speaker 6:  and tired of it. And it did not help. It did not help our
Speaker 5:  Former colleague, Chris Welch, I think, I think the reason he doesn't work
Speaker 5:  at The Verge anymore was that he couldn't deal with the ongoing
Speaker 5:  non-existence of Spotify Hi-Fi every year. He just, he just needed a clean
Speaker 5:  break.
Speaker 6:  He, on the anniversary of the announcement every year he wrote a post being
Speaker 6:  like, what, what happened? Why isn't it here? It's here.
Speaker 6:  This is, again, most of the other streaming services already
Speaker 6:  offer this as a feature. The good news is Spotify isn't charging more.
Speaker 6:  So that's great. The bad news, And I don't know if there's a technical reason
Speaker 6:  for this, but no airplay support, no Google cast
Speaker 6:  support, which means I'm not listening to it. All of my stuff
Speaker 6:  is Google cast. So this is not useful. You gotta use Spotify Connect, which
Speaker 6:  I think is a little bit more reserved for like higher end gear,
Speaker 6:  which I, I, I have one thing that can do Spotify Connect, but I can't like
Speaker 6:  street the things that I use most are not Spotify Connect. Right. So,
Speaker 5:  And also Spotify Connect is like, it, it just sort of uses the bandwidth
Speaker 5:  differently. So like I can understand why it's actually restricted to that.
Speaker 5:  Trying to move that kind of quality
Speaker 5:  around would just be a challenge. But yeah, spot
Speaker 5:  spot. Spotify like two thirds did the job here
Speaker 5:  that like technically it's here, you can, you can listen to it. It's, if
Speaker 5:  you follow these three instructions and pay a toll to
Speaker 5:  that person under the bridge, then you can have lossless
Speaker 5:  streaming. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  It's an improvement from before.
Speaker 5:  Sure.
Speaker 6:  And they're not charging for
Speaker 5:  Of all
Speaker 6:  Praise charging, which I appreciate.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And I, and it's free. So there's already conspiracy theories
Speaker 5:  that the reason it's not sort of fully baked is that Spotify is eventually
Speaker 5:  going to release a fully baked version that it's gonna make you pay more
Speaker 5:  for, which would be very funny. And I help us all.
Speaker 5:  Hayden, what's your first story?
Speaker 11:  Okay, my first one is that Claude can now make you a spreadsheet
Speaker 11:  or a slide deck. So basically it can create and edit
Speaker 11:  files in Excel and PowerPoint. It can make a PDF, it can create
Speaker 11:  documents. And it's exciting because this is something that I feel
Speaker 11:  like a lot of people thought it could already do, but it could not. And
Speaker 11:  so finally we're getting a little bit closer to agent stuff,
Speaker 11:  you know, I mean, it's awesome that it can create, I hate, hate
Speaker 11:  creating Excel spreadsheets. It's like something that I feel like a lot
Speaker 11:  of people learned in school or they started doing like just on the side
Speaker 11:  in their personal life. I never learned, I never learned the shortcuts.
Speaker 11:  I just don't, I just had to make one And I, I was like
Speaker 11:  a baby with like, I didn't understand it all. So I'm very excited about
Speaker 11:  this. But it is crazy that it's just happening now. I will
Speaker 11:  say like when last year they rolled out computer use and
Speaker 11:  like agentic tools and just now is it able to like
Speaker 11:  create a doc or a PDF? So, you know, it's, it's a give and take, but
Speaker 11:  it's, it is exciting that it's coming a little more useful to actual
Speaker 11:  consumers. It's
Speaker 5:  Funny, this is one of those features that I feel like Google has been talking
Speaker 5:  about at Google io for like several decades at this point where
Speaker 5:  they're just like, the only thing Google can think of for Gemini to do is
Speaker 5:  to turn your sheets numbers into slides, slides and vice
Speaker 5:  versa. And it's the kind of thing that actually seems like a
Speaker 5:  very doable for an agent that's just like, here's a bunch of numbers, put
Speaker 5:  'em on slides in a way that looks sort of normal with this as the template.
Speaker 5:  Like should be pretty doable. And I feel like it was a few years ago that
Speaker 5:  everybody was like all the like junior associates at
Speaker 5:  firms everywhere who just do this for a living are going to be out of jobs.
Speaker 5:  And it is weird to see this like launched with a lot of fanfare now 'cause
Speaker 5:  it's like this is like, this seems like a very straightforward thing that
Speaker 5:  these have been good at for a long time.
Speaker 6:  AI creating spreadsheets is actually like, that feels high risk to me,
Speaker 6:  right? Like if, if you have a spreadsheet with a bunch of numbers,
Speaker 6:  oh that's a lot of individual data points that need to be analyzed
Speaker 6:  correctly and moved around correctly. And that kind of precision
Speaker 6:  is actually exactly what AI is bad at.
Speaker 5:  And if you have to fact check each number that goes into the spreadsheet,
Speaker 5:  what the hell is the point of the spreadsheet? Right?
Speaker 6:  And so listen, I I see the appeal. I a hundred percent do because
Speaker 6:  like analyzing data and creating spreadsheets,
Speaker 6:  not skills that, that most people have developed like to, to a really high
Speaker 6:  degree. It makes a lot of sense that, that people would want this. It's exactly
Speaker 6:  where I get worried. And so I have asked, you
Speaker 6:  know, AI bots in the past for specific formulas and
Speaker 6:  they're quite good at that 'cause it's basically just programming, but it's
Speaker 6:  still, it's all manual. Like where I'm moving stuff around and I'm making
Speaker 6:  sure I know what I do
Speaker 6:  slides. That feels like a little bit lower risk. 'cause you can still, you
Speaker 6:  can go in and edit them, but if you're having AI move a bunch of numbers
Speaker 6:  around for you and you're not a numbers person, oh man. Like you, you, you
Speaker 6:  might have no idea what's gone wrong.
Speaker 11:  Once again, it's sadly one of those things where you can only trust it with
Speaker 11:  low stakes things. Yeah. And then once it useful for, you know, but, you
Speaker 11:  know, I think David should test it with the baby
Speaker 11:  tracker info and let us know. Yeah, that's a good idea. That's
Speaker 5:  Better. Okay. I'm gonna, I will make you a deeply
Speaker 5:  designed presentation about my baby's poops And I will, I'll report
Speaker 5:  back. My first one is I have not had a chance to talk
Speaker 5:  about my, my guy David Z. Love CEO of Warner Brothers Discovery in a while.
Speaker 5:  He thankfully did not rebrand HBO Max again
Speaker 5:  while I was gone, which I thought was very nice. But two interesting
Speaker 5:  bits of news about our guy, David this week, he was
Speaker 5:  at a Goldman Sachs conference, which is called the Communa Copia
Speaker 5:  and Technology Conference, which I hate and everyone should be ashamed of.
Speaker 5:  He basically was talking about how bad he thinks
Speaker 5:  the current experience of television is, right? Lots of
Speaker 5:  app switching, lots of trying to find things on different platforms, the
Speaker 5:  kind of stuff that we talk about a lot, right? That now everything is on
Speaker 5:  a million different streaming services. It's all very hard to find, everything
Speaker 5:  is different. I actually largely agree with most of what he's saying. Then
Speaker 5:  in the same breath, what he said was actually
Speaker 5:  it is all incredibly underpriced and we are going to
Speaker 5:  crack down on password sharing and make it more expensive. And so it's like,
Speaker 5:  well buddy, you might have missed the point. And
Speaker 5:  I think the, the funny thing is, what he's clearly saying is
Speaker 5:  actually what we've done here is we've bundled a bunch of stuff and so now
Speaker 5:  we can charge more money. And what he's doing is called cable.
Speaker 5:  And we did that already. And it's just what's happening again. And every
Speaker 5:  time that everybody turns around, they are just innovating their way
Speaker 5:  into the cable television era of the 1980s. And it
Speaker 5:  is driving me absolutely up the wall then, just to keep all of
Speaker 5:  this being extra insane. There is some reporting this afternoon from the
Speaker 5:  Wall Street Journal saying that Paramount, which now has a new owner in
Speaker 5:  David Ellison backed by Larry Ellison, now the richest man in the world
Speaker 5:  might be interested in buying Warner Brothers discovery in cash.
Speaker 5:  And so, so David Zs love, who has just only made bad
Speaker 5:  decisions over and over and over for years and decided to bring the
Speaker 5:  company together and now split up. The company is gonna sell the company
Speaker 5:  and make a just a boatload of money. All thanks to Larry Ellison
Speaker 5:  and the $300 billion he's gonna get from an OpenAI cloud deal. And
Speaker 5:  this is how I lose my mind every week on The Vergecast,
Speaker 5:  sorry,
Speaker 6:  OpenAI is now owned by Paramount. Is that where I
Speaker 5:  Think it's essentially
Speaker 6:  That's, is that what happened here?
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Oh God, I you were right about the
Speaker 6:  bundles. The, like this is all just artificially merging things,
Speaker 6:  right? They have done too many deals. They have too much stuff and people
Speaker 6:  won't pay for all the things individually. They're shoving stuff together
Speaker 6:  and therefore they're like, oh, there's more value here. We have to charge
Speaker 6:  more for it. I recently wanted to watch Alien Earth. Alien
Speaker 6:  Earth is on Hulu. And so I went to reactivate my Hulu account,
Speaker 6:  could not figure out how to, I, it kept trying to sell me Hulu plus Disney.
Speaker 6:  And I'm like, I don't want Disney plus, I don't need Disney Plus, they're
Speaker 6:  the same thing. Now I ca I ca I could not listen if there's a way
Speaker 6:  I missed it, I couldn't figure out a way to sign up for one and not the other.
Speaker 6:  And okay, maybe that is a better value because they're bundled. Okay.
Speaker 6:  It's a better value up until the value doubles And I have to start
Speaker 6:  paying that. And I don't wanna pay that because I don't need to stream all
Speaker 6:  the Marvel movies. There are a lot of people who do and that is great for
Speaker 6:  them and they're having a great time. You
Speaker 5:  Know, what's fantastic about that is somewhere in the audience of The Vergecast,
Speaker 5:  there is a a up and coming startup founder who just said,
Speaker 5:  oh, you know what would be so cool is if you could just pay for the stuff
Speaker 5:  that you wanted to watch and you didn't have to subsidize all the other stuff
Speaker 5:  that other people watch. We'll, we'll call it, maybe we'll just call it like
Speaker 5:  a, like a skinny bundle and we'll, we'll just a skinny bundle. We'll just,
Speaker 5:  or we'll, you can just have the stuff that you want and, and it's just, we're
Speaker 5:  just gonna, we're just doing this again. It's,
Speaker 11:  It's just so meta. So meta. And also, funnily enough, I had the opposite
Speaker 11:  experience to you where I was trying to log into my
Speaker 11:  Hulu, which is actually my college roommate's brother's Hulu. Oh my God.
Speaker 11:  And I couldn't, And I was like, oh no, did he finally kick me out? But no,
Speaker 11:  it was that it merged And I do have Disney plus I, I
Speaker 11:  only congrats use it. Congrats. Yeah. I only use it at like Halloween because
Speaker 11:  I like watching like the spooky movies for my youth. But yeah, it was
Speaker 11:  weird because I just didn't, I didn't hear anything about this, so then
Speaker 11:  I like, and it also doesn't seem like everything transferred over, so they
Speaker 11:  had a few things, but I don't, I don't know. We gotta investigate this.
Speaker 11:  So
Speaker 6:  What, when nowadays when it comes to movies, I I, I rent them all
Speaker 6:  individually for right? Like, because that is way better and way
Speaker 6:  cheaper and gets me a better selection. But you just don't have that option
Speaker 6:  at, at least that, that I'm aware of when it comes to TV shows. And
Speaker 6:  I guess, can you still buy individual episodes on iTunes? Is that a thing?
Speaker 6:  Is iTunes real?
Speaker 11:  I I think it's not a thing anymore.
Speaker 6:  I don't don't think that's a
Speaker 11:  Thing you can buy a season.
Speaker 5:  You know, what's happened to me though recently is I've started buying more
Speaker 5:  movies again because there's so many times where it's like three bucks to
Speaker 5:  rent a movie and five to own it. And it's just like, well, okay, I'll spend
Speaker 5:  $5 to own super bad. Like, I guess I just own super bad
Speaker 5:  now.
Speaker 11:  I also rewatch so many movies that I have been doing the same thing, like
Speaker 11:  on Prime video or whatever. I'll just buy it instead. Like, I bought the
Speaker 11:  dumbest movie from my youth the other day about like high school girls
Speaker 11:  like feuding called the Click. And I was so happy I bought it. I was like,
Speaker 11:  yes, I will rewatch this at some point. But the thing that gives me the
Speaker 11:  most joy is that in my neighborhood in New York, there's now a DVD store.
Speaker 6:  Oh my gosh.
Speaker 11:  It's, and it's still survived. I think it's been like six months and it's
Speaker 11:  still there, which we love. Oh my god, we love to
Speaker 5:  See it. Oh my God. So we're really going full. We're not going back to eighties
Speaker 5:  cable. We're going back to like, we're, we're just gonna go all the way back
Speaker 5:  to the beginning of like, we're recorded media
Speaker 11:  Analog baby. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna do the phonograph again next. It's gonna be sick. We're all gonna
Speaker 5:  gather around our enormous radios and listen to Orson Wells.
Speaker 5:  It's gonna be too many cover
Speaker 11:  Fireside
Speaker 5:  Chats. I love this. All right, Jake, what's your next one? Alright,
Speaker 6:  So speaking of retro tech and people
Speaker 6:  going back old school Canon is
Speaker 6:  reviving a point and shoot camera from
Speaker 6:  2016. It's called the Power Shot Elf 360 hs.
Speaker 6:  It is wildly popular because Kendall Jenner and
Speaker 6:  Dua Lipa both love this thing. It's just a very trendy point and shoot camera.
Speaker 6:  They, I I believe they're actually still selling it, but now they have a
Speaker 6:  new model of it that costs more money and has fewer features.
Speaker 6:  And so that's, that's what we're doing now. I mean this makes, but it's
Speaker 5:  Available, which
Speaker 6:  Is key. It's available. That's that's the thing, right? You can buy it for
Speaker 6:  sale buy and you don't have to find a weird, super expensive version
Speaker 6:  on eBay. This is
Speaker 5:  A weird one to me because I actually fully
Speaker 5:  understand why if you're Canon you would do this, right? Like we are very
Speaker 5:  much in a like point and shoot digital camera
Speaker 5:  revival for I think a lot of good interesting reasons. And so the idea that
Speaker 5:  if you're a company, you would chase that and try to like
Speaker 5:  be the cool one that people like makes a lot of sense to me because we've
Speaker 5:  talked about it on the show that the, like the cameras go viral that actually
Speaker 5:  haven't been on sale in a decade and like companies should take advantage
Speaker 5:  of that. It makes complete sense to me why you would make this particular
Speaker 5:  camera, which doesn't have USBC, it doesn't have
Speaker 5:  particularly interesting or high-end. Like they're deliberately making a
Speaker 5:  old outdated camera.
Speaker 11:  I know why, it's because in the movie that I just referenced from the two
Speaker 11:  thousands about the feuding high school girls, they have this camera, so
Speaker 11:  that's obviously why they brought it back. Yeah, they do.
Speaker 6:  Oh wow. Yeah, it's, it's so funny how lazy this is. Like to your point,
Speaker 6:  micro USB, right? They didn't change the USB
Speaker 6:  po. Oh, I'm sorry. It gets worse. It is USB mini. It is
Speaker 6:  mini. Oh no. Right. They, they changed nothing.
Speaker 6:  They, they, they just like stripped some stuff out to make it a little bit
Speaker 6:  cheaper for themselves. They didn't like lean into this in any way,
Speaker 6:  which maybe that just adds to the effect because
Speaker 6:  they literally didn't change anything. Like maybe, maybe the people do just
Speaker 6:  want to dig up old terrible USB cables and go, maybe
Speaker 5:  They want you to think it's the camera from 2016. Yeah. Like maybe that is
Speaker 5:  part of the appeal that like trying to be sort of faux retro.
Speaker 11:  That is what's crazy to me is the cable thing because I mean, like, you
Speaker 11:  know, disposable cameras are super popular right now. Like the
Speaker 11:  other day I tried to develop two and it cost me $65, which is
Speaker 11:  like so much. But yeah, I mean this,
Speaker 11:  the cable thing would really get me here. I just, I don't know if I could
Speaker 11:  reconcile that,
Speaker 6:  Put a lightning port on that thing. Now we're talking,
Speaker 6:  I, I think there's, there's something there.
Speaker 5:  I would, I really hope somebody tries to do like an
Speaker 5:  honest to god 2025 version of an entry level point and shoot.
Speaker 5:  I'd be, I'd be, I'd just be curious to see how it does because it, it might
Speaker 5:  totally not work because the point is that it looks like it's from 2016
Speaker 5:  maybe. Maybe that is it. This
Speaker 6:  Is the thing, like in my head I'm like, why didn't they make it better? And
Speaker 6:  it's like, because if they make it better, it gets worse, right? They can't
Speaker 6:  make it better. They can't make it take better photos. They can't make it
Speaker 6:  easier to use. It needs to be bad. It needs to look bad.
Speaker 6:  That's the point.
Speaker 5:  I think that's right.
Speaker 11:  I want it to be the same, but with a lightning port,
Speaker 6:  That's it. That, that both makes it worse and more
Speaker 6:  retro in a weird roundabout way.
Speaker 5:  And it doesn't, the lightning port doesn't even work or connect to anything
Speaker 5:  because they know all you're using this for is to show it. It's, it's, it's
Speaker 5:  it's arm candy. It doesn't even have to work as a camera. Doesn't matter.
Speaker 5:  All right Hayden, what's your second one?
Speaker 11:  My second one is how unsurprisingly
Speaker 11:  X'S contract with the DOD is being questioned by Senator
Speaker 11:  Warren and other people who think it's, the company is basically just not
Speaker 11:  equipped to deal with the level of influence it would have with a DOD
Speaker 11:  contract. Because you,
Speaker 5:  You're saying Brock running the government is not like cool, we're not fi
Speaker 11:  Exactly. Shocking news. Especially since they only started I
Speaker 11:  think building their safety team a couple months ago, like I think
Speaker 11:  maybe after the contract. I'll have to check that. But yeah, I saw
Speaker 11:  the tweet about them like hiring for their safety team And I was like, huh,
Speaker 11:  this is happening like pretty late. Like I know, I think it was after GR
Speaker 11:  four came out. I'll check. But yeah, I mean it's, you know, the,
Speaker 11:  basically the letter that Senator Warren sent
Speaker 11:  ETH was saying that XAI wasn't up for this
Speaker 11:  contract and being like looked at in the same way that other companies were,
Speaker 11:  that they kinda like skipped the line a little bit. There's a lot of like
Speaker 11:  questions in this letter that they're asking be answered. So
Speaker 11:  yeah, I mean, you know, basically Mecca Hitler running
Speaker 11:  the government. Like maybe not the best idea.
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna to, to borrow from another delayed full
Speaker 5:  VERGE cast segment that you guys piloted this summer that I liked and we're
Speaker 5:  gonna keep doing. This is all just a shenanigan, like full
Speaker 5:  on 100% shenanigans,
Speaker 11:  Truly shenanigans with like huge influence that could be really
Speaker 11:  problematic. So worst kind of shenanigan this
Speaker 6:  Deal was also announced the week after the Mecca
Speaker 6:  Hitler incident, which like in any normal timeline,
Speaker 6:  in any normal administration, you'd probably be like,
Speaker 6:  look, maybe maybe we shouldn't make this deal
Speaker 6:  at the very least, maybe we shouldn't publicize this deal. Maybe we should
Speaker 6:  wait a little bit. Maybe we should put some time between, you know,
Speaker 6:  us cutting the deal and, and the thing that we're paying for
Speaker 6:  declaring that it's Mecca Hitler. But no, they're just like, whatever, you
Speaker 6:  know, we we're with the Department of Defense, we deal with a bunch of really
Speaker 6:  important and dangerous materials.
Speaker 6:  We, we
Speaker 5:  And also Elon Musk is here. Yeah. It's just, it's just no problem. No, we
Speaker 5:  do,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And they're currently hiring for their safety team, so please apply.
Speaker 11:  And one of the questions that's in this letter is like wondering how Musk
Speaker 11:  is gonna maybe improperly benefit from the unparalleled
Speaker 11:  access to DOD data and information. So yeah,
Speaker 11:  I mean there's just a lot here to unpack, but crazy
Speaker 11:  bad, questionable, all of it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I, I appreciate the, the vibe of this letter and you wrote a great
Speaker 5:  piece about it. We'll, we'll put it in the show notes, but the, the distinct
Speaker 5:  vibe of this letter is just like, what is happening?
Speaker 5:  Like how, how is this, what we're doing here?
Speaker 5:  It's just like so incredulous the whole way along. And I, I
Speaker 5:  appreciate the vibes coming out of Congress on that front. All right,
Speaker 5:  my last one before we get outta here, two pieces of Reddit news
Speaker 5:  this week that I find individually not that interesting, but in
Speaker 5:  combination there, there's like something happening here. So the first thing
Speaker 5:  is Reddit is dropping the subscriber counts on sub Reddit. So when you go
Speaker 5:  to sub Reddit, it'll say like, you know, X number of people joined. They're
Speaker 5:  dropping that in favor of some, like much squishier seeming metric about
Speaker 5:  like, how many people have been there in the last 28 days or something. Like,
Speaker 5:  they're trying to make it seem more sort of real time. I guess the,
Speaker 5:  the thesis is people who subscribe are not a good metric of how popular something
Speaker 5:  actually is. I don't know. And then the other one is Reddit appears to be
Speaker 5:  working on a way to read articles that
Speaker 5:  you've like that, that you click on and discover on Reddit
Speaker 5:  inside of Reddit. And I will just say the thing in the
Speaker 5:  screenshot that we have looks very much exactly like
Speaker 5:  Facebook instant articles, and this is just Reddit.
Speaker 6:  Oh, we'll get there,
Speaker 5:  Trying to put the internet inside of Reddit again. And to me it's like,
Speaker 5:  there, there's, there's some, Reddit is either like really feeling
Speaker 5:  itself and thinks it is like the only website left that matters.
Speaker 5:  And so it can just take over and win or is like trying to quietly
Speaker 5:  pivot to something else. And I just, I can't figure out what Reddit is doing
Speaker 5:  here.
Speaker 6:  I think that, so Reddit is having maybe the, the
Speaker 6:  opposite experience of the rest of the internet because suddenly Reddit is
Speaker 6:  the only thing you can find via Google. Yes.
Speaker 6:  And so Reddit is blowing up. Absolutely. And I think they know that they
Speaker 6:  are super reliant on Google and you are correct. They're trying to put
Speaker 6:  the entire internet inside Reddit so that when Google inevitably
Speaker 6:  removes that funnel, everybody's still gonna Reddit. Right? This is what
Speaker 6:  they're, they're doing. They're, they're making it seem more lively.
Speaker 6:  They're like, this is how many people are here right now. This is an active
Speaker 6:  community. This is one you want to continue to check in on. And they're
Speaker 6:  not letting you leave and go to the actual internet when you click an
Speaker 6:  article. It does. I think it is just like a fancy popup
Speaker 6:  browser. So it's like, it's not, it's not quite instant articles
Speaker 6:  yet, but you, you can see how they get there, right? Yeah. I think they're
Speaker 6:  trying to bring more of the internet inside Reddit so they can continue to
Speaker 6:  get more people and keep them inside the Reddit app
Speaker 11:  And the fact that you can, you know, read comments while you're reading
Speaker 11:  the article, you know? So I think it's just all about, like Jake said, like,
Speaker 11:  you know, keeping them on the platform, keeping you engaged. Like,
Speaker 11:  okay, maybe you're reading the article, you see a comment while you're reading
Speaker 11:  it, okay, now you go back to the subreddit and comment something else. So
Speaker 11:  I think it's all about like, just yeah, keep like creating a walled garden
Speaker 11:  because they feel like, you know, they don't wanna be dependent on Google
Speaker 11:  anymore.
Speaker 6:  And Reddit's always been really thirsty too. It, whenever, if you
Speaker 6:  find one of their links, if you, if you visit a Reddit link
Speaker 6:  from a browser on mobile, it, it like
Speaker 6:  graze it out and gives you some popup and they're like, do you wanna continue
Speaker 6:  in your browser or the Reddit app? And I'm like, no, I'm, I don't wanna open
Speaker 6:  it in the Reddit app. I'm in my browser. Just let me read it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I, the it's
Speaker 6:  All about keeping you inside.
Speaker 5:  One of my alternate summer takes was death
Speaker 5:  to the open in app popups because everybody does it and it's all
Speaker 5:  horrible. It drives me crazy. And the thing where Instagram won't let you
Speaker 5:  look at posts on the way,
Speaker 6:  Just, oh my gosh,
Speaker 11:  This is my so annoying.
Speaker 5:  True disaster. But yeah, I think Reddit's in this weird place where like,
Speaker 5:  Reddit is very powerful because it is a place
Speaker 5:  where humans are, and there are increasingly few of those at scale on the
Speaker 5:  internet,
Speaker 5:  but also for, for all the reasons you guys are talking about, it's
Speaker 5:  completely reliant on Google for that fact to continue. So
Speaker 5:  I think I, it's, it's just weird seeing it try to figure
Speaker 5:  out what to do with this like, maybe brief moment in the
Speaker 5:  sun as AI destroys everything else around us.
Speaker 6:  I mean, it, can I tell you something a little trippy? I I did a Google search
Speaker 6:  for iPhone air, you know, 'cause that's a thing that's happening this week.
Speaker 6:  Sure. And I think the top result that was not a,
Speaker 6:  a, a sponsored Apple thing or, or was not just Apple itself
Speaker 6:  was a Reddit result. It was somebody being like, Hey, the iPhone air was
Speaker 6:  announced. Wow. And it's just like, Reddit is everything
Speaker 6:  now on search.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It, it feels like, and and whatever that deal was that Google and Reddit
Speaker 5:  signed was basically just Reddit being like, yeah, we are search now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And Google's like, fine, there's no other good websites anymore. Here
Speaker 5:  you go. Alright. We have gone way over as we
Speaker 5:  are want to do, you guys didn't go over at all this summer. I don't think
Speaker 5:  those terrific work by you. You were always exactly to time Jake. You
Speaker 5:  were a true task master. But now I'm back and chaos rains and so does the
Speaker 5:  lightning round. So maybe
Speaker 14:  The thunder round isn't slower.
Speaker 6:  Our producers are too powerful.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, this is, this is, I'm, I've, I've ruined everything forever. I'm gonna
Speaker 5:  have to bring my own soundboard next week and then that's the real move.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Y'all are toast After that. Alright, we gotta get outta here. One quick
Speaker 5:  housekeeping thing. Next week's Tuesday episode is going to be a
Speaker 5:  Wednesday episode because there's just a lot of Apple stuff happening next
Speaker 5:  week and we just wanted to give ourselves as much time as possible to cover
Speaker 5:  as much of it as possible. So that episode is gonna come out next Wednesday
Speaker 5:  if you have questions about all of it, all the new gadgets, all the new software.
Speaker 5:  If you hate Liquid Glass as much as I do, we wanna hear about it on the hotline.
Speaker 5:  8 6 6 VERGE one one. Send us an email at vergecast at The Verge dot com.
Speaker 5:  The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network.
Speaker 5:  The show is produced by Eric Gomez, Brandon Keefer, and Travis Uck, Hayden
Speaker 5:  Field, and Jake Kaki. It's an honor to be back doing this with you guys.
Speaker 5:  Thank you for doing this with me.
Speaker 6:  We missed you. We really
Speaker 14:  Did.
Speaker 5:  We'll see you next time. Rock and roll.