# Transcript
ID: d6ff3106-4fb1-4e5e-92ca-c5a37c93ca82
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/9112765397457275637/-2040474314247192729/s93290-US-5817s-1737110681.mp3
Description: David Pierce and Richard Lawler are joined by The Verge's Ash Parrish and Andrew Webster to talk about the Nintendo Switch 2 launch — all the things we know, and all the things we don't. (There's a lot of both.) Then The Verge's Adi Robertson joins to talk about the latest machinations in the potential TikTok ban, plus a Supreme Court hearing about adult content that might just be about the future of the internet. Finally, in the lightning round, David and Richard talk about Patrick Spence leaving Sonos, the Blue Origin launch, Drake's latest beef with Kendrick Lamar, and more.
Speaker 6:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of additional
Speaker 6:  USB ports. I'm your friend David Pierce. Neil a Patel is doing some fancy
Speaker 6:  journalism thing today that I don't totally understand so he's not here.
Speaker 6:  Richard Lawler is here. Hi Richard.
Speaker 7:  Hey, how you doing?
Speaker 6:  We do not do fancy journalism things here. That's NE's job.
Speaker 6:  We're just here to talk about Nintendo. Ash Parrish is here. Hi Ash.
Speaker 6:  Hi. And Andrew Webster is here. Hi Andrew. Hello
Speaker 6:  Andrew. True or false, the last time you were on camera was the last time
Speaker 6:  there was a Nintendo Switch.
Speaker 7:  That is correct. 2017 in New York.
Speaker 6:  How does it feel to be back?
Speaker 7:  I'm here,
Speaker 6:  I'll take it. So there's a lot of stuff to talk about today.
Speaker 6:  The TikTok ban either is or is not going to happen and literally
Speaker 6:  no one knows and everybody changes their mind every five minutes. There's
Speaker 6:  a bunch of Sonos news, a whole bunch of policy and politics stuff
Speaker 6:  happening. As the Biden administration comes to a close and the Trump administration
Speaker 6:  comes to a start. But we have to start with The Nintendo Switch, which
Speaker 6:  after, I don't know months, Andrew of you
Speaker 6:  sort of waking up every morning wondering if the today was going to be the
Speaker 6:  day that The Switch too came out finally exists
Speaker 6:  ish. Kind of Andrew, just explain what we know
Speaker 6:  and learned about The Switch today.
Speaker 7:  I mean pretty much what you said it exists. We have a three minute video
Speaker 7:  that shows shows it's a real thing and a press release that tells us
Speaker 7:  that it's a real thing but we know nothing else. It's bigger.
Speaker 7:  They won't say what size the screen is. The Joy Con are
Speaker 7:  slightly different. How, I don't know, they attach differently.
Speaker 7:  That's pretty much it. It is
Speaker 6:  Like The Switch too in every way that If you had sat down and been like,
Speaker 6:  what might The Switch to be? You would've come up with basically this, right?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It's like that old allergy clip where he is like, I, I always
Speaker 7:  thought they should make a PlayStation but better. And then they came up
Speaker 7:  with the PlayStation too. It's, it's that, but Nintendo did it.
Speaker 6:  Ash, Andrew and I have been talking forever about how this is like roughly
Speaker 6:  what we wanted out of The Switch. Is this what you wanted out of The Switch?
Speaker 8:  I don't want anything out of them. I just accept what they give
Speaker 8:  me because there's no way to anticipate and there's definitely no way to
Speaker 8:  demand of them. So like I'm, I'm pleased. This is exactly
Speaker 8:  what I expect because I had no expectations patients,
Speaker 8:  but we, we can say at least one potential thing is that there's a new
Speaker 8:  Mario Kar. True. We did get a brief glimpse
Speaker 8:  of what looks to be a new Mario Kar. It looks like it might support more
Speaker 8:  racers than normal, which might hint at some
Speaker 8:  increased multiplayer capacity. So that's cool.
Speaker 8:  But it's all, you know, caveated heavily with might and could.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And that's actually like a bigger deal than it sounds 'cause like there
Speaker 7:  hasn't been a Mario, a New Mario Kart since the Weu technically, even though
Speaker 7:  Mario karts The Switch is bestselling game, it's just, it's a port. So they
Speaker 7:  haven't like done a brand new one in a very long time.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So can I just run down the list of the things that I I that we,
Speaker 6:  we think we learned from this trailer and you guys tell me what I missed.
Speaker 6:  So like you said, bigger screen, smaller bezels
Speaker 6:  joy cons are black and bigger
Speaker 6:  and some of the, the, the triggers are bigger. There's a new button somewhere
Speaker 6:  on the thing. There's also a new port on the top next to the headphone jack.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Is that
Speaker 8:  It? Yes,
Speaker 6:  That might be.
Speaker 8:  Yeah that sounds correct.
Speaker 6:  And then some like little tiny design tweaks.
Speaker 8:  Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. The kickstand looks a little different.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah, the kickstand. I will say the fact that there is like a good kickstand
Speaker 6:  or seemingly better kickstand that does more than one thing seems
Speaker 6:  very exciting. The kickstand on my switch is trash and does not
Speaker 6:  hold it at a usable angle and makes me angry every single time.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Honestly the OLED version is like good for its screen but the
Speaker 7:  the improved kickstand makes it like the best version
Speaker 7:  of The Switch. Yeah. For that reason.
Speaker 6:  So I, is there anything else? Is that, did I miss anything on the list of
Speaker 6:  like things we actually learned from this trailer?
Speaker 8:  I'm trying to go over the video trailer in my head to Sure. Did make seem
Speaker 8:  connect
Speaker 7:  Just slightly differently.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, so they don't slide down anymore. They kind of like slot
Speaker 8:  in and there's like a little port or ping
Speaker 8:  protrusion that they kind of hook into.
Speaker 8:  Oh, also, also there's
Speaker 6:  Also some people online being worried about that, that that might be like
Speaker 6:  a thing that can break.
Speaker 8:  I mean there, there's that concern but from what it looks like it doesn't
Speaker 8:  look like it sticks out far enough to be breakable unless you like
Speaker 8:  really wanna get your fingers in there and break it deliberately. Oh, another
Speaker 8:  thing that you did potentially miss is that the, the, the joy cons might
Speaker 8:  have like some kind of cool mouse functionality because in the video we saw
Speaker 8:  them like snap to their little covers and then like zoom around like it was
Speaker 8:  a mouse. So that might be also something new to expect.
Speaker 8:  I
Speaker 6:  Saw people saying that and I, I went back through the video and I was like,
Speaker 6:  what in the holy hell is everybody talking about? I cannot see where this
Speaker 6:  thing is acting like a mouse. But there's that moment where it's like they're,
Speaker 6:  they're sort of on their edge like scooting around the table. Is that what
Speaker 6:  you're talking about? Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And it like at first glance it might look like oh this is just like a cool
Speaker 8:  affectation to show off the controllers but it actually might belie something
Speaker 8:  functional.
Speaker 7:  Yeah and that's because there was like leaks before saying it's gonna have
Speaker 7:  mouse stuff. I think if we didn't have those, no one would put that together.
Speaker 7:  What would skating
Speaker 6:  Around that be four though? Like are we playing, do we want like a pointer
Speaker 6:  on The Switch?
Speaker 8:  So I heard from people who are discussing this that it could potentially
Speaker 8:  lead to like things where we could see more three Ds
Speaker 8:  games on The Switch and that's how it interacts somehow. Maybe
Speaker 8:  possibly not sure. But that's an idea that people are spitballing.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And you also think of all the PC games that are like portable now because
Speaker 7:  of the steam deck and it makes a lot of sense and you know,
Speaker 7:  it's been a long time since there's been a new Mario paint so. Hmm.
Speaker 6:  I I mean I do wonder how many of those things are now
Speaker 6:  sort of due for a rev because I, I went back and I watched the original
Speaker 6:  trailer to the first switch from 2017, which is like vibes
Speaker 6:  wise the complete opposite of Yeah the one that we got today.
Speaker 6:  Like that one is pure lifestyle video, right? It's like it's all
Speaker 6:  like people running around hanging out with each other and like there's a
Speaker 6:  party on a rooftop and then a bunch of people who are like playing multiplayer
Speaker 6:  games and they're like diagramming like a soccer plays or something
Speaker 6:  that had for reasons. But they were like trying to get you to understand
Speaker 6:  like here is what this thing is for and all the different ways you can use
Speaker 6:  it on an airplane and all this stuff. This one was just pure like we took
Speaker 6:  the thing and we changed the size and shape of it the end,
Speaker 6:  which is probably true but it does make me think like, okay, if
Speaker 6:  you're not going to blow people's mind with some like new idea about
Speaker 6:  hardware, maybe, maybe the games push is gonna have to be
Speaker 6:  bigger. That they're gonna have to reinvent some of that stuff for this in
Speaker 6:  order to make this feel as exciting as a new console Rev might be. Does
Speaker 9:  It have to be They sell a million of billion switches anyway. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  With no changes.
Speaker 8:  It's true. And they didn do anything with like there was no Switch Pro
Speaker 8:  we got an ole which was just like a bigger brighter screen, but we did
Speaker 8:  like, we didn't have any like real console refreshes for The Switch and it
Speaker 8:  still sold like gangbusters. There's no need to reinvent the wheel with this.
Speaker 8:  Nintendo knows that.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, this video is just like we won, like we figured it out.
Speaker 7:  Like what else is there to do?
Speaker 7:  And like even, even, I don't know, I'd be surprised if when they do the the
Speaker 7:  game reveal stuff, there's a lot of stuff that's like exclusive exclusive
Speaker 7:  'cause they still have like 150 million switches out there and people wanted
Speaker 7:  to buy games for it. So I think there's gonna be like, in the same way that
Speaker 7:  like with the PS five and Xbox series, whatever, it's been like
Speaker 7:  a long transition period to getting games that only play on there. I think
Speaker 7:  it's gonna be similar to The Switch too.
Speaker 6:  Okay. And speaking of that, we, there was some slightly vague
Speaker 6:  information about how games are gonna work on this thing, right?
Speaker 6:  Because the, the last bit of news we got, if I'm remembering this correctly,
Speaker 6:  was on election night in the United States when they just dropped this thing
Speaker 6:  about games being backward compatible. But then it sounds like the, the
Speaker 6:  trailer puts a little bit of an asterisk on
Speaker 8:  That. Yeah, they said some, they will be able to play
Speaker 8:  physical and digital copies of games from the original switch, but not
Speaker 8:  everything would transfer over and they did haven't given us an idea
Speaker 8:  of what games won't. But we can imagine at least some
Speaker 8:  things like the Nintendo Labo stuff, like that's not gonna be
Speaker 8:  compatible.
Speaker 8:  I can't think of anything else. But that one's the fur foremost in my mind.
Speaker 8:  Like those really, really, really weird gimmicky Nintendo Switch games
Speaker 8:  probably won't pour over.
Speaker 6:  Right. But I will say the, the thing that made me worried and maybe I'm worrying
Speaker 6:  about this for no reason, is that what that might mean is that
Speaker 6:  anybody who makes a switch game has to do something in order to support
Speaker 6:  The Switch too. That there is some like, I don't know what, like when
Speaker 6:  Apple introduces a new screen size, you have to like go in and it's not a
Speaker 6:  ton of work, but it is some work to like make it work on the new thing that
Speaker 6:  maybe it was gonna be like that and not just sort of pure
Speaker 6:  outta the box backward compatibility.
Speaker 7:  I think it's entirely the controllers is my guess. Mm. Like
Speaker 7:  Labo only is designed specifically for those tinier versions of the
Speaker 7:  JoyCon to fit in. So there's no way to make it work with the bigger one.
Speaker 7:  I think like
Speaker 7:  Ring Fit Adventure might be a similar one 'cause it has an accessory that
Speaker 7:  like it fits snugly in there. You can't put a bigger one in there. I think
Speaker 7:  it's just those weird oddball ones. I mean we'll, we'll like, we'll find
Speaker 7:  out soon, but there's always, I think with every Nin hano platform there's
Speaker 7:  always like one or two of those. Like we made something weird and now
Speaker 7:  it doesn't work. But the backwards compatibility thing, I think
Speaker 7:  it'll be those ones
Speaker 6:  Which I think is fine. Like I, I don't know that Labo backwards compatibility
Speaker 6:  is like a thing I'm super concerned about for the next version of The Switch.
Speaker 7:  I mean maybe the better screen will make Zelda and VR slightly Lewis
Speaker 7:  nauseous, who knows,
Speaker 6:  Counts for something I suppose. Yeah. So the only game we saw at all
Speaker 6:  was this potentially new Mario Kart. We'll see what that turns out to be.
Speaker 6:  Did it surprise any of you guys that we didn't see more games? I sort of
Speaker 6:  assumed we'd see more games.
Speaker 8:  I mean we didn't see any games hardly for the first one. We saw a glimpse
Speaker 8:  of a breath of the wild and Skyrim of all games. Oh yeah. And that was it.
Speaker 8:  So this isn't too far off the mark where we
Speaker 8:  have one fewer game and though second game was like a a,
Speaker 8:  a game that Bethesda has been trotting out for the last 20 years. So I don't
Speaker 8:  think we're missing much.
Speaker 6:  Why does Nintendo do this like this? Like the, the, I was, I was, I was thinking
Speaker 6:  about the cadence of this right before we were getting on and it's like,
Speaker 6:  okay, Nintendo puts out a video and then says we're gonna have more to share
Speaker 6:  at a direct in April three full months from
Speaker 6:  now and then there's gonna be a bunch of hands-on stuff and then it's launching
Speaker 6:  for some price at some time in the future this year, like
Speaker 6:  no other company launches a product like this. What what like
Speaker 6:  Andrew, I, I grant that trying to understand Nintendo as a company is, is
Speaker 6:  insane and no one should try to do it, but what is going on here?
Speaker 6:  Why would Nintendo,
Speaker 7:  This one is like very simple. Like the answer is the we you like when that
Speaker 7:  was announced, no one knew what this was like literally like
Speaker 7:  I remember writing the, the breaking news post and I was like, is this a
Speaker 7:  we accessory, is this new console? Like nobody knew. Oh, interesting. The
Speaker 7:  messaging around that was like so confusing and it was,
Speaker 7:  you know, a massive flaw after like
Speaker 7:  how do you mess up after the we that was like a huge breakthrough console,
Speaker 7:  right?
Speaker 7:  So like whatever you say about Nintendo, like they have become very
Speaker 7:  good and precise at messaging and so they are doing it
Speaker 7:  in stages so you don't mess things up. Like the first message is just like,
Speaker 7:  you know, you guys are safe. We didn't mess it up, we just made a bigger
Speaker 7:  we or a bigger switch. And then they get into the other stuff after
Speaker 7:  they like, I think they're just very
Speaker 7:  certain that like there's of what they wanna say
Speaker 7:  and they wanna make sure it gets out clearly.
Speaker 6:  So if that's true, it seems to me the one thing Nintendo
Speaker 6:  whiffed on is not saying something about
Speaker 6:  the processor. Like looking at our comments and looking at social and looking
Speaker 6:  all and, and like even my own reaction is like, the main thing I want to
Speaker 6:  know is if this thing is more powerful because
Speaker 6:  it needs to be, and the The Switch was like,
Speaker 6:  it wasn't underpowered when it came out, but it wasn't
Speaker 6:  powerful when it came out and it has like since gotten
Speaker 6:  sort of pathetic in a certain way, like as a raw horsepower
Speaker 6:  thing. And overwhelmingly like what people seem to have wanted
Speaker 6:  to know is like, is this thing going to be more powerful? Is it going to
Speaker 6:  be able to run the kinds of games that I want? Is it gonna be able to run
Speaker 6:  like new kinds of games over time? And we will
Speaker 6:  get the answer to that in two and a half months and maybe it doesn't matter
Speaker 6:  because it's a new switch and everybody's gonna buy it anyway. Richard, like
Speaker 6:  you were saying, but it does feel like that's the biggest detail that we
Speaker 6:  still don't know anything about.
Speaker 7:  But again, that's just like clouding their message. I think
Speaker 7:  you, I think you look at like the PS five pro reveal and they have like Mark
Speaker 7:  Cerney talking about whatever tariff flops are and like no normal
Speaker 7:  person knows what that video is saying. Sure. And anyone who's complaining
Speaker 7:  about not knowing the specs is a person who's still gonna buy a new switch
Speaker 7:  anyways. Like Yeah I think that is like the thing
Speaker 7:  in the same way that the original video was like all about vibes, like this
Speaker 7:  is it, it's just they want, they don't wanna tell you everything. They want
Speaker 7:  to tell you the most important thing, which is it's The Switch and
Speaker 7:  bigger. Like that's it. Right?
Speaker 6:  That's well that's the thing. It's like the, and and there were a bunch of
Speaker 6:  folks in our comments who were like, there this is like a passive aggressive
Speaker 6:  launch video, which I didn't immediately read it as,
Speaker 6:  but there is kind of something to that where Nintendo is like, yeah,
Speaker 6:  dumb asses switch to whatever, leave us
Speaker 6:  alone here. It's, and like there, there is a little bit to that where it's
Speaker 6:  like we don't have to tell you anything. It's a switch to you'll buy it shut
Speaker 6:  up.
Speaker 9:  Not only will you buy it, you'll buy several of these. Yeah, you'll own more
Speaker 9:  than one. You know it, we know it. Everyone knows it. We don't have to tell
Speaker 9:  you how powerful it is and really, I'm not sure of how powerful it is matters
Speaker 9:  that much because they don't, they don't need that much horsepower to be
Speaker 9:  a slightly better Fortnite machine. Like they need a little bit but, but
Speaker 9:  only a little And it's, it's, I think at this point
Speaker 8:  Nobody's playing Fortnite on The Switch.
Speaker 7:  Well we need to get Charles on here. You know
Speaker 9:  What it, you know what some of my teammates would, would disagree.
Speaker 8:  Not enough. Not a lot. But yeah, part of the thing that
Speaker 8:  makes Nintendo Nintendo is the fact that they are very good at doing more
Speaker 8:  with less. And I don't think I want to see them change that
Speaker 8:  anyway by building a better mousetrap or a more powerful mousetrap
Speaker 8:  anyway. So we can wait for them to reveal all of the
Speaker 8:  specs. The, the only thing that's of concern to me is the fact that, you
Speaker 8:  know, can we play games like Kingdom Hearts and not have to do it via cloud
Speaker 8:  streaming because that was not a great feeling at all. So as
Speaker 8:  long as it can take care of that, I'm okay.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Like to be clear like that stuff is important. It's just not the important
Speaker 7:  thing, which is the first message they want to be out there. Right.
Speaker 6:  And what is that message other than just yes, The Switch two exists? No,
Speaker 7:  That's it, it's it's the number two. That's it. That's the message.
Speaker 6:  I did see somebody, I think it was Brian CTE who wrote a thing who was like
Speaker 6:  weird. He, he had a lot of feelings about the fact that it was called The
Speaker 6:  Switch two and not the Super Switch or anything else. And he was saying it
Speaker 6:  was the first time ever that Nintendo has just done like the numeral after
Speaker 6:  the console, which I thought was sort of fascinating. And
Speaker 6:  it's like there there's a bunch of like Galaxy Brain theories you can have
Speaker 6:  about Nintendo as a company here and Andrew you have some of those and I'd
Speaker 6:  like to hear them, but I don't know there is, there is part of me that
Speaker 6:  is like this console is both exactly what I wanted and maybe less
Speaker 6:  imaginative than you would expect from a company like Nintendo right
Speaker 8:  Now. Well can you, If you imagine like them calling it the Super
Speaker 8:  Switch or The Switch Advance or something like that, I feel like that
Speaker 8:  muddles the message more than just calling it The Switch
Speaker 8:  too, because unlike, you know,
Speaker 8:  PlayStation or whatever, like we, we know like the
Speaker 8:  the, The Switch is like a family console, right? And so you've got a lot
Speaker 8:  of grandmas and grandpas and people who don't know what video games are buying
Speaker 8:  these consoles for their kids or even for themselves and muddying it by calling
Speaker 8:  it like a Super Switch or a switch advance or some other, you know, kind
Speaker 8:  of name kind of messes with that. I'm sorry, I'm trying not to curse and
Speaker 8:  just calling it simply The Switch too clearly informs those,
Speaker 8:  those kinds of buyers that okay, this is the next step. It's
Speaker 6:  Like the opposite of the Ds, which I feel like by the end of it had like
Speaker 6:  800 names that were totally indiscernible from one
Speaker 6:  another.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, you had the three Ds and the two Ds and you know, xl.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So you had no idea If you were like a layman for lack of a better
Speaker 8:  term. Like okay, what does, what is this an advancement? Is this like a
Speaker 8:  same thing but you know, with more bells and whistles keep a simple stupid
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I think you just need to look at like Xbox's naming scheme to see
Speaker 7:  like how badly that can go. Yeah. Because
Speaker 8:  Like 100% you mean
Speaker 6:  Going from Xbox to 360 to one doesn't that, that's not,
Speaker 6:  that's not simple. That doesn't make sense to you.
Speaker 7:  Listen, anyone who's ever tried to put series x slash S in a headline
Speaker 7:  absolutely despises this naming scheme.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That I mean that's fair. And the the PlayStation thing like
Speaker 6:  we made a PlayStation but better and it's called the PlayStation, like it
Speaker 6:  it does kind of work. That's that's fair. And Andrew, you also made the case
Speaker 6:  that I think is right, that this is like just an
Speaker 6:  incredible flex from Nintendo that they're like, yeah this thing we did almost
Speaker 6:  a decade ago, like we crushed it and you suckers are like still
Speaker 6:  trying to catch up to this thing that we did forever ago and so we're just
Speaker 6:  gonna kick it and continue to win because we
Speaker 6:  are a thousand miles ahead of where everyone else has been this entire time.
Speaker 7:  Yeah and like everything about the way they did this to even like
Speaker 7:  not pre announcing it, like Nintendo usually is like, you
Speaker 7:  know, on Wednesday we're gonna have a direct and we're gonna announce blah
Speaker 7:  blah blah and they give some information. This was like, nope, it's 8:00 AM
Speaker 7:  on a Thursday, here's our new console. So it's like they know
Speaker 7:  like people will pay attention no matter what. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Richard, what do you make of this thing? Is this, is this everything you
Speaker 6:  wanted it to be?
Speaker 9:  How does it work with the alarm mode?
Speaker 6:  Maybe that's what the USB port is for
Speaker 9:  When I know the answer to that question I'll have have my answer for you,
Speaker 9:  but I mean otherwise yeah. You know, it's a switch. It, it will continue
Speaker 9:  to switch and I thought that it was interesting it, especially when you look
Speaker 9:  back at the original video for the, for the first switch
Speaker 9:  that the, the actual joy, the actual kickstand is better
Speaker 9:  now. So you can actually use it to do the things that they advertise the
Speaker 9:  first one to do. Yeah. So maybe an admission of some mistakes, but yes,
Speaker 9:  that overall their, their viewpoint that their angle, that the, the way that
Speaker 9:  they're going, they're saying this is right.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I don't know. There there is a thing where it's like this is, this
Speaker 6:  is the equivalent of like the iPhone 12 to 13 where they're just
Speaker 6:  like, we made everything a little better. We've been working on the things
Speaker 6:  that you work on and now here's some new ones.
Speaker 6:  And I, I can't decide how much of me is
Speaker 6:  bummed that Nintendo didn't do something insane and weird and
Speaker 6:  potentially bad because I think that's like fun and interesting versus
Speaker 6:  assuming the specs are what I think that they are. Like when I look at my
Speaker 6:  switch, my, I have this like gross yellow switch from
Speaker 6:  2017 that I still use and literally all I want out of
Speaker 6:  it is a faster wifi chip. Like the, the wifi on my
Speaker 6:  switch is trash and if they would just make it fast wifi so that
Speaker 6:  my pings would go down in the games I play online, I would be perfectly happy
Speaker 6:  with this console. And so I'm, I'm torn between like I wish they had done
Speaker 6:  more and also like I'm super, super glad they didn't do more
Speaker 6:  and like we unify The Switch and make it worse. There's
Speaker 8:  Still time, I mean there's a lot of breathing room between now
Speaker 8:  and April 2nd that is fair for them to show, you know, go crazy with it.
Speaker 8:  So I mean don't count 'em out.
Speaker 6:  What crazy is there to do though? That's The Switch too. They're like, yeah
Speaker 6:  we finished this thing years ago,
Speaker 8:  It's Nintendo. They have ways of surprising, like we have no
Speaker 8:  idea what they, it's in what's in store for us. Kind of like what Andrew
Speaker 8:  has written about on The Verge about like I've given up trying to predict
Speaker 8:  what Nintendo will do. They still have that element of, you know, the ability
Speaker 8:  to surprise.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I do think the the the surprise things will be
Speaker 7:  not directly tied to the console. It'll be like we're using this in some
Speaker 7:  weird way in like a Labo like project. 'cause that's
Speaker 7:  like, you know, doing it, making it a core part of the console is like
Speaker 7:  a huge risk which they don't want to take obviously,
Speaker 7:  but you know, if no one buys some weird ass cardboard device,
Speaker 7:  you know, they're still experimenting but it's not like a big loss. So I
Speaker 7:  think they're still gonna take weird swings because that's who they are.
Speaker 7:  But I think it's just not baked into the hardware
Speaker 6:  And I feel like the last decade of big swings in gaming
Speaker 6:  sort of teaches us that that's the right approach. Right? I feel like every
Speaker 6:  time, and Microsoft just can't help itself from doing this, but every time
Speaker 6:  somebody has a big bonkers idea that they like build into the
Speaker 6:  console in a really meaningful way, it goes sideways, right? Microsoft is
Speaker 6:  like, we're gonna reinvent entertainment through the Xbox and everybody's
Speaker 6:  like, no thank you. And then they're like, the connect is now bundled in
Speaker 6:  and everybody's like, no thank you. Whereas like the PlayStation has just
Speaker 6:  continued to be like, it's mostly about playing games with a controller sitting
Speaker 6:  on your couch If you want some other stuff, here's some other stuff that
Speaker 6:  we'll sell you, here's VR and here's Move and here's all these other things.
Speaker 6:  If you want those things, terrific. But fundamentally we're just building
Speaker 6:  a thing to hold in your hands and play games. That has continued to be
Speaker 6:  the thing that works. And I feel like even with the first switch, what
Speaker 6:  Nintendo has done is essentially build a pretty straightforward thing
Speaker 6:  and an escalating series of insane accessories.
Speaker 7:  Even like the gimmicks that they had initially. Like no one uses them. I
Speaker 7:  don't know If you guys remember when like The Switch was announced and they
Speaker 7:  were testing it, like HD Rumble was like a big thing and they were like showing
Speaker 7:  executives like listening to Ice cubes. You could tell how many ice cubes
Speaker 7:  were falling into something by the vibrations and that's like
Speaker 7:  a relatively minor gimmick and didn't end up, you know, they enforce every
Speaker 7:  developer to put that in their games and so it didn't screw things up but
Speaker 7:  like that's the kind of thing I think we're gonna see is like stuff
Speaker 7:  that you can ignore if, If you need to
Speaker 9:  Street fast is coming back. Hmm. Get ready.
Speaker 7:  That's what, that's what the button's for
Speaker 8:  Picto chat. I want Picto chat back.
Speaker 6:  What was Picto chat dude
Speaker 8:  From the the ds?
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah,
Speaker 8:  That was
Speaker 6:  Fun. Oh my
Speaker 7:  God, I don't know If you want Picto chat in. Okay.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, maybe not 2025 now.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it was simpler times when we hit Picto chat.
Speaker 6:  So what Andrew, your, your long national nightmare of having to
Speaker 6:  follow The Switch to launch is is not over.
Speaker 6:  What is the next kind of drumbeat here?
Speaker 7:  Well, we'll see, I mean they said they're gonna talk about in April, but
Speaker 7:  I've also been hearing there may be like a gaming
Speaker 7:  direct games focused direct in February, so
Speaker 7:  there's gonna be more beats to this and there will probably be
Speaker 7:  dropped on us on a random evening of
Speaker 7:  importance for American politics.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean there's one of those coming up on Monday, so like it's it might
Speaker 6:  happen.
Speaker 7:  That's when the price is coming.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Right.
Speaker 6:  What do you guys think the price is gonna be? Let's, let's make some educated
Speaker 6:  guesses here. What do we think this thing is gonna cost
Speaker 8:  If it costs more than $400? I'll be surprised.
Speaker 6:  What was the original switch when it
Speaker 8:  Came out? 300. Okay, let's set that. And the OLED was three 50, like
Speaker 8:  the 404 50, that's it. And even four 50
Speaker 8:  sounds wrong in my ears. In my, yeah. To, to me
Speaker 6:  Four 50 feels like a lot.
Speaker 8:  Yeah it does. But if, I guess we have no way of knowing unless we know the,
Speaker 8:  the specs on it because four 50 absolutely might be a justified price depending
Speaker 8:  on what's in that thing. But 400 has to be,
Speaker 8:  I mean Nintendo's a, they're not like, you know, a PlayStation or an Xbox
Speaker 8:  where they can show you the big shiny box and charge you like 600 bucks for
Speaker 8:  it because you know it's a family company and they, they work with families
Speaker 8:  that have budgets and they don't wanna, you know, they wanna, they don't
Speaker 8:  wanna price people out like their core audience of people out. So it's gotta
Speaker 8:  be, you know, of course adjusted for inflation and the cost of like
Speaker 8:  computer chips and things like that, but it still have to be affordable so
Speaker 8:  it's probably gonna be 400 bucks.
Speaker 6:  Richard, you're making a face that makes me think you're about to be like,
Speaker 6:  it's a thousand dollars.
Speaker 9:  That's what The Switch to pro will be.
Speaker 9:  I think the, I think The Switch to like, maybe they'll just keep it at 300
Speaker 9:  or three 50.
Speaker 8:  That would be incredible. I
Speaker 9:  Think one of the questions I have is like, is The Switch going to, is the
Speaker 9:  original switch that's going to kind of disappear? I, I expected it won't,
Speaker 9:  they'll keep selling it and sell them side by side at least for a while.
Speaker 9:  And how long is it until we get games that are only for The Switch too? Or
Speaker 9:  do they have reduced capabilities if you're playing on The Switch or, or
Speaker 9:  If you have like someone like that in your party or something like that.
Speaker 9:  That's probably the, I think the bigger question is, is
Speaker 9:  how quickly does your old switch get deprecated? Mm.
Speaker 7:  I like how all of Richard's answers relate to his Apex legend squad.
Speaker 9:  That's the most important thing. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Don't take this away from me. Nintendo, Andrew, what about you? What do you
Speaker 6:  think? I've
Speaker 7:  Been trying to convert into American dollars. I do, I do think it'll be
Speaker 7:  like less than 400 because the whole point of them
Speaker 7:  having the lower specs is because they find the cheapest
Speaker 7:  tech older technology to squeeze into these things. So that's,
Speaker 7:  if you're not gonna do that, then what's the point? Like you may as
Speaker 7:  well put out, you know, a powerful device if you're gonna go for a higher
Speaker 7:  price. So the whole point of cheaping it on there is like to pass
Speaker 7:  that on to consumers. So it's gotta be sub 400
Speaker 6:  If this thing stays at 2 99 or whatever, it's, that's gonna be pretty
Speaker 6:  spectacular.
Speaker 7:  They're gonna do that and then put The Switch down to like a super
Speaker 7:  cheap price purely so they can beat the PS two.
Speaker 6:  Oh that's interesting. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  In terms of lifetime sales, that's what's gonna happen.
Speaker 6:  They just like, they, they want the, they want the victory even one Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Teeny tiny margin at a time. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I I think If you put like the, the original switch down to like a very cheap
Speaker 7:  price, it's still gonna move a ton.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean truly other than, well okay I have two grapes
Speaker 6:  with my switch and thank you for coming to my Ted talk about the things I
Speaker 6:  hate about my 7-year-old switch. One is that I lost the cable
Speaker 6:  for the dock and I can't find another power cable for the dock that makes
Speaker 6:  it work. So it's just, it's just useless now because it only works at the
Speaker 6:  one stupid cable and I don't wanna buy a whole nother doc just for the one
Speaker 6:  stupid cable and the other one is the wifi
Speaker 6:  chip. Just simple things. They're like, and, and then like people have had
Speaker 6:  issues with the joycons over the years. I think they're like fine. But I
Speaker 6:  know a lot of people are much more sophisticated controller users than I
Speaker 6:  am who are very curious about how these joycons are gonna work. I just feel
Speaker 6:  like there's, there's all these like little tiny things that if Nintendo
Speaker 6:  would just do those and change nothing else, I will be a very happy
Speaker 6:  owner of somewhere between one and six switch tos.
Speaker 8:  We'll see what colors they come up with and if they release like a special
Speaker 8:  win waker edition because that one is gonna sell like hotcakes.
Speaker 6:  Do we think there's gonna be another like huge
Speaker 6:  earth shattering game that comes with it? I mean like we got Breath of the
Speaker 6:  Wild with The Switch. Is Mario Kart gonna
Speaker 6:  be that thing for The Switch too? Like is that just where we're headed? Could
Speaker 6:  be Mario
Speaker 7:  Kart could be the Pokemon 'cause that's like a huge launch style Pokemon.
Speaker 7:  What the hell is it called? Legend Z.
Speaker 8:  It's legend.
Speaker 7:  ZAZA. Yeah, I think either of those is, that's like a launch
Speaker 7:  title for sure. Those are bestselling games. I love Metro
Speaker 7:  but that's not like a A system seller for No for launch.
Speaker 7:  So either one of those. You're good.
Speaker 8:  Probably a new 3D Mario.
Speaker 7:  Yes,
Speaker 6:  That's true. Yeah. But even that doesn't feel quite as big as
Speaker 6:  as like Pokemon feels like the only one that's kind of at the level of Zelda
Speaker 6:  in terms of like culture shaking release. Nah,
Speaker 6:  the
Speaker 8:  Terrible. I feel like Mario occupies that space as well. You
Speaker 6:  Think? Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Terrible movie made a billion dollars
Speaker 6:  So I mean that's fair. Other people who aren't you liked that movie
Speaker 6:  I will say,
Speaker 7:  Well they haven't had to watch it as many times as me.
Speaker 6:  So did you like it the first time you saw it?
Speaker 7:  It was fine. It was, it was inoffensive.
Speaker 6:  Now you're just increasingly mad at the song peaches every time you hear
Speaker 6:  it. Is that, is that what's happening? Pretty much.
Speaker 6:  Fair enough. Anything else on the, on The Switch? Do we, we're still in this
Speaker 6:  place where like this thing has launched and we still don't know all that
Speaker 6:  much about it's gonna very three
Speaker 9:  Months talk about, let's do it, let's get into it.
Speaker 8:  Let's not, I hope The Switch two cartridges taste better.
Speaker 6:  Do you?
Speaker 8:  No, let's, let's
Speaker 6:  Talk about that.
Speaker 8:  That was a choke
Speaker 6:  Richard.
Speaker 7:  We do not, we do not endorse child
Speaker 8:  Danger material. Yeah, please don't. Please don't put those in your mouth
Speaker 6:  Richard. You can have 20 seconds to talk about DL Ss and then we're taking
Speaker 6:  a break. Here you go. Ready? I go. I'm just
Speaker 9:  Saying that AI in graphics processing is very important. It could be really
Speaker 9:  relevant to the games that we play on our switch tools. It it is the number
Speaker 9:  one factor that I'm waiting to hear more about. Thank you.
Speaker 6:  There we go. Alright, we're gonna take a break. Ash and Andrew, thank you
Speaker 6:  guys for being here. Unfortunately
Speaker 6:  All right, we're back. Addie Robertson's here. Hi Addie. Hi. Our
Speaker 6:  resident RedNote expert, as it turns out, was just teaching us how to pronounce
Speaker 6:  the correct name of everybody's favorite new TikTok competitor. Do you want
Speaker 6:  to, do you wanna give us a lesson here on what it's actually called?
Speaker 10:  I need to caveat this that I am not Chinese and I have not spoken
Speaker 10:  Chinese for a very long time. My impression is
Speaker 6:  Okay, Richard, how do you feel about that?
Speaker 9:  I'm getting there. Yeah, a little. I feel like I feel like I'm getting I
Speaker 9:  I'll, I'll have it by the next week. I'll be a star on
Speaker 10:  The first
Speaker 10:  is as little and then Hong is red
Speaker 10:  and then Shu, which is book
Speaker 6:  It's, this app is literally called Little Red Book
Speaker 10:  I believe so yeah,
Speaker 9:  I think the US governor is gonna love that
Speaker 10:  Possible that, you know, there's a better colloquial translation.
Speaker 6:  This is what we've come to. So, okay, the, the scene setting I
Speaker 6:  just wanna do here real quick before we get into it is the, the
Speaker 6:  potential TikTok ban is now two days away. As you're hearing
Speaker 6:  this three days away as we're recording it, we did a whole thing with Lauren
Speaker 6:  Finer on Tuesday show talking about what might happen and then it feels like
Speaker 6:  a hundred new possibilities appeared since Tuesday about what might happen.
Speaker 6:  So I want to talk through some of the things that have come
Speaker 6:  up, some of the things we think might be happening and the deep polarity
Speaker 6:  of what everyone has done in response to the impending TikTok
Speaker 6:  ban.
Speaker 6:  But let me just start by throwing out some of the like
Speaker 6:  possible outcomes that seem to have arisen over the last few days and we
Speaker 6:  can talk a little bit about them. Outcome number one, I would say
Speaker 6:  probably most likely in terms of actual things that might happen is
Speaker 6:  some kind of delay in the ban.
Speaker 6:  Senator Ed Markey introduced something or said he was
Speaker 6:  gonna introduce something that would give it a 270 day extension to either
Speaker 6:  divest or be banned. There was, was it Trump was gonna do
Speaker 6:  an executive order that was gonna delay it by 60 or 90 days?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, he is floated one at least.
Speaker 6:  Okay, so a lot of ideas in the area that like we're just gonna kick the can
Speaker 6:  down the road a little bit. Addie do either. Does that, does that strike
Speaker 6:  you as like a real plausible outcome here?
Speaker 10:  Well there was always the option of kicking the can down the road 90 days
Speaker 10:  if there is a deal in place and depending on the definition of
Speaker 10:  what a deal is, I think that's kind of where people le are leaning
Speaker 10:  is we're just gonna give them time to figure this out.
Speaker 10:  It seems pretty unlikely to me that they're going to pass a whole new law
Speaker 10:  in what, like three days.
Speaker 6:  I mean there's, there's some other stuff going on in in the political universe
Speaker 6:  too. So I I think you're probably right on that. This is the thing that I
Speaker 6:  don't understand though is like, can anyone actually do this
Speaker 6:  stuff? 'cause there's like, there's, there's the ban on Sunday and
Speaker 6:  then there's an inauguration day on Monday and then
Speaker 6:  something will happen and TikTok will be back. Like there's, there's
Speaker 6:  rumors that TikTok is gonna go away just for a day and then potentially come
Speaker 6:  back. Like, I just dunno how to handicap the realistic possibility
Speaker 6:  of any of this right now.
Speaker 10:  Some of it depends on what the Supreme Court does and unfortunately we have
Speaker 10:  been frantically waiting for a ruling for several
Speaker 10:  days now. But part of the question is, okay, so
Speaker 10:  the rule here is it's either banned or they have to bite dance
Speaker 10:  has to divest it. And the question of what divestiture means, like
Speaker 10:  what can actually satisfy that requirement is a little bit of an open
Speaker 10:  question. I think the thing that Trump really wants and that a lot of people
Speaker 10:  really want is the idea that they can just switch a little bit of
Speaker 10:  ownership around and maybe shuffle, shuffle the board a bit
Speaker 10:  in a way that satisfies the Chinese government and the ruling for divestiture.
Speaker 10:  And then nothing necessarily changes that much, but it comes under
Speaker 10:  the ownership of someone American and the Chinese government doesn't feel
Speaker 10:  like it's lost the TikTok algorithm or like it's gotten
Speaker 10:  strong armed. And then at that point, if there are disagreements,
Speaker 10:  you still get to have this three month delay in which they could hammer
Speaker 10:  them out.
Speaker 6:  What would that in theory look like? If it's, if it's basically, so the,
Speaker 6:  the number I've heard at least is that this, the, the bar
Speaker 6:  for foreign ownership under this bill is I think it's 20%
Speaker 6:  ownership. Yeah. So in theory all all bite dance would have to do is
Speaker 6:  find a way to lower its ownership stake under 20%
Speaker 6:  and then everything would be okay. Is that, is that the idea here?
Speaker 10:  I think that's a thing that could happen and could be logical. It is
Speaker 10:  possible that you could still then have questions about, all right, but
Speaker 10:  does ance still potentially have some kind of backdoor?
Speaker 10:  But at the very least, that does seem like it has
Speaker 10:  some kind of reasonable standard in the law that yeah, you just
Speaker 10:  reduce the, the dependence. I,
Speaker 6:  That just doesn't make any sense to me because again, like if, if the
Speaker 6:  big argument we're having here is about national security and access to data,
Speaker 6:  like, you know what buys you the back door is 20%. Like whether
Speaker 6:  you have 49% or 20% or 99%,
Speaker 6:  like you're still gonna have the admin login, right? Richard? Like, am I,
Speaker 6:  am I insane here that it feels like this solves nothing? If this is an actual
Speaker 6:  thing we're gonna do, would
Speaker 9:  You give a 20% owner an admin login? Yeah. No, no, no. You're, you're,
Speaker 9:  you're a minority owner. No, no admin login for you. And they've already
Speaker 9:  done some things like the project Texas moving the data around
Speaker 9:  it. It just, it sounds like we've got this group project that's due on Sunday
Speaker 9:  and no one has done the work. You know, you, you got the Chinese government,
Speaker 9:  they're not picking up the phone. You got one of these students that's already
Speaker 9:  checked out Biden, he, he's, he's on his way out. This, this is not his grade.
Speaker 9:  You got someone coming in, but they're not gonna be here before the due date
Speaker 9:  and Congress and the Supreme Court just haven't done it.
Speaker 10:  I really wish I had a clever way to build on this analogy, but the things
Speaker 10:  that complicate that are that a, nobody wants to finish the project. Everybody's
Speaker 10:  sick of this. Trump doesn't want to TikTok to shut down on his watch Biden
Speaker 10:  as far as we can tell, there's some level of buyer's remorse and the
Speaker 10:  administration is maybe trying to find a way to delay it. And then
Speaker 10:  the Chinese government, and by dance obviously before the ban, they're going
Speaker 10:  to give you the most apocalyptic pronouncement ever. They're not gonna say,
Speaker 10:  oh yeah, no, it's fine. We're in talks with all these other guys. They're
Speaker 10:  going to just wait until the last minute to see if they can hammer on a
Speaker 10:  deal. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I mean to that end, there was a, a report going around. I forget exactly
Speaker 6:  where I thought that that one possible outcome is that TikTok will just kind
Speaker 6:  of performatively go away, just like pull the plug
Speaker 6:  more aggressively than it even needs to on the 19th just to prove how
Speaker 6:  bad it would be if TikTok was gone. 'cause I think a lot of people have been
Speaker 6:  talking about the idea that what might happen is it might just sort of slowly
Speaker 6:  degrade over time that people who have it on their phones will be able to
Speaker 6:  continue to use it. But that actually what might happen is TikTok will just
Speaker 6:  be like, oh, you wanna see TikTok gone? Tiktoks gone suck on that. And
Speaker 6:  it'll just be sort of, it'll, it'll just make everybody miss it
Speaker 6:  a little bit for 24 hours and then we'll come back on inauguration
Speaker 6:  day with, with Chuchu the ceo, EO sitting on the day
Speaker 6:  I said Inauguration day with Trump. Like there's
Speaker 6:  a version of that that actually makes a lot of sense to me that TikTok is
Speaker 6:  gonna be like, oh, you wanna ban us? Check this out. Just as a
Speaker 6:  flex,
Speaker 10:  That both makes political sense and it might kind of be necessary
Speaker 10:  because hosting services also have to work with, have to cease working
Speaker 10:  with by dance and Oracle hosts a bunch of American data,
Speaker 10:  right? So it's possible that you're gonna see that no matter what.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I So are we really at a point where like just
Speaker 6:  none of this makes sense and anything could happen? I guess we might get
Speaker 6:  a real answer if and when we hear from the Supreme Court, which I would
Speaker 6:  say we're all sort of surprised, has taken this long to issue any kind of
Speaker 6:  pronouncement about how it
Speaker 10:  Feels. I think not everyone is surprised, but it is definitely
Speaker 10:  very annoying and not people's first choice.
Speaker 10:  This is also all ignoring the, obviously I say this
Speaker 10:  in a way where it's bad, but to me, much like by far funniest option, which
Speaker 10:  is the law goes into effect and Trump says he's not going to enforce it.
Speaker 10:  And then he asked all of the app stores have to play chicken
Speaker 10:  and like see if they're going to go with these rules.
Speaker 10:  So, which based on Supreme Court arguments, it sounds like that's still
Speaker 10:  a pretty huge risk for them, but that is still an outcome that
Speaker 10:  people have not completely ruled out.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Can you just game that out a little bit? We talked about this with
Speaker 6:  Lauren A. Little on Tuesday too, but it, it does seem like this question
Speaker 6:  of if, if Trump puts out an executive order on
Speaker 6:  day one saying, I'm not going to enforce this law
Speaker 6:  for some period of time, in theory, everyone could just
Speaker 6:  go terrific and resume business as normal and, and TikTok
Speaker 6:  continues, but there, there, there seems to be this sort of extent
Speaker 6:  pressure on all of the players that exist even outside of that.
Speaker 6:  Can you just explain like what, what the tension is there for those companies?
Speaker 6:  There
Speaker 10:  Are a few different tensions. The first tension is that it is very risky
Speaker 10:  to trust Trump's loyalty on a thing. And that this
Speaker 10:  creates a lot of leverage to, If you make him mad,
Speaker 10:  let him do something that's going to hurt you very badly. There is
Speaker 10:  also the chance that the administration could be held in contempt of court
Speaker 10:  if they have gotten an explicit order to enforce this law and they just
Speaker 10:  refuse to. And then there's also the chance that even if they say they're
Speaker 10:  not going to enforce it, the platforms and the app stores say, yeah, this
Speaker 10:  is just too big a risk. It doesn't matter what you say, we're kicking them
Speaker 10:  off.
Speaker 6:  Richard, what would you do if, if I'm who in this? You're Google,
Speaker 6:  you're, you're Sundar Phai and you're, you're sitting there in front of the
Speaker 6:  TikTok is in the app store switch, what are you doing? I'm
Speaker 6:  replacing it with YouTube shorts.
Speaker 6:  Just every time someone searches TikTok, it just instantly takes you to YouTube
Speaker 6:  shorts. The thing is that I love is that Google legitimately has the power
Speaker 6:  technically to just do that. Like If you google TikTok, it's like,
Speaker 6:  nevermind, you want to YouTube shorts, right?
Speaker 9:  There's only YouTube shorts now
Speaker 6:  TikTok never existed. You didn't even, you TikTok was a figment of your
Speaker 6:  imagination. There has only ever been YouTube shorts. Speaking
Speaker 6:  of YouTube shorts, this comes back to our favorite
Speaker 6:  app, RedNote slash Little Red Book. One of the
Speaker 6:  funniest things that has happened this week is a lot of people, rather
Speaker 6:  than leave TikTok for
Speaker 6:  quote unquote more stable places like Instagram or YouTube
Speaker 6:  shorts, these other platforms that have just basically relentlessly copied
Speaker 6:  TikTok for several years. People have instead gone the other way and found
Speaker 6:  more Chinese apps.
Speaker 6:  RedNote and Lemonade being I would say the, the big two.
Speaker 6:  Addie can you, can you explain what these apps are and how this is happening
Speaker 6:  like this?
Speaker 10:  Okay, so Lemonade and RedNote are both, they're
Speaker 10:  Chinese apps that present in theory basically all of the same
Speaker 10:  risks as TikTok Lemonade is owned by Ance the same parent
Speaker 10:  company as TikTok. And I feel like at this point right now,
Speaker 10:  there's a little bit of, it's kind of a free for all. People are just, this
Speaker 10:  is summer break, everybody's experimenting and that if TikTok were
Speaker 10:  long-term band, then we would see people say, I need to make
Speaker 10:  money. I'm going to go to these platforms even though I find them boring
Speaker 10:  and they annoy me.
Speaker 10:  So I don't know what the long-term future would be, but yeah, the short-term
Speaker 10:  future is that people have gone to just the exact
Speaker 10:  same thing and possibly it to some level
Speaker 10:  just to actively spite the people who passed this law.
Speaker 6:  Oh. I mean I think it's, I think it's extremely just spite those people.
Speaker 6:  I mean the, the like goodbye to my Chinese spy thing has been, has
Speaker 6:  become rampant on TikTok and everybody's making fun of it by going to these
Speaker 6:  apps. Like, what was the thing I saw today? Duolingo is booming and
Speaker 6:  suddenly ton tons of people are wanting to learn Mandarin in order to be
Speaker 6:  on these apps. Like this bit has now gone so far that I'm like, at what point
Speaker 6:  is this not a bit, and at what point is everybody just going to excitedly
Speaker 6:  start using Chinese social media apps?
Speaker 9:  I think we're there. I think, I think we're at the point where it's, it has
Speaker 9:  stopped being a bit, I mean people went over to this, this app,
Speaker 9:  Schu Chu I'm gonna get there, I'm gonna get the pronunciation right
Speaker 9:  just So I can, I can get my following up. They found out that Cardi B has
Speaker 9:  been there for years posting really, you know this. Yes. The
Speaker 9:  the weird thing about it is that unlike the other apps, they don't separate
Speaker 9:  their Chinese and American audience or Chinese and international audiences.
Speaker 9:  So you suddenly have these people talking directly to people from China in
Speaker 9:  a way that they probably never have. And
Speaker 9:  there's, there's something there. I, I don't know, I don't know how long
Speaker 9:  it will last if it will be banned two or, or what, what might happen, but
Speaker 9:  something has happened also, American companies apparently
Speaker 9:  cannot make good algorithms.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I I will say I I have continued to be
Speaker 6:  flummoxed by this fact that like, it, it is clearly
Speaker 6:  true that there is something about TikTok that neither
Speaker 6:  YouTube nor Instagram has replicated despite both
Speaker 6:  being desperate to replicate TikTok. Like they're just nakedly trying to
Speaker 6:  do TikTok. They're not even trying to do like their own versions of TikTok.
Speaker 6:  They're just trying to do TikTok and still
Speaker 6:  nothing has been able to quite do it. And, and to your point, Richard, people
Speaker 6:  are, are flooding to these other apps and being like, yes, this gives me
Speaker 6:  the same thing. And it is like, what, what have these Chinese companies
Speaker 6:  in particular by dance, which just keeps making identical looking apps under
Speaker 6:  different names, apparently they've just figured out some
Speaker 6:  turn in the system here that no one else has figured out or is willing to
Speaker 6:  do or something. And it's just very strange to me, like somebody
Speaker 6:  Adam Macer should be able to just turn the dial to full TikTok
Speaker 6:  and they should have just known how to do this by now and yet they
Speaker 6:  can't.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. I mean, have you used Instagram reels? Like, it's awesome. Sometimes
Speaker 9:  I'll get stuff that I like, but sometimes it'll show me like something absolutely
Speaker 9:  horrible that makes me never want to open that app again. And TikTok has
Speaker 9:  that problem much less,
Speaker 6:  I will say YouTube is the one that really gets me. YouTube is the, is the
Speaker 6:  one that I hate the most and frustrates me the most because YouTube,
Speaker 6:  no service on the internet has as much
Speaker 6:  good declarative information about what I want than
Speaker 6:  YouTube. I have clicked on so many things on YouTube on purpose
Speaker 6:  for 15 years. I have been like, I would like to watch this video for
Speaker 6:  20 minutes, like it should have my interests nailed. And
Speaker 6:  like YouTube music is actually very good as a result of that because you
Speaker 6:  turn on YouTube music and it just looks at everything you've ever watched
Speaker 6:  and listened to on YouTube before and suddenly starts giving you recommendations.
Speaker 6:  So the, like the Cold Start problem there is solved and it's awesome
Speaker 6:  and yet shorts is nonsense. Like it doesn't make any sense to me that it's
Speaker 6:  like you YouTube knows me or should know me better than
Speaker 6:  any service on the internet and it cannot figure out which short to
Speaker 6:  recommend to me. And like, and TikTok is just like, do you wanna watch New
Speaker 6:  Girl Clips? And I'm like, sure, I'll watch New Girl Clips. Like, great, let's
Speaker 6:  do it. YouTube cannot do that. And it drives me nuts.
Speaker 9:  And Eddie, Eddie, I wanna know what you think about this, but I, I think
Speaker 9:  that the saying goodbye to my Chinese spy taps into
Speaker 9:  my personal conspiracy theory about TikTok that I've always had, which is
Speaker 9:  that, and also about a lot of AI things is that it's not ai, it's just a
Speaker 9:  guy named Al. And that there's a lot more human curation behind the scenes.
Speaker 9:  And that's why it's so good is because you're kind of tapping into these
Speaker 9:  cues of content and there's just someone saying, oh yeah, that's a good video.
Speaker 9:  I'll put it at the top. And that's why you keep getting good videos. That's,
Speaker 9:  that's my guess. And I, whatever it
Speaker 9:  is, it would be great if someone else could figure it out because someone
Speaker 9:  needs to know that I want to see 1980s car ads and that's
Speaker 9:  the only thing I wanna see. And If you just show me that I'll never close
Speaker 9:  the app ever again. But Eddie, what do you think?
Speaker 10:  I unfortunately cannot speak to the actual algorithmic changes here. I know
Speaker 10:  that for a long time, TikTok did really push to be sort of the
Speaker 10:  shiny happy place on the internet, which sometimes produce weird, very
Speaker 10:  bad effects. Like it would demote content from people who seemed likely
Speaker 10:  to be bullied, which was say LGBT people.
Speaker 10:  But it's possible that it's just optimizing for a different metric than
Speaker 10:  say Instagram or which is constantly dialing up and down
Speaker 10:  things like political content and news and can't seem to figure out what
Speaker 10:  it's going for. At least that's meta in general. So I
Speaker 10:  can't tell if it's that it would be a, it's badly tuned or if it's tuned
Speaker 10:  in a way that has sort of different business logic
Speaker 10:  and that just produces less of a certain thing or possibly that it's the
Speaker 10:  user base itself ended up producing a thing and the
Speaker 10:  network effects kind of snowballed that.
Speaker 6:  I do think there's something to that last part in particular that I think
Speaker 6:  TikTok got kind of a last mover advantage that
Speaker 6:  by, by being able to just show up from scratch and build something,
Speaker 6:  especially in kind of the, like it, it blew up in the
Speaker 6:  US especially during the pandemic when everything was weird and everybody
Speaker 6:  just wanted like an escape and dance challenges suddenly made sense that
Speaker 6:  I think in the same way that If you had just like in 2019 and
Speaker 6:  2020 just flooded Instagram with dance challenges, a lot of people actually
Speaker 6:  would've hated it. But on TikTok, because it was new and different and
Speaker 6:  people hadn't really experienced it yet it, it felt good.
Speaker 6:  And So I think like to some extent on Instagram and on other places,
Speaker 6:  you're, you're trying to like, you have to unlearn some things before
Speaker 6:  you can relearn some things, whereas TikTok just got to show up and do things
Speaker 6:  differently. And I think that actually really worked to its benefit.
Speaker 6:  But then again, I keep coming back to this idea that everyone has decided
Speaker 6:  that TikTok is the best at it. So just go do that. Like just piss
Speaker 6:  off all the Instagram users for three days and then they will decide that
Speaker 6:  they love it because everybody hates reels and the only thing anybody says
Speaker 6:  about reels is that it is just old tiktoks. And so it's like you're, you
Speaker 6:  don't have anything to lose, just throw the thing away and make it TikTok
Speaker 6:  and it'll probably work.
Speaker 9:  Throwing out the rule book had had some advantages and I think like a
Speaker 9:  lot of people during the pandemic, I opened up TikTok, I was kind of bored
Speaker 9:  and it immediately diagnosed me with a DH adhd, you know, waving an app.
Speaker 9:  It should not do, it's bad, it should not, no, that's, that's not diagnose
Speaker 9:  medical conditions like that. It was correct
Speaker 9:  and Instagram reels doesn't really do that and I'm just like, you
Speaker 9:  could probably do a little bit more to, to figure out who your users are.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, you have enough data.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's just, it's just sitting there. So okay, we should talk about one
Speaker 6:  other possible TikTok outcome before we fully throw up our
Speaker 6:  hands and just wait for somebody to tell us what's happening, which is the
Speaker 6:  Elon Musk of it all. Richard, can you, can you make this make sense to me?
Speaker 6:  There, there has been some sort of loose reporting that maybe what'll
Speaker 6:  happen is Elon Musk will save TikTok.
Speaker 9:  Well, in one of the possibilities that that you know, Addie has mentioned
Speaker 9:  is that by dance could divest, that they could own less of TikTok.
Speaker 9:  So someone would need to own more, someone who has a lot of money and who
Speaker 9:  can get a lot of money because TikTok is unquestionably worth a lot.
Speaker 9:  So who can get a lot of money in a hurry to buy a social media site.
Speaker 9:  Elon Musk, who is much loved in China, Elon Musk,
Speaker 9:  who might be able to be influenced by the Chinese government because he needs
Speaker 9:  to sell cars in the country and they control that and also the resources
Speaker 9:  in the country to make those cars. Elon Musk
Speaker 9:  Fitz a lot, I mean I don't know if he checks all of the boxes, but he does
Speaker 9:  check a lot of them.
Speaker 10:  Also the box of being tied specifically to the Trump administration, which
Speaker 10:  has made China hawkishness a big deal.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's as close as you can come to selling part of your company to
Speaker 6:  the United States as you can kind of get right now is selling it to Elon
Speaker 6:  Musk. Do we think this is a real possibility, Addie, If you were to
Speaker 6:  like handicap this on the list of possible outcomes, do you think this is
Speaker 6:  like X absorbs TikTok is a, is a real thing that might
Speaker 6:  happen?
Speaker 10:  I might phrase it as TikTok absorbs X, but Sure, I think it's
Speaker 10:  not impossible. It it seems like much,
Speaker 6:  You know, he'd rename it X though. He'd be, it would be called like X video
Speaker 6:  and everybody would be like, oh, I'm an X video now.
Speaker 10:  I mean once all the porn sites get banned, X videos will be up for sale
Speaker 10:  again. Yeah, no, I think that for a while there
Speaker 10:  was a lot of noise about how the Chinese government absolutely was going
Speaker 10:  to refuse, but given all the reports now it certainly doesn't seem
Speaker 10:  impossible.
Speaker 6:  It seems like a terrible idea. Like I hate the idea that this might happen,
Speaker 6:  which makes it potentially likely that it's going to happen. Yeah, like Richard
Speaker 6:  to your point, no, like I, I think one of the, the two
Speaker 6:  things really that I have seen as, as total impediments to this are TikTok
Speaker 6:  is enormously expensive and China is not interested in
Speaker 6:  selling. And I do think it's possible that Elon Musk is the only person capable
Speaker 6:  of solving both of those problems. He has clearly an infinite ability to
Speaker 6:  raise money and also, like you were just
Speaker 6:  explaining is, is as palatable to the Chinese government as any person in
Speaker 6:  the United States for a variety of reasons.
Speaker 6:  It like, it, it fits, I don't like it, but it kind of fits.
Speaker 9:  Well I guess I'll see you guys on Seattle. Shoot,
Speaker 10:  I'm interested in it because I think it will be the absolute
Speaker 10:  purest test of inertia you could possibly devise
Speaker 10:  that TikTok is just so notoriously moderated
Speaker 10:  that is the thing that defines it. And it also, it is a place
Speaker 10:  that tends to try to at least I think, focus on positivity
Speaker 10:  ostensibly that is the absolute opposite of what Elon Musk is interested
Speaker 10:  in. It is a thing that is notably full of silos and
Speaker 10:  you're trying to just split people up into the perfect
Speaker 10:  thing for them as much as possible. And X has now become a thing that just
Speaker 10:  feeds you Elon tweets, they're just kind of polar
Speaker 10:  opposites to each other. And it seems to be not really just a business decision
Speaker 10:  on Musk's part, it's a thing that he just genuinely thinks social media
Speaker 10:  should be. And I'm very curious how the TikTok community would react to
Speaker 10:  that.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean I I, I keep coming back to, I, I made the, the ship of theses
Speaker 6:  comparison on Tuesday's show too, but there, there is to me
Speaker 6:  this real thing where like there is no version of TikTok that
Speaker 6:  gets divested that still to me feels like TikTok
Speaker 6:  and, and so it's like the upside is it, it would continue to be TikTok, it
Speaker 6:  would have a lot of users, it might be called X videos, but it,
Speaker 6:  it would, the people wouldn't have to go somewhere else. And like you
Speaker 6:  said, that's a very powerful thing, but like,
Speaker 6:  I don't know, it turns out people are willing to go somewhere else. The number
Speaker 6:  of people who just randomly signed up for a, an app with
Speaker 6:  literally a Chinese name in the American app store, like
Speaker 6:  it, it actually turns out maybe the inertia is not nearly as strong as anybody
Speaker 6:  thought that when people need somewhere to go, they'll go,
Speaker 10:  I don't wanna overdetermine that given just how big TikTok is. And of course
Speaker 10:  some people are going to jump ship, but I do. Yeah, it does
Speaker 10:  seem like other platforms say x have meaningfully lost some number of
Speaker 10:  users and that that definitely can happen.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean it, it is, I think the, the X thing is actually a really interesting
Speaker 6:  comparison there because like we, we've talked about this a lot where there
Speaker 6:  was the, there was the big boom on Mastodon that slowed down and then there
Speaker 6:  was the big boom on threads that continues to happen. But
Speaker 6:  now threads is weird and there's now there's been a big boom on Blue Sky
Speaker 6:  and Blue Sky is like meaningful and and large now, but is still
Speaker 6:  a tiny fraction of the size of threads, which is still a fraction of the
Speaker 6:  size of X. And so maybe for Elon Musk what you've learned is,
Speaker 6:  I you you can weather these storms because they end up being really vocal
Speaker 6:  and maybe not that sticky over time.
Speaker 9:  I, I think one thing that gets really tricky there is what happens to cap
Speaker 9:  cut in really any of these scenarios because in a way that's maybe
Speaker 9:  different from all other kinds of social platforms, the way
Speaker 9:  that you make the videos really influences the videos that are on the platform
Speaker 9:  and the people who want to use the app and having an a video editor that
Speaker 9:  a lot of people like to use and find easy to use to make really high quality
Speaker 9:  videos has been a huge part of tiktoks appeal.
Speaker 9:  So that's a kind of just another question that has to be asked. And in the,
Speaker 9:  in the case of something like X or something like that, that's, that's not
Speaker 9:  really the issue. You, you everyone can type into the box the same way that
Speaker 9:  they did before, but if something happens to the editor
Speaker 9:  just as much as the algorithm, that's a problem.
Speaker 6:  Right. And on the flip side, it that combination of things might make
Speaker 6:  TikTok harder to copy than anything else. Like you,
Speaker 6:  you could sort of peel away each of the pieces that makes it work,
Speaker 6:  but as long as it has that collection of things, it's, it's gonna be
Speaker 6:  harder to copy TikTok than it is to just like in theory all you need is a
Speaker 6:  bunch of people in text boxes and you can beat X at its own game. Like
Speaker 6:  that's essentially what Threads has been trying to do. TikTok has
Speaker 6:  a larger collection of things that are hard to beat.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, there are also just sort of symbiotic
Speaker 10:  businesses like they've tried to move into book publishing based on the
Speaker 10:  popularity of book talk, which is not like a killer app, it's not
Speaker 10:  going to destroy it but it does mean there's just a lot of stuff going on
Speaker 10:  here
Speaker 6:  For sure. Alright, well this is like
Speaker 6:  God help us, we're gonna do this again next week I'm sure, but be before
Speaker 6:  we, before we go to a break adding, can we talk about the other Supreme Court
Speaker 6:  thing that happened this week? We can, you spent I would say an unusual amount
Speaker 6:  of your week listening to Supreme Court live streams like this is not like
Speaker 6:  a normal thing you spend most of your time doing.
Speaker 10:  The court is definitely Sunday before a group project mode right now.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So okay so it was, this was the the porn trial. Can you explain what's
Speaker 6:  going on here?
Speaker 10:  Alright, so this is the trial called Free Speech Coalition v Paxton
Speaker 10:  and the idea is that Texas passed this
Speaker 10:  law that's very similar to a lot of other state laws that says that if a
Speaker 10:  site has a more than a third adult content,
Speaker 10:  then it needs to age gate its platform in a way that is
Speaker 10:  more rigorous than like clicking a box that says I'm 18. And in
Speaker 10:  Texas's case it also has to put up these warnings that
Speaker 10:  porn destroys your health, which is not scientifically
Speaker 10:  proven that causes addiction and harms minors and all that.
Speaker 10:  That's
Speaker 6:  Just a thing you can say If you want to I guess. Sure.
Speaker 10:  So this was then taken up to the court, a district court blocked
Speaker 10:  it said look, there are all kinds of problems with making people hand over
Speaker 10:  identifying information before they go and look at sensitive
Speaker 10:  content, especially during a period where Texas is say
Speaker 10:  cracking down on LGBT people and then the
Speaker 10:  fifth circuit, which is where law goes to die, said, no this
Speaker 10:  is fine. We're gonna apply just the lowest standard for considering
Speaker 10:  speech, not literally the lowest standard but an unusually low standard
Speaker 10:  for considering whether this is going to chill speech,
Speaker 10:  which means okay we're good, let this happen. It happened
Speaker 10:  and then after that it is gone to the Supreme Court. It was
Speaker 10:  argued yesterday, it is probably not even remotely close to over
Speaker 10:  but we got a pretty broad section of questions about
Speaker 10:  it.
Speaker 6:  So what is the free speech argument here? I think age verification is the
Speaker 6:  kind of thing that has come up a bunch of different times in a bunch of different,
Speaker 6:  you know, cases around the the legal world recently. But why
Speaker 6:  is this a free speech debate at all? So
Speaker 10:  This has come up a few times. It has primarily during the
Speaker 10:  late nineties and early aughts, which is that If
Speaker 10:  you put a burden on people to access
Speaker 10:  something that is speech related, that burden has to have a compelling interest
Speaker 10:  and it has to be sort of the, the thing that's really
Speaker 10:  the best solution that there can't be a sort of more narrow,
Speaker 10:  less onerous system. And a lot lot of
Speaker 10:  the argument for making age verification
Speaker 10:  unconstitutional is first of all it's just a barrier to access speech
Speaker 10:  for children and adults alike. It adds this process to get
Speaker 10:  to something that is legal and that is protected by the First Amendment.
Speaker 10:  The other issue is there really has never been an age verification
Speaker 10:  system that is both rigorous enough that it's not trivial to
Speaker 10:  circumvent and not producing something that creates
Speaker 10:  a pretty significant security and privacy risk. Right? So
Speaker 6:  I feel like the one end of that spectrum is like the the things on the alcohol
Speaker 6:  webpage where they're just like enter your birthday and you just enter like
Speaker 6:  I was born in 1931 and it's like terrific and lets you in,
Speaker 6:  it's like we have, we have satisfied something here but we're not actually
Speaker 6:  accomplishing anything all the way to the flip side of like you can make
Speaker 6:  these things very secure but then they cause all kinds of other problems,
Speaker 10:  Right? The sort of worst case scenario is you put your
Speaker 10:  government issued ID into a system and it permanently
Speaker 10:  links you with a something that you don't want people to see and then a
Speaker 6:  List of all the porn you watch, you mean? Yeah.
Speaker 10:  And then everything gets hacked and then the exact details of
Speaker 10:  your viewing of adult video is out there for everyone to see. This is not
Speaker 10:  how most age verification systems work at this point. They have added in
Speaker 10:  more safeguards but we still don't have
Speaker 10:  a really great solution. And anyway, back to
Speaker 10:  20 years ago, the thing they determined at that point was the internet as
Speaker 10:  it stands then you just, you have the better
Speaker 10:  option of content filtering that it is possible for you to
Speaker 10:  prevent children from accessing porn on your computer by
Speaker 10:  putting a filter on it. And that means we are not going to go
Speaker 10:  this extra higher step of burdening everybody including adults
Speaker 10:  with a system that creates privacy and security risks and now it's been
Speaker 10:  20 years and we're considering this again.
Speaker 6:  So is the question now, does that still
Speaker 6:  work? Like is that still the right approach, the content filtering thing?
Speaker 6:  Like is that, is that again the question, is that a better way the,
Speaker 10:  The question before the Supreme Court at this point was actually what standard
Speaker 10:  do you apply to evaluate whether this chill speech which
Speaker 10:  is known as scrutiny, it's
Speaker 6:  One of those of those where they're like, we're not even arguing the case,
Speaker 6:  we're just arguing the case about the case and it's just like we're just
Speaker 6:  gonna lawyer it all the way down.
Speaker 10:  It's kind of a little bit in between, which is that? Yeah, that's the question
Speaker 10:  is whether we send this back and say you have to decide this based on
Speaker 10:  a different standard. But there were also a lot of questions that were about
Speaker 10:  the broader issue of, alright well has the internet changed?
Speaker 10:  Do has age verification changed? Is there a compelling enough
Speaker 10:  interest in protecting children from adult content that
Speaker 10:  we should reconsider this? It was, it was a hearing that
Speaker 10:  I think doesn't necessarily provide a clear picture of what's gonna happen
Speaker 10:  next.
Speaker 6:  Well that sounds like every tech related hearing anyone has had in the
Speaker 6:  last several years. So I'm glad we're making a lot of progress in just kind
Speaker 6:  of arguing around the edges without actually talking about the real things
Speaker 6:  going on for people
Speaker 10:  With the exception of TikTok, which after that everyone was like, oh TikTok,
Speaker 10:  TikTok is screwed.
Speaker 6:  That's fair. That is, that is very fair. So you actually make
Speaker 6:  the case that these two cases are somewhat connected to each other that you
Speaker 6:  can kind of draw a line between the, the porn hub hearing and the TikTok
Speaker 6:  hearing. Can you, can you explain the connection there?
Speaker 10:  I think this is not necessarily the biggest issue in either of these, but
Speaker 10:  in both cases what you're doing is pitting two government interests
Speaker 10:  against each other. In TikTok you've got, there is this national security
Speaker 10:  risk, the Chinese government could harvest everybody's data
Speaker 10:  or push covert propaganda and we're going to pit this
Speaker 10:  against the speech rights of a company that operates
Speaker 10:  in the United States and a bunch of people who are using that platform for
Speaker 10:  speech. So it's national security versus speech.
Speaker 10:  Then in FSCV Paxton you've got
Speaker 10:  this issue of, alright, there is a compelling state interest in protecting
Speaker 10:  miners. If you run a store, you can't sell
Speaker 10:  Playboy to a minor in like a brick and mortar outlet.
Speaker 10:  Okay, we're gonna try to apply the same thing to the internet because there
Speaker 10:  is just such a clear risk for minors accessing
Speaker 10:  adult content and we're gonna weigh that against everybody
Speaker 10:  else's rights.
Speaker 6:  As we've talked about so many times in this show, we're at a moment politically
Speaker 6:  where it feels like If you want to get any kind of broad agreement
Speaker 6:  about technology, you have to either yell about children or yell about China.
Speaker 6:  And it's very funny that we are just kind of simultaneously doing both of
Speaker 6:  those things in the Supreme Court right now. It just feels like we've, we've
Speaker 6:  hit a nexus of something.
Speaker 10:  Children in the national security are Yeah, clear the classic
Speaker 10:  we are going to change speech law. Yeah, I think we're also just at a moment
Speaker 10:  where the First amendment has just produced a lot of side effects that make
Speaker 10:  everybody mad and a lot of them are legitimately really
Speaker 10:  frustrating. And so there's this sort of, if the law you
Speaker 10:  made led you here what uses the law idea going around,
Speaker 10:  right?
Speaker 6:  And and yeah, and it is, I mean and and you've, you've written about this
Speaker 6:  a few times that the, the question underneath all of it is like
Speaker 6:  how important is the first amendment right? And it's like are we, are we
Speaker 6:  ready to start tearing it down piece by piece in
Speaker 6:  order to solve some of these other problems or is the first amendment worth
Speaker 6:  these other problems?
Speaker 10:  And we're looking at Europe right now, which is passing a bunch of tech
Speaker 10:  regulation and obviously has a different speech framework and there are
Speaker 10:  things there that I think that I would say have not worked out great
Speaker 10:  but we're also looking at this and saying the internet could be different
Speaker 10:  and I think there are people for whom that's appealing
Speaker 6:  Fair. So I think we have a pretty clear sense of how
Speaker 6:  the Supreme Court was leaning with the TikTok stuff. We're still infuriatingly
Speaker 6:  waiting on them to issue some actual information. But I feel like everybody
Speaker 6:  came outta that hearing pretty aligned on where it seemed like the,
Speaker 6:  the winds were blowing. What's your sense with the the PornHub stuff?
Speaker 10:  I really don't know. We talked to several people and they were like, we
Speaker 10:  really don't necessarily know. Interesting. I do think that, so one of
Speaker 10:  the things that came out of this was this quote everybody kind of dunked
Speaker 10:  on, which was that Justice Alito says alright so one of the covered
Speaker 10:  companies here is PornHub, right? Or one of the covered platforms. Alright
Speaker 10:  so If you go on PornHub, do you have essays on there? Do you have
Speaker 10:  the equivalent of Gore Vidal and William F. Buckley Jr. And everyone was
Speaker 10:  like, Alito, what are you doing? Do you have any idea how PornHub works?
Speaker 10:  And I think that was actually, I think that's the wrong read of it.
Speaker 10:  I think that maybe I am wrong on this but I don't think really for a minute
Speaker 10:  that he genuinely thinks this thing is
Speaker 10:  has a bunch of intellectual value and I think there was just this really
Speaker 10:  running through line of we are going to prove that anything that is
Speaker 10:  porn on the internet is worthless and that it should not have speech protections.
Speaker 10:  It is obviously just harmful, harmful to kids. You're making this argument
Speaker 10:  that it's going to hurt sexual health sites or
Speaker 10:  educational content or things that aren't artistic and no
Speaker 10:  we're saying no it doesn't have Gore. Al
Speaker 6:  I read PornHub for the articles is really, it's like that was your, you put
Speaker 6:  that in in one of the stories and it is the best sentence that has been on
Speaker 6:  the verse.com this week. I was very proud of that moment.
Speaker 10:  And there is they, the lawyer did raise the point that there is like sexual
Speaker 10:  health content. There is funnily enough a woman whose deal is that she just
Speaker 10:  does video essays and like teaches things and
Speaker 10:  makes money off it.
Speaker 6:  Apparently the rev share on PornHub is very good.
Speaker 10:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  The economics, maybe that's where TikTok will go. Go, go do that.
Speaker 6:  pornhub.com/tiktok make it happen. So this could do it.
Speaker 6:  Richard, what do you think about PornHub just in general? What are your
Speaker 6:  thoughts?
Speaker 9:  I'm gonna talk about free speech and an app that you can use
Speaker 9:  where you can see what it's like without the first amendment. It's called
Speaker 9:  Yahoo Shoe. You should try it out.
Speaker 9:  A lot of people on there who can do can talk to you about the Constitution,
Speaker 9:  why they don't use it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, say hello to your Chinese spy while you're there. Alright, we gotta
Speaker 6:  take one more break. Addie, thank you for joining us Richard. We're gonna
Speaker 6:  come back and we're gonna blow through some news because holy God is there
Speaker 6:  a lot going on this week. We'll be right back.
Speaker 6:  All right, we're back. There's more policy stuff. Let me just
Speaker 6:  read you some headlines. Joe Biden signs, executive orders speed AI data
Speaker 6:  center reconstruction, US finalizes rule to effectively ban
Speaker 6:  Chinese vehicles, FTCs Sues John Deere, which is not a sentence I expected
Speaker 6:  to read this week. There's some DJ I stuff
Speaker 6:  and controversy going on. I don't wanna talk about policy and politics anymore.
Speaker 6:  There's like, there's a lot of this to come for the next few weeks.
Speaker 6:  Richard, do you care about any of that at this moment or can we just like
Speaker 6:  move on to more fun gadgety things? Remember drones just, just saying remember
Speaker 6:  drones, remember drones? I feel the same way about drones in 3D printers
Speaker 6:  where like for years everybody was like, everybody's gonna have one of these.
Speaker 6:  And it's like, probably not though. Seems unlikely. I was at CES and there
Speaker 6:  were a bunch of people who were like, it's time for the the second coming
Speaker 6:  of the at-home 3D printer for mainstream users. And I was like, okay,
Speaker 6:  best of luck with that friends. And they're, the thing they were showing
Speaker 6:  off was like six feet tall and like $4,000 and I was like,
Speaker 6:  I don't think this is the one y'all. But anyway, all right, let's talk about
Speaker 6:  Sonos because I actually think in the, in the gadget world,
Speaker 6:  this was probably the biggest and both most
Speaker 6:  surprising and most unsurprising thing that happened this week. What happened
Speaker 6:  this week? Richard,
Speaker 9:  Their CEO stepped down and some other executives left
Speaker 6:  Full house cleaning at Sonos. Basically. Yeah, like
Speaker 9:  Yeah, it turns out that releasing an app update that doesn't work when your
Speaker 9:  whole thing is giving people a system that works when they want it to work
Speaker 9:  is bad and means that a lot of the leaders of your company have to leave.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So, okay, so Patrick Spence, the CEO is out
Speaker 6:  Tom Conrad who is, I would argue one of the most sort of quietly
Speaker 6:  fascinating people in tech. He has just been like at every weird inflection
Speaker 6:  point in the tech industry over the years. Can I just quickly read you a
Speaker 6:  list of some of the places that Tom Conrad has worked over the years? Hit
Speaker 6:  me. He was at Pandora for 10 years in the middle of like
Speaker 6:  the crazy online music revolution. He was the VP of product at Snapchat.
Speaker 6:  He was the chief product officer at Quibi for all of qui
Speaker 6:  B's life. Yeah, quibi, everybody's favorite number one streaming service
Speaker 6:  and now was the director of the board at Sonos for a
Speaker 6:  while and is now the interim CEO. But according to like the
Speaker 6:  memos we've seen and the changes that are being made sure seems like he is
Speaker 6:  not acting like an interim CEO. So Tom Conrad, just like
Speaker 6:  guy around the tech industry when weird things are happening. Very interesting.
Speaker 6:  Real Jeff
Speaker 9:  Teague of tech execs.
Speaker 6:  It's exactly right. Who knows if he's as good a podcaster as
Speaker 6:  Jeff Teague though Tom Conrad, If you ever wanna come to The Vergecast and
Speaker 6:  tell war stories about your time in the NBA, let us know we're ready.
Speaker 6:  But yeah, so the, the chief product officer also leaving, I think the chief
Speaker 6:  commercial officer I believe was her title, also leaving the company
Speaker 6:  Big huge changes at Sonos.
Speaker 6:  This feels both like maybe the right thing given what
Speaker 6:  has happened to Sonos, but also like not a good sign that
Speaker 6:  this company is like, it's one thing to say we made a mistake. I think
Speaker 6:  it's, it's pretty obvious now that Sonos got kind of way out over its skis.
Speaker 6:  They were like, we need new things to do and new ways to make money as a
Speaker 6:  public company. So they decided to make headphones and they were like, we're
Speaker 6:  gonna get into the TV space and had all these big ideas about expansions
Speaker 6:  when actually what they should have done is just kept making really good
Speaker 6:  speakers that people liked. And you can see how
Speaker 6:  the next thing to do is kind of retrench, but I think in many cases
Speaker 6:  you can do that without turning over
Speaker 6:  all of the leadership of your company. And this just seems
Speaker 6:  like not a great sign for what is happening and what
Speaker 6:  is maybe to come from Sonos at this point.
Speaker 9:  It feels like it usually doesn't work out well. But yeah, so they, they had
Speaker 9:  to get those headphones out, just had to release these Sonos the headphones,
Speaker 9:  so they kinda had to change all of their technology. And I mean, as I understand,
Speaker 9:  I'm one of the few people I think who doesn't own a Sonos system, but it's
Speaker 9:  always seemed like Sono sells multi-room audio that costs a little too much,
Speaker 9:  but it works. Yeah. Is that that? No,
Speaker 6:  I think that's exactly right. And for years it was the only thing like it
Speaker 6:  that it was like, it was, it was too expensive probably by,
Speaker 6:  I don't know, 40 or 50%, right? It was like you could get, you could get
Speaker 6:  a speaker that sounded just as good for somewhere in the range of half
Speaker 6:  the price, but then If you wanted a bunch of them and you wanted it to make
Speaker 6:  sense and work with the apps that you used, there just wasn't anything like
Speaker 6:  it. And then Google started building a system like it and then they got
Speaker 6:  into that whole lawsuit about it and you know, Amazon's audio systems got
Speaker 6:  better and then you, you can just like cast audio around and like Bluetooth
Speaker 6:  speakers work fine. And so we're, we're at a point now where the idea
Speaker 6:  of w Sonos is basic thing I think is a
Speaker 6:  little less special than it once was. But still
Speaker 6:  until this app fiasco Sonos was still better at this than everybody else.
Speaker 6:  And it feels like over the last 12 months in,
Speaker 6:  in order to ship headphones that I never, ever hear anyone talk about and
Speaker 6:  have never once seen in the wild, just burned all
Speaker 6:  of its goodwill. And I think I'm at the point now where like I, I wouldn't
Speaker 6:  consider Sonos to be the thing that just works, even though like my SOO system
Speaker 6:  still works great, I have zero problems with it. I never used the Sonos app,
Speaker 6:  which is I think part of it, but like it
Speaker 6:  we're sort of at a point both where with all this product stuff and now with
Speaker 6:  all of this change, it's like I Sonos feels unstable like
Speaker 6:  existentially in a way that I think is sometimes very hard to come back
Speaker 6:  from. I
Speaker 9:  I think that the takeaway that I'm, I'm getting from this is that that
Speaker 9:  reputation is something that's, that's worth a lot to people. That that's
Speaker 9:  what people were paying for is that they, they knew Sonos was the one that
Speaker 9:  they could buy and it would probably work pretty well and if it didn't work,
Speaker 9:  you know, you could probably be get somebody to make it work for you. And
Speaker 9:  so of these other tech companies, yeah, I mean, okay, so Google's getting
Speaker 9:  into Multiroom audio, apple is sort of in in
Speaker 9:  speakers, but neither of them were very serious about it. It's just a side
Speaker 9:  business for them. Person Sonos, it's their business. They care, they wanna
Speaker 9:  make it, they wanna make the experience good for you. But then they, they
Speaker 9:  it, it was the one thing, it was the one thing that they had that their competitors
Speaker 9:  really couldn't buy even with all of their tech billions and they seem
Speaker 9:  to have squandered it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I I I completely agree and I think it's, it's
Speaker 6:  maybe not impossible to get it back, but it's gonna take a lot of work and
Speaker 6:  there are a lot of like long time Sonos users. One of the things that
Speaker 6:  Sonos had going for it, like the company's greatest problem was
Speaker 6:  nobody needed to upgrade their Sonos stuff because it was so good. And I
Speaker 6:  think there are a lot of people now who are feeling pretty burned by that
Speaker 6:  relationship and getting that back is gonna be a real challenge.
Speaker 6:  Anyway, this is a lightning round as you can tell already. We're going
Speaker 6:  very quickly through this. Let's do a few more. We got some information
Speaker 6:  about the, the supposed slim iPhone 17,
Speaker 6:  which might be called the iPhone 17 air. Richard, I hate this.
Speaker 6:  I hate it. That's it, that's all I have to tell you.
Speaker 9:  Speaking of companies that are very successful and need to build a new product
Speaker 9:  for some reason to sell something else, here comes a slim iPhone that you
Speaker 9:  didn't ask for. I think some of the rumors have have been that this could
Speaker 9:  replace the, the plus model that those big but still
Speaker 9:  with the lower specs. So I think based on the rumors that we've heard is
Speaker 9:  that this is something that would be, have a design that looks a lot different
Speaker 9:  than the current iPhone than, you know, the regular iPhones and iPhone pros.
Speaker 9:  It maybe wouldn't have quite as high of the specs as the pro,
Speaker 9:  but it would probably be more expensive. It'll be very slim when you, when
Speaker 9:  you take it outta your pocket and you're somewhere people will know you've
Speaker 9:  got the, the iPhone air. If that's, if that's the name,
Speaker 9:  it's something that they can do. It's, it's something new. And and I think
Speaker 9:  that's a, a real issue for Apple and for really these other
Speaker 9:  companies and also Samsung who is rumored to be about to debut a slim phone
Speaker 9:  as well because of course if I, if Apple has one, so will Samsung,
Speaker 9:  how do you sell an iPhone when everyone has an iPhone and the iPhone that
Speaker 9:  they have is pretty good. Apple intelligence
Speaker 6:  platform. So you can just like Google a show and click on it on Google and
Speaker 6:  start watching the show, which I think is a
Speaker 9:  And most that happens a surprising amount with things that I want to watch.
Speaker 9:  It turns out they're on Tubby just, they're like, yeah, you could watch it
Speaker 9:  for free right now. Oh yeah, thanks.
Speaker 6:  Toy's Library. If you, If you think kind of like
Speaker 6:  B list shows and Below Tuby has as good a library
Speaker 6:  as anybody and especially like if, If you really love like
Speaker 6:  three generations ago, like the, the shows our parents grew up watching
Speaker 6:  are like all over Tuby. They're,
Speaker 9:  They're there the ones that you think are nowhere, turns out they have them.
Speaker 9:  There was this movie that I saw the other day, baby Assassins, it's on Tub
Speaker 9:  Beat. It's great Japanese movie If you love action. Good. I
Speaker 9:  I did not watch it on Tub Beat, but it is there.
Speaker 6:  Totally. And I should say I actually, I got one thing wrong. You
Speaker 6:  will need an account to watch the Super Bowl on Tubi. I just, I I
Speaker 6:  just caught this looking this up right now. Okay. Which is very interesting
Speaker 6:  because part of Tub B's whole thing is that you don't need an account. And
Speaker 6:  we talked about this a a little bit in a thing we're doing on The Vergecast
Speaker 6:  on Tuesday about venue, but Fox, which owns Tubi
Speaker 6:  doesn't have a like premium streaming service of its own. And
Speaker 6:  one very compelling thing to do when you have the Super Bowl is try and use
Speaker 6:  it to get people to sign up for your streaming service because it is the
Speaker 6:  Super Bowl and that's a very good thing to do. So Fox
Speaker 6:  doesn't have that move. There's no like Fox Plus that they can try to get
Speaker 6:  you to pay 10 bucks for and then forget about and keep doing like Comcast
Speaker 6:  can do with NBC and Peacock or CBS can do with
Speaker 6:  Paramount Plus. So Tubi is the move, but they can't charge you for Tubi.
Speaker 6:  So this is clearly just a, like they're making a big play just to get people
Speaker 6:  into this ecosystem, which is really
Speaker 9:  Well the last time Fox had the Super Bowl they ran an ad where Tubi took
Speaker 9:  over the stream and people it like ripped over the, over the screen
Speaker 9:  and made it seem like you were watching Tubi instead of watching the Super
Speaker 9:  Bowl. Oh
Speaker 6:  That's right. That's the one where like it was whole thing, the interface
Speaker 6:  came up right and everybody was like, what is suddenly controlling my smart
Speaker 6:  tv?
Speaker 9:  Yes.
Speaker 6:  Such a good idea.
Speaker 9:  So they really are using this to, to promote tuby and it's,
Speaker 9:  it's there of course you could use an antenna, which you have I'm
Speaker 9:  sure, I'm sure you do. I'm sure everyone has an antenna to watch free tv,
Speaker 9:  but If you don't then there's tuby.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, a antennas are great. I didn't get one for a very long
Speaker 6:  time 'cause I was like, this is probably complicated. Turns out it's not.
Speaker 6:  You can buy on on Amazon and set it up in like a minute and a half and it's
Speaker 6:  a super good idea and it works way better than you think. It's very ugly
Speaker 6:  and you have to stick it to your window most of the time. But works super
Speaker 6:  well. But also, yeah, I think it's gonna be really interesting to see how
Speaker 6:  two B does with this because I'm willing to bet that
Speaker 6:  to be a, a service that is not necessarily known for having like
Speaker 6:  destination appointment viewing is gonna have
Speaker 6:  some, some traffic spikes that it has never really reckoned with before
Speaker 6:  and during that, during the Super Bowl is a bold strategy.
Speaker 6:  So we'll see. Alright, couple more that we should get to explain to
Speaker 6:  me what's going on with Drake. I have, I I confess to you, I have avoided
Speaker 6:  following this thing because it's just a bunch of shenanigans,
Speaker 6:  but there were new shenanigans this week. What is Drake doing now?
Speaker 9:  So you may have heard that Kendrick Lamar made a song about Drake last year
Speaker 9:  in which he accused him of some things that you probably
Speaker 9:  don't want to be accused of. Kendrick
Speaker 6:  Lamar won the beef, right? Like we all agree that they were beefing and Kendrick
Speaker 6:  Lamar sort of resoundingly defeated Drake.
Speaker 9:  Well Kendrick Lamar was had a free concert in LA where he was dancing
Speaker 9:  on stage with NBA players as they all called Drake a pedophile. So yeah,
Speaker 9:  I think so I think that is
Speaker 6:  What winning looks like generally.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. By, by most definitions. Yeah. But Drake and Kendrick
Speaker 9:  Lamar are on the same label, universal Music Group and
Speaker 9:  Drake has turned his eye toward the label,
Speaker 9:  Spotify to some extent and others. And so he had filed this legal
Speaker 9:  petition a couple of months ago kind of looking for information, saying and
Speaker 9:  accusing the label of certain things that they were doing illegal things
Speaker 9:  to promote the, the Not Like Us song by Kendrick
Speaker 9:  Pay payola to DJs and people to put it on playlists using
Speaker 9:  bots to drive up the view numbers on YouTube and the streaming numbers on
Speaker 9:  Spotify. And so now he has, he pulled one legal petition
Speaker 9:  that was against UMG and Spotify and filed a federal lawsuit
Speaker 9:  against UMG saying that the song is defamatory number one,
Speaker 9:  that it's not true, the accusations in it are not true and
Speaker 9:  that Universal knows they're not true because otherwise they wouldn't be
Speaker 9:  in business with him or they could have just called him and asked him if
Speaker 9:  they're true, which, which he would say that they are not. That's
Speaker 6:  Quite a phone call. Like, Hey Kendrick's about to put out a song, we have
Speaker 6:  some questions for you.
Speaker 9:  And accusing them of doing all these things to promote it, claiming that
Speaker 9:  this was done to kind of affect their negotiations with him on his record
Speaker 9:  deal and to affect negotiations with Kendrick on his record deal and that
Speaker 9:  they would have have all of these things. But now, yeah, there is a, a lawsuit
Speaker 9:  in federal court over a rap beef saying that the song is defamatory, which
Speaker 9:  If you make a dis track about someone, it probably is defamatory. If it isn't,
Speaker 9:  you did it wrong.
Speaker 9:  But, you know, legally I don't know what what that means for, for the future
Speaker 9:  of this lawsuit. But I find it interesting that he's not, it's not like
Speaker 9:  he's suing Kendrick or anything he's suing specifically Universal, claiming
Speaker 9:  that they did all of these, these things that would be probably
Speaker 9:  illegal to promote the track. Also things that people believe labels do
Speaker 9:  to promote songs. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  The idea of like using bots to juice plays and payola and all that stuff
Speaker 6:  is like, those are the kinds of things that are kind of open secrets
Speaker 6:  in a lot of parts of the music industry. I I, I have no evidence on this
Speaker 6:  particular one or UMG or whatever, but like it is a thing that happens and
Speaker 6:  every people talk about it pretty openly as a thing that happens.
Speaker 9:  And that is, that is what Drake's lawsuit says. So I guess we're kind of
Speaker 9:  gonna see where that goes. But curiously, you know, he's not suing
Speaker 9:  Spotify or iHeartRadio who had been named in the previous kind of
Speaker 9:  thing. Things that he put out, or at least not yet. This is, this lawsuit
Speaker 9:  is just against his like
Speaker 6:  Interesting
Speaker 9:  Who he is still signed to.
Speaker 6:  I I would, I would ask you if this was like a Streisand effect thing where
Speaker 6:  all he was doing was making it bigger, but I feel like Not Like Us Totally,
Speaker 6:  pretty big does not need help. Yeah, that song that's on is platformed itself
Speaker 6:  pretty successfully, I would say. Alright, one
Speaker 6:  more and then we're gonna get outta here. Blue Origin,
Speaker 6:  which is Jeff Bezos's Rocket Company successfully
Speaker 6:  launched New Glen, it's it's big rocket. I think that was on,
Speaker 6:  is that today? Thursday?
Speaker 9:  Thursday? That was today. That was Thursday morning.
Speaker 6:  Super early this morning. Delayed two o'clock in the morning.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, Monday morning was the first attempt and but it has now launched and
Speaker 9:  parts of it went into orbit. This
Speaker 6:  Seems like a big deal, right? For a couple of reasons. One, because
Speaker 6:  this company has had a lot of money and a lot of, I
Speaker 6:  would say Amos and kind of false ish starts over the years.
Speaker 6:  They've been at this for like a decade, but then also because
Speaker 6:  it, it, if this continues Blue Origin becomes
Speaker 6:  real competition to SpaceX for kind of the first time. Like
Speaker 6:  SpaceX is still pretty far ahead in all of this and has been doing this for
Speaker 6:  a very long time and is very good at this. But the idea of just there being
Speaker 6:  another company meaningfully in this race seems
Speaker 6:  pretty interesting to me,
Speaker 9:  Particularly as they're trying to do the reusable rocket thing that SpaceX
Speaker 9:  does and that others don't yet even the ESA just started
Speaker 9:  launching a new rocket, but it doesn't have the reusable boosters and, and
Speaker 9:  stuff like that because that really helps you get the price down on the launches,
Speaker 9:  which is key to SpaceX's business model. And right
Speaker 9:  now for all of these companies, and there are a lot of companies that are
Speaker 9:  interested in launching stuff into Orbit, starlink,
Speaker 9:  SpaceX, starlink being one of them, but also many others including Jeff Bezos's
Speaker 9:  own Amazon and the Kuper satellite internet satellite constellation
Speaker 9:  that they're trying to build. You need to be able to launch stuff a lot and
Speaker 9:  to, to get it up there and having reusable rockets that work is a big part
Speaker 9:  of it. Doing work that they wanna do for NASA is a big part of having these
Speaker 9:  reusable rockets going to the moon as Elon Musk says that he wants
Speaker 9:  to go to Mars If you can get there, but you, you gotta
Speaker 9:  have it. And they have had so many delays. I think this was supposed to be
Speaker 9:  launched in 2020, but now it has launched. It mostly
Speaker 9:  worked. They didn't get the rocket returned, but I think that was, you know,
Speaker 9:  kind of a, a, a secondary goal and so they're gonna try that on future flights.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it again kind of illustrates how far behind they really
Speaker 6:  are, but also how much progress they've made that like, it, it's, I I
Speaker 6:  forget this occasionally and it's nice to be reminded that just launching
Speaker 6:  a rocket into space, it's very hard, quite
Speaker 6:  and kind of a big deal when you can do it from scratch. There's a lot
Speaker 6:  more to do. The, the landing thing is hard. SpaceX is out here like catching
Speaker 6:  it with chopsticks. Like there's a lot of work left to do to catch up to
Speaker 6:  what SpaceX is up to. But this is, this is a, like a huge step and I
Speaker 6:  think the more I've talked to people in the kind of private space
Speaker 6:  industry, the more, the more I get the sense that there's a real kind
Speaker 6:  of rising tide moment happening where a lot of people are leaving
Speaker 6:  SpaceX who know how to do this stuff and they're starting new companies and
Speaker 6:  there's more stuff being done and that technology is becoming more kind of
Speaker 6:  commoditized and available and like the, the acceleration of the
Speaker 6:  competition in this space might start to happen pretty fast in the same way
Speaker 6:  that like Tesla had a commanding lead for a long time and then everybody
Speaker 6:  kind of all at once in part because of a lot of people who left Tesla also
Speaker 6:  learned how to make electric cars. That there's a real sense that the same
Speaker 6:  thing is going to start to happen in the kind of private commercial space
Speaker 6:  industry, which I think is very cool. Just as somebody who really likes watching
Speaker 6:  two hour long launch videos like the one that that Blue Origin put out
Speaker 6:  today. I would just like more of those. That's all I I need. And
Speaker 9:  It's all controlled by the same few tech billionaires slash
Speaker 9:  oligarchs.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, they all have the same plan. It's get a lot of money and then launch
Speaker 6:  internet into space. Sure. It's, it's fine. It is what it's,
Speaker 6:  it's what
Speaker 9:  I'd do.
Speaker 6:  I mean it kind of is right? Like at some point you have so much money, what
Speaker 6:  are you gonna do except launch Rockets or do the, the other
Speaker 6:  Bezos thing, which he's like, what if I made a clock that lasts forever and
Speaker 6:  like perfect rich guy brain like that. That's it. Jeff, you
Speaker 6:  did Rich Guy brain crushed it. Bill Gates is like, what if I cured all
Speaker 6:  diseases and Jeff Bezos is like clock That goes all always. All right,
Speaker 6:  Jeff. Godspeed my friend. All right Richard, we have gone
Speaker 6:  way over. It's time for us to go. Thank you for being here.
Speaker 6:  This has been a delight. Neli is no longer invited back to this show. He's
Speaker 6:  off being fancy and he can stay off being fancy as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 6:  There's so much more to happen here. I'm so tired. It's middle of January,
Speaker 6:  the TikTok ban may or may not happen on Sunday. Inauguration
Speaker 6:  is on Monday. There's all kinds of news and tech stuff.
Speaker 6:  There's like I, I learned recently, I live in DC and all the tech CEOs are
Speaker 6:  here like partying around the inauguration, which is bizarre in ways that
Speaker 6:  I'm not really prepared to reckon with a lot's happening. We have a
Speaker 6:  show on Tuesday that I will just tell everybody. We have mostly already recorded
Speaker 6:  because it's a holiday weekend. So we wanna give people some time off. We'll
Speaker 6:  have some updates. We're gonna talk a lot more about this next week and the
Speaker 6:  week after and God help us forever and ever. But for now,
Speaker 6:  Richard, thank you. Thank you as always. That's the first guest, rock and
Speaker 6:  roll.
Speaker 1:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 1:  you. Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one.
Speaker 1:  The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast Network.
Speaker 1:  Our show's produced by Wil Pour, Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer.
Speaker 1:  And that's it. We'll see you next week.