# Transcript
ID: 0908029c-1082-43fb-9188-a4dd2f462d58
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-5598332316944854281/-6787370208146472682/s93290-US-4949s-1748337362.mp3
Description: After more than a month of testimony, the Meta antirust trial is beginning to slow down. The Google search remedies trial, meanwhile, is about to heat up again, with closing arguments coming soon. The Verge’s Lauren Feiner has been in the DC courthouse for all of it, and has finally emerged to tell us about what she’s seen, and learned, from two all-important monopoly trials. After that, The Verge’s Victoria Song tells us about her latest experience with Google’s smart glasses prototypes, what Google is doing differently from Meta and Apple, and what she thinks Jony Ive and OpenAI might be building. Finally, we answer a question on the Vergecast Hotline about what to do now that Mozilla is shutting down Pocket.
FTC v. Meta: The antitrust battle over WhatsApp and Instagram
Did WhatsApp really need Meta?
Why the FTC argues Meta is a closer rival to MeWe than TikTok
Instagram CEO testifies about competing with TikTok: ‘You’re either growing, or you’re slowly dying’
Android XR is getting stylish partners in Warby Parker, Gentle Monster
Xreal teases Project Aura smart glasses for Android XR
We tried on Google’s prototype AI smart glasses
Android XR and Project Moohan hands-on: Gemini is the killer app
Mozilla is shutting down Pocket
Raindrop.io
Instapaper
Matter
Wallabag
Readwise Reader
Email us at vergecast@theverge.com or call us at 866-VERGE11, we love hearing from you.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (23 ads detected)
Speaker 1:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of endless Litigation.
Speaker 1:  I'm m your friend David Pierce, and I am sitting here down one of the
Speaker 1:  deepest rabbit holes. I have been down in a long time, So I started
Speaker 1:  reading this book called Riptide, which I bought just sort of on a whim because
Speaker 1:  it was like on sale for a dollar and it had good reviews. It's about treasure
Speaker 1:  hunters. So I started reading this book, got very into this book. It's very
Speaker 1:  good. Highly recommend it. And this has sent me just
Speaker 1:  spiraling in the weirdest, most fun way on all things
Speaker 1:  treasure hunters and shipwrecks. So there's this great New Yorker
Speaker 1:  story about treasure hunters from a bunch of years ago. There's a great story
Speaker 1:  from much more recently about shipwreck detectives. I've
Speaker 1:  literally, I bought the game uncharted to go play it now. I watched
Speaker 1:  the movie Uncharted the other night. I'm reading about treasure hunters.
Speaker 1:  I'm watching documentaries about treasure hunters. This is like a whole universe
Speaker 1:  of basically puzzle solvers that is
Speaker 1:  full of technology and full of interesting ways that people are doing
Speaker 1:  research. It's like all kinds of just my
Speaker 1:  interests colliding all at once. And I make fun of my wife
Speaker 1:  all the time because she loves every true crime show you can possibly imagine.
Speaker 1:  But I'm realizing that I am falling deep into like the treasure hunter
Speaker 1:  world for exactly the same reason, and It is
Speaker 1:  blowing my mind and it's also the only thing I care about. So if I bring
Speaker 1:  up treasure hunting 65 times, or if three VERGE casts from
Speaker 1:  now, I'm just coming to you from the bow of a ship attempting
Speaker 1:  to find several hundred years worth of treasure, you'll know this is how
Speaker 1:  it all started. Anyway, as much as I can, that is not what we are here
Speaker 1:  to do today. Today on the show, we're gonna do two things. First, I'm gonna
Speaker 1:  talk to Lauren Finer, who finally emerged from a courtroom
Speaker 1:  and is going to talk to me about the Google trial and the Meta trial and
Speaker 1:  everything that we've learned about the antitrust case for and against two
Speaker 1:  of the biggest companies in tech. Then V Song is gonna come on and we're
Speaker 1:  gonna talk about Smart Glasses. She was at Google IO last week. She saw the
Speaker 1:  Android XR glasses. She's seen Project Mohan, Samsung, and
Speaker 1:  Google's project before. We have thoughts on what Johnny I
Speaker 1:  and Open AI are up to. We have a lot to talk about. It's a very fun show
Speaker 1:  and V thinks more deeply about smart glasses than just about anybody I know.
Speaker 1:  So we're gonna have some fun. We also have a hotline question about Pocket
Speaker 1:  three later app, which is shutting down. People wanted some alternatives.
Speaker 1:  I have some ideas for you. We're gonna get into all of that, just a second.
Speaker 1:  But first I'm, I'm gonna go play Uncharted. It just finished downloading
Speaker 1:  and I'm gonna go play it and then we'll be right back. This is The Vergecast.
Speaker 1:  See you in a sec.
Speaker 1:  on what, how you're feeling after this much time sitting in
Speaker 1:  mostly the Meta trial, but also some of the Google trial down the hall.
Speaker 1:  How are you holding up?
Speaker 5:  It's good. You know, I've gotten a lot of my steps in going between the
Speaker 5:  courtrooms and media rooms running up and down the stairs.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, a little bit of Stockholm syndrome as we were just talking about.
Speaker 5:  But you know, overall it's, you know, it's good to be on the other side.
Speaker 5:  It's a little bittersweet 'cause this is such a historic time. I think
Speaker 5:  that like so much has converged in this one courthouse
Speaker 5:  and I've been covering these cases since they were filed. So
Speaker 5:  It is kind of crazy that it's now somewhat in the rear view,
Speaker 5:  but you know, there's still a long way to go, so don't, don't worry about
Speaker 5:  that.
Speaker 1:  It, It is a weird time in that this moment feels both
Speaker 1:  hugely consequential and also just kind of procedural. And I've been trying
Speaker 1:  to figure out this out about the Google trial in particular. It's like we're,
Speaker 1:  we're in a phase where a judge has to decide whether to break up Google,
Speaker 1:  which is
Speaker 5:  Huge. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  But then Google is like, we don't care what happens, we're just gonna appeal
Speaker 1:  and we're gonna do this all over again several four times. And so part of
Speaker 1:  me is like, what are we even, what are we even doing here?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I But
Speaker 1:  It's also so important what's happening here.
Speaker 5:  Exactly. And I think it's so clear to me with the Facebook
Speaker 5:  case in particular, like how long it took for them to get to trial
Speaker 5:  and you know, there were, it, part of that was because the initial complaint
Speaker 5:  was thrown out and then the judge gave the FTC an
Speaker 5:  opportunity to refile, but the original case was filed like in
Speaker 5:  2020 and you know, the fact that
Speaker 5:  it took this long to get to trial and in that time TikTok
Speaker 5:  became a huge player in the space. It,
Speaker 5:  it's just, you know, really underscores how quickly tech moves and how
Speaker 5:  slowly the legal system moves.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I think I, I mostly wanna talk about the Meta trial because I think
Speaker 1:  a, we've, we've talked a bunch about the Google trial and BI think in a
Speaker 1:  certain way it's a little more straightforward just because of where It is
Speaker 1:  in the process. We kind of know what everybody wants. We know what's going
Speaker 1:  on. The Meta trial, I think last we talked
Speaker 1:  was at the very beginning and there was this sense that, okay, the FTC is
Speaker 1:  trying to prove a thing that is going to be very complicated to prove, which
Speaker 1:  is essentially that me we is very important, right? And like there
Speaker 1:  we were having this big debate about whether this is the service
Speaker 1:  that people go to that has monopolized talking to friends and
Speaker 1:  family, that that is like, that's the market. And that we were gonna spend
Speaker 1:  a lot of time over the next six weeks arguing about the market
Speaker 1:  definition of this thing. And I think to your point, I
Speaker 1:  hadn't really thought about this until you just said it, but I think this
Speaker 1:  would've been a really different trial five years ago than it was. So
Speaker 1:  much has changed in the market since this
Speaker 1:  thing got filed originally. But I'm curious now, we, we at
Speaker 1:  the very beginning we were like, okay, this is going to ultimately be about
Speaker 1:  market definition and it seems like the FTC has a pretty steep hill to climb
Speaker 1:  to prove its case here. How do you feel about how that's
Speaker 1:  gone on the other side of this?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean I think market definition is still going to be
Speaker 5:  at the crux of the judge's decision here. And you know,
Speaker 5:  I think as part of that, it's how important
Speaker 5:  is, you know, this kind of core use case that the
Speaker 5:  FTC is pointing to of, you know, being able to go on Facebook and Instagram
Speaker 5:  to share things with your friends and family and see what they're
Speaker 5:  doing. How important is that still to
Speaker 5:  these apps and you know, this market that they've laid out that they
Speaker 5:  say that Meta dominates. And you know, I
Speaker 5:  think what is interesting here is it doesn't have to be
Speaker 5:  necessarily that it's the main thing people do on these apps
Speaker 5:  anymore, but the judge has to feel
Speaker 5:  like it's important enough still that it's, you know,
Speaker 5:  something that Meta can monopolize, that it matters to consumers,
Speaker 5:  that it's not something that's like, you know, gonna die in a year
Speaker 5:  or so. So I think, you know, when I read comments
Speaker 5:  on stories, we write about this, I see people saying, yeah, I
Speaker 5:  don't feel like I can connect with my friends and family as well on these
Speaker 5:  apps anymore. And I think that's something that we hear a lot. So, you know,
Speaker 5:  obviously that's very anecdotal, but you know, the judge is gonna have to
Speaker 5:  decide, is that a few users who just
Speaker 5:  really want to see what their grandchildren are doing on
Speaker 5:  Facebook? Or is this really an important use
Speaker 5:  case for consumers?
Speaker 1:  Right. And it, it seems to me like, I think you're right, there's a lot going
Speaker 1:  on here, but it does seem like a lot of the rest of It is downstream of that
Speaker 1:  question, right? Because if, if, if the thing we're litigating here was,
Speaker 1:  was it illegal for Meta then Facebook to
Speaker 1:  buy Instagram and WhatsApp? The way you get there is
Speaker 1:  by saying Facebook was where people went to hang out with their friends.
Speaker 1:  And then Instagram and WhatsApp showed up providing competitive ways to hang
Speaker 1:  out with their friends. And so Facebook bought them to
Speaker 1:  essentially quash a competitor, right? Like, 'cause it, it, that line actually
Speaker 1:  to me has gotten sort of straighter and straighter over the course of this
Speaker 1:  case that you, you don't have to believe that logic. And I think the question
Speaker 1:  will come down to whether the judge believes that logic, but increasingly
Speaker 1:  to me it feels like It is that few steps, if you start from
Speaker 1:  Facebook is a place where people hang out with friends and family. That's
Speaker 1:  how you get where the FTC is trying to go. And it seems like that has actually
Speaker 1:  sort of crystallized over the last several weeks.
Speaker 5:  Exactly. Yeah. And I think, you know, it's, it's a less straightforward
Speaker 5:  case than the one Meta wants to make, which is that of course we
Speaker 5:  compete with TikTok and YouTube because we're all, you know,
Speaker 5:  everyone has, many people have all these apps on their phone and we're competing
Speaker 5:  for people's time and attention to make sure they click on ours.
Speaker 5:  But, you know, I think what the FTC has been arguing
Speaker 5:  did become more clear throughout trial that they're saying, you know,
Speaker 5:  Facebook was worried that Instagram was going to compete
Speaker 5:  with it at this time when it was struggling to
Speaker 5:  do the shift from desktop to mobile and Instagram was
Speaker 5:  built on mobile and it worried that it would
Speaker 5:  become a real threat to its power. And with WhatsApp, I
Speaker 5:  think maybe the argument is a, a little bit less clear because
Speaker 5:  it's so evident that the founders really were not
Speaker 5:  interested in building a social network. Although they've tried to
Speaker 5:  undermine that argument a little bit. But I think ultimately
Speaker 5:  the fear was also, well maybe they don't wanna do it, but maybe Google
Speaker 5:  buys them and Google is able to make, you know, this major
Speaker 5:  social platform by leveraging this power
Speaker 5:  that WhatsApp has.
Speaker 1:  Well, the other part of the WhatsApp one that is so interesting to me, and
Speaker 1:  I, I confess that throughout this, I have found the WhatsApp piece of this
Speaker 1:  to be vastly more interesting than the Instagram side of things. I think
Speaker 1:  in a certain way the Instagram thing is more sort of straightforward, which
Speaker 1:  is maybe why it's less interesting to me. It's like it was a competitor
Speaker 1:  and did Meta buy it and help it or buy it and hurt it? It is like,
Speaker 1:  that's the question. You can do that, you can do it that which you will.
Speaker 1:  But there's like, it's so funny to rewind back to like 2013
Speaker 1:  before all of this is happening, WhatsApp was a completely different
Speaker 1:  animal. It was like they were charging people a dollar a year to like
Speaker 1:  message their friends around the world and it was growing like crazy and
Speaker 1:  it was a whole different thing and you never heard about them. And like 11
Speaker 1:  people worked at the company and they had no ambitions or so it seemed of
Speaker 1:  being anything more than just that. And yet
Speaker 1:  it was taking over the world. Right. And I think this is the thing that I
Speaker 1:  keep just sort of spinning around in my head is like, at least
Speaker 1:  from what I can tell and from what you've been reporting, there's been a
Speaker 1:  ton of evidence to suggest that Facebook was terrified of how popular WhatsApp
Speaker 1:  was becoming,
Speaker 1:  both because in theory it could become that popular and then add a bunch
Speaker 1:  of other social networky stuff. But also because even back then it seems
Speaker 1:  like Facebook understood that group chat was gonna win and that
Speaker 1:  like pretty fundamentally messaging among friends was going
Speaker 1:  to be the actual next phase of social networking. And that
Speaker 1:  if WhatsApp did that, even if they didn't make any money off of it, it
Speaker 1:  was a huge threat to Facebook's business if people went and used this
Speaker 1:  like adorable mostly free service that had no ambitions of ever
Speaker 1:  trying to be a trillion dollar company. And I just, it's such a weird thing.
Speaker 1:  Like it both was and was not a competitor and I have not, I cannot figure
Speaker 1:  out how to weigh those things in my head.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it, it's so fascinating 'cause I think one of the core
Speaker 5:  arguments that kept coming up when it came to WhatsApp was like, no,
Speaker 5:  seriously, the founders of WhatsApp do not wanna build a social network.
Speaker 5:  They have absolutely no interest. They don't wanna have an ad model.
Speaker 5:  Like no one is gonna strong arm them into it. And you know,
Speaker 5:  even when Brian Acton, the co-founder came and testified
Speaker 5:  this past week, you know, he kind of said that too, I was
Speaker 5:  not interested in an ad model. I did not wanna build a feed into
Speaker 5:  WhatsApp and my investors were not gonna make me.
Speaker 5:  Interestingly, on cross examination, the FTC was kind of able to pull out,
Speaker 5:  well, you know, when you signed this deal with
Speaker 5:  Meta, you understood that the valuation they were giving you
Speaker 5:  came in part from, you know, them thinking about how this would work in an
Speaker 5:  ad supported business. Mm. And he wasn't able to get them
Speaker 5:  to completely rule out ever running ads on WhatsApp. I think there
Speaker 5:  was some language about monetization in their contract, but
Speaker 5:  you know, it, it seemed like he at least went into it knowing
Speaker 5:  that this was a possibility. And despite all the resistance,
Speaker 5:  maybe if push came to shove one day, WhatsApp would've
Speaker 5:  had an ad supported model or, you know, would've allowed some social
Speaker 5:  features or sold to another company that would've made it into leveraged
Speaker 5:  it into a social play.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I thought that was so interesting and, and I, I really liked the thing
Speaker 1:  you said at one point that it came up in testimony that
Speaker 1:  Facebook overpaid by somewhere between six and $10 billion for
Speaker 1:  its actual evaluation of WhatsApp. And it's like, oh yeah, okay. Everyone
Speaker 1:  understood that this was a massive overpay for the
Speaker 1:  thing that you were getting. And the inclination was there's, there's, you
Speaker 1:  know, there's, there's money in the couch cushions here. And, and Facebook
Speaker 1:  was actually probably better equipped to get it than almost anybody. And
Speaker 1:  ironically never really figured it out. Like, we're still here in
Speaker 1:  2025 and WhatsApp is like, you know, Titan popular all over
Speaker 1:  the world and it's still not like the earth shattering the
Speaker 1:  humongous business that it needs to be to be worth that valuation. So like
Speaker 1:  history has proven all of that to just be more and more complicated over
Speaker 1:  time.
Speaker 1:  But what, what do you make of the, the WhatsApp side of it in particular?
Speaker 1:  Do you think the, the story that is being told
Speaker 1:  by Meta about what WhatsApp was going to be or might have
Speaker 1:  been planning to be, or why it could have been a threat or whatever, is that,
Speaker 1:  is that working? Who, who is winning this side of the argument here, do you
Speaker 1:  think?
Speaker 5:  I think it's hard to tell. It's kind of complicated because there's some
Speaker 5:  things that seem like they could cut both ways. For example,
Speaker 5:  you know, they show that there were several of these messaging apps that
Speaker 5:  were really exploding at the time and WhatsApp was particularly
Speaker 5:  exploding and exploding in a lot of different markets where some of these
Speaker 5:  other apps like Cacao Talk or Line or WeChat were really more
Speaker 5:  like localized to a certain region. But WhatsApp
Speaker 5:  was actually the only one of those that wasn't really expanding into social
Speaker 5:  features. So arguably it's one that was, you know, the least
Speaker 5:  competitive with Facebook's business and that's the one that Facebook decided
Speaker 5:  to go after. But on the other hand, you know, it was
Speaker 5:  exploding in growth and you know, they saw potential for it maybe in different
Speaker 5:  ways than they saw for these other apps. And so, you know,
Speaker 5:  maybe that's a reason they did end up going after it. So I,
Speaker 5:  I think there's a lot of things like that where it's hard to fully tell which
Speaker 5:  way the judge is going to ultimately take it.
Speaker 5:  And I think it's also tough when you hear over and over from the founders
Speaker 5:  themselves, from everyone who's testified, who had insight into the founders
Speaker 5:  that they did not wanna sell ads, they were not going to be
Speaker 5:  pushed over by their investors. Mark Zuckerberg said he was surprised
Speaker 5:  that, you know, they basically just wanted to run a lifestyle
Speaker 5:  company and compared it to Craigslist. You know, like
Speaker 5:  these were painted as like extremely unambitious people
Speaker 5:  in a certain way
Speaker 1:  As if that's like an outrageously horrible thing to want is to just
Speaker 1:  be Craigslist, right?
Speaker 5:  But it's also, it's somewhat hard to believe when then you're seeing, well
Speaker 5:  these are founders who got billions of dollars for this app
Speaker 5:  that they created. Like were they really that unambitious and
Speaker 5:  were they really going to, you know, leave their investors and their employees
Speaker 5:  hanging at the end of the day
Speaker 1:  They did go buy yachts, you know what I mean? Like at, at some point you
Speaker 1:  did buy a yacht. Yeah, Yeah, yeah. So
Speaker 1:  I, I think I, I I think that's right and it, it, one of the things that has
Speaker 1:  struck me just in, in reading and reporting is that it, it seems so much
Speaker 1:  like the, the vibe in the courtroom has just sort of
Speaker 1:  whipsawed back and forth in a way that I think I'm not used to in covering
Speaker 1:  a lot of these trials. You sort of see momentum kind of builds
Speaker 1:  and, and waxes and wanes a little bit, but it feels like even
Speaker 1:  like witness to witness in this, you've had these like
Speaker 1:  wildly different stories about what's going on. And I just think about like
Speaker 1:  from from Kevin's Strom to Adam er talking about what's going on at
Speaker 1:  Instagram, even with the same people asking them the same
Speaker 1:  kinds of questions, just completely different perspectives on how all of
Speaker 1:  this has worked. And on the one hand, like of course that's true, but on
Speaker 1:  the other hand, this whole thing just strikes me as like, it has gotten sort
Speaker 1:  of more unknowable than ever over time. And
Speaker 1:  like on the Instagram side, it seems like the, the big question is
Speaker 1:  did Meta help or hurt Instagram? Right? Like, is that, is that a, am I
Speaker 1:  overgeneralizing to say that's kind of what it boils down to? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I, I think for sure, and I think we saw that, especially in
Speaker 5:  Kevin RA's testimony, the co-founder of Instagram
Speaker 5:  where, you know, it was really about, okay, you know,
Speaker 5:  he took this offer from Meta thinking that they're really going to
Speaker 5:  help grow the company. And in a lot of ways it's really hard to
Speaker 5:  look at Instagram and see, you know, billions of users
Speaker 5:  and you know, this huge platform for
Speaker 5:  advertising and think that it's could have been more
Speaker 5:  successful than It is today. But on the other hand, Kevin
Speaker 5:  Strom seemed pretty confident that it could be, and he could have
Speaker 5:  done it himself, and that, you know, Meta withheld resources for
Speaker 5:  growth, for integrity that, you know, they could have
Speaker 5:  used to make Instagram better in various ways. So
Speaker 5:  it's really hard to say, you know, is this just another Silicon
Speaker 5:  Valley executive just like blowing steam
Speaker 5:  or is this, you know, really what could have happened. And
Speaker 5:  I think that's always the challenge in antitrust cases is what would've happened
Speaker 5:  if, you know, this major event didn't occur. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Have they used the phrase the but for world a lot? Oh yes.
Speaker 1:  The Google case has also been full of the but for world. Yes. Which I
Speaker 1:  enjoy very much. And It is like a phrase I say to myself all the time now,
Speaker 1:  and I'm like, well, in a but for world I wouldn't be having goldfish right
Speaker 1:  now, but today I'm eating goldfish. It's, it's very good.
Speaker 1:  Have you found yourself as an observer being in the courtroom all day,
Speaker 1:  leaning towards one side or the other of the Instagram argument
Speaker 1:  has, is, is, is, are you compelled by one version of the argument or the
Speaker 1:  other?
Speaker 5:  I mean, I'd say it's not necessarily that I'm compelled one way
Speaker 5:  or the other, but I find that the FTC has a pretty
Speaker 5:  tough case here. 'cause I think it's just, it's
Speaker 5:  not that they can't win it and not that, you know, they haven't presented
Speaker 5:  strong arguments. I just think it's obviously they have the burden to
Speaker 5:  begin with. And it's really difficult looking at
Speaker 5:  Instagram and seeing, you know, at one point Meta's chief
Speaker 5:  marketing officer Alex Schultz testified about how
Speaker 5:  Instagram has seen such growth that, you know, they have reached almost
Speaker 5:  like all of the something like 250 million potential
Speaker 5:  eligible smartphone users in the US who could
Speaker 5:  possibly be on this app. And to grow any more than
Speaker 5:  that is, that's really gonna happen at a much slower
Speaker 5:  rate than it used to. And so later on, judge
Speaker 5:  Boberg had brought that up to the FTCs expert and said, you know, could
Speaker 5:  this really have been more successful than where It is now? They
Speaker 5:  have like almost all the users they could get. And I think that
Speaker 5:  makes this really challenging. But at the same time, I, I
Speaker 5:  guess the argument from the FTC is, well yeah, they have all these users
Speaker 5:  but they have nowhere else to go. So, you know, that's kind of
Speaker 5:  the point there. Yeah, I, I think it's just, it's difficult because
Speaker 5:  we're in a world now with TikTok and I think friends and family
Speaker 5:  does seem like it's still important. The question is just how important and
Speaker 5:  for how long.
Speaker 1:  Talk me through that actually. 'cause I think it was, it was Tom Allison,
Speaker 1:  the head of Facebook who was on the stand just the other day, right? Talking
Speaker 1:  about this. And he, like some other Meta
Speaker 1:  employees who have testified during this trial kind of
Speaker 1:  seemed to argue out of both sides of their mouth about like, yes, these are
Speaker 1:  platforms where people connect with friends and family and that is important
Speaker 1:  and It is core to what we're doing. And Mark Zuckerberg is out here in, in
Speaker 1:  the meanwhile like talking about OG Facebook and wanting to bring all that
Speaker 1:  back. And yet over and over these people seem very happy
Speaker 1:  to talk about the fact that actually no, this isn't for friends and family
Speaker 1:  at all. Help me figure out what's really going on there.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I, I mean I think this is a really interesting
Speaker 5:  element of this trial and I think something where I think the
Speaker 5:  FTC does have something to kind of sink their teeth in here. And
Speaker 5:  I think with Tom Allison's testimony, one thing that was interesting
Speaker 5:  to me was when they brought up this new kind of, yeah, the
Speaker 5:  OG Facebook where they're focusing back in on
Speaker 5:  connecting with your friends, like bringing you back to your roots. And to
Speaker 5:  me that felt like some kind of internal recognition from
Speaker 5:  Meta that this is still something people want.
Speaker 5:  And you know, I think the company was kind of arguing, well
Speaker 5:  yeah, like we know this is something that some people want. And
Speaker 5:  the fact is that now, because most people really, you
Speaker 5:  know, they might tell us they wanna see friends and family, but if we only
Speaker 5:  show them friends and family posts, they're gonna leave. And so that their
Speaker 5:  actions kind of tell us they want more engaging content than whatever, you
Speaker 5:  know, your uncle is posting on Facebook. Sure. So they
Speaker 5:  end up putting more, you know, unconnected content, content from people you
Speaker 5:  don't follow in your feed. So, you know, one thing that was interesting
Speaker 5:  was Tom Allison said, if you did really wanna see only your friend's content,
Speaker 5:  you'd have to scroll like all day to see all of it. Yeah. Because
Speaker 5:  you'd have so much of this unconnected content in between.
Speaker 5:  So, you know, they figure for the people who really wanna see that, let's
Speaker 5:  stick it in a tab and they can go to it when they want. So,
Speaker 5:  you know, on the one hand maybe that says that this is really
Speaker 5:  something that's a novelty or you know, just a small
Speaker 5:  part of what we do. And now a bigger part is all of this like
Speaker 5:  algorithmically recommended content. But on the other hand you could say
Speaker 5:  while they're recognizing that It is something that's still important, even
Speaker 5:  if it's less important than, you know,
Speaker 5:  things like reels and things of that nature. And I think
Speaker 5:  that's why we heard throughout trial Meadow would say something
Speaker 5:  like, well, you know, it's becoming a much smaller part of our business.
Speaker 5:  And then the FTC would ask, well, but in absolute
Speaker 5:  terms, is it still growing? And the answer would usually be
Speaker 5:  yes. So, you know, yes it's small, but small on,
Speaker 5:  you know, a really large base.
Speaker 1:  Right. Well, I mean to me it makes me think of like, have you ever heard
Speaker 1:  the saying that there are, there are three u's there's the, you think you
Speaker 1:  are the, you other people think you are, and then the, you actually are like,
Speaker 1:  yeah, I, I've been thinking about this so much with Facebook in the context
Speaker 1:  of this whole trial that like the, the you that Facebook thinks It is
Speaker 1:  has always been about friends and family, right? Like It is, It is a place
Speaker 1:  for real people to connect to real people. And I think that is like the reason
Speaker 1:  Zuckerberg is so into this idea of the OG Facebook is partly about people
Speaker 1:  use it, but it's also about, like that is, that is his conception of what
Speaker 1:  this thing does and why It is important and why It is valuable and why it
Speaker 1:  became what It is now. I don't think Mark Zuckerberg's
Speaker 1:  conception of why Facebook is great is because it shows you all the
Speaker 1:  AI nonsense, right? But I think, I think that's what people see on Facebook
Speaker 1:  now that is, that is our conception of Facebook and that is what Facebook
Speaker 1:  has become for so many of us. Like I don't, I have probably
Speaker 1:  been on Facebook to see what my friends are up to one time in
Speaker 1:  the last decade, otherwise it's like marketplace and
Speaker 1:  groups. That's it. That's what Facebook is for me. And I think that's true
Speaker 1:  for a lot of people. And so this question of like, I, I just keep seeing
Speaker 1:  people on the stand be like, okay, yes, I said in an interview that it's
Speaker 1:  for friends and family. Yes, it's on our website that it's for friends and
Speaker 1:  family. Yes, we tell people all the time that it's for friends and family,
Speaker 1:  but when you look at how people actually use it, it's not remotely for friends
Speaker 1:  and family and Yeah, like there was the, the thing Tom,
Speaker 1:  I think it was Tom Allison who said a lot of people now make Facebook accounts
Speaker 1:  and have no friends. Yeah, yeah. And that to me is, so that was such an eyeopening
Speaker 1:  moment of like, oh, that is a complete inversion of the whole idea
Speaker 1:  of what Facebook was supposed to be when we get to that point.
Speaker 5:  Exactly. Yeah. That was really interesting. And you know, I think he's basically
Speaker 5:  saying those people maybe are going on marketplace groups, whatever. But
Speaker 1:  I also think that I bet, and this would be an interesting experiment to run.
Speaker 1:  You could show up on Facebook, make zero friends and still have an infinite
Speaker 1:  feed of content immediately available to you.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And that's what makes the experience so different than it used to be.
Speaker 5:  Right. But I think at the same time, like if I just think as like a very
Speaker 5:  casual social media user, if I'm going to
Speaker 5:  go try to see what a friend's up to or you know, message
Speaker 5:  them or something, I'm not really going to TikTok and that's kind of their
Speaker 5:  point here. I'm going to Instagram or Facebook. Right. And you know, maybe
Speaker 5:  I'm doing those things less on Instagram and Facebook in general than I used
Speaker 5:  to. And maybe I'm doing more of it in just regular old messaging, but
Speaker 5:  I'm not really going to TikTok for that. And maybe some people
Speaker 5:  are, but one of tiktoks executives even said that their
Speaker 5:  friends tab about like 1% of users are watching videos
Speaker 5:  in there. So
Speaker 1:  I honestly didn't know the friends tab existed until Exactly they said that
Speaker 1:  on the stand. Like straight up had no idea. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I think to me that has actually been the most compelling part of the
Speaker 1:  FTCs argument here is that it, it's not necessarily that
Speaker 1:  this is the main thing people do, it's that if this is
Speaker 1:  what you want to do, there is nowhere else to go. And the reason there is
Speaker 1:  nowhere else to go is because of Facebook. Like that's just true. Whether
Speaker 1:  you can prove that in, in court, I don't know. But like
Speaker 1:  I've, I, you and I have been covering the space to know long enough
Speaker 1:  to know that like Facebook ate that market, it, it just did.
Speaker 1:  And then we get back to the question of like, if Instagram had been left
Speaker 1:  alone, could it have done? And so that's a whole separate thing. But, but
Speaker 1:  that piece of it I find very compelling that, that FTC is like, this is
Speaker 1:  a thing people wanna do, and you have made sure that there is nowhere else
Speaker 1:  for them to do it. And I think every time that they've done a successful
Speaker 1:  job of coming back to that is when I end up like back on the FTC side of
Speaker 1:  this case because I'm like, no, you're right. This may not be, we don't have
Speaker 1:  to litigate everything that Facebook is, we just have to litigate that part.
Speaker 1:  And I think whether the judge buys that sort of,
Speaker 1:  you know, slicing of the pie of Facebook remains to be seen. But I do find
Speaker 1:  that part of the argument pretty convincing.
Speaker 5:  I agree with that. And I think that's where I wonder, you know, judge Boberg
Speaker 5:  has kind of admitted he is not really a social media user. So,
Speaker 5:  you know, Adam, er, before the trial started did a tutorial where he
Speaker 5:  walked him through these apps No. Where it just, you know, felt like a,
Speaker 5:  you know, teenager explaining to their dad how
Speaker 1:  What I would give to be a fly on the wall for that. Yeah. Like in the judges'
Speaker 1:  chambers, just Oh, scrolling. I was in the program. Oh, you were there. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Was it, was it, was it the most awkward thing in history or was it amazing?
Speaker 5:  It was. So, I mean, throughout the trial, one thing that's happened is Judge
Speaker 5:  Boberg played basketball at Yale, I believe.
Speaker 5:  Cool. And so everyone is working basketball references
Speaker 5:  into their exhibits. So we had some like NBA videos
Speaker 5:  referenced in the Instagram demo.
Speaker 1:  That's very good. Yeah. Let, let's talk about TikTok for a minute because
Speaker 1:  you, you brought this up and it does feel like, you know, back to the, what
Speaker 1:  would this case have been like if it was tried five years ago? TikTok is
Speaker 1:  sort of the big wrench here, right? And, and it has come up a lot kind of
Speaker 1:  on both sides of the argument. How would you explain sort of
Speaker 1:  tiktoks role in what this case has been? Because it does seem like It is
Speaker 1:  everybody's favorite comparison in all directions and
Speaker 1:  it's very strange.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean I think TikTok is just kind of the elephant in the room because
Speaker 5:  yeah, it existed when the FTC filed this case, but
Speaker 5:  it really was nothing like It is today. That has become such a huge
Speaker 5:  competitor for Meta in a general sense of the term. You know,
Speaker 5:  if you told anyone that Meta doesn't compete with
Speaker 5:  TikTok, they'd be like, what are you talking about? Right? But you
Speaker 5:  know, we're talking about this very like legal
Speaker 5:  case where it has a very specific definition about
Speaker 5:  what is really a competitor. And so in this case, the
Speaker 5:  FTC says that we're talking about personal social networking services, which
Speaker 5:  are used to connect with friends and family. They have a social
Speaker 5:  graph, which means, you know, they connect, they, you know, kind of map out
Speaker 5:  like all of your connections based on you know, who you know
Speaker 5:  versus like what you're interested in, which is more of how TikTok does it.
Speaker 5:  And it, they say in that market it's really just Facebook,
Speaker 5:  Instagram, Snapchat, and then some of these other apps like me, we and BeReal.
Speaker 5:  And So I think with TikTok, you know, they're saying that's more of a passive
Speaker 5:  experience. You're, you know, scrolling through, you're getting served
Speaker 5:  different videos that you might be interested in, but it's not really about
Speaker 5:  who you know, or, you know, you're not really gonna like message a friend
Speaker 5:  on there, maybe you will, but like, that's not really what you're going to
Speaker 5:  TikTok for. And So I think that's really what it comes down to.
Speaker 5:  And what Meta says is that, well, it doesn't really matter
Speaker 5:  why users specifically come to the app because first of all,
Speaker 5:  a lot of users come to Instagram to do the same thing that they do
Speaker 5:  on TikTok, which is scroll reels, right? And second of all, they say
Speaker 5:  it's really about time and attention because that's what really
Speaker 5:  constrain our power is we're thinking about how do we make sure that
Speaker 5:  people spend more time on our apps versus on TikTok or
Speaker 5:  something else. And you know, that's what we should be focused on. Because
Speaker 5:  internally you can see that that's what we look at. We look at, you know,
Speaker 5:  how do we win users' time? We're not saying like, oh, let's like try
Speaker 5:  to get more of the friends and family sharing group.
Speaker 1:  Can't both of those things be true? At the same time, this is what I, I'm
Speaker 1:  so hung up on this, like, the, the, every time anybody makes an
Speaker 1:  argument about TikTok, I'm like, of course you're right. Everybody's like,
Speaker 1:  everybody's like, no, people don't do the same things sort
Speaker 1:  of in relation to each other that they do on Facebook. And even
Speaker 1:  Instagram, like my Instagram experience in terms of like how I
Speaker 1:  interact with my friends is completely different from TikTok, but most of
Speaker 1:  the time I open Instagram or TikTok, it's, it's for the same purpose like
Speaker 1:  you're saying. And so everybody keeps bringing up this like, was it an
Speaker 1:  Instagram outage?
Speaker 5:  It was the Meta outage. It was the Meta 21
Speaker 1:  Meta, yeah. So everybody brings up this outage and, and points out
Speaker 1:  where people went as, as a way of saying, okay, who are our actual
Speaker 1:  competitors? Like, where do they go when they're not here?
Speaker 1:  And like, it's the obvious place, like everybody went to YouTube and TikTok,
Speaker 1:  right? And so yeah, Meta is like, of course that's where they went. They're,
Speaker 1:  those are our competitors and that's also obviously true. And
Speaker 1:  so like I, I just don't know how to piece those two things apart or if I
Speaker 1:  even need to that like these two sides just sort of seem like they're saying
Speaker 1:  true things that have nothing to do with each other.
Speaker 5:  Right. Well then I think the other part of that is that the FTC then points
Speaker 5:  out that, yeah, okay, there's like some percentage that
Speaker 5:  was diverted to these other apps, but this doesn't add up to a hundred percent
Speaker 5:  some of these diverted users just like logged off. Like we
Speaker 5:  dunno, maybe they went to, maybe they went to other apps, but maybe they
Speaker 5:  also like touched grass or went to sleep sleep. So I think
Speaker 1:  We're suing grass it's time. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And you know, actually Judge Boberg has kind of touched on this
Speaker 5:  before because he, when he was ruling on the motion for
Speaker 5:  summary judgment late last year, he said that, you know, the fact
Speaker 5:  that a Meta competes with TikTok for time and attention
Speaker 5:  is true, but beside the point. And
Speaker 5:  he also said quote, Meta competes not just with YouTube, TikTok and
Speaker 5:  X, but also with watching a movie at a friend's house, reading a book at
Speaker 5:  the library and playing online poker. Antitrust law does not require
Speaker 5:  consideration of such an infinite range of possible substitutes.
Speaker 5:  So I think Okay, you know, that's gonna be somewhat of a difficult argument
Speaker 5:  for Meta to make that, you know, it really does matter that we compete for
Speaker 5:  time and attention. And I think they would say it's because, you know, people
Speaker 5:  have multiple apps on their phones already. And Yeah, we've like almost reached
Speaker 5:  saturation maybe with how many more people could download it. So at this
Speaker 5:  point we're competing on, you know, who spends more time on each app.
Speaker 1:  So this comes back yet again to market definition. Yeah. Because like if,
Speaker 1:  if you can convince Judge Roseberg to buy the idea that there is
Speaker 1:  a market for I want to find my friends and family on the internet,
Speaker 1:  then we're somewhere. But if you can't, I think
Speaker 1:  all like rational evidence suggests that you can't
Speaker 1:  come at Meta for, it's a place where people watch videos
Speaker 1:  and, and So I, this this also now kind of makes the FTC ass
Speaker 1:  whole plan here makes sense. Like we, we even talked about at the beginning,
Speaker 1:  this is a pretty tricky needle to thread,
Speaker 1:  but by the, the way you're talking about it and the way the judge sees it,
Speaker 1:  that's kind of, its only move.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I I think that's right. I think, you know, they have to, they have
Speaker 5:  to show that there is this market, however small It is, that
Speaker 5:  it's not so small that it doesn't matter. It's still matters and
Speaker 5:  it's still something that Meta can leverage even over the
Speaker 5:  users who maybe really are just coming there for reels and
Speaker 5:  that that really separates them out. And I think one way
Speaker 5:  that we've seen this throughout trial is Meta keeps bringing up these three
Speaker 5:  screenshots of reels, TikTok and
Speaker 5:  YouTube shorts and it's like on the same video and they look exactly
Speaker 5:  the same. And you know, interestingly the FTCs
Speaker 5:  expert actually couldn't distinguish which was witch, which was not a great
Speaker 5:  look,
Speaker 1:  That's a bad look for everyone. Like no one comes out of that looking like
Speaker 1:  they're doing a good job.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But you know, I think it was tiktoks executive who
Speaker 5:  had looked at the same kind of screenshot side by side and was
Speaker 5:  like, yeah, you know, they do seem very similar. But when you
Speaker 5:  click out of that experience, you get to what is core to the app.
Speaker 5:  And for TikTok, this is the core like that. That's it. It's the
Speaker 5:  short form video player. And for YouTube it's the long form
Speaker 5:  videos. And for Instagram and Facebook, it's the
Speaker 5:  feed and stories and you know, those are elements that the
Speaker 5:  FTC says are really about sharing with your friends and family, even if they
Speaker 5:  include some other kinds of content.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So as everybody's hearing this on Tuesday,
Speaker 1:  you will be back in court for what we think is the last day of
Speaker 1:  this, right? For now.
Speaker 5:  That's
Speaker 1:  Right. Yes. The last day until the next first day. And then we do this all
Speaker 1:  over again, presumably several more times.
Speaker 5:  Exactly. Okay.
Speaker 1:  I like it. You and I both live in DC and I've seen you more in the DC District
Speaker 1:  courthouse than anywhere else since we've been working together. It's been
Speaker 1:  great.
Speaker 1:  I I will not hold you to this and neither will all of the many people listening
Speaker 1:  to this, people to this. If you had to call it right now, where do you think
Speaker 1:  it lands?
Speaker 5:  O
Speaker 5:  if I had to call it right now, I would say
Speaker 5:  I think Meadow wins.
Speaker 1:  I think that's what I meant
Speaker 5:  Too. But yeah, I mean I just think it's, it's a tough case
Speaker 5:  and it, you know, the burden is always on the plaintiff that said,
Speaker 5:  will I be shocked if the FTC wins? No, but
Speaker 5:  I, I think it's just, we had Google go first. I think that was a
Speaker 5:  very strong case and it, that was tough because it was the first
Speaker 5:  one out of the gate. It's hard to be the first judge to make a ruling like
Speaker 5:  that. Totally. But this is a very different kind of case, you
Speaker 5:  know, that was really about contracts. A lot of it actually lined up really
Speaker 5:  neatly with the Microsoft case. So
Speaker 5:  I think it was very different. I think this is a different kind of case.
Speaker 5:  And the judge, in that same order on the motion for summary judgment
Speaker 5:  in November, he said that the government's claims quote
Speaker 5:  at times straightened this country's creaking, antitrust precedents to their
Speaker 5:  limits. Oh boy. So I, it's just, you know, it's a hard case to bring
Speaker 5:  given the state of antitrust law and where
Speaker 5:  we're at today. But you know, it, it's not out of the question. And I think
Speaker 5:  Judge Boberg seemed like he was asking really astute
Speaker 5:  questions by the end. He didn't ask a ton of questions, but the ones he did
Speaker 5:  ask seemed like, okay, he's really following this. Mm. So I will be
Speaker 5:  very interested to see what he ends up saying.
Speaker 1:  You and me both. Yeah. There's, there's a lot of these all happening at once.
Speaker 1:  And this one, this one feels like maybe the hardest to call.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But it's gonna be fascinating. Alright, for now I will, I
Speaker 1:  will leave you alone. But thank you for doing this. It's great to see you
Speaker 1:  come. Yeah. Leave the courtroom occasionally. We're gonna, we're gonna do
Speaker 1:  this more. It's gonna be great. Great. Would
Speaker 7:  Love that.
Speaker 1:  All right, we gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back and we're
Speaker 1:  gonna talk smart glasses. We'll be right back.
Speaker 10:  post-conference high.
Speaker 10:  comparatively about AI instead of just going ai. Though there
Speaker 10:  was a lot of that too with many charts, albeit with Y
Speaker 10:  axes, unlike other conferences that we shall not name. And
Speaker 10:  you know, I think this is one of the first years where we felt where I felt
Speaker 10:  at least that hardware was present in some way in, in the
Speaker 10:  keynote. Not in a large way, but in a way.
Speaker 1:  Interesting. Well, and one of the reasons I wanna talk to you is it felt
Speaker 1:  to me like Google makes this like long series of product
Speaker 1:  announcements about Mariner and Astra and AI mode and all this
Speaker 1:  stuff where they're like, okay, what we want to do is make AI
Speaker 1:  that is like interactive with you all the time and it can see everything
Speaker 1:  and it's always listening and proactive and all this stuff. And all I kept
Speaker 1:  hearing all the time was it's s smart glasses that it's like this is, this
Speaker 1:  is a world you build if you believe that smart glasses
Speaker 1:  are going to take over the world. Was that your sense too that like
Speaker 1:  all of this is like kind of phony, but it's like built
Speaker 1:  for smart glasses.
Speaker 10:  I 100% feel that way because what did they
Speaker 10:  end on? Smart Glasses. Right? Right. It was a very interesting
Speaker 10:  concept because they went like, search, search, search. Here's a bunch
Speaker 10:  of projects whose names you absolutely won't remember the difference between
Speaker 10:  by the end of this conference and smart glasses at the end.
Speaker 10:  So I, I feel like they were just kind of handholding everyone to go to this
Speaker 10:  thesis that Android XR is how they're going to
Speaker 10:  embody all of this ai. Because AI is not really
Speaker 10:  something that is tangible at the moment. Like it's software, right?
Speaker 10:  It's on your devices but it's not necessarily
Speaker 10:  integral to your devices. And you know, the thesis that Meta
Speaker 10:  and now Google have kind of come up with in the last two years
Speaker 10:  or so is that Smart glasses are the hardware vehicle for AI
Speaker 10:  for Normies. We got the headsets for you, you early
Speaker 10:  adopters, tech enthusiasts, you know, gadget nerds,
Speaker 10:  but for the Normies weird pairing up with a
Speaker 10:  Gentle Monster and Warby Parker and you'll have smart glasses and you'll
Speaker 10:  like it. Right. That that's kind of the, that's kind of the vibe.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So you got a couple of new demos this time. What did you actually get
Speaker 1:  to see and try at ia?
Speaker 10:  No new demos for me. I think this is the, the public unveiling
Speaker 10:  of what demos they're comfortable letting out into the
Speaker 10:  world with minimal guardrails. Okay. It was actually
Speaker 10:  really funny because I came in my sneakers and running shorts
Speaker 10:  under a skirt as soon as the keynote was done, I used all of my training
Speaker 10:  to run to the demo. I got there and they
Speaker 10:  were like, you've got five minutes with everything. And I was like, oh my
Speaker 10:  God, that's not a lot of time. Right? And I think that's on purpose, not
Speaker 10:  only because this was the thing that everyone was gonna wanna try, but because
Speaker 10:  you know, as they said on the keynote on stage when they did the live AI
Speaker 10:  translations, it stuck out to me 'cause they're like, this is a risky demo
Speaker 10:  because these are risky demos. Live AI demos are always going to be risky,
Speaker 10:  but inherently so in a device that Google is known for failing
Speaker 10:  at. So the demos I got in Wuhan,
Speaker 10:  I was like, oh, here we go again. This is like what I saw in December. This
Speaker 10:  is a Android flavored Apple Vision pro
Speaker 10:  that is much, much, much, much, much, much like 10 times more comfortable
Speaker 10:  to wear.
Speaker 1:  Interesting. Okay.
Speaker 10:  But the demo I got in there was not particularly special as
Speaker 10:  like, I have a problem. 'cause I saw all of it. I saw
Speaker 10:  all of it. I think what's important is what they chose to let people
Speaker 10:  try. And so what they're choosing to let people try is talking to
Speaker 10:  Gemini in some very guided ways. Okay. And
Speaker 10:  then for the headset it was like,
Speaker 10:  here's a ability for you to ask Gemini to take you
Speaker 10:  to a place without opening the Google Maps app. But it's gonna take you
Speaker 10:  there contextually and then you can look around. Okay. And then
Speaker 10:  the other thing is like, also we know people wanna use headsets for immersive
Speaker 10:  content. What if we took a video that was filmed on a drone
Speaker 10:  and made it 3D eh, eh, eh, spatializing, eh,
Speaker 10:  eh, that that, that was the, the Wuhan demo I got. Which
Speaker 10:  I don't think is gonna convince people of Android xr. I really don't think
Speaker 10:  that's what's gonna, I actually think the lighter form factor is what is
Speaker 10:  gonna make people go like, oh, okay, vision Pro. Very cool,
Speaker 10:  but wearable. So I think that's kind of the takeaway I had from
Speaker 10:  Moan. Again, solidified And the glasses. The glasses
Speaker 10:  is what everyone was just like, move aside project moan.
Speaker 10:  I'll get to you later. The glasses. Let me have the glasses. And
Speaker 10:  that was interesting because the three
Speaker 10:  demos that they had, everyone try, I think were very intentional and
Speaker 10:  purposeful. So one of the demos was, Hey, there's two paintings in
Speaker 10:  here. Ask Gemini facts about those paintings. And you
Speaker 10:  can ask it questions contextually, like compare these two paintings.
Speaker 10:  There was one that was very brightly colored and pointless. And another
Speaker 10:  that was just like, you know, like in TV shows where they wanna
Speaker 10:  show you that the person is sad now. So everything is in like cool lighting.
Speaker 10:  Sure. That was that, that was that picture. And you know, you, you go
Speaker 10:  like, hey, you tap the side, the, the side arm and it brings up
Speaker 10:  Gemini Live and I think it was Gemini Live at least. And you know, you can
Speaker 10:  see the little display in one of the lenses and it,
Speaker 10:  it's like, Hey, yeah, I, you have the little animation that shows that it's
Speaker 10:  listening and then it gives you captain obvious
Speaker 10:  observations. Like Right. You know, if you're a seeing person, if you're
Speaker 10:  not a seeing person, then that might be very helpful what it's describing
Speaker 10:  to you. But for me they were just like, oh, the, the picture on the right
Speaker 10:  is brightly colored. It has pointalism in it and the picture on the left
Speaker 10:  has moodier subdued hues. And I was like, yes.
Speaker 1:  It's on the level of like, you point the camera at a bag of nuts
Speaker 1:  that says nuts in large letters and it tells you it's a bag of nuts. It's
Speaker 1:  like, yes, it's not unimpressive technology, but it's not
Speaker 1:  hard work. Right. Like this, this is stuff we know we have solved. And I
Speaker 1:  think it, it sounds like that's a lot of what you're saying here. It's like
Speaker 1:  what you've described is a bunch of things that Google has known it's very
Speaker 1:  good at for a while and is actually
Speaker 1:  now just trying to do inside of glasses, which does present new kinds of
Speaker 1:  problems. Right. The cameras and the processing, all that stuff that's new
Speaker 1:  and different stuff. So the fact that even the easy stuff works is not nothing,
Speaker 1:  but it's also not, you have not invented a new thing
Speaker 1:  if you just give me a new way to do my camera.
Speaker 10:  Yes. So these are very, very tightly controlled and like short,
Speaker 10:  purposefully, short demos that we were getting at this event.
Speaker 10:  The other one in December were much longer you were like able to ask
Speaker 10:  Gemini to do more impressive things. Like one was you could look at a
Speaker 10:  bookshelf and the glasses would remember the books that you saw. So
Speaker 10:  if you left and you went, oh hey, what was that book that I
Speaker 10:  saw in yellow? Like the yellow cover, what was the title of that? It would
Speaker 10:  be able to remember that for you. And that is something if you're forgetful,
Speaker 10:  you'd be like, oh, maybe I would use that if I could remember to use that.
Speaker 10:  But you know, that that is something that feels a little more magical and
Speaker 10:  not something that we were able to try. Right. In this like setting where
Speaker 10:  people are finally allowed to take photos of the prototype where they're
Speaker 10:  finally allowed to try the prototypes and they're finally allowed to take
Speaker 10:  video of people trying these prototypes. Another thing like
Speaker 10:  a slightly modified version of that demo that I got where they had all these
Speaker 10:  travel books on a shelf and they were like, why don't you try
Speaker 10:  asking Gemini which book you should read based on like
Speaker 10:  your preferences. So, you know, I come up with a persona and I go, Hey,
Speaker 10:  I am planning a trip to Japan. I'm not an outdoorsy person. Which of these
Speaker 10:  travel guides is gonna be most helpful for me? And I picked one. Okay. And
Speaker 10:  I'm like, cool. I guess that's helpful. If you're
Speaker 10:  in a bookstore and you're like, I don't know which one of these books to
Speaker 10:  choose, why don't you choose that one for me? So
Speaker 10:  ostensibly you could do that, but
Speaker 1:  Well, but again, it's, it's the, the, the little bits of rails there I think
Speaker 1:  are what's so interesting. 'cause it's like, It is one thing to do that from
Speaker 1:  a series of travel guides. It is another thing entirely to
Speaker 1:  just be in a room or a bookstore or whatever and be like,
Speaker 1:  I'm going to Japan. What in this Barnes and Noble should I read? Which is
Speaker 1:  like that that's the thing. Yeah. Right. If you're already standing in front
Speaker 1:  of the shelf of travel guides, the the question of do I look at the
Speaker 1:  Japan travel guide for my Japan trip is not interesting user
Speaker 1:  interface stuff. But I think like, this is
Speaker 1:  not to like diminish what's happening here. All of this is like a stepping
Speaker 1:  stone to that. And I think this is where I go back to the, the sort
Speaker 1:  of point counterpoint between all of the stuff Google was announcing at
Speaker 1:  IO and these glasses. 'cause like all of the Project ASRA stuff, and you
Speaker 1:  and I have talked about this before, all of that is smart glasses, right?
Speaker 1:  The idea that this thing can be on all the time and seeing everything that
Speaker 1:  I'm seeing and listening is like, and and sort of proactively piping
Speaker 1:  up when it has something to tell me or remembering what all the books are
Speaker 1:  and then telling me later, like that's all the stuff they're working on with
Speaker 1:  Astra. This like universal AI assistant. All of that is for smart glasses.
Speaker 1:  And they've said as much like, I talked to the team that's building this
Speaker 1:  and they were like, we're doing it for phones and smart glasses. But it's
Speaker 1:  pretty clear to us that the best version of this thing works
Speaker 1:  on smart glasses. Because you can see all the things you see and hear all
Speaker 1:  the things you hear. It makes perfect sense. But It is so painfully clear
Speaker 1:  that putting those two things together, the glasses and
Speaker 1:  the AI and the underlying like sensing technology,
Speaker 1:  all the pieces of that are happening. But the, the shoving them together
Speaker 1:  I think is gonna be way harder than most people are reckoning with. It's
Speaker 10:  Gonna be much harder, the parts exist, but the problem is that the
Speaker 10:  parts have existed for a really long time. It's just putting together that's
Speaker 10:  very difficult. And then on top of that, you know,
Speaker 10:  the problem with all of this is that I've seen it. Have you seen it?
Speaker 10:  Do you get it? Do you get why these people are so gung-ho about it? Because
Speaker 10:  I can describe it to you, I can describe it to you at length, I can describe
Speaker 10:  it to you in detail. You just don't fully
Speaker 10:  get it. You know? And Yep. You know the readers are just like, well isn't
Speaker 10:  your job to describe that to us? And I'm like, yes I am. But what I'm
Speaker 10:  trying to convey to you is that I can be
Speaker 10:  the most descriptive person in the world. I can hype it up
Speaker 10:  so much. You're still not going to get it until you put
Speaker 10:  a pair of glasses on. And then when you put the pair of glasses on, you
Speaker 10:  still may not be convinced because the tech is so nascent at this point
Speaker 10:  in time, our brains and our cultural cues have not evolved to the point
Speaker 10:  where we naturally think, oh yeah, this is what I'm gonna ask it
Speaker 10:  to do. Like within the whole keynote and the whole demo, the thing that
Speaker 10:  I was like, aha, this is what's gonna get people to think
Speaker 10:  about the possibilities, was that demo of the guy trying to fix
Speaker 10:  his bike and just going like, pull this up. Hey, I'm looking at this.
Speaker 10:  What do I need to do right there? Because like if you're trying to solve
Speaker 10:  that, now what are you doing? You're pulling up YouTube videos, you're trying
Speaker 10:  to sort between the five different YouTube videos doing the same thing all
Speaker 10:  with the same tedious two minute intro where you're just like, just get
Speaker 10:  me to the part that I need to know. And then you're having to physically
Speaker 10:  reference other stuff, you know? And it's saying that it's gonna do that
Speaker 10:  seamlessly for you based on what you're seeing. So that part,
Speaker 10:  I think everyone can look at that and go, Hey, I think there's a time where
Speaker 10:  I would've loved that to be easier with less friction.
Speaker 10:  So that yes, people will get that. And that's why they did the low
Speaker 10:  vision and blind use cases scenario there too. Because that is
Speaker 10:  another clear cut thing where you go, oh, now
Speaker 10:  I get why we might want smart glasses for this very specific subset of
Speaker 10:  people who it could very much help. And those are the kinds of things that
Speaker 10:  you need to get normal people on board. Whereas like
Speaker 10:  the, so the final third demo that I got that they were ready
Speaker 10:  to share publicly and they think is going to convince people that this
Speaker 10:  is, this is it was the fact that you can take a picture with the glasses,
Speaker 10:  which no bigs snap glasses have been doing that. Metal ray band glasses
Speaker 10:  have been doing that. The difference now is there's a display. So you snap
Speaker 10:  the photo and you can see what it looks like. You get a preview. And the
Speaker 10:  problem with the Meta ray bands for a lot of content creators is that there's
Speaker 10:  no framing, right? So like when I tested the Ray bands, I noticed that
Speaker 10:  I tilt my head a lot because all of my photos had an unintentional Dutch
Speaker 10:  angle. I was like, Ooh,
Speaker 1:  I'm so glad that's not just me. That's exactly been my experience too, is
Speaker 1:  like every time I think my head is straight, it turns out my head is actually
Speaker 1:  at like a 20 degree angle.
Speaker 10:  You know, it's at, it's at an angle. I, I was like, oh, I must be such a
Speaker 10:  thoughtful person 'cause I'm at an angle and I'm thinking so hard about
Speaker 10:  what I'm looking at or you know, I realized that if you're
Speaker 10:  gonna wear glass smart glasses where the camera's usually in the hinges
Speaker 10:  so far, you really shouldn't have bangs or you should tie your
Speaker 10:  hair back. Sure, yeah. Because there were so many pictures where just pieces
Speaker 10:  of my hair were ruining the framing in the shot. So if you have a display,
Speaker 10:  you take the shot, you see what the picture's gonna look like and you can
Speaker 10:  go, oh, I've tilted my head. Let me just straighten my head and get this
Speaker 10:  photo again. So, and it happens in a blink of a second. It's like really
Speaker 10:  cool. It's a small thing, but it's also a thing that
Speaker 10:  they're very subtly like, Hey, you know who can't do that just yet?
Speaker 10:  Meta Meta, yeah. We got the display. Yeah, I,
Speaker 1:  I'm fascinated by how all of these companies
Speaker 1:  are gonna try to use those tiny screens because like the screens aren't very
Speaker 1:  good, at least in the, the demos that I've gotten in the past. Maybe these
Speaker 1:  are better, but in general the screens mostly suck, but they're there
Speaker 1:  and so you, you have to figure out what you can do. But even the thing you
Speaker 1:  described where like it shows the animation that Gemini is listening to you.
Speaker 1:  Like I instinctively hate that because I'm like, actually your job is to
Speaker 1:  not put interface in my way while something
Speaker 1:  is not happening. Right. That that's the equivalent of like putting a loading
Speaker 1:  screen in front of my face 24 hours a day. Like that's bad. I don't want
Speaker 1:  that. But the like one second to frame your shot
Speaker 1:  as you're taking a photo makes a ton of sense to me. And it's like, this
Speaker 1:  is the thing I think is so interesting about smart glasses in general is
Speaker 1:  we're just gonna have to make a million of those decisions about how
Speaker 1:  everything is supposed to work all the time because it should be as little
Speaker 1:  screen as possible, but you also need the screen for lots of things.
Speaker 1:  And I think like that getting that balance right I think is like kind of
Speaker 1:  the whole product ballgame with a lot of this stuff.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. We're at the spaghetti phase 'cause I don't think we know what we
Speaker 10:  want fully. The other thing that they're trying to do is heads up display.
Speaker 10:  So they're talking about Google maps and this isn't exactly
Speaker 10:  the scenario you're talking about, David, where you know your, your head's
Speaker 10:  up. They're only gonna give you the little kind of, if you have a heads
Speaker 10:  up display in a car, you probably know what I'm talking about. Where it's
Speaker 10:  just like 500 feet in a, in an arrow in a tiny little display in the
Speaker 10:  peripheral of your vision. And then when you look down it morphs
Speaker 10:  into a little map. Oh see? So you, you can kind of get
Speaker 10:  a little, a little sense. Some people I talked to were like, I don't, I
Speaker 10:  don't know if I like that 'cause I wanna see the map, I wanna see the blue
Speaker 10:  arrow floating in the sky. And I was like, I don't wanna see that. I want
Speaker 10:  something less obtrusive. I wanna, if I'm, if I'm trying to get
Speaker 10:  out of a New York subway, I never know what is up down north south once
Speaker 10:  I get out of the subway. 'cause I've emerged from the, the infrastructural
Speaker 10:  depths of hell and I, I wanna know what direction I go in if
Speaker 10:  I could just look down and go like, oh I'm supposed to go that way. Cool.
Speaker 10:  And then have like a guide of where I'm supposed to go So I can stay
Speaker 10:  interacted with my surroundings. That, that feels like a good use
Speaker 10:  to me. But I, I met so many people who are like, I want the big blue
Speaker 10:  arrow floating in space. I wanna see that. And you know,
Speaker 10:  the prototypes that we saw, they were only one type
Speaker 10:  of prototype that I know Google has. Because when I went from my
Speaker 10:  December hands-on where we were not allowed to have photos, we were not
Speaker 10:  allowed to have cameras. We could just only see and I, I almost feel like
Speaker 10:  I was gaslit into thinking did this exist? Did I see that? Because
Speaker 10:  I wasn't able to take anything but my own written experience and recording
Speaker 10:  and my notes out of that. I saw binocular versions.
Speaker 10:  I saw versions that were sunglasses, you know, so it's clear
Speaker 10:  that they're trying to refine what this display is gonna look like because
Speaker 10:  the ones that we all got shown in public was the
Speaker 10:  monocular single lens display in one of the lenses.
Speaker 10:  Okay. But I saw versions where there were two one in each and
Speaker 10:  that allows a much bigger screen to appear that gives you
Speaker 10:  more options. Like I saw a wild demo back in December where
Speaker 10:  you could just like really kind of watch a movie
Speaker 10:  inside of your smart glasses. Was it good? No, it has the same all the,
Speaker 10:  it was like the same problems that maybe watching a movie on a
Speaker 10:  projector in your living room versus on an actual TV has a lot of that same
Speaker 10:  issue, you know? And I asked them, Hey how did you solve the ambient
Speaker 10:  light question? That's my gotcha question. And more people have better answers
Speaker 10:  to that in the last few years than they have ever with regard to smart glasses.
Speaker 10:  And they say, oh you know it has ambient light sensors, it'll be
Speaker 10:  able to adjust the brightness based on where you're at. And I was like,
Speaker 10:  cool, but we are in a tiny little room right now. We're not doing these
Speaker 10:  demos outside in direct sunlight. Right. This is what I mean by guardrails
Speaker 10:  controlled, trying to bottle the magic. I heard
Speaker 10:  references to Iron Man and Jarvis because
Speaker 10:  ironically I think Tony Stark looms large over our
Speaker 10:  imagination of what smart glasses ought to. Very much so. Yeah. So like
Speaker 10:  you should be having Jarvis in your glasses, it should be able to
Speaker 10:  project all this information. And then the reality is, is that
Speaker 10:  that's not where we're at. We're probably more in the, I'm gonna say the
Speaker 10:  Kingsman exy scenario where you have a pair of smart glasses that look very
Speaker 10:  discreet and you can see green holograms is like one
Speaker 10:  that these are actual glasses that people at CES brought where you can see
Speaker 10:  like green light. Totally. 'cause that's their answer to
Speaker 10:  ambient light. And I'm just gonna say it, it's the spaghetti phase.
Speaker 10:  Everyone does not know what people actually want or
Speaker 10:  what they will actually buy or what their reservations are. So they're like,
Speaker 10:  here, here's a version with a display. Here's a version that's just audio.
Speaker 10:  Here's a version with camera, here's a version with a, where the camera
Speaker 10:  is in the nose bridge, what are we gonna call smart glasses? Is
Speaker 10:  everything going to be called a smart glass? Because here's another interesting
Speaker 10:  tidbit in the developer keynote. So not the main keynote, the developer
Speaker 10:  keynote X reel was announced to have the first official
Speaker 10:  Android XR pair of, I'm gonna call them smart
Speaker 10:  glasses, but were they allowed to call it smart glasses? I don't know because
Speaker 10:  their press release said optical see-through XR
Speaker 10:  device. Huh. So not glasses but if you look at them they're glasses
Speaker 1:  XR device. I don't even know what to make of that sentence.
Speaker 10:  Well what's an optical see-through XR device that you wear on your face?
Speaker 10:  It's glasses, right? Like that's it's it's optical. It's, you can see through
Speaker 10:  it but you know XR X reels made a a name for
Speaker 10:  itself making like little portable screens that you carry around that happen
Speaker 10:  to look like glasses that you have to plug into another device and it's
Speaker 10:  just like a portable monitor that you can bring around. Yeah, this version
Speaker 10:  we have very few details. They didn't have it on hand. They were there but
Speaker 10:  they didn't have it on hand. And the render shows cameras
Speaker 10:  in the nose bridge, which we haven't seen yet. We haven't seen cameras in
Speaker 10:  the nose bridge just yet. So I'm like ooh that's interesting.
Speaker 1:  So it's like if you're imagining you're cross-eyed and that's how you take
Speaker 1:  pictures, I love that.
Speaker 10:  Or just trying to get beyond the bangs problem. Fair to be quite frank.
Speaker 10:  So it's interesting, it's an interesting
Speaker 10:  reclamation of Google's history with this particular form
Speaker 10:  factor as well because I Google, you ain't fooling me. That
Speaker 10:  keynote comes out there, you have Azadi out on
Speaker 10:  stage and he is like, we've been in this space for 10 years. I was like,
Speaker 10:  really? 'cause I really do feel like you tried to bury that under the
Speaker 10:  enterprise tech carpet for a good number of years.
Speaker 1:  It's so funny you bring this up. I was thinking about that as they were saying
Speaker 1:  this. So I was like is when was the last time Google willingly acknowledged
Speaker 1:  the existence of Google Glass? And I think it a, it's actually a
Speaker 1:  lot longer than 10 years Friend OS and B,
Speaker 1:  you spent like eight of those 10 years trying to get everybody to forget
Speaker 1:  that you had ever done any of this in the first place.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, it it like from the outside it looks like, oh,
Speaker 10:  oh the Meadow Ray bands are people actually want
Speaker 10:  that. Oh well you know we got like these 20 years of notes
Speaker 10:  and research and partnerships like let's get back on that, that train,
Speaker 1:  It's actually the most Google thing in the world, right? Yeah. This is the
Speaker 1:  same company that like invented all of the important technology behind
Speaker 1:  chat GPT and then chat GPT launched and Google was like, you want that?
Speaker 1:  Oh we can do that. People like this. Sure we'll make a product
Speaker 1:  out of that. But I think on the glasses front, the the other piece of news
Speaker 1:  that I think I I found even more interesting than the RA stuff is some of
Speaker 1:  the partnership stuff that yes Google announced about who they're making
Speaker 1:  glasses with and these are companies you know a lot more about than I do.
Speaker 1:  Can you just like set in context who these partners are for Google?
Speaker 10:  So the big two that they announced on stage are Gentle Monster
Speaker 10:  and Warby Parker. I'm gonna guess most people Forge
Speaker 10:  listeners
Speaker 10:  probably may not know about Gentle Monster. You know, Gentle Monster
Speaker 10:  if one you are Korean because every Korean person,
Speaker 10:  their mother turns to them and goes, did you know that company was Korean?
Speaker 10:  And so that's how I actually know interesting about Gentle Monster because
Speaker 10:  it's a big brand in Korea and it's super
Speaker 10:  popular with Luxury Ho Couture.
Speaker 10:  You have 100% seen Gentle Monster glasses
Speaker 10:  because Kendrick wears them. Kendrick Lamar wears them, Beyonce wears them,
Speaker 10:  Rihanna wears them. Billie Eilish wears them.
Speaker 10:  Everybody famous who has worn kind of a weird
Speaker 10:  silhouette, cool pair of sunglasses or glasses
Speaker 10:  in the last, I wanna say 10 years guarantee you one of them is
Speaker 10:  probably Gentle Monster.
Speaker 1:  I'm looking at this collection now and Gentle Monster, they have a bunch
Speaker 1:  of the like very skinny sort of like
Speaker 1:  vaguely like Blade Runner futuristic looking ones that
Speaker 1:  you're right, I've seen on like you, you you see red carpets everywhere filled
Speaker 1:  with this like there's like slightly wide, slightly skinny
Speaker 1:  glasses that, and now I'm thinking a lot of these are probably Gentle Monster
Speaker 10:  Or or if you see someone with extremely large
Speaker 10:  glasses, like extremely like don't talk to me,
Speaker 10:  these are obscenely large S sunglasses, those are also Gentle Monster.
Speaker 10:  Love it. Okay. They're very artsy-fartsy,
Speaker 10:  edgy, bold, that kind of vibe. So that's, that's an
Speaker 10:  interesting pick.
Speaker 1:  So like less mainstream than Ray Band but maybe like
Speaker 1:  cooler than RayBan at the moment.
Speaker 10:  Yes. Okay. Interesting. Busier than RayBan. Yeah. Much bigger
Speaker 10:  with Gen Z.
Speaker 1:  That seems like a big win for Google. If you can't be like Meta and get
Speaker 1:  s sort Luxottica and have all of the glasses that exist in the universe as
Speaker 1:  your partners, this is what you do. Right? Instead
Speaker 1:  of like try to go and Warby Parker is the other partner. And I think this,
Speaker 1:  it's like that's more along the lines of what I would've expected Google
Speaker 1:  to do, which is not a ding, but Warby Parker is like very straightforward,
Speaker 1:  very kind of like earnest regular people glasses and
Speaker 1:  that's fine and like Warby Parker is like a very
Speaker 1:  millennial company for millennials and that's fine, but what, what
Speaker 1:  you need if you're Google is something that is the like absolute cultural
Speaker 1:  opposite of Google Glass and Gentle Monster from the way you described it
Speaker 1:  sound like about as close to that as there might be right now.
Speaker 10:  Yeah and my conspiracy theory is that they got it because they're partnering
Speaker 10:  with Samsung. So you know, Samsung is an
Speaker 10:  institution in Korea, It is responsible for a huge
Speaker 10:  chunk of the country's GDP. There's a saying in Korea that if
Speaker 10:  Samsung's knees the whole country shakes, like that's the cultural cachet
Speaker 10:  that Samsung has in Korea.
Speaker 1:  So we're gonna start seeing like K-pop s bands wearing moan pretty
Speaker 1:  soon is what you're saying. Like that's coming,
Speaker 10:  You know, honest to God probably yes. You'll see BT S is
Speaker 10:  back from the Army. You're gonna see John Cook in, in Moan probably Stray
Speaker 10:  Kids as well. Grag, these are, if you know K-pop, these are huge
Speaker 10:  names that I'm, I'm listing right now. But you know, Gentle Monster has
Speaker 10:  done these huge celeb collabs. They know how to be like, we are the
Speaker 10:  artsy one, we are the cool one. And I think from a strategic
Speaker 10:  perspective, what you're seeing here is they're going accessibility,
Speaker 10:  affordability, and people not wanting to look crazy
Speaker 10:  with Warby Parker. That's a great play. Especially
Speaker 10:  because Warby Parker is direct to consumer, right? Right. So
Speaker 10:  it's easier than having to go to your LensCrafter, which is what I have
Speaker 10:  to do with a lot of Cel Luxottica stuff because that's
Speaker 10:  their thing. And RayBan's, the Ray band to Warby Parker is probably more
Speaker 10:  of a one-to-one in terms of classic frames. Yes, that's right. Things that
Speaker 10:  that are, you know, people aren't gonna be afraid to wear, but
Speaker 10:  then they're trying to get this cool, this cachet of cool with
Speaker 10:  Gentle Monster that I don't know if RayBan
Speaker 10:  and Meta fully have that because the rumor is that they're gonna go
Speaker 10:  with Oakley's for their next thing and that's just targeting
Speaker 10:  the athletes. Right. And, and, and I guess dads in Texas, which
Speaker 1:  Makes sense, but it's a very different play than this one.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, it's a very different play. I think it's a very interesting one. I
Speaker 10:  think Maui Jim was another brand that was kind of mentioned
Speaker 10:  under the, I forget the name of the, the company that they're working with
Speaker 10:  in their umbrella of eyewear, but Maui gym are, they're,
Speaker 10:  they're also sunglasses that are au wears. So you know, they're kind of
Speaker 10:  going for that Yeah. Vibe as well, which is smart because
Speaker 10:  the, the biggest eyewear brand in the world is Essilor Luxottica.
Speaker 1:  I agree. All right, I'm gonna let you go here, but before we do, I
Speaker 1:  need to know what you think about this Johnny, ive Sam Altman thing I'm losing
Speaker 10:  Last
Speaker 1:  Week. We think it's not smart glasses. The the the, the winds seem to be
Speaker 1:  saying it's not smart glasses. People tell lies all the time. It might
Speaker 1:  still be smart glasses, you never know, but what, what is your like
Speaker 1:  earliest read on what you think this thing is?
Speaker 10:  So here's what we know, right? It's not glasses 'cause they've kind of outright
Speaker 10:  said it's not glasses sort
Speaker 1:  Of, again, people tell lies but I people, people tell lies it does all
Speaker 1:  existing evidence points to it's not glasses.
Speaker 10:  Yeah. Joni, I've kind of shaded humane and
Speaker 10:  rabbit. If he's gonna go that far to shade them and say those are bad products,
Speaker 10:  probably not in that vein. Right.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Can I, can I just very quickly make the opposite case of that?
Speaker 10:  Okay, yeah, sure.
Speaker 1:  That's Apple's thing, right? Like what, what Johnny I did is the equivalent
Speaker 1:  of putting up the slide of all the ugly smartphones before you announce your
Speaker 1:  own smartphone. I, I'm just, I'm not ruling it out. I think the funniest
Speaker 1:  possible outcome would be if they just made it a nicer looking humane pin,
Speaker 1:  which I still think is possible.
Speaker 10:  So I'm cor I sort of was just like, oh, they're not gonna do a pin because
Speaker 10:  he, he shot on the pin and then the more details that
Speaker 10:  slowly trickle out, I'm just sort of like, oh, he's not doing humane pin,
Speaker 10:  he's doing plot, he's doing the plot notin. Hmm.
Speaker 1:  That's
Speaker 10:  A good tip. 'cause that's, that's kind of where I'm landing
Speaker 10:  at now because let's think of the components that go into AI
Speaker 10:  hardware as we know it now that companies seem to be
Speaker 10:  converging on, they kind of want it to be screenless
Speaker 10:  because as we've just spent a great amount of time talking about, no one
Speaker 10:  can, no one can agree on what the displays should be or how it should look.
Speaker 10:  So cut that out of the equation. No display. Yep. And also
Speaker 10:  you probably don't wanna do the humane thing where you make people
Speaker 10:  pay for a separate phone LTE connection thing. No one wants that. So
Speaker 10:  correct. Let's have it connect through your phone or another device. They're
Speaker 10:  saying it's the third device you buy because the first is gonna be a computer,
Speaker 10:  the second is gonna be your phone or you could reverse that order. So this
Speaker 10:  is the third device we want you to have. We want it to fit in your pocket
Speaker 10:  but also on your desk. But also maybe you could wear it around your neck
Speaker 10:  and I'm landing on the PLA note pin or B, that
Speaker 10:  vein of device, but make it Joni. Ive make it beautiful,
Speaker 10:  make it less stupid compared to Humane under
Speaker 10:  Promise what it can do.
Speaker 10:  But flaunt the fact that it's with OpenAI officially.
Speaker 10:  You get the subscription to OpenAI and they send you this hardware, it could
Speaker 10:  sit on your desk, it that can fit in your pocket and you can wear it, but
Speaker 10:  it doesn't need to be wearable. That's I'm landing on
Speaker 10:  something that looks and feels like the Claude note pin,
Speaker 10:  which let's face it, that's kind of the category that's gaining buzz
Speaker 10:  outside of glasses.
Speaker 1:  Fair enough. All right v thank you as always. We gotta take a break and then
Speaker 1:  we're gonna come back and take a collection from The Vergecast hotline. V
Speaker 1:  Go Sleep. I'll see you soon.
Speaker 10:  Ah, thank you for letting me ramble.
Speaker 1:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Let's do a question from The Vergecast hotline. As
Speaker 1:  always, the number is 8 6 6 VERGE one one. The email is vergecast at The
Speaker 1:  Verge dot com. We love hearing from you. Thank you by the way, to everybody
Speaker 1:  who's reached out with responses to Allison's question about phone therapy.
Speaker 1:  If you're going through a phone conundrum, we want to hear from you. We've
Speaker 1:  gotten some really fun questions. That's gonna be a super fun episode this
Speaker 1:  summer, so keep 'em coming, keep calling, keep emailing this time.
Speaker 1:  I have one that I actually got a bunch of emails and calls about just in
Speaker 1:  the last like couple of days since this news dropped. Lemme just read you
Speaker 1:  one email. This comes from Blake. It says, I've been using pockets since
Speaker 1:  it was called Read It Later. The news that Mozilla is shutting it down is
Speaker 1:  sad but not surprising. Agree and agree. By the way, other alternatives
Speaker 1:  I've tried like Matter or read Wise, I've bounced off of. Is that the main
Speaker 1:  recommendation now or what should I be trying to migrate my read Readit later
Speaker 1:  workflow into additional context? I do desktop reading in a chromium based
Speaker 1:  browser. Arc Edge Chrome Most people do and mobile and Safari
Speaker 1:  and ideally want a nice native app. I use Reader Classic for Feedly and
Speaker 1:  Pocket. So I guess if I wanna keep using that then my options are limited
Speaker 1:  to iCloud or Instapaper and the latter of which definitely won't be around
Speaker 1:  forever either. Thanks Blake. Okay, I have
Speaker 1:  five answers to the what should you replace
Speaker 1:  Pocket with question and I will say there are, there are two different things
Speaker 1:  people use an app like this for and I'm a big believer in both of them, but
Speaker 1:  they have different answers. So the one version of
Speaker 1:  a pocket user is somebody who just like uses it to dump links into. It's
Speaker 1:  like a searchable bookmarking system for that
Speaker 1:  pocket was never really the best option. And I think there are many better
Speaker 1:  options out there if you're an Apple user. There are apps like Any
Speaker 1:  Box and good links that do that more specifically, there's also one called
Speaker 1:  Pliny that I like, but the one that I recommend to most people
Speaker 1:  is called Raindrop dot io. It's basically a bookmarking service
Speaker 1:  but it works on every platform you can think of. It's really easy to share
Speaker 1:  stuff to. It is very good search. It has desktop apps, it's really good for
Speaker 1:  exporting, which I think is really important. You can get stuff out of it
Speaker 1:  really easily. It does cost money for some of the
Speaker 1:  main features, but the free tier I think is actually plenty for most people.
Speaker 1:  So that's where I would start you if you're just like, where do I put all
Speaker 1:  of my links? I still think browser bookmarks are a terrible
Speaker 1:  and underused system. I don't recommend that I would start you with
Speaker 1:  Raindrop and see where you get. But if you want a place to like read
Speaker 1:  articles, there are a bunch of possibilities. One is like
Speaker 1:  use the reading mode in your browser and that's fine. But I
Speaker 1:  don't think that's the answer. Like if that's all you need, terrific. But
Speaker 1:  I I, I don't think that's all people who are looking for a way to replace
Speaker 1:  Pocket actually need. So lemme just go in order of
Speaker 1:  chaos. I guess the simplest version is Instapaper
Speaker 1:  and Blake mentioned it but I think Blake and I disagree on
Speaker 1:  whether Instapaper is gonna be around for a while. So Instapaper has been
Speaker 1:  through kind of a weird history. It was one of the earliest apps in this
Speaker 1:  space. It eventually sold to Pinterest.
Speaker 1:  It has like morphed over the years through a couple
Speaker 1:  of different owners, but now the guy who owns it and runs It is
Speaker 1:  this guy named Brian Donahue who has been doing it for a long time. He's
Speaker 1:  very serious about It, is doing a really good job. The app kind of languished
Speaker 1:  for a while but has really come up recently. And I think in terms of just
Speaker 1:  basic, I would like a nice reading experience offline on my phone to read
Speaker 1:  articles. Instagram, Francisco as it gets, again, there's a premium tier
Speaker 1:  that you have to pay for if you want, but a lot of the stuff that you need
Speaker 1:  is in the free tier. So I would say actually most people who are looking
Speaker 1:  for somewhere to go from Pocket, I would send you to Instapaper.
Speaker 1:  Option number two is an app called Matter and Matter
Speaker 1:  is amazing and beautiful and really clever and has some really
Speaker 1:  interesting AI features, but it has one big downside, which is that It is
Speaker 1:  expensive and It is Apple products only. So if you're on your
Speaker 1:  iPhone and your iPad and the web and that's where you wanna do all of your
Speaker 1:  stuff, fine. But if you are cross-platform or want desktop stuff,
Speaker 1:  you're just sort of stuck going elsewhere. So that's option number two. Option
Speaker 1:  number three is Readwise Reader, which I
Speaker 1:  think is the best and most powerful reading app out there. It's the
Speaker 1:  one that I use but also like I read and research for a living. So
Speaker 1:  I need much more than a lot of people. I really like the way that it does
Speaker 1:  highlighting. I like the way that it integrates with lots of other apps So
Speaker 1:  I can get my highlights out into my note taking app. I like all the organizational
Speaker 1:  systems that it has. I like the way that you can also add PDFs and you can
Speaker 1:  add books and you can search through all the text of everything and It is
Speaker 1:  like the app is not attractive and it feels
Speaker 1:  like a work app if that makes sense. It's much closer to like a
Speaker 1:  B2B SaaS piece of software than to like a
Speaker 1:  lovely little reading app. But for my purposes
Speaker 1:  it does the job. It has a great speech thing that
Speaker 1:  lets you read articles out loud. It's expensive like some of these other
Speaker 1:  ones, but It is, I think for my money, the best one on the market.
Speaker 1:  That's option number three. Option number four is an app called
Speaker 1:  Walla Bag. And Walla Bag is different than the other ones in the sense that
Speaker 1:  It is an open source project that is kind of meant to be
Speaker 1:  self-hosted. And the upside of Walla Bag is that means no one can take it
Speaker 1:  away from you. You can run it pretty easily. It's really easy to spin up
Speaker 1:  on your own hardware. It's a, I don know, it's like a fine
Speaker 1:  app. It's not great looking, but it's fine. It does the job
Speaker 1:  and if you are willing to do a little bit of work, It is a much more future
Speaker 1:  proof way to roll something like this for yourself. I think that's
Speaker 1:  way more work than most people want to do. But if you wanna do the work,
Speaker 1:  Walla Bag is a great place to start. Then the last
Speaker 1:  option I would offer you is I think to try
Speaker 1:  and combine a Relator app with an RSS reader.
Speaker 1:  My guess is if you're a person who uses something like Pocket, you're also
Speaker 1:  a person who might use something like Feedly or Feed Bin
Speaker 1:  or one of these other apps that lets you sort of put all of the things
Speaker 1:  that you care about into one place. I really recommend doing that by the
Speaker 1:  way, I, I have been using Feed bin for years and love it to pieces and recommend
Speaker 1:  it to everybody. But many of these things have a place that you can
Speaker 1:  manually send an article into your RSS reader and it just treats it like
Speaker 1:  another feed of articles that you've saved. That's really useful in the sense
Speaker 1:  that it, It is yet more stuff all in one place. The problem with a lot of
Speaker 1:  these read later apps is it just turns into another inbox to check and as
Speaker 1:  the list of stuff to read gets longer, you wanna check it less. And so it
Speaker 1:  just becomes this like thousands of things. Long list of stuff you're never
Speaker 1:  gonna read, not bad. But if you put it in the place where you're actually
Speaker 1:  reading the news all the day and you have this other feed of like, here's
Speaker 1:  the stuff I wanna get back to, I actually have found that that balance works
Speaker 1:  really well and there are a bunch of really beautiful read apps for
Speaker 1:  RSS, like Reader, R-E-E-D-E-R, and
Speaker 1:  you can kind of make that whole experience work. So I would tell
Speaker 1:  most people, if you're looking for somewhere to go from Pocket and you don't
Speaker 1:  have like a giant long list of additional feature requests, try instant paper
Speaker 1:  first and see how far that gets you. But for my money, if
Speaker 1:  you're willing to do the work and willing to spend the money, Readwise Reader
Speaker 1:  is the best one out there and I actually don't think it's super close.
Speaker 1:  I hope that helps. I'm very sad. Pocket is gone. Pocket did a lot of good
Speaker 1:  for a lot of people for a long time and it's a bummer to see it go,
Speaker 1:  but this is what happens.
Speaker 1:  Anyway, that's it for the show today. Thank you to everybody who came on
Speaker 1:  and thank you as always for listening. As ever, if you have thoughts, questions,
Speaker 1:  feelings, if you have smart glasses you want to tell us about. If
Speaker 1:  you are thinking about what's gonna happen at the end of all of these trials
Speaker 1:  and you have a theory that we haven't talked about yet, get at us. 8 6 6
Speaker 1:  VERGE one. One is the hotline. Vergecast at The Verge dot com is the email
Speaker 1:  address we love hearing from you. This show is produced by Will Poor Eric Gomez
Speaker 1:  and Brandon Keefer. The Vergecast is The Verge production and part of the
Speaker 1:  Vox Media podcast network. Neli and I'll be back on Friday to talk about
Speaker 1:  more stuff with Johnny Ivan OpenAI, all of the stuff we're hearing
Speaker 1:  leading up to WWDC and lots more. We'll see you then rock and
Speaker 1:  roll