# Transcript
ID: 3f52521e-d1ad-444f-963e-ea557c51a4ff
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5634961014875255901/-3994392368395356345/s93290-US-6633s-1740138618.mp3
Description: Lots of gadget news this week! David, Jake Kastrenakes, and Allison Johnson start by talking about the iPhone 16E, which is both the cheapest compelling iPhone in a long time and a deeply odd addition to Apple's phone lineup. They also discuss the end of the Humane AI Pin, the latest from the Rabbit R1, and whether AI gadgets are even going to be a thing. After that, it's time for the lightning round: David and Jake talk about Amazon Chime, Mira Murati's new startup, and the future of James Bond. Then, in a special DOGE lightning round, Lauren Feiner joins the show to discuss everything happening with Trump, Musk, DOGE, and the US government. Because there's a lot of it.
Speaker 5:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of the Humane
Speaker 5:  AI pin for what I assume will be the very last time I'm your friend
Speaker 5:  David Pierce. Neli is out on vacation somewhere. I don't even
Speaker 5:  know where he is. He's on a beach doing vacation things. He's gone. Jake
Speaker 5:  Kakis is here. Hi Jake. Hey, thanks for having me. It's been a minute. I'm
Speaker 5:  very happy you're back. Allison Johnson is also here. Hi Allison.
Speaker 6:  Hello
Speaker 5:  Allison. You're gonna hang with us for a while and then you're gonna go
Speaker 5:  do more fun things than hang with us. But we have a lot of stuff to talk
Speaker 5:  about. The Humane AI pin is dead and I think we
Speaker 5:  are obligated to spend several hours talking about that as the leading
Speaker 5:  publication on all things humane AI pin. There's a
Speaker 5:  new iPhone, Amazon Chime is dead, which no one has talked to me about
Speaker 5:  yet. And I have really strong feelings about that. I cannot wait to discuss.
Speaker 5:  There's a lot of politics stuff that we're gonna wait and get to at the very
Speaker 5:  end of the show. We are going to save as much Trump,
Speaker 5:  Elon DOGE stuff for the very end, and we're going to tell you when you can
Speaker 5:  stop listening If you don't want to hear it anymore. All that is coming.
Speaker 5:  Let's start with the iPhone. This is this, it's this like turned into sort
Speaker 5:  of an accidental iPhone launch. Alison, you, you wrote the story,
Speaker 5:  you've talked to folks. What is going on here? Tell us about this new phone.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so we've been kind of expecting a new iPhone
Speaker 6:  SE successor for a little while now. The, the rumors were
Speaker 6:  swirling and what we got is the
Speaker 6:  iPhone 16 E. The s SE series
Speaker 6:  is dead. Question mark,
Speaker 5:  Do we know what E stands for?
Speaker 6:  Okay. I like David Emil's explanation. It's E
Speaker 6:  stands for eggs and that's why it's so expensive.
Speaker 6:  No.
Speaker 5:  Okay, cool. Because S se was s se officially special edition or
Speaker 5:  was it one of those where like Apple just sort of makes up letters and refuses
Speaker 5:  to explain what they're,
Speaker 6:  I feel like Apple probably circulates a rumor that it was special
Speaker 6:  edition and we all just like repeat it and then it becomes fact.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, do not know. I do not know what e stands for. Easy
Speaker 6:  extra. I don't think either of those terms apply.
Speaker 6:  So the gist is like, it's sort of an
Speaker 6:  se successor, but they're really positioning it as like
Speaker 6:  part of the 16 family. So it's
Speaker 6:  a 6.1 inch screen. It's basically like an iPhone
Speaker 6:  14 kind of chassis.
Speaker 6:  So it's, it's a modern phone, which the last SE was
Speaker 6:  not. It had a tiny screen and it does,
Speaker 6:  apple intelligence of course
Speaker 6:  has wireless charging, but no mag safe, which is a
Speaker 6:  very weird reality. And
Speaker 6:  all the kinds of like modern iPhone things you
Speaker 6:  would expect, like what are we on a 18 processor now? Oh,
Speaker 6:  and the new Apple modem, the C one,
Speaker 6:  so Right. This is its debut appearance.
Speaker 5:  So I, I wanna talk about the C one separately 'cause I think that's super
Speaker 5:  interesting. But the more I look at this phone,
Speaker 5:  the less I think I understand why it exists.
Speaker 5:  Except like If you just wanna say Apple should sell a phone for
Speaker 5:  less than $800. Sure, fine. Whatever. Apple
Speaker 5:  itself has never bought into that theory like this. This company
Speaker 5:  has spent the entirety of its smartphone selling life,
Speaker 5:  refusing to sell cheap smartphones because it can make a lot of money and
Speaker 5:  sell a lot of phones for a lot more money. So I
Speaker 5:  don't buy that as the whole reason for the existence of the 16 e.
Speaker 5:  This the se weirdly I understood more
Speaker 5:  'cause it's like, look, you want the little phone? Here it is. They did it
Speaker 5:  with the mini, they did it with the, it's like, look, it's cheaper, it's
Speaker 5:  smaller.
Speaker 7:  It wasn't the little phone, it was the, we kind of forgot about this.
Speaker 7:  We still have some lying around. Yeah, it's
Speaker 5:  Fair. If you'll,
Speaker 7:  If you'll take it like you'll give us money. Sure, yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's like the leftover bin of funds, which weirdly is a strategy I
Speaker 5:  actually understand more. Yeah. Which
Speaker 7:  I, I I, I personally, I was offended by the SE line,
Speaker 7:  the se he was, it was embarrassing like that that should not have been
Speaker 7:  allowed in stores. This is
Speaker 6:  A hot take.
Speaker 7:  This is, I I I think it's a completely reasonable take this, this
Speaker 7:  phone. Ha it had the design of essentially the iPhone
Speaker 7:  six. It, it has been a decade and they
Speaker 7:  were still selling that thing.
Speaker 5:  Apple shows me the SE and just had it only be
Speaker 5:  refurbished. Like, just, just never even acknowledge that it's a new phone
Speaker 5:  just jumps straight to like it's in the
Speaker 5:  clearance section at a Best Buy. Like that's, that's what the SE should have
Speaker 5:  been.
Speaker 6:  Someone's old iPhone. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Right. And even though no one's ever had it, it's been sitting in a factory
Speaker 5:  Yeah. For six years. Right. So like sure it's
Speaker 6:  Old. Yeah. The previous se the outgoing one, it was bad.
Speaker 6:  I mean, the screen was way too small for like a modern phone. It did
Speaker 6:  feel like kind of leftovers. I, but, but it
Speaker 6:  cost $429 with like
Speaker 6:  poultry 64 gigabytes of storage. So that's like
Speaker 6:  kind of, you figure out that's like a $500 phone. So that was
Speaker 6:  something that was like, hey, sure you want a cheap
Speaker 6:  kind of iPhone that exists. I
Speaker 6:  didn't think anybody should buy it, but it was there. So this one costs
Speaker 6:  5 99 with 128 gigs of storage, which is
Speaker 6:  like a, a reasonable amount of storage in a modern
Speaker 6:  screen, but that's like way more expensive. So yeah,
Speaker 6:  we're not talking about a cheap iPhone
Speaker 6:  anymore. We're not talking about like
Speaker 6:  the like cost to feature trade off
Speaker 6:  is just like all outta whack this time. I feel like
Speaker 7:  From the Apple making money perspective, I'll agree. I don't, I don't totally
Speaker 7:  understand. Right. 'cause they, they want to go high-end expensive
Speaker 7:  from the value prop for the average buyer.
Speaker 7:  It, you know, my early take is this is going to be the phone
Speaker 7:  to buy. Interesting. Right. This is almost
Speaker 7:  everything you'd get from the standard iPhone 16 for $200 less,
Speaker 7:  $200 for MagSafe, whatever.
Speaker 5:  I could not disagree more. This is so fun. Oh
Speaker 7:  Really?
Speaker 5:  So we've all been reviewing phones for a very long time and, and I think
Speaker 5:  the thing that I have had drilled into my head over a decade
Speaker 5:  is that the difference in actual cost in
Speaker 5:  terms of like how people feel it between a $500 phone and
Speaker 5:  a thousand dollars phone is smaller than you think. And the it,
Speaker 5:  the, there has been no market for a $600 phone for 10
Speaker 5:  years because it doesn't matter because that's not how people buy phones.
Speaker 5:  Because people trade in their phones to remove the costs. They pay
Speaker 5:  them over time. So it's, it comes out to like a couple of dollars a month.
Speaker 5:  Like people keep their phones a long time so they're able to amortize the
Speaker 5:  cost over a long period of time. So the idea like if this were $199,
Speaker 5:  I would, I would be all in on it. And I would completely agree with you Jake,
Speaker 5:  that like, bang for your buck, this is the best iPhone
Speaker 5:  at five ninety nine. I'm like, okay, you're looking at, I dunno,
Speaker 5:  a dollar 50 a month less on your thing and
Speaker 5:  who that is a bad trade. And so I'm at the point now where
Speaker 5:  like I wanna talk about the trade offs Apple made here. 'cause I think they're
Speaker 5:  actually really interesting. But e even absent all of those,
Speaker 5:  I'm like, I
Speaker 5:  even if every trade off is the right one, and I don't think they made all
Speaker 5:  the right trade offs. It's, it's not that big a
Speaker 5:  savings, I don't know, like cut this price in half. And I think it's super
Speaker 5:  interesting.
Speaker 7:  I think there are so many people who are just like, what, what iPhone should
Speaker 7:  I buy? If you have to ask that question, get this one.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So the, the test keys is my husband,
Speaker 6:  he has an iPhone 10 R it barely,
Speaker 6:  you know, gets through a day and he was just like, it's
Speaker 6:  time to buy a new iPhone. He's the person who will just be like,
Speaker 6:  which one's the cheapest? I'll take that one. I asked him, I was like, are
Speaker 6:  you gonna miss Mag safe? And he said, what is mag safe? So
Speaker 6:  there you go. All
Speaker 5:  Right. Well you have done your husband a great disservice, Allison.
Speaker 6:  I know
Speaker 7:  We have to test it. We have to see if it's good, but assuming it is, it is
Speaker 7:  as like expected.
Speaker 7:  I don't know what you would be missing out on. Right? Like I think If you
Speaker 7:  got the, the old se I would be like, that looks like an old phone. Right?
Speaker 7:  You're not, you're gonna have a very different experience. The 16 e, same
Speaker 7:  processor, same screen, everything is is is essentially
Speaker 7:  the same as the, the standard 16. You're just like not missing out in the
Speaker 7:  same way that you used to be.
Speaker 5:  I do largely agree with that. And again, I think the, the, I think the only
Speaker 5:  thing I'm really thrown by here is that this thing is like $200 more
Speaker 5:  expensive than makes sense for it to be in my head. But let, let's put that
Speaker 5:  aside for a minute. So I, I do think the trade-offs Apple is making here
Speaker 5:  are really interesting for exactly that reason, Jake, because what they're
Speaker 5:  clearly trying to do is get rid of all the things you don't care about
Speaker 5:  down to a price that is more affordable,
Speaker 5:  but essentially solves the, it'll still do all the iPhone things you need
Speaker 5:  it to thing. So Alison, I I, this is a
Speaker 5:  complicated thing to ask you to do off the top of your head, but like between
Speaker 5:  the, the iPhone 16, which until this week was the, the base one
Speaker 5:  in the line and the 16 e, what are the things you lose
Speaker 5:  by downgrading the 200?
Speaker 6:  I think MagSafe is a big one.
Speaker 6:  I mean, the complicating thing in there is that the iPhone 15 is
Speaker 6:  still a thing you can buy. Right? So Apple,
Speaker 5:  Ignore that for now. We'll come back to that. Yeah. But I think the, the,
Speaker 5:  like the should you buy last year's phone thing just makes everything
Speaker 5:  complicated. So let's just throw that out for now. Okay. Let's just go 16
Speaker 5:  versus 16 E
Speaker 6:  For now. Yeah. So 16 E does the,
Speaker 6:  the thing where it has one camera so you lose the ultra
Speaker 6:  wide and with that you lose the macro
Speaker 6:  capabilities. So there's that
Speaker 6:  again, not a thing my husband is gonna care about. I keep coming
Speaker 6:  back to,
Speaker 6:  yeah, I, it's not a huge list of things. I don't think the camera
Speaker 6:  control obviously is not there. You get that action button.
Speaker 6:  That's kind of it. Am I missing anything? Huge.
Speaker 7:  You lose the dynamic island
Speaker 5:  Dynamic.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Instead, so
Speaker 5:  If I'm being completely honest, you
Speaker 7:  Are a, a dynamic island fan boy. I know. No, I
Speaker 5:  Know the opposite. I, I had to, I had to tap on
Speaker 5:  my phone screen to double check and make sure that the 16 didn't
Speaker 5:  also have a notch. Like
Speaker 5:  I cannot, I don't know, the dynamic island is actually neat. Like as somebody
Speaker 5:  who follows sports a lot, the idea of having the the little live activities
Speaker 5:  is, is great. I actually think Apple has done that really well.
Speaker 5:  Don't think it's a thing I would like miss in a huge constant way.
Speaker 5:  If I didn't have it anymore, pay
Speaker 7:  $200 more and get better access to sports scores. That's a selling
Speaker 7:  point.
Speaker 5:  I feel like that would work.
Speaker 5:  The one other spec I think that has made a a lot of people feel
Speaker 5:  feelings is the 60 Hertz display on the 16 E. And I think
Speaker 5:  again, if, if the rubric is, does Allison's husband care?
Speaker 5:  The answer is almost certainly no. We've talked about this on the show before,
Speaker 5:  but like I downgraded from, I've had a pro or a pro Max
Speaker 5:  every year for years, and I downgraded to the, the 16
Speaker 5:  because I wanted the blue one. A decision I have never
Speaker 5:  for one second regretted. Like, I'm not kidding. It is, it was such a good
Speaker 5:  decision. The blue one makes me so happy. The 60 hertz display
Speaker 5:  thing is like, it's really noticeable If you hold two phones
Speaker 5:  side by side, one with the 60 hertz display and one with 120 hertz promotion
Speaker 5:  display, it is a real meaningful upgrade. I
Speaker 5:  do not believe it has changed my day-to-day experience of using an iPhone
Speaker 5:  one tiny iota. Yeah. Like I just, I don't see it.
Speaker 6:  I always notice it like right when I switch from a
Speaker 6:  120 hertz display to a phone with 60 hertz for
Speaker 6:  like a day and then I kind of forget about it. And then it's nice when I
Speaker 6:  go back to the 120 hertz display, I'm like, Ooh, this is really smooth and
Speaker 6:  nice. But yeah, I think it's, it's a thing you can put outta your mind or
Speaker 6:  a lot of people can, some people can't and that's fine. It, it's like
Speaker 6:  weird. The apple doesn't include it. It's, you know,
Speaker 6:  we, when we're comparing this to the regular iPhone
Speaker 6:  16, it's like, yeah, they all have a 60 hertz display, but that
Speaker 6:  kind of forgets the fact that like, maybe they shouldn't, I think
Speaker 6:  it sort of highlights. I I mean you can pick up any Android
Speaker 6:  phone that's $500. It has 120 hertz display, but that's, I
Speaker 6:  don't know. So the
Speaker 7:  Rumors, the, the rumor out there are,
Speaker 7:  are suggesting that the iPhone 17, just the standard one is gonna get
Speaker 7:  the promotion one 20 oh display.
Speaker 5:  Oh, interesting. Which
Speaker 7:  I think maybe actually puts the 16 EA little bit more in
Speaker 7:  perspective. Like you can see they're gonna level up the baseline one,
Speaker 7:  the pro model has already has a bunch of differentiators.
Speaker 7:  I think it starts to separate those levels a little bit more
Speaker 7:  clearly than the e versus the standard right now where it's like, you
Speaker 7:  know,
Speaker 5:  That is yet another piece of evidence that suggests
Speaker 5:  something that I don't wanna believe and have no evidence for, which is that
Speaker 5:  the whole iPhone lineup is about to get more expensive. Oh. Which I
Speaker 5:  think would make the 16 EI think might seem cheaper in September
Speaker 5:  than it does right now. And that is a thing that I worry about.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I believe that,
Speaker 7:  I mean, I I know you said where you'd save politics for later, so I give
Speaker 7:  brief, but like
Speaker 5:  Tariffs are allowed. We, we can tariffs matter to every gadget we buy that
Speaker 5:  counts.
Speaker 7:  Is this phone $600 if the tariffs didn't
Speaker 7:  hit or is it right or or is it $600 because they know the
Speaker 7:  tariffs are here because they know the other phones are probably gonna have
Speaker 7:  to get more expensive. Yeah, that feels really possible to me.
Speaker 6:  The thing if, if this phone was $500, like
Speaker 6:  sold, you know, MagSafe fine, whatever, it feels like a
Speaker 6:  $500 phone that they're charging $600 for. So I'm, I will
Speaker 6:  accept any theory about why that is.
Speaker 5:  I do think there, there is an interesting piece of math in there that is,
Speaker 5:  is what people are upgrading from and how much they're getting
Speaker 5:  in trade-in value right now. Because I think like if you're coming from,
Speaker 5:  I don't know, an iPhone 13 let's say, and
Speaker 5:  you're getting like three or $400 in trade-in value and that would turn
Speaker 5:  a $500 16 e into like a hundred dollars phone. Like
Speaker 5:  that's what becomes pretty compelling. And I think
Speaker 5:  this is why the phone price thing is so complicated because everybody is
Speaker 5:  actually paying a different price. The the price of a phone is not
Speaker 5:  the price of a phone. It is actually dependent on so many other things,
Speaker 5:  especially in the US where everything is mediated by carriers and everything
Speaker 5:  has long-term deals. It's just a mess. Like I, I have to
Speaker 5:  buy my wife a new phone because she is just
Speaker 5:  spectacularly good at breaking her phones. I love her very much and she just
Speaker 5:  can't keep a phone alive and just try. She's basically in, she's
Speaker 5:  a, an Android diehard and absolutely steadfastly refuses to get an iPhone
Speaker 5:  even though it would make it easier to video chat with our entire family.
Speaker 7:  Can we have her on the show?
Speaker 5:  She would love to be on the show and tell me how irritating her phone choices
Speaker 5:  are.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I I need this, I need this.
Speaker 5:  But she is basically like, all I want is like a pretty good phone that's
Speaker 5:  pretty cheap. Which, which one do I get? And I have found that to be such
Speaker 5:  a more complicated question to answer than I ever expected. Especially because
Speaker 5:  like now I'm like, oh, well the, the pixel nine A is probably coming soon,
Speaker 5:  but then as soon as that comes out, like the Pixel eight will be a lot cheaper
Speaker 5:  and that's probably a better, and it's just like all of this is so confusing
Speaker 5:  and so I I find myself spending less time worrying about how much a phone
Speaker 5:  costs unless it is like
Speaker 5:  $300 and then it then it counts, right? Yeah. And then it's like, okay, this
Speaker 5:  is a very cheap phone now.
Speaker 6:  That's what it kind of feels like the, the SE was in the territory of
Speaker 6:  like, you could pay that out of pocket or I think that
Speaker 6:  a, a good chunk of people could pay that out of pocket. Yeah. It wasn't out
Speaker 6:  of the question. An $800 phone I is different.
Speaker 6:  And then yeah, once you get to $600, does that push it into
Speaker 6:  the bracket of like, well I don't have that lying around.
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna subsidize this through my carrier. And then you get into what are
Speaker 6:  the deals right now, what are they offering? And I did this with my hairstylist
Speaker 6:  recently when it's like, you, what phone do you buy? And
Speaker 6:  we ended up starting with like what carrier deals are
Speaker 6:  there right now. And that's how we got to like she has the Pixel
Speaker 6:  nine now and I
Speaker 5:  That's such a sad state of affairs.
Speaker 6:  It's like, look through coupons, what is Mint Mobile gonna give
Speaker 6:  you for free? And it was like, well that was the
Speaker 6:  better deal than paying for something else out of pocket. So
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Says an awful lot about the state of smartphones that that is the case. Sure
Speaker 5:  it does. Let's talk about MagSafe because I think this is
Speaker 5:  the, of all the trades that Apple made, this is the one that I
Speaker 5:  stuck on. And Alison, it sounds like you did the same that it was like, is
Speaker 5:  this, is this a correct trade off to make
Speaker 5:  in exchange for making a phone cheaper? Jake, I don't know how you feel about
Speaker 5:  MagSafe. You notoriously, Jake runs around the office hating MagSafe. So
Speaker 5:  Yes, I it's true. I, well I have a Pixel eight and so I have never
Speaker 5:  even seen a magnet in my life. I
Speaker 5:  not sure what they're used for. So the thing everybody says about MagSafe
Speaker 5:  is that it's for, it's for wireless charging and that is true,
Speaker 5:  but it's also only part of why I really like MagSafe. Like
Speaker 5:  I have no case, but I have a, I have a mag safe pop
Speaker 5:  socket on the back of my phone and this is how I hold my phone
Speaker 6:  And that stays on there.
Speaker 5:  It stays on it, it slides around in a way that is like very fun
Speaker 5:  to fidget with and also very dangerous. But it has never once
Speaker 5:  actually fallen off while I have been using it. So, okay, for now
Speaker 5:  we're, we're still alive, but also like I have a, I have a a stand
Speaker 5:  here that I put my phone on when I'm sitting at my computer so that I can
Speaker 5:  look at it directly and unlock it that way and do like two-factor
Speaker 5:  authentication and that kind of thing. It I have, I have one in my car that
Speaker 5:  mag saves too. It's like I see it less as a, as a
Speaker 5:  charging system and more like an accessory system. And the MagSafe accessory
Speaker 5:  system is actually really good now. And I think like
Speaker 5:  there are going to be a lot of people who get this phone and switch from
Speaker 5:  lightning to USBC and that's going to be annoying but good because
Speaker 5:  all of your gadgets are going to be USBC and life with all of your gadgets
Speaker 5:  being USBC is better. But I think there are going to be a bunch of people
Speaker 5:  who miss out on a big part of what makes the iPhone
Speaker 5:  ecosystem great, which is increasingly filled with MagSafe
Speaker 5:  stuff.
Speaker 6:  So we don't have a lot of MagSafe in my house either with
Speaker 6:  my husband having the 10 R
Speaker 5:  And you having every phone that exists simultaneously.
Speaker 6:  I have all the phones, so I just do like regular wireless charging, which
Speaker 6:  the 16 E does do wireless charging without the MagSafe.
Speaker 6:  Right. But something that our, our colleague Jen
Speaker 6:  Tuey said was that one of her kids, her
Speaker 6:  like kind of older kids doesn't have is
Speaker 6:  the last person in the house without mag safe. And it's becoming a problem
Speaker 6:  because everybody else can use the MagSafe accessories and she's the one
Speaker 6:  stuck without it. So that was really like, okay, this is maybe like
Speaker 6:  if your household is invested in this,
Speaker 6:  I can see how that would be annoying. And the thing I'm thinking about
Speaker 6:  is If you hold onto this phone for seven years, which
Speaker 6:  my husband Charlie would do that,
Speaker 6:  is it gonna be annoying in seven years that he doesn't have mag safe? And
Speaker 6:  I'm like, can't you just stick your phone to the wall over here?
Speaker 6:  Whatever we're doing then, I dunno. It is, it is the thing that feels like
Speaker 6:  why like on a $500 phone maybe I could see no mag safe.
Speaker 6:  Just why, why did they leave it out? It it's irritating.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It struck me as the most obvious sort of
Speaker 5:  missing feature. Like the rest of the stuff is downgrades on things.
Speaker 5:  And I'm actually coming around to the camera choice. I think one of the things
Speaker 5:  I saw, and I, I forget who was posting about it, but basically the argument
Speaker 5:  that they made is you can now make iPhone decisions based on how much
Speaker 5:  you care about the camera. And I actually think that makes a lot of sense,
Speaker 5:  right? Like If you just look at the iPhone as a series of, of kind of
Speaker 5:  base camera to excellent camera and you just pay more for more camera,
Speaker 5:  that's actually like the simplest way to think about the iPhone line now
Speaker 5:  and kind of works. And I think most people
Speaker 5:  just want a thing that takes pictures, right? Like that's it,
Speaker 5:  it'll take pretty good pictures. You don't have to think a ton about it.
Speaker 5:  You'll, you, you open the thing with the action button and take a photo and
Speaker 5:  move on. It's your day. Like I think that describes most people's iPhone
Speaker 5:  photography and if it doesn't describe you, you're not gonna buy the 16 e
Speaker 5:  Anyway. So that I think I've, I've actually come around to,
Speaker 5:  we also know cameras are a really expensive part of smartphones. So If you
Speaker 5:  wanna save money on smartphones, that is one way to do it. MagSafe is one
Speaker 5:  that it's like, this feels like a thing that you've gone from
Speaker 5:  not just having better to having worse like the screen or the camera, but
Speaker 5:  to just not having anymore and like the camera control, I can happily
Speaker 5:  lose because I don't ever ever use the camera control on my iPhone.
Speaker 5:  Maybe that's just me. I just don't, I don't like it, I don't use it. I forget
Speaker 5:  it's there for weeks at a time. MagSafe is, is like a
Speaker 5:  core part of the iPhone for me now and I, I feel like it would be very hard
Speaker 5:  to get rid of that. What
Speaker 7:  They're doing in the Android world right now is that because basically none
Speaker 7:  of the phones have a mag safe equivalent, which they should.
Speaker 7:  There's a whole standard for it called she two. It's existed for a year and
Speaker 7:  a half at this point. The case companies are just putting a ring of magnets
Speaker 7:  in their cases. So If you have a phone that supports wireless charging, you
Speaker 7:  just buy a MagSafe compatible case, slap it on, and now you've got
Speaker 7:  MagSafe. Now it's obviously not quite as good because you can't use those
Speaker 7:  accessories like the super slim, you know, wallet that just smacks right
Speaker 7:  onto the, the phone itself. But you know, If you are somebody
Speaker 7:  who just really wants Max, If you can get it, there's ways to get it true.
Speaker 7:  And I suspect that's a possible outcome for the, for the 16 E
Speaker 7:  here. Surely somebody's gonna fill that market,
Speaker 7:  you know, it's not as elegant. I agree with you. I I think there's probably
Speaker 7:  gonna be a lot of people who are bummed about this, but there's, there's
Speaker 7:  some options and the, the Android world has lived slightly
Speaker 7:  unapply without it for a few years now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. I think, I think the the case thing is actually a pretty
Speaker 5:  good argument and, and like you can get into this ecosystem
Speaker 5:  If you really want to and like honestly the way Apple is
Speaker 5:  gonna sell this based on the way that they sell everything else is like,
Speaker 5:  well If you want all that stuff, it's only $200 more. Yeah. Like this,
Speaker 5:  it's such a, they now have the thing where they're gonna be able to sell.
Speaker 5:  You start with the 599 phone and then you're gonna accidentally leave the
Speaker 5:  store with like a $2,000 pro max and you'll be like, I don't understand how
Speaker 5:  this happened. All I wanted was MagSafe. And that is a thing Apple
Speaker 5:  is extraordinarily good at. Before we get off this subject, and
Speaker 5:  Allison, you're gonna review this thing at some point and when you do, we'll
Speaker 5:  have to check back in because I'm, I'm very curious what it's like to actually
Speaker 5:  live with some of these tradeoffs after using the big fancy
Speaker 5:  iPhones, but we should talk about why this modem is a big deal. Jake, can
Speaker 5:  you explain why this modem is a big deal?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, apple has been trying to make its own
Speaker 7:  cell phone modems for years at this point. You know, I think we
Speaker 7:  all know they have increasingly been trying to make more and more of their
Speaker 7:  own in-house parts and that has worked out really phenomenally well for things
Speaker 7:  like processors. They have really struggled when it
Speaker 7:  comes to the modem. At one point
Speaker 7:  Intel really wanted to get into the cell phone modem game. And so
Speaker 7:  Intel had this big unit working on cell
Speaker 7:  phone modems and it was not going well at all. Apple
Speaker 7:  at the same time wasn't going well for them either. Apple bought
Speaker 7:  Intel's entire team Oh, that's great. An entire team that was
Speaker 7:  failing. Yeah. And so fast forward several more
Speaker 7:  years, they have taken that team and they have finally put together
Speaker 7:  a modem and we haven't got a chance to test it out. I think this is really
Speaker 7:  interesting because
Speaker 7:  If you look at the iPhone 16 E, we've essentially tested
Speaker 7:  every part of it in other phones before. The
Speaker 7:  one new thing here is the C one, which is what Apple is calling is first
Speaker 7:  modem. And Whether it can
Speaker 7:  keep up with the standard Qualcomm modem that has been in every
Speaker 7:  other iPhone is going to be the big question here
Speaker 7:  because
Speaker 5:  That is a thing people will notice if their cell connection is spotty and
Speaker 5:  drops out. I don't know If you guys have seen this, but the, the conspiracy
Speaker 5:  theories about this are just rampant No in our comments
Speaker 5:  on Reddit everywhere and, and the the leading conspiracy theories that Apple
Speaker 5:  has actually been sabotaging the Qualcomm modems in the other iPhones
Speaker 5:  in order to make it so that the performance gap between those phones and
Speaker 5:  the 16 God is small. I should be clear that there's absolutely no reason
Speaker 5:  to believe any of this. Oh no, I think somebody was like, oh, there's a
Speaker 5:  Qualcomm chip, but they use the other more mysterious Qualcomm chip and I'm
Speaker 5:  like, I don't know what a mysterious Qualcomm chip is, but like, it it is,
Speaker 5:  it it is a really interesting and measurable thing, right? Like to your point,
Speaker 5:  Jake, you're gonna be able to hold two iPhones next to each other. And the
Speaker 5:  only reason one would get faster speeds than the other is because Apple made
Speaker 5:  one and Qualcomm made the other. And I have a feeling actually both
Speaker 5:  companies are going to be very nervous about how that's gonna go. Because
Speaker 5:  like if, If you Qualcomm, you look at what Apple has done to the Silicon
Speaker 5:  world over the last several years and has the way it has just lapped
Speaker 5:  intel in particular on all kinds of different devices.
Speaker 5:  And if you're Qualcomm, that suddenly starts to seem sort of nerve wracking.
Speaker 5:  You're, you've been like the only company in this game for decades and you
Speaker 5:  have made an awful lot of money by being the only one who makes modems that
Speaker 5:  are any good. And then if you're Apple, you're like, oh God, we've we bought
Speaker 5:  this crappy team from Intel. We put all this time and energy
Speaker 5:  into it. We've, we've sort of staked our thing in the ground and it's not
Speaker 5:  like if we have Antennagate two because the C one isn't very
Speaker 5:  good, that's gonna be a really tough look for Apple.
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna be careful to hold it correctly. I
Speaker 6:  dunno, it's
Speaker 5:  A weird thing. Think the way is you hold it sort of by the, by the top middle
Speaker 5:  and just kind of dangle
Speaker 6:  Your phone. That's not what I plan to do. No, it's a really strange thing
Speaker 6:  to be contemplating or a review of this device
Speaker 6:  and it's like a, a modem is a, a solved problem,
Speaker 6:  you know, in every other phone where I'm like, it's, it's something I am
Speaker 6:  like aware of when I test a
Speaker 5:  Phone. Well it's, it's a solved problem parentheses by Qualcomm, right?
Speaker 5:  In every way. It's just Qualcomm all the way down. Well, it's just, you
Speaker 6:  Put the Qualcomm thing in your phone, it works. I nev rarely
Speaker 6:  notice like, oh, the, you know, signal seems
Speaker 6:  to be dropping out and it shouldn't. But yeah, this
Speaker 6:  is, this is something I'll be on obviously, you know, very interested
Speaker 6:  in with the 16 E. So we'll
Speaker 6:  see.
Speaker 5:  I'm kind of excited about it. I first got into tech journalism
Speaker 5:  and reviewing phones like right as LTE was becoming a thing,
Speaker 5:  which feels like thousands of years ago now. But like doing the thing
Speaker 5:  where you just wander around on the streets taking a hundred speed tests
Speaker 5:  just to see what happens is like a surprisingly joyful part of
Speaker 5:  these.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's gonna be a throwback.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's great. I'm gonna run some speed
Speaker 5:  Tests. I'm, I'm very curious to see. I will say the other thing that has
Speaker 5:  come up a bunch in our comments is people who are now
Speaker 5:  wondering if Apple making these modems in-house is
Speaker 5:  going to make it easier slash more compelling for Apple to put
Speaker 5:  modems inside of MacBooks, which is a thing
Speaker 5:  that I have hoped for for many years and would very, very much love to see.
Speaker 5:  I
Speaker 7:  Have no idea why any human would pay for that, but
Speaker 7:  I I underst like, I do not understand why Apple has not
Speaker 7:  done it charge you an extra 200 bucks for that done. Sure.
Speaker 7:  I don't understand why they haven't
Speaker 5:  Done that. I I would have agreed with you until an experience I had last
Speaker 5:  year with the M four iPad Pro, which was the first
Speaker 5:  time I had my whole life sort of eim and I literally
Speaker 5:  just turned on the iPad Pro. I never, I was like out at
Speaker 5:  a coffee shop, I didn't connect it to wifi, I didn't do anything and it was
Speaker 5:  just online. I logged into my account and was just online
Speaker 5:  and it was, it was one of the coolest technology experiences I've had in
Speaker 5:  years of just like, like it's the difference between
Speaker 5:  when you had to turn your computer on and off every time you used it and
Speaker 5:  just opening the lid and it started to be on again. That all of a sudden,
Speaker 5:  like the whole thing just feels better and more accessible. This idea that
Speaker 5:  everywhere I am I can just pop my laptop open and start working is like,
Speaker 5:  there's something real there.
Speaker 7:  I I would use a Starbucks hotspot from
Speaker 7:  my house if it saved me money on my my cell phone bill.
Speaker 7:  What, what like adding another device to, to your thing.
Speaker 7:  I understand. I I think it makes a ton of sense for business users. It,
Speaker 7:  it does sound amazing and magical, but whoof it's a lot, lot
Speaker 7:  of gadgets, lot of gadgets.
Speaker 5:  I know I say all that but I've, I've always been too cheap to buy the cellular
Speaker 5:  Apple watch for like, and it's, it's the same thing, right? It is like
Speaker 5:  magically connected everywhere is the whole pitch and I get it and I want
Speaker 5:  it and I wouldn't pay anymore for it. But I think I would on a laptop,
Speaker 5:  I would almost never use it because I just sit at home on my Mac mini every
Speaker 5:  day. But like it would make me feel good. Yeah, I would enjoy it. Alright,
Speaker 5:  we should talk about one more phone before we get off of phones.
Speaker 5:  And that phone is the Oppo Find N five
Speaker 5:  A phone that is not coming to the United States. Don Preston on our team
Speaker 5:  reviewed it. Alison, I just wanna know how jealous you are that you have
Speaker 5:  not gotten to my gosh, try and review this phone. This is the thinnest foldable
Speaker 5:  phone in The world according to Dom. It got a lot of the hardware things
Speaker 5:  right. It's basically as thick as A-U-S-B-C port
Speaker 5:  plus like the least metal you can possibly imagine.
Speaker 5:  I believe. Lemme see, I I'm just gonna read the sentence that he wrote
Speaker 5:  when closed. This is less than a millimeter, thicker than an iPhone 16 Pro
Speaker 5:  Max or Samsung Galaxy S 25 Ultra and weighs only two grams more than the
Speaker 5:  Apple phone open. It boasts a bigger screen than an iPad mini, but is thinner
Speaker 5:  and weighs less. It's lighter than any of the foldables you can buy in the
Speaker 5:  US right now. And is a full three millimeters thinner than the Galaxy Z fold
Speaker 5:  six. Like this is, this looks like what a foldables supposed to look like.
Speaker 5:  They did it.
Speaker 6:  They did it. Yeah. And I kind of, I
Speaker 6:  love dom's kind of thesis on this review is like now
Speaker 6:  what, you know, it's still a, a pretty
Speaker 6:  expensive phone. I think we just got rid of the
Speaker 6:  pricing is is like around, well it's not coming
Speaker 6:  to us, which we've established, but it would cost around
Speaker 6:  $1,800 If you just did the calculation,
Speaker 5:  Which to be fair is like that's the going rate for foldables. Yeah. But that
Speaker 5:  is still literally a hundred percent too expensive.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It is. It should be half of that price. And then I think these things would
Speaker 5:  have a ratio. It's
Speaker 7:  Only three I iPhone 16 es so I I can see There you go.
Speaker 7:  You get there like the onscreen amount alone If you kind of, that kind of
Speaker 7:  adds up. It's
Speaker 6:  Interesting. Yeah. You could take three 16 Es and make a
Speaker 6:  trifold.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, like a accordion style. Your your three
Speaker 7:  16. That's the dumb ass. Is this the, the end and the answer is no
Speaker 7:  more screens.
Speaker 5:  Yep. What if I took all these and just took them apart into many screens?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it looks so beautiful. I am gonna
Speaker 6:  find one at Mobile World Congress and put it in my pocket and
Speaker 6:  run out of the the conventional. No, it, and it, it sounds
Speaker 6:  silly or like, well they were already pretty thin,
Speaker 6:  like comparably and, but like every
Speaker 6:  millimeter really does make a difference, especially when you're folding
Speaker 6:  in half and it, I just keep coming back to the pixel
Speaker 6:  fold too, whatever, nine pro fold where
Speaker 6:  you're like, could that really be as nice as it seemed like the, the
Speaker 6:  specs, the dimensions seem right and then you pick it up, you're like, this
Speaker 6:  is right. Yep. It feels so nice to use this. That's the impression
Speaker 6:  I I got from Dominic on the, on the APO phone
Speaker 6:  and I wanna pick one up and not give it back.
Speaker 5:  I do think it's really exciting that it, it seems like we are getting
Speaker 5:  closer to the point where the hardware works,
Speaker 5:  right? Like I I I quibble with Dom a little bit on the idea
Speaker 5:  that like, you can't see the crease and it's like, no, it's right there in
Speaker 5:  the picture in every picture. Like I see it, there's still a crease
Speaker 5:  and these things all need to be sturdier. They need to be more durable, they
Speaker 5:  need better cameras. Like I actually think there's quite a bit of refining
Speaker 5:  and improving left to do in a lot of these devices, but as a, as
Speaker 5:  a pure piece of hardware design. Like we're actually, we're getting close
Speaker 5:  and then it's like, okay, now we just have to take this thing and cut
Speaker 5:  $700 off it and and sincerely, I
Speaker 5:  have no idea if that's possible, but I think if it's not,
Speaker 5:  we're sort of done here. Right? Yeah. Like I think the, the market for an
Speaker 5:  $1,800 phone of any kind is just never gonna be very big. Yeah. I just
Speaker 5:  don't see it. And I think most people are like, if if I could have
Speaker 5:  this phone Exactly. Or this phone. Exactly. But it opened
Speaker 5:  up to be bigger. I would take the one that opened up to be bigger. But that's,
Speaker 5:  I'm not willing to make any trades in service of that thing, I think is where
Speaker 5:  most people are.
Speaker 7:  That's a hundred percent where I like and I huge nerd would love a
Speaker 7:  folding phone. Really cool. The cameras are ever so slightly worse and it
Speaker 7:  costs $600 more. Yeah. Yeah. Like
Speaker 6:  I,
Speaker 7:  That, that's not worth it for me. Right.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And it's like, I think it's a phone that like
Speaker 6:  my parents would really like, like they would love to
Speaker 6:  unfold their phones and read something and be able to make the text bigger
Speaker 6:  or whatever, see pictures of their grandkid and
Speaker 6:  big, bigger size. But I am never gonna recommend one to them.
Speaker 6:  It's, you know, the, the durability is just too much of
Speaker 6:  a question mark. And Dom makes a good point in the review that If you can't
Speaker 6:  afford to replace this phone or
Speaker 6:  make a very expensive repair to it, then you should not buy a folding
Speaker 6:  phone. And I think that's exactly right.
Speaker 5:  That's a good rule of thumb. Yeah. Like If you, If you couldn't afford to
Speaker 5:  walk into the store and buy two of these, you probably shouldn't walk into
Speaker 5:  the store and buy one of these.
Speaker 7:  Have I fixed the like your, your fingernail will crease the
Speaker 7:  screen forever. Problem foldables yet. 'cause that's that's horrifying.
Speaker 6:  That's better. Yeah. Better.
Speaker 7:  Okay. Better. Is
Speaker 6:  It? Yeah. I still don't risk
Speaker 6:  it too much. And you definitely don't wanna like have a piece of
Speaker 6:  debris in your bag and like that, like the phone
Speaker 6:  folds over on, I've carried a lot of folding phones
Speaker 6:  in the bottom of my tote bag, which is dusty and gross and they have all
Speaker 6:  been okay. But I haven't done that for like
Speaker 6:  two years or three years, you know, so
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The, the long-term durability of one
Speaker 5:  of these is still the biggest question to me. Like the, is it going to
Speaker 5:  break the first time you open it thing? Not completely solved
Speaker 5:  for any of these companies, but like mostly solved. It's, it's gotten a lot
Speaker 5:  better than the like, oops, I accidentally peeled off the screen,
Speaker 5:  which was not that long ago, but we're still at a point now where like
Speaker 5:  that that thing you just said Alison about like debris in your pocket
Speaker 5:  is like you, you're gonna get a little nervous every time you just throw
Speaker 5:  this into your purse or your backpack. And until you solve that,
Speaker 5:  we're just not quite there. But we're getting there. And I think the
Speaker 5:  idea that there are a bunch of companies pushing really hard at this design
Speaker 5:  stuff is cool and I wish they'd stop worrying about thinness and
Speaker 5:  start fixing the durability stuff. But that's how I feel about
Speaker 5:  all phones right now. The iPhone air, I'm gonna say this again in September
Speaker 5:  and whenever we get the Galaxy S 25, was that the air
Speaker 5:  too?
Speaker 6:  Edge.
Speaker 5:  Edge, that's right. I feel the same. Like we're we're doing a thin phone
Speaker 5:  year and I'm like, what if our phones didn't break? That'd be cool
Speaker 5:  into
Speaker 6:  That. You would like that?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But yeah, this thing is not coming to the us which is
Speaker 5:  sad. It's
Speaker 7:  Devastating,
Speaker 5:  But we're we're, we're gonna, we're gonna find one. There was a world in
Speaker 5:  which we thought one plus might take this and launch it
Speaker 7:  Itself. Yeah. I don't understand why one plus just came out and we're just
Speaker 7:  like, we're not gonna do it. I know they just came out and broke our har
Speaker 7:  broke our hearts. Yeah. They have to, I don't understand what was in this
Speaker 7:  for them. They could have kept us going at least for
Speaker 5:  I think it was about what, nine months ago? Oh
Speaker 5:  God. That the AI pin had launched. It
Speaker 5:  went poorly. I would, I would say I was mean to it and not
Speaker 5:  as mean to it as I should have been. In retrospect we, we'll get back to
Speaker 5:  that, but there was this rumor going around that Humane was
Speaker 5:  actually looking to sell itself, right? This company had raised a ton of
Speaker 5:  money, it had brought on a ton of hype. It kind of bombed with this first
Speaker 5:  product. We didn't think it was gonna work and then we,
Speaker 5:  it was trying to sell itself to HP for somewhere
Speaker 5:  between 750 million and a billion dollars. And we were all like,
Speaker 5:  that seems high. Also, LOL at HP
Speaker 5:  paying a billion dollars for Humane's weird
Speaker 5:  AI operating system. And this thing, the AI pin
Speaker 5:  that basically didn't work at all, that never came to anything
Speaker 5:  Humane kind of went quiet. They got, they were like slightly apologetic and
Speaker 5:  then were like, well, we're also making an operating system. That's gonna
Speaker 5:  be a whole thing. Batten down the hatches, do their thing. And then
Speaker 5:  this week it was announced that HP
Speaker 5:  was buying technology from Humane. HP actually
Speaker 5:  reached out to us to very carefully confirm that HP was not
Speaker 5:  acquiring Humane. It was buying some technology and
Speaker 5:  assets and, and hiring some people from Humane.
Speaker 5:  But that humane as we know it, including the AI pin is shutting down.
Speaker 5:  And as of February 28th, so a week from Friday, today
Speaker 5:  as you're hearing this, the AI pin will essentially be
Speaker 5:  dead. They're turning off the service. It won't do any cloud stuff. There's
Speaker 5:  a thing in Humane's, FA Q1 of the questions is
Speaker 5:  basically like, what will my device be able to do? And it's like, it'll be
Speaker 5:  able to tell you its battery level.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. This thing is, this is really, really rough. Like, like it's immediate.
Speaker 7:  Like you, you, If you bought one, you knew you were an early adopter, but
Speaker 7:  like, like straight up you're $700, $800 pin, just, it's just
Speaker 7:  dead. Like it's doing nothing. And basically nobody's getting a
Speaker 7:  refund
Speaker 5:  In less than a year. That hurts just gone. Yeah. Yeah. That's, that's bad.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Humane is doing refunds for people who are in the 90 day window
Speaker 5:  in which people could normally get refunds. Would love,
Speaker 7:  Love to know how many people that is.
Speaker 5:  Oh my God, I had the same thought. Like,
Speaker 7:  Like
Speaker 5:  If, If you bought,
Speaker 7:  You think they set aside any money for that.
Speaker 5:  Like, let's see, three months ago would've been like Thanksgiving.
Speaker 5:  So If you, If you bought a humane AI pin, let's say between
Speaker 5:  November 1st and today, please email
Speaker 5:  us Vergecast at The Verge dot com and tell us everything
Speaker 5:  about why and who and under the influence of
Speaker 5:  what and what has happened since I want to, I want to know
Speaker 5:  everything. Who got one for Christmas? Oh no.
Speaker 5:  Oh my God, I bet that happened. There are people who were like, oh, I have
Speaker 5:  a, I have a nerdy nephew. Like what can I buy? Oh no.
Speaker 5:  A 700 pin Oh man. Which
Speaker 7:  Required subscription as well.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. Great. Love, love to spend all of the money in The world.
Speaker 5:  You could buy an iPhone 16 E for less Okay. Than a human
Speaker 5:  have. So
Speaker 7:  David, you you reviewed this thing I did, right? They had these, these big
Speaker 7:  promises about the future of ai, the future of wearables. They were trying
Speaker 7:  to redefine gadgets, right? Mo move into a a
Speaker 7:  postmortem era. Were they onto anything?
Speaker 5:  Well, this is where Alison and I have been fighting for a year and will continue
Speaker 5:  to fight because I, I still think the answer is
Speaker 5:  yes. I think, I think the answer to
Speaker 5:  how much are they onto and how meaningful is the thing that they were
Speaker 5:  onto
Speaker 5:  TBD. Right? But I think the idea that you should have a way to interact with
Speaker 5:  AI that doesn't involve taking your phone out of your pocket. Yes. I
Speaker 5:  I am convinced there is something there. And I think after this happened,
Speaker 5:  Wes Davis on our team dmd me and like, this thing would've been better if
Speaker 5:  it was just a, a Siri microphone that you could wear, wouldn't it? And I
Speaker 5:  was like, yep, it would have. And I think that's really true. But
Speaker 5:  Humane's thing was they just went too
Speaker 5:  hard at it and they did a bunch of stuff that was technically
Speaker 5:  sort of impossible that they, they like, they made a laser projector
Speaker 5:  as one of the key user interfaces. Like all this stuff sounds absurd in
Speaker 5:  retrospect. And it seemed absurd then frankly it seemed absurd the whole
Speaker 5:  time. But they, they had a laser projector instead of a touchscreen. And
Speaker 5:  it's like we're all pretty good at messing around on screens now. It was
Speaker 5:  designed to do everything by voice. It was designed to have
Speaker 5:  everything be totally abstracted away from you. And
Speaker 5:  the vision of that is actually what a lot of people have. Like people
Speaker 5:  talk about age agentic ai and the idea that all of these systems should be
Speaker 5:  able to go work for you. OpenAI is working on that. Google is working on
Speaker 5:  that. We've seen some of the stuff that they're working on, they're all working
Speaker 5:  on it as like chatbots in web browsers and apps on your phone.
Speaker 5:  Humane was like, okay, well what if this is actually a dedicated device and
Speaker 5:  requires a complete rethinking of how everything happens. And I think that
Speaker 5:  was where it got the thing wrong. So it's like If you, If you boil it all
Speaker 5:  the way down, I think Humane's like the, the
Speaker 5:  very first like meeting at a bar where they were like, here is the
Speaker 5:  thing we should do, I think was not that far off. And then every decision
Speaker 5:  they made After that was the wrong one. I
Speaker 7:  I think, I think what's so hard there is like what they wanted to do
Speaker 7:  within the current, you know, world of phones is just
Speaker 7:  impossible for a third party app, right? Yes. And what they were
Speaker 7:  trying to do even a year ago when they launched
Speaker 7:  was not something you could do on your Android phone was not something you
Speaker 7:  could do on your iPhone. I fast forward a year and you have
Speaker 7:  AI built in natively that is starting to be able to do these
Speaker 7:  things. And so it it's almost like they were, you know, they're
Speaker 7:  pirates trying to board the ship and it, it just
Speaker 7:  wasn't gonna happen. Allison, where where was it that you were
Speaker 7:  clashing with David on this? You were, you were in the just do it in the
Speaker 7:  smartphone camp.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It, the, the future of the AI gadget is,
Speaker 6:  it's a phone is is my stance and I love a gadget and I
Speaker 6:  saw the humane pin a year ago at Mobile World Congress and it was like,
Speaker 6:  this is a gadget. Like it's kind of fun. Is it a good idea?
Speaker 6:  No,
Speaker 6:  we clearly that's how it panned out. But yeah, it's like why
Speaker 6:  take all of these things and try to like reinvent
Speaker 6:  the wheel and like put a worst processor and
Speaker 6:  you, you know, make a whole new interface system that people
Speaker 6:  have to learn and figure out heat
Speaker 6:  dissipation, which they did not because the thing
Speaker 6:  would shut itself down all the time and Yeah. Clearly
Speaker 6:  like that didn't, didn't work out for them.
Speaker 5:  So Alison, I think the, the, it's a real bummer that the AI pin didn't
Speaker 5:  work out because it makes your argument look even stronger than it did already.
Speaker 5:  It did.
Speaker 6:  I noticed that.
Speaker 5:  But I do think the, the thing to me that gives
Speaker 5:  me the strongest evidence against everything should just be a phone is the
Speaker 5:  camera on the meta ray RayBan smart glasses because that,
Speaker 5:  that is a thing in which my experience of taking photos is
Speaker 5:  meaningfully different and in many ways better because I'm not holding
Speaker 5:  my phone in front of my face. And so it's like that's the thing that I look
Speaker 5:  at as like, okay, there are things we can do if we're going to sort of
Speaker 5:  disintermediate the phone and put those components in different places
Speaker 5:  that can be better for it. Yeah. And that's unfortunately
Speaker 5:  the only one that I have found so far. But it is like, that's the one I hold
Speaker 5:  onto that I'm like, maybe there is something to this. And I think the idea
Speaker 5:  of a microphone that is also more accessible than the one in my pocket feels
Speaker 5:  meaningful to me in that same way.
Speaker 6:  And I think it like, like building on what the phone
Speaker 6:  already has, like it already has a processing power, it can al it already
Speaker 6:  connect. Most phones can already connect reliably
Speaker 6:  to cloud services with their Qualcomm modems or whatever.
Speaker 6:  Like instead of throwing all that away and starting
Speaker 6:  like way out here with something else, like the meta ray bands makes
Speaker 6:  so much sense 'cause it just sort of starts with like, okay, here's one
Speaker 6:  capability and it works with your phone
Speaker 6:  and you don't need it If you don't wanna carry it at that particular moment.
Speaker 6:  And then kind of building on that, the way they've been adding the
Speaker 6:  AI features I think is way more compelling
Speaker 6:  than just throwing it all out and being like, what if
Speaker 6:  no phone?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I've been thinking a lot about last, let's see, it
Speaker 5:  would've been right about now, last year I went to
Speaker 5:  New York two Humane's offices and actually like spent some time
Speaker 5:  with Imran Choudry and Bethany Bonno who are the co-founders. And
Speaker 5:  they were like, it was right before the product was launching. So they had
Speaker 5:  one of those like room set up where they had the exploded parts and walked
Speaker 5:  me through how it all works and all the stuff they had developed and they
Speaker 5:  had early prototypes and we were just talking through basically like how
Speaker 5:  they had built this thing and where it came from. And one of the questions
Speaker 5:  I asked them was, why do this much the
Speaker 5:  first time? Like you're, you're a first gen hardware startup, you've never
Speaker 5:  done any of this before. Nobody has seen any of this stuff before. Why
Speaker 5:  push this hard on something this expensive and this
Speaker 5:  complicated and this new on your first try? And I believe it was Imran
Speaker 5:  said, because if now that we've done all of this work,
Speaker 5:  it will make doing the lesser things much easier.
Speaker 5:  And I actually, like there is something sort of compelling in that argument,
Speaker 5:  right? It's like we've done the incredibly complicated things, so now we're
Speaker 5:  gonna strip out the cellular modem, we're gonna basically make this thing
Speaker 5:  an accessory to your phone and it'll, it'll be easier and cheaper
Speaker 5:  and better. And now we can do that because we've done the hard work already.
Speaker 5:  The thing that they didn't reckon with is that they were never gonna get
Speaker 5:  the chance because this thing went so badly. Right. And I think
Speaker 5:  what I look at the opposite is like the, the rabbit where like this thing
Speaker 5:  couldn't do anything but it was $200 and it was like cute and fun.
Speaker 5:  And I think it bought that company some time
Speaker 5:  because people didn't have the same sort of like visceral
Speaker 5:  negative reaction to how bad it was because it wasn't trying nearly as
Speaker 5:  hard. And I think the lesson there was like, and, and frankly
Speaker 5:  like Apple where Iran and Bethany worked before, learned the same
Speaker 5:  thing with Vision Pro. Like what, what Meta did with the Ray bands is like,
Speaker 5:  do the least and then try to build from there. And Apple was like, what if
Speaker 5:  we did the most? And it turns out that's actually in a lot of ways, the wrong
Speaker 5:  approach. And I've just been thinking like the, the prototype for these simpler,
Speaker 5:  cheaper phone attached thing that I think would've made
Speaker 5:  more sense for Humane, I am very sure exists
Speaker 5:  and they should have shipped that instead.
Speaker 7:  Humane went way too far in the hardware, which is, I think part
Speaker 7:  of the thing that was attention grabbing about Humane was right. It's this
Speaker 7:  mysterious gadget as a projector. It's tiny, doesn't have a screen.
Speaker 7:  Obviously it was a disaster, but I am curious. You got to use it. You tested
Speaker 7:  it, you reviewed it,
Speaker 7:  we know what was bad about it. Was there anything about the hardware that,
Speaker 7:  that you're like, you know what, there's something there.
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 5:  no,
Speaker 7:  I tried, I tried to find
Speaker 5:  Something. I'm torn on this in the, in a certain way
Speaker 5:  it speaks very highly of the team that made it, that it exists at
Speaker 5:  all. Like it's a beautifully made little thing. Like it's,
Speaker 5:  it's small. It's, it's really nice to like fiddle and worry with it, have
Speaker 5:  a really clever set of accessories. The magnet works really well. It has
Speaker 5:  really pleasant noises. Like the, the touch reaction is good. There's
Speaker 5:  like all the little tiny details that most companies don't get right on the
Speaker 5:  first try. They got right on the first try, right? Like there are, there
Speaker 5:  are surprisingly few of those sort of rough edges we're used
Speaker 5:  to from startup products, but then they had the opposite problem,
Speaker 5:  which is that all the big things they were trying to do didn't work at all.
Speaker 5:  And, and the big swings that they made were things like the laser projector,
Speaker 5:  which just essentially was useless. Like the interface didn't make any
Speaker 5:  sense. You functionally couldn't use it at all in any kind of light,
Speaker 5:  and it just didn't, they just didn't need to exist, right? And so
Speaker 5:  you could tell that all of the stuff they spent like real huge
Speaker 5:  money and resources on were just pointed in the wrong direction.
Speaker 5:  But then there's a team who was tasked with like, making the thing nice and
Speaker 5:  they did a really good job. Like the, we talk about like polished turds a
Speaker 5:  lot and it's, it's a real, like we, we kind of mean as an insult,
Speaker 5:  but it, this is like a really nicely polished turd. It really is.
Speaker 7:  I mean it's, it's like right you, like you said it like the rabbit sold because
Speaker 7:  it's $200 and it's bright and it's colorful and it's nice and this thing
Speaker 7:  also very pretty just just
Speaker 7:  way in a different world.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean, and I think the other mystique that humane made was the way
Speaker 5:  that they went about talking about this thing. Like
Speaker 5:  in, in writing about it this week, I went back and watched the first Ted
Speaker 5:  Talk that Imran Chari gave
Speaker 5:  where he like described the thing and a,
Speaker 5:  that demo is fake. Like it, I just, I please
Speaker 5:  lawyers come at me with evidence that that is not true. And I will happily
Speaker 5:  recant it. I have now watched that demo a hundred times, I've been using
Speaker 5:  this product for a year. And it is, it is impossible that he was able to
Speaker 5:  do those things on stage to get it to translate between
Speaker 5:  languages without any prompting to get it to answer a phone call. I know
Speaker 5:  how you answer a phone call on this thing, and it is by doing a gesture with
Speaker 5:  your hands that he doesn't do standing on stage and it answers the phone
Speaker 5:  call. It's just impossible. But anyway, so they,
Speaker 5:  they made it out to be this very like, you know, hugely important.
Speaker 5:  Like they were very quiet about it and they made this like very dour,
Speaker 5:  serious video about how important this gadget was gonna be.
Speaker 5:  And they got it named to Times Inventions of the year. And it was like
Speaker 5:  they, they set this up to be some huge
Speaker 5:  consequential moment in the history of technology
Speaker 5:  and it sucked.
Speaker 7:  I mean, it's very funny. Like it, it couldn't do what they promised it would
Speaker 7:  do, which, you know, it's kind of a, a big strike to start out with. But
Speaker 7:  I think there's also this element of like, they promised it would, you know,
Speaker 7:  bringing this sort of new world of ambient computing where you're not
Speaker 7:  staring at your phone so much, things just sort of happen in front of you
Speaker 7:  and you don't have to worry about it. And I think what we see with the meta
Speaker 7:  ray bands is people already wear glasses
Speaker 7:  and sunglasses that's really natural. And putting a
Speaker 7:  chunky pin on your shirt that is kind of
Speaker 7:  uncomfortable and may not stick on and then having to like hold your hand
Speaker 7:  up and look at a projector that's actually like more obtrusive than just
Speaker 7:  quickly pulling out your phone and doing something. Yeah. And so like
Speaker 7:  there, there was clearly this kernel of an idea that, that I,
Speaker 7:  I think really resonates with like everyone like it, it would be great to
Speaker 7:  use our phones less, it would be great if things just sort of happened a
Speaker 7:  little bit more ambiently
Speaker 7:  and executed on it in I think one of the most perplexing
Speaker 7:  ways imaginable. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So Josh Miller, the, the CEO of the browser company, I don't think
Speaker 5:  he'll mind me telling this story on The Vergecast. We'll see Josh, sorry,
Speaker 5:  introduced me not that long ago to this concept of novelty fatigue, which
Speaker 5:  is basically that If you try to do
Speaker 5:  too many new things, even if they're the right things, at the same
Speaker 5:  time it will feel wrong to people. And that, and that actually what
Speaker 5:  you have to do in product design is
Speaker 5:  build slowly. Like you, you can have improved
Speaker 5:  everything imaginable all at the same time and you'll
Speaker 5:  still leave people behind because it won't, it won't feel right. It won't
Speaker 5:  feel familiar. And so that that cadence of introducing novelty to people
Speaker 5:  is actually a huge part of the process of product design. And I think
Speaker 5:  like the most generous possible interpretation of
Speaker 5:  what happened to Humane, and I, I don't believe this at all, but I think
Speaker 5:  one of the mistakes that they made, and one way to look at all of this is
Speaker 5:  they just went way beyond novelty fatigue with everybody. They
Speaker 5:  were like, we are going to reinvent everything about how you do everything
Speaker 5:  all at once. And I think even if it had all worked, it wouldn't have worked
Speaker 5:  because it just, it felt wrong and it wouldn't have made sense.
Speaker 7:  It, it's funny, like I I understand exactly why he is saying that and it's
Speaker 7:  because his browser arc is really perplexing when you first use it.
Speaker 7:  I bounced off that thing like five different times and now I use it every
Speaker 7:  day and I'm furious that they're like low key maybe not working on
Speaker 7:  it anymore.
Speaker 7:  I do, I I think you're probably
Speaker 7:  mostly right there, but there I do think there's also this thing of like,
Speaker 7:  you know, the two of you have tested every phone
Speaker 7:  under the sun. I feel like
Speaker 7:  usually you can tell if if there's, if there's a little kernel of something
Speaker 7:  in there that is working, you can see it and
Speaker 7:  it, it, I think you were right that they, they tried way too many things,
Speaker 7:  but I I'm not even sure if there was one thing that was clicking there for
Speaker 7:  people.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, just seems like the concept really. And
Speaker 6:  the, the way they sold it was like, yeah, don't
Speaker 6:  look at your phone, just talk to this thing. Just be free in The world. And
Speaker 6:  like, who doesn't want that? But yeah, it, it has to work.
Speaker 7:  But like how, how are you free in The world when there's this like heavy
Speaker 7:  chunky thing, like literally pulling your shirt down? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I think ultimately one of the most convincing arguments against the
Speaker 5:  humane pin from the beginning was everything about this
Speaker 5:  makes more sense in an Apple watch. Mm. Yeah. And I, I think that
Speaker 5:  is true. Even the things about it that I like, which are like, it's not in
Speaker 5:  my pocket. It's easier to access. It's something I can sort of discreetly
Speaker 5:  talk to without having to stare at a screen. Like we've
Speaker 5:  found the wearable spot for that and I think it's probably on your wrist
Speaker 5:  and I
Speaker 7:  Would feel like straight up, I I think it is like troubling and
Speaker 7:  unfortunate and bad for technology as a whole that basically
Speaker 7:  we have to wait for Apple or Google to do this, right? Yep. It would
Speaker 7:  be great if, if Humane could come along and say, Hey,
Speaker 7:  we made a watch. It's gonna hook into your iPhone, it's gonna do it all the
Speaker 7:  iPhone things and we've added all this stuff that Right. In a world
Speaker 7:  where they could do that, I I would not be surprised if they had just
Speaker 5:  Done that. Yeah. This is why I'm so curious to see what Sam Altman and Johnny
Speaker 5:  Ive are working on Because there, there is a, there is a version of
Speaker 5:  some AI gadget that is essentially
Speaker 5:  headphones or mostly just a microphone or something that
Speaker 5:  is like, like give me a, a tool that just lets me
Speaker 5:  do the sort of advanced voice mode stuff with my
Speaker 5:  AI bot. And there's something pretty interesting inside of that, especially
Speaker 5:  as these models start to get better and more capable. But again, you, you
Speaker 5:  can't, it is, it is not allowed. Yeah. Because Google and
Speaker 5:  Apple will not let you,
Speaker 7:  Which also like Meta is freaking out about this. Like, thi this is
Speaker 7:  going to be the big limitation on future versions of the raybans.
Speaker 7:  Yep. Which is is I think like a little frightening If you look at it because
Speaker 7:  the raybans are, are one of the most interesting and sort of exciting
Speaker 7:  products because they're doing so much with so little and
Speaker 7:  clearly they have big dreams there and is not quite clear. Even if
Speaker 7:  they could pull 'em off, it's not clear how much they can pull off
Speaker 5:  Meta phone. We need the meta phone.
Speaker 5:  What was that called? Was that the Chacho? Was that the Facebook phone? Was
Speaker 5:  it the HTC Chacha?
Speaker 7:  I think there's name
Speaker 5:  Before my time that no one has said out loud in a really long time. Wait,
Speaker 5:  hold on.
Speaker 7:  I just, I literally just, I think that is still in the reviews closet. We
Speaker 7:  have, Joshua
Speaker 5:  Was primarily messaging and also features tight integration with the
Speaker 5:  social network Facebook, which includes a dedicated Facebook button below
Speaker 5:  its keyboard, which allows users to quickly share content on the service.
Speaker 5:  I just like imagine Wow. Like a
Speaker 5:  poorly designed blackberry that they finished making and
Speaker 5:  at the very, like the, like the last second five minutes
Speaker 5:  before they shipped it, somebody went, oh God, we were supposed to have a
Speaker 5:  Facebook button and just slapped it on the bottom. That's the a CCC chacha.
Speaker 5:  I never saw one in the wild. I'm gonna go looking for that. And if, If
Speaker 5:  you owned one, get at me. I have a lot of questions
Speaker 5:  for you. Alright, so this HP thing
Speaker 5:  we we're just writing off, right? Like there's no reason to continue to believe
Speaker 5:  anything is gonna happen here. The the press release for this
Speaker 5:  was so like damning in the way that it
Speaker 5:  came out from HP. Like can I just read you a a sentence from
Speaker 5:  please HP's executive? This is from Wan Tran who
Speaker 5:  is the president of technology and innovation at HP Humane's
Speaker 5:  AI platform. Cosmos backed by an incredible group of engineers, will help
Speaker 5:  us create an intelligent ecosystem across all HP devices, from
Speaker 5:  IPCs to smart printers and connected conference rooms
Speaker 5:  like just the fall, the fall from Grace from
Speaker 5:  we have found the successor to the smartphone to connected
Speaker 5:  conference rooms and smart printers. I can't is just
Speaker 6:  Tought, I can't think of a place I want AI less than a printer.
Speaker 6:  Like printers are annoying to start with,
Speaker 6:  with no extra, with nothing. No chat bot
Speaker 6:  like making things up. Like can you imagine I it's a nightmare.
Speaker 7:  I listen if they put, they put one of those projectors in the printer,
Speaker 7:  I I there's something there. It's like in instead of printing is I, I
Speaker 7:  I guess projectors exist. I
Speaker 5:  Don't know, I don't think it could get worse is my theory on the Smart Printer
Speaker 5:  thing is like sure. Chat GPT, like let me, let
Speaker 5:  me just tell you the website I'm trying to print and you figure it out. I
Speaker 5:  don't care what could possibly go wrong.
Speaker 6:  I'll describe it to the printer and it can invent
Speaker 6:  the thing I'm trying to print.
Speaker 6:  I love it that
Speaker 5:  Before we switch gears, Heather, we should briefly talk about Rabbit, which
Speaker 5:  I think is actually
Speaker 5:  continuing to like push it the thing it's trying to do, like
Speaker 5:  the the R one sucked.
Speaker 7:  I like watching you very gently try not to over,
Speaker 7:  over give him too much credit.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like I want to, I want to give Rabbit the least possible credit while
Speaker 5:  still giving them credit is where I'm at with Rabbit.
Speaker 5:  But they're, they're trying to do the thing they, the big promise of
Speaker 5:  Rabbit and the R one at the beginning was this thing called the the local
Speaker 5:  action model that was going to actually go and do stuff for you. This is
Speaker 5:  what we now call agentic ai. Like again, these are the right
Speaker 5:  ideas, at least If you believe the rest of the tech industry, this is what
Speaker 5:  everyone is working on right now. And Rabbit was actually relatively early
Speaker 5:  to be like, we're going to build a thing that lets you do stuff and we'll
Speaker 5:  go do stuff on your behalf. That stuff didn't work
Speaker 5:  ever reliably in any way because all it's doing is
Speaker 5:  clicking around a virtual instance of a really insecure browser for you.
Speaker 5:  But Rabbit has continued to poke at this and I think
Speaker 5:  smartly got pretty quiet for a while. Like the thing came out,
Speaker 5:  everybody's like, this is stupid. And then everybody's like, ah, whatever,
Speaker 5:  it's $200, I won't worry about it. And I think that like bought Rabbit
Speaker 5:  a minute to just kind of go do their thing and they've been slowly
Speaker 5:  launching some of the stuff that they've been talking about. So the, the
Speaker 5:  thing that came out this week is an agent that can
Speaker 5:  actually go and use Android apps for you and it's just a research
Speaker 5:  prototype and it's essentially like if you've used operator or any of these
Speaker 5:  other things or even like read the white papers, it's exactly what you think.
Speaker 5:  It's basically like clicking around an app on your behalf. But
Speaker 5:  like it's starting to be able to do those things. And so I think
Speaker 5:  again, this question of do I want it to happen on this device
Speaker 5:  that is going to go in my pocket or do I want it to happen on my phone that
Speaker 5:  is already in my pocket? That's, that's a big hurdle
Speaker 5:  even once somebody figures out this technology, but like
Speaker 5:  genuine kudos to Rabbit for continuing to plug away at this thing, I think.
Speaker 5:  And I think it'll be interesting to see where it goes.
Speaker 6:  It's the, the other answer to your question, Jake, of like,
Speaker 6:  how do you build AI for people? If you aren't
Speaker 6:  Apple or Google, how do you get in, you know, without
Speaker 6:  getting into those ecosystems is like you, you make a little
Speaker 6:  flashy gadget and release it and get a lot of attention.
Speaker 6:  And then maybe they were just always gonna do this,
Speaker 6:  you know, the large action model and, and maybe it's like
Speaker 6:  sort of tangentially related to the hardware, but it just
Speaker 6:  clicks around for you. And like, it's,
Speaker 6:  it's interesting, it's intriguing, but I still, I see it and I
Speaker 6:  think like, well the app intent that's coming, you know,
Speaker 6:  with the like smarter theory and iOS 18 is
Speaker 6:  kind of gonna be able to do those things for you. It seems like, it seems
Speaker 6:  like they're trying to shortcut their way around. Like we can't
Speaker 6:  get into the operating system the way that Apple obviously can.
Speaker 6:  And it's like a weird wonky kind of workaround.
Speaker 7:  I I, I do think there's something really delightful in that we
Speaker 7:  were like, well, it's too complicated to get all the APIs and nobody can
Speaker 7:  give us access to all this. Let's just train computers to be
Speaker 7:  able to understand everything that they see and move a mouse around and
Speaker 7:  just do all the things a human can do. And then we don't have to get actual
Speaker 7:  access, which is just so wildly complicated.
Speaker 7:  But also like, I I get that works that you can do everything If you
Speaker 7:  can do that.
Speaker 5:  It's just hard. It's such a damning critique of like regulatory systems and
Speaker 5:  capitalism that is the case. It's like, oh no, you
Speaker 5:  can either make Apple Play nice
Speaker 5:  or you can invent several unforeseeably new
Speaker 5:  technologies that just end around the whole process.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it's like, well I guess we'll just go invent the new technologies
Speaker 5:  and it'll be fine. To that end, actually one more thing we should talk about
Speaker 5:  before we take a break and then go to the lightning ground is Amazon is having
Speaker 5:  an event next week where I would say we're somewhere between like
Speaker 5:  kind of confident and extremely confident that they're going to finally launch
Speaker 5:  this new Alexa we've been hearing about forever. It would be so funny
Speaker 5:  if this was just like, here's some new heroes, like the ones we launched
Speaker 5:  this week. Look at arrows, here it is. We did a ring again,
Speaker 5:  but I think it's gonna be the new Alexa. And I think Amazon is
Speaker 5:  the company maybe best positioned other than Apple and Google
Speaker 5:  to build this AI stuff in a much more coherent way,
Speaker 5:  right? Like it has lots of business relationships with the
Speaker 5:  companies it would need to get the data to do this stuff. We've heard that
Speaker 5:  it's working with providers more directly instead of like
Speaker 5:  trying to do the hacky go to use the DoorDash website, they're actually going
Speaker 5:  to like integrate with DoorDash in a more meaningful way. And if
Speaker 5:  anybody has the, the literal resources and time and
Speaker 5:  energy and whatever to bake this stuff in, in, in a way that feels
Speaker 5:  st sturdier than just clicking around a virtual Chrome instance,
Speaker 5:  it would be Amazon. And yet every single piece of reporting and rumor about
Speaker 5:  Amazon suggests that the new Alexa is going to be very bad. And I just,
Speaker 5:  I don't know how to feel about that.
Speaker 7:  I still do not think people are gonna pay for this.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Oh, I ha yeah, they keep getting that gonna charge. That's the, the
Speaker 5:  rumor has been that it's gonna, it's gonna come with an up charge. Oh no.
Speaker 5:  Okay. And I don't think that's a good idea. I mean, Google and Microsoft
Speaker 5:  have both found very quickly that people will not pay extra. Yeah. And they're
Speaker 5:  starting to roll it back. So like now in workspace, you just get it for free
Speaker 5:  and you're like, can I turn off Gemini? And Google says, absolutely not.
Speaker 5:  Under no circumstances will you turn off Gemini. Gemini, Gemini is gonna
Speaker 5:  ask you every time you try to type anything, If you wanted to type
Speaker 5:  your address
Speaker 7:  Instead If you put the Gemini button in the spot where the comment button
Speaker 7:  used to be,
Speaker 6:  Oh no. And
Speaker 7:  Oh my God, is this driving me insane?
Speaker 5:  Command shift M Jake what? Command shift m this
Speaker 7:  Is, oh,
Speaker 5:  It'll change your life.
Speaker 7:  This is great, David talking to you for an hour and a half every
Speaker 5:  Day, the text command shift for these hacks, this is what we're here
Speaker 6:  For. That's change that they'll change that to the Gemini. And then what
Speaker 6:  will you do, David?
Speaker 5:  Then I'm, then I'm done. I'm switching to I'm switching to teams After that.
Speaker 5:  I don't know.
Speaker 5:  All right Allison, we're gonna let you go. Thank you for joining us. You're
Speaker 5:  gonna have to come back once you've used the 16 e and and report back on
Speaker 5:  life without Mac safe because I'm very curious.
Speaker 6:  Sounds good. Thanks for having me.
Speaker 5:  All right. And we're gonna take a break and then we're gonna come back in
Speaker 5:  a sliding round time. We'll be right back
Speaker 1:  Let, let's,
Speaker 5:  All right, we're back Time for the lightning round. Unsponsored for
Speaker 5:  flavor. I just wanna say, I suggested on the show, Jake, you, you were not
Speaker 5:  here for this, but Neil, I just randomly out of nowhere called the Lightning
Speaker 5:  round Unsponsored for Flavor like two weeks ago.
Speaker 5:  He didn't know what he meant by that, but it has stuck in my brain ever since.
Speaker 5:  And last week I suggested that we should make t-shirts that say Unsponsored
Speaker 5:  for flavor on it. And you would be amazed at the number
Speaker 5:  of people who have since told me they would buy these t-shirts. So
Speaker 5:  I can't promise this is going to happen, but this is now a thing. I'm increasingly,
Speaker 5:  I mean,
Speaker 7:  You guys talked literally the entire lightning round into existence.
Speaker 7:  You, you took, so I listen, I, I think there's something here.
Speaker 5:  Listen, if we, if we can make a shirt that just says emails that is a reference
Speaker 5:  no one gets, I think we can do on sponsor for flavor. Yeah, I feel good about
Speaker 5:  it. Alright, we have a lightning round. We're gonna do this lightning round
Speaker 5:  in two parts. First, Jake, you and I are gonna run through some news.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna talk about some stuff and then we're gonna take, we're gonna
Speaker 5:  stop. We're not gonna take a break, we're just gonna stop. And then we're
Speaker 5:  gonna call Lauren Finer who's going to come in and she's going to tell us
Speaker 5:  about the week in Trump and Elon and DOGE and various governmental
Speaker 5:  shenanigans. Everyone's favorite segment. Brendan Carr is a dummy,
Speaker 5:  is on hiatus for this week while Mila is on vacation. But we'll be back with
Speaker 5:  a vengeance on next Friday show. And so If
Speaker 5:  you, we will give you a moment to stop listening If you wanna stop
Speaker 5:  listening or watching or experiencing us in whatever way you
Speaker 5:  experience us when we start talking. So that's what we're gonna do. But
Speaker 5:  first, Jake, let's run through some news. Let's roll. The first thing I would
Speaker 5:  like you to do is explain quantum computing to me.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Easy in, in, we have how much time now? Yes. Okay. So there's
Speaker 7:  these little blah. Yeah. Okay. Sorry. Should
Speaker 7:  we describe the story? Yeah. So
Speaker 5:  Microsoft announced a thing called Myana one, which
Speaker 5:  is a new chip for quantum computing that
Speaker 5:  includes several amazing words that I would just like to say to you out loud
Speaker 5:  very quickly.
Speaker 5:  Microsoft's called it the world's first topo conductor, which kicks ass.
Speaker 5:  It also has a new material made from Indium
Speaker 5:  arsenide and aluminum also kicks ass. There is a thing called a
Speaker 5:  topological qubit. Love this. I don't know what any of this means, but
Speaker 5:  it appears as far as I understand, that Microsoft made a chip that it thinks
Speaker 5:  is going to make quantum computing more accessible for more things. Am I
Speaker 5:  close?
Speaker 7:  So I think it's one of those, I think with all of
Speaker 7:  these quantum computing achievements, there's a little bit of like a maybe,
Speaker 7:  like nobody's quite sure, you know, it's a stepping
Speaker 7:  stone towards something bigger. I will say, I think, you know, with
Speaker 7:  ai, If you had asked me three years ago, is AI gonna happen in our lifetime,
Speaker 7:  I would've been like, not a chance. Not even close. And with quantum
Speaker 7:  computing, I have been the same way where I'm like, I, I don't need to worry
Speaker 7:  about this. This is like, it's not a thing, it's just not gonna happen. And
Speaker 7:  there have been a bunch of really big announcements about quantum computing
Speaker 7:  recently, and it feels like, you know, the researchers in the field are
Speaker 7:  maybe finally taking steps there. And I don't think the answer is that we're
Speaker 7:  going to have Myron on one ships in our houses anytime
Speaker 7:  ever.
Speaker 7:  But I, I, I also, one thing I've started to realize about quantum computing
Speaker 7:  is you don't necessarily need them to be everywhere. You just need one quantum
Speaker 7:  computer and you can do a lot. And I think we're still quite a ways away,
Speaker 7:  but it's a cool name. Cool chip.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think the, the thing that is making it feel more real for me is exactly
Speaker 5:  what you just said. The idea that this is not like the
Speaker 5:  next next computer that you own in your house. It's the
Speaker 5:  next next thing that exists in a data center that makes all
Speaker 5:  of this stuff vastly more powerful. Yeah, and it's really interesting. I
Speaker 5:  would encourage everybody to go watch the video that Microsoft published
Speaker 5:  because the way that they talk about the possibilities for quantum computing
Speaker 5:  is a lot of what we hear companies say about ai, which is just the
Speaker 5:  things you can do when you massively scale the amount of processing
Speaker 5:  and the amount of information that a system can understand are very
Speaker 5:  similar. It's really interesting. So that's one thing. Number two
Speaker 5:  is, I would just very quickly like to pour one out for Amazon Chime.
Speaker 5:  The funniest and worst piece of video conferencing software
Speaker 5:  that I have maybe ever used in my life, Amazon is shutting down
Speaker 5:  Chime, which is, it's, I think there was a brief period where
Speaker 5:  Chime was going to be like an important part of an Amazon suite of business
Speaker 5:  services, but then video calling became completely commoditized
Speaker 5:  and that just, everybody kind of gave up. And the only time I've
Speaker 5:  ever used Chime is when I'm forced to, in order to talk to people
Speaker 5:  who work at Amazon. And even the people at Amazon, even the people who use
Speaker 5:  Chime think it's bad. I, I, I know that for sure,
Speaker 5:  but the thing I just wanted to say is that this, this thing was announced
Speaker 5:  and a bunch of people were in our comments talking about it, and
Speaker 5:  all anyone said was, chime sucks. I worked at Amazon, it was awful.
Speaker 5:  And it was, it was great and I just enjoyed it very much. A bunch of people
Speaker 5:  who had AWS reps who forced them to use Chime and now they will not have
Speaker 5:  to. It's a good day for everybody. I
Speaker 7:  Just have to say that, you know, before this segment started, David said
Speaker 7:  to me, Jake, are there any of these stories that you don't wanna talk about?
Speaker 7:  And you can't say Chime. And the only story that I
Speaker 7:  did not wanna talk about Chime. So Jake, this
Speaker 5:  Is the last time I'm ever gonna get to talk about the AI pin I and
Speaker 5:  chime on this podcast. You have to let me have this.
Speaker 7:  I I feel like Chime was just inve. Like who was using
Speaker 7:  this thing? Why were they using it? Why did it exist?
Speaker 5:  I have always thought there was like a 50,000 word feature.
Speaker 7:  Why is it called Chime? What
Speaker 5:  Company? Choices of business software.
Speaker 7:  Why did Amazon think they needed a a video calling service? I
Speaker 7:  don't, there are 900 of them. Well, do you remember that moment? They have
Speaker 7:  a team subscription one
Speaker 5:  Would think, do you remember that moment though at the beginning of the pandemic
Speaker 5:  all
Speaker 7:  Of sudden didn't
Speaker 5:  Verizon we're
Speaker 7:  Like, have one?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, Verizon bought blue jeans. Remember Blue jeans? This is
Speaker 5:  what I'm saying. And for Verizon.
Speaker 7:  Verizon got mad at me once because I used Blue Jeans wrong. I was like, I
Speaker 7:  I'm pretty, this is your fault. This is, I didn't choose BlueJean.
Speaker 5:  I'm pretty sure Meta used Blue jeans for a minute. Like truly,
Speaker 5:  I have always thought there is a big story in how companies pick
Speaker 5:  conference call providers. Like Apple uses WebEx and demands that everyone
Speaker 5:  who speaks to 'em uses WebEx.
Speaker 7:  I'm just gonna say there are two acceptable video calling services.
Speaker 7:  There's Google Meet, there's Zoom and anything else. Get it
Speaker 7:  outta my face.
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent agree. I have no notes done. Also, If you
Speaker 7:  Phone, If you online subscription, bring back phone
Speaker 5:  Calls.
Speaker 7:  I'm sorry. Phone. I'm so with you. Listen, people don't answer
Speaker 7:  their phone anymore. I'm gonna sound so old and crotchy. Listen,
Speaker 7:  anytime I get a phone call, I'm like, ooh, who's always calling? I wanna
Speaker 7:  pick this up. This could be anything. It's a surprise.
Speaker 5:  It's exciting stuff. It really is.
Speaker 7:  It's always spam, but, but I had a That's fine. Nobody answers.
Speaker 5:  I had a person I was talking to for a story this week text me right before
Speaker 5:  we were supposed to get on our Google meet and she was just like,
Speaker 5:  Hey, can, can we instead just do a phone call so I can like go on a walk?
Speaker 5:  And I responded to being like, that sounds like that's an awesome idea. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  of course. And truly the, the joy in her
Speaker 5:  voice when I called her and she was like, I'm outside talking
Speaker 5:  to you. Oh my God, I was like this. Let's bring that back. Anyway, enough.
Speaker 5:  Chime. RIP Chime. You were a real one.
Speaker 5:  Mira Murati, former CTO of OpenAI joins
Speaker 5:  the, the OpenAI diaspora in starting
Speaker 5:  a, I would say somewhat mysterious new AI company.
Speaker 5:  I dunno that we know much about this company at all yet. Do we?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, she's spoken a bunch of vagaries. They're like, we're going to release
Speaker 7:  research. And I'm like, oh, sick. Great. That like,
Speaker 7:  I, I, listen Mira obviously a wildly talented AI
Speaker 7:  engineer. Clearly, you know, she, she was a CT of OpenAI
Speaker 7:  while they did some very impressive stuff. So I think there's a lot of potential
Speaker 7:  here. She's attracting a lot of major talent.
Speaker 7:  However, to your point, there are a lot of companies in this,
Speaker 7:  you know, AI diaspora and I, I don't
Speaker 7:  know if there's room for all of them.
Speaker 5:  It is sort of fascinating how much of this industry is going
Speaker 5:  to be people who started their company because they disagreed
Speaker 5:  with Sam Altman in some meaningful way. Like that's the anthropic story.
Speaker 5:  That's the Mira's company is called Thinking Machines Lab, which is not
Speaker 5:  a good name.
Speaker 7:  I like it. I like it. It's if it were, it's like the browser company. If
Speaker 7:  it was, it's
Speaker 5:  If it thinking machines, labs, If you be fine with it. If it were thinking
Speaker 5:  machine labs, that's true. Fine with that too. It's, they put the s in the
Speaker 5:  wrong place. What about it? His
Speaker 7:  P possessive thinkings machine lab.
Speaker 5:  Oh, I like
Speaker 7:  It. It's Doctor Thinkings. Yeah, I like that a lot. Yeah, he's their, their
Speaker 7:  mascot and he know he's got a little lab coat on
Speaker 5:  Doctor thinking like a, he's like a question mark. Yeah. With a cloud above.
Speaker 5:  That's pretty good. Yeah. I like that a lot. Doctor thinking, TM
Speaker 7:  Thinking that's who you chat with. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But yeah, and we're, we're just in a space where it is kind of o
Speaker 5:  open AI's ideas percolating out in these sort of
Speaker 5:  mutated forms in lots of different ways. In the same way that like a
Speaker 5:  huge portion of the electric car industry is people who cut their teeth at
Speaker 5:  Tesla and then went on to do other things. And I think that has made that
Speaker 5:  industry different as a result. Opening AI is very much
Speaker 5:  doing the same thing around the AI world. Yeah. Fascinating. All
Speaker 5:  for it. We'll see, everybody's raising the most money it is
Speaker 5:  possible to raise on earth. So congrats to everybody. Next one,
Speaker 5:  the New York Times. Speaking of companies against OpenAI,
Speaker 5:  which is suing OpenAI. Oh, we should disclose here that Vox Media has some
Speaker 5:  kind of content sharing deal with OpenAI. That, that's all I
Speaker 5:  know about. So disclosure, the New York Times, which is
Speaker 5:  suing OpenAI is put out some
Speaker 5:  guidance to its team about how to use AI in
Speaker 5:  their actual work in journalism. And I put this one on here for you, Jake
Speaker 5:  in particular, you are our executive editor, you run our newsroom.
Speaker 5:  How do you feel about this?
Speaker 7:  I mean, it's funny because I I I don't think there are any reporters
Speaker 7:  who want to use ai, like, at least for the writing,
Speaker 7:  right? Like the writing is the fun part. Like that's the part of the job
Speaker 7:  that we want to do.
Speaker 7:  A and so, and it's funny, If you look at the New York Times guidance,
Speaker 7:  they're kind of, they're like, don't write with this.
Speaker 7:  The thing that the a that the New York Times suggested that
Speaker 7:  their teams do with AI is like, I I, I don't know that everybody
Speaker 7:  will know this, but like when you publish an article onto the internet, you
Speaker 7:  know, you would think there's a headline and an image and then the entire
Speaker 7:  article and you'd be like, great, I put those things in, I'm done. But
Speaker 7:  there's actually like 50 other really annoying
Speaker 7:  and kind of tedious fields you have to fill out. You gotta fill out a separate
Speaker 7:  headline for Google. You gotta fill out a separate headline for Facebook.
Speaker 7:  You gotta fill out separate descriptions for all of those things.
Speaker 7:  And, and this kind of just multiplies. And so New York Times is like maybe
Speaker 7:  you could use to fill out stuff out that you just don't wanna do.
Speaker 7:  Maybe you could use it to like write copy for a tweet or
Speaker 7:  whatever. And you know, I I think
Speaker 7:  those are the areas that people find this stuff tedious. I wanna say like
Speaker 7:  currently we are not using it for any of that. Right. And I do think it is
Speaker 7:  really interesting to see the New York Times like a, a pretty
Speaker 7:  a clearly like the, a very, very traditional newsroom
Speaker 7:  trying to offer their their team some leeway. But yeah,
Speaker 7:  I think like for us internally, again, like the writing is the fun part.
Speaker 7:  We're not going to using that. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I think the question of kind of where does a good use
Speaker 5:  of AI end and a problematic use of AI begin is
Speaker 5:  like the open question, right? Yeah. Because I think a lot of what the time
Speaker 5:  said is, is the stuff you're talking about like all this sort of metadata
Speaker 5:  and the kind of the work around the work, but then it's like there was a,
Speaker 5:  a training video. A lot of this is according to to good reporting from
Speaker 5:  Samphire, a training video that included using AI to like
Speaker 5:  develop news quizzes. And that's a really interesting one. 'cause to some
Speaker 5:  extent that's a, that's a real like honest to God editorial product.
Speaker 7:  And I think the thing ultimately becomes, for me with AI is like, okay, great,
Speaker 7:  if if it can like do this stuff faster, like I, I can like potentially see
Speaker 7:  it. But once you're having AI put together a large
Speaker 7:  body of work, the amount of work you personally are going to have to put
Speaker 7:  in to fact check it to make sure it is correct is is potentially going
Speaker 7:  to be more work than If you had just done it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The, the whole I have to let AI do it and then I have to fact check
Speaker 5:  every part of it so it actually takes longer. Yeah. Is extremely real. Alright,
Speaker 5:  two more. One kind of breaking ish news today,
Speaker 5:  Thursday as we're recording this, Amazon now has creative control
Speaker 5:  over the James Bond franchise. This is something I suspect you
Speaker 5:  and I both have feelings and maybe deep misgivings about. Okay,
Speaker 7:  This is hilarious because like a month ago, the, the Wall Street Journal
Speaker 7:  had some like blockbuster report about how the, the
Speaker 7:  Broccoli family, which controls, you know, the
Speaker 7:  bond rights in some manner just like hated
Speaker 7:  Amazon. And so now it sounds like maybe they were paid a lot of money.
Speaker 7:  Like that seems to be what
Speaker 5:  Happened. Okay. I'm glad we're on the same page about this. I I I went through
Speaker 5:  exactly the same, like
Speaker 7:  A lot of money. Like here,
Speaker 5:  Here is a quote from the Wall Street Journal story to Friends
Speaker 5:  Broccoli, Barbara Broccoli who has for decades overseen
Speaker 5:  all of the James Bond stuff has characterized her thoughts on Amazon. This
Speaker 5:  way these people are fucking idiots. That was
Speaker 5:  December 19th. That was two months ago. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And now, yeah, I, the only answer I can come to is Amazon wrote
Speaker 5:  a big giant check, which makes sense. If I were Amazon, I would write a big
Speaker 5:  giant check. Yeah. Amazon bought MGM for a huge amount of money. James Bond
Speaker 5:  is the most important IP that MGM owns. The franchise
Speaker 5:  is a disaster. Like it's been a while since they put out a movie. The
Speaker 5:  franchise is great. Like I love James Bond movies, but in recent years
Speaker 5:  it's been a mess. They don't have a movie, they don't have an actor, they
Speaker 5:  don't have a script. Like James Bond does not exist because the
Speaker 5:  broccoli and Amazon have been at the stalemate. So at some point
Speaker 5:  write the checks so you can start making James Bond movies is just the
Speaker 5:  obviously correct thing to do.
Speaker 7:  There's something very like old school and nice about, you know, the,
Speaker 7:  the franchise having, I don't know, this, this
Speaker 7:  protector and obviously it, it relies a lot on, on the
Speaker 7:  broccoli having good taste and making correct decisions with the franchise.
Speaker 7:  You know, I I think they've done okay.
Speaker 7:  I'm not a bond expert, I don't, but
Speaker 7:  you know, I I do think like, oh good, the mega corporation that
Speaker 7:  owns lots of things now controls one of the most lucrative
Speaker 7:  franchises in existence. Like yeah, like this. If you want more bond content,
Speaker 7:  this is fantastic news.
Speaker 5:  If you want more good bond content, TBD Yeah. Strong
Speaker 5:  TBD it really does feel like we're, we're, we're like one turn of this
Speaker 5:  away from like a Prime video series
Speaker 5:  where James Bond is wearing like Amazon Basics t-shirts and this
Speaker 5:  all just like James Bond is gonna start appearing on Thursday night football.
Speaker 7:  Okay. But the Bond Alexa voice, that's gonna be
Speaker 7:  good. Ooh.
Speaker 5:  That I would be into, I would take that, yeah. But then it would have to
Speaker 5:  say Alexa at the beginning of every single like as if it was Bond. That's
Speaker 5:  good stuff. Yeah. So I, that one as somebody who has
Speaker 5:  almost universally loved James Bond movies, that one is exciting
Speaker 5:  because I think we'll get movies but also does not bode well for them
Speaker 5:  being any good. So we'll see. All right, last one before we switch gears,
Speaker 5:  a headline, I swear we have run 600,000 times on The
Speaker 5:  Verge dot com. Spotify's Hi-Fi streaming could finally arrive this year.
Speaker 5:  We can't help ourselves. Jake
Speaker 7:  Chris Welch has a tradition every year on the
Speaker 7:  anniversary of Spotify saying it would launch
Speaker 7:  a Hi-Fi streaming service posting. Hey, they still haven't done it.
Speaker 7:  It has now been four years, but hey,
Speaker 7:  it, this could be it. This could be the one.
Speaker 5:  You know what? I think, I think no one will care anymore. I think
Speaker 5:  ironically, it has been so long that the number of people who were
Speaker 5:  like psyched about the idea of truly lossless streaming
Speaker 5:  has gone down to almost zero. Everybody just bought AirPods and moved
Speaker 5:  on with their life.
Speaker 7:  Like, and oh, so, so the, the rumor is, or or the, the story here is
Speaker 7:  Spotify's gonna add an additional subscription for
Speaker 7:  $6 a month that gets you Hi-Fi and like early access to
Speaker 7:  concert tickets and some other features and, and I think like,
Speaker 7:  feels like a hard sell. 'cause I think you're right. Like do people care?
Speaker 7:  It was hard to tell that you were listening to Flack
Speaker 7:  under even the best of circumstances
Speaker 7:  and every other music service just includes it in their default plan.
Speaker 7:  So like, you know, I I I'd like it,
Speaker 7:  but yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it'll be, it'll be interesting to see. Yeah. The, the report is that
Speaker 5:  The's gonna be a new tier called Music Pro.
Speaker 5:  And it'll be fascinating to see what Spotify can put in there because obviously
Speaker 5:  Spotify needs to figure out a way to charge people more money in order
Speaker 5:  to make all of its investments in Joe Rogan worth it. And
Speaker 5:  the question of like, what else will people pay for remains
Speaker 5:  relatively hard to know, I would say. Alright,
Speaker 5:  hard pivot time If you do
Speaker 5:  not want to listen to us, talk about Donald Trump and Elon
Speaker 5:  Musk and politics for the next, I don't know, 20 minutes.
Speaker 5:  Turn off the first cast. We're done. We're already way over. We did it for
Speaker 5:  you. Anyway,
Speaker 5:  that's, that's it. That's The Vergecast. But
Speaker 5:  If you, we, there is a lot going on and we have to talk about this stuff
Speaker 5:  because it matters and it is important to everything The Verge covers.
Speaker 5:  So Lauren Finer is gonna join us right now and she's gonna walk us through
Speaker 5:  all of the latest in DOGE and Elon and Trump
Speaker 5:  and chaos. So let's get into that. Lauren Finer welcome.
Speaker 7:  Hi, thanks for
Speaker 5:  Having me. We have brought you here for a new way of talking about
Speaker 5:  governmental chaos on the show, which is quickly and at the
Speaker 5:  very end,
Speaker 5:  I think this is, this felt like a good week to do this because there's been
Speaker 5:  like a, a lot has happened, but not that much sort of
Speaker 5:  hugely new stuff has happened. So this felt like a good moment to just kind
Speaker 5:  of catch up on all of the goings on because I think unless you're paying
Speaker 5:  attention minute to minute, all of the little stuff adds up to so much that
Speaker 5:  it can be hard to keep track of. So at the risk of
Speaker 5:  making you do a completely unfair thing that is impossible.
Speaker 5:  Walk us through what has happened this week. Let's start with DOGE. What's
Speaker 5:  DOGE been up to this week?
Speaker 16:  Oh, DOGE. Well, DOGE has been
Speaker 16:  continuing to be showing up at different
Speaker 16:  government agencies. Yesterday there was some reporting that
Speaker 16:  the 19-year-old do staffer who's gone by
Speaker 16:  big balls in the past showed up at CI
Speaker 16:  S A, which is the cybersecurity arm within
Speaker 16:  DHS.
Speaker 5:  Can I just say by the way, that the, the speed with which we've all just
Speaker 5:  gone to saying big balls without it like being you, you don't even notice
Speaker 5:  that. It's like just saying a person's name, you're like, oh yeah, big balls
Speaker 5:  is there the other day. It sucks and I hate it.
Speaker 16:  Yeah, we do have a federal office named after a meme coin, so at this point,
Speaker 16:  every, this is what we're doing is our game. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But anyway, keep going.
Speaker 16:  Yeah, so I mean we've seen, you know, DOGE continuing to do its
Speaker 16:  thing. We've seen some attempts to,
Speaker 16:  you know, pull back on that.
Speaker 16:  Y you know, so far there's kind of been this like mixed bag
Speaker 16:  from the courts. A judge ruled this week that
Speaker 16:  DOGE could keep accessing government data for now
Speaker 16:  basically they said, you know, this emergency motion, there wasn't
Speaker 16:  enough there to keep DOGE from transferring data from
Speaker 16:  a handful of government agencies immediately.
Speaker 16:  But the judge also indicated there could be, there could be a
Speaker 16:  different ruling on the merits later on. So, you
Speaker 16:  know, they're continuing to move forward at this point. And
Speaker 16:  you know, in the meantime, you know it, even in an
Speaker 16:  accelerated way, the courts are gonna take time to
Speaker 16:  sort all of this out. And in the meantime, a lot of government
Speaker 16:  employees are still being laid off. The CFPB was gutted
Speaker 16:  late last week, you know, pretty much all their technology
Speaker 16:  staffers that help investigate the tech side
Speaker 16:  of things within
Speaker 16:  FinTech have been let go. So, you know, a lot of
Speaker 16:  this is already, the damage is gonna be done
Speaker 16:  and it's still causing a lot of chaos around here.
Speaker 5:  And that's kind of the bet, right? Is that the, the speed with which
Speaker 5:  this team can work will outpace anyone's
Speaker 5:  attempts to stop it and they'll, the damage will essentially already be done.
Speaker 16:  Exactly. I mean, Musk has been known for, you know, sleeping and
Speaker 16:  on factory floors trying to just work around the clock to get
Speaker 16:  these things done. And there was reporting earlier on
Speaker 16:  that this is part of it that he's thinking he can kind of
Speaker 16:  outpace government staffers that he sees as,
Speaker 16:  you know, lazy or not that productive, which,
Speaker 16:  you know, a lot of government staffers that I've talked to find pretty
Speaker 16:  offensive. You know, these are people who have devoted their lives to,
Speaker 16:  to these jobs that are in the civil service. And they,
Speaker 16:  in a lot of cases, especially in tech roles, take big tech, big pay cuts
Speaker 16:  to work in these sort of roles. So yeah,
Speaker 16:  that does seem to be the bet here that they can just move forward at
Speaker 16:  a pace that accomplishes what they wanna accomplish before the
Speaker 16:  courts can catch up.
Speaker 5:  And it also seems like it's not like DOGE is like covering itself in
Speaker 5:  glory and getting everything right and making a series of incredibly like
Speaker 5:  smart, thoughtful decisions too, right? Like what was the, the
Speaker 5:  8 million versus $8 billion, you know,
Speaker 5:  teeny tiny miss that that they made this week,
Speaker 16:  Right? So there was a, on the DOGE
Speaker 16:  website where they try to keep track of like
Speaker 16:  everything they're cutting, there was this,
Speaker 16:  I guess decimal place error where there was a contract
Speaker 16:  that they claimed to have cut that was
Speaker 16:  that they listed as $8 billion, but it actually was
Speaker 16:  8 million. And you know, the problem might have stemmed from an
Speaker 16:  issue in how that number appeared in a different, you know,
Speaker 16:  government database. But, you know, it kind of just
Speaker 16:  goes to show that this is something that's being
Speaker 16:  done very quickly maybe with not a lot of
Speaker 16:  checking on the finer details here. And
Speaker 16:  you know, I I think that Elon Musk has even said, you know, there'll
Speaker 16:  be some error, you know, we're not always gonna get it completely right,
Speaker 16:  but,
Speaker 16:  and it, that's to be expected. But at the same time, when you're talking
Speaker 16:  about government services that impact a lot of people, it,
Speaker 16:  it's really important to get it right in a lot of these cases.
Speaker 5:  There was a wired headline this week that
Speaker 5:  was like the, the DOGE incompetence is a feature and not a bug.
Speaker 5:  And I've been thinking about that ever since. Like, doing well is not the
Speaker 5:  point, right? Like you call this whatever you want every, I keep talking
Speaker 5:  to people who are like, well they're not even like identifying the things
Speaker 5:  that would save all that much money. And I keep being like, that's the money
Speaker 5:  is not the point.
Speaker 7:  I mean this is the Twitter playbook, right? Yeah. Like E Elon didn't care
Speaker 7:  if it broke a little bit. He, he, he gutted the company
Speaker 7:  and he let things break and then he just sort of built on top of that
Speaker 7:  broken core. And you know, it's one thing when it's
Speaker 7:  a, a micro microblogging service or whatever
Speaker 7:  and it's another thing when it is the federal government of the United States
Speaker 7:  and there are millions and millions and millions of people who
Speaker 7:  rely on getting checks and services and benefits
Speaker 7:  to, to survive. Like, you know,
Speaker 7:  in many ways we optimize to make sure that everything happens
Speaker 7:  correctly. And he is optimizing to make sure that
Speaker 7:  there are no, or you know, he claims he claims
Speaker 7:  to be opt optimizing for making sure that there's zero error. But in
Speaker 7:  doing that,
Speaker 7:  there's going to be so much error in what gets missed
Speaker 5:  Because he is just
Speaker 7:  Pulling stuff apart.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I, Liz Lato and I were joking on the show a couple of weeks ago
Speaker 5:  about like, thank God we filed our taxes early
Speaker 5:  before DOGE got into the IRS and blew it all up. And it now seems like
Speaker 5:  DOGE is in the IRS blowing it all up. And I think
Speaker 5:  like we, we've talked a bunch about what will be the thing that
Speaker 5:  really makes this feel real for people. Because so much of this is like
Speaker 5:  theoretical, right? Like big balls is has your social security number, right?
Speaker 5:  Like that seems bad, but it's hard to know what to do with that. That's like
Speaker 5:  a very 20, 25 sentence. But I think most people don't really know what
Speaker 5:  to make of that piece of information. But this thing about like, oh it's
Speaker 5:  my, my tax refund is going to be massively delayed or canceled or
Speaker 5:  taken away from me for political reasons is like, those are the things
Speaker 5:  that may start to happen fairly quickly here and
Speaker 5:  it's gonna be some mix, like you're saying Jacob of like commission and omission,
Speaker 5:  right? Things that fall apart on purpose and things that fall apart because
Speaker 5:  there's literally no one left to pay attention to them.
Speaker 16:  Yeah, I definitely think that's gonna be the thing that gets people kind
Speaker 16:  of clued into what's going on here. If things that they rely on
Speaker 16:  start to break or you know, they're not getting their VA benefits or
Speaker 16:  Medicare benefits or things like that. I also think that there might be
Speaker 16:  some things that won't become apparent for quite some time.
Speaker 16:  You know, for example, at the CFPB who, who's checking
Speaker 16:  on the consumer complaints now, who's getting back to those, right?
Speaker 16:  And that might not be something that you file every day or even, you know,
Speaker 16:  every year, but at some point it's going to become apparent
Speaker 16:  If, you know, those sorts of complaints aren't being answered to,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, wasn't there a bill last week to like
Speaker 5:  increase bank fees? That's like, this is the sort of thing that the CF
Speaker 5:  PB exists to make sure does not happen and that
Speaker 5:  overdraft fees can't kill you as a person who made a mistake with
Speaker 5:  your ATM card. Like these are the things that we just don't have in place
Speaker 5:  anymore. Lauren, a couple of specific things I do want to touch on here.
Speaker 5:  One is Trump's executive order about the FTC and
Speaker 5:  the FCC. Can you explain that?
Speaker 16:  I can try.
Speaker 5:  It's the best we can hope for.
Speaker 16:  Yeah, yeah. Basically in this new
Speaker 16:  executive order this week, president Trump
Speaker 16:  basically asserted that the, the
Speaker 16:  White House has this kind of authority to supervise what
Speaker 16:  have typically been independent regulatory agencies.
Speaker 16:  Agencies like the Federal Trade Commission, the Federal Communications Commission.
Speaker 16:  And these are agencies that the president does get to
Speaker 16:  select who leads the agency and therefore sets
Speaker 16:  the agenda, decides what things get voted on or not. But
Speaker 16:  at the same time, they're staffed by other
Speaker 16:  commissioners from different parties. There's rules about how many commissioners
Speaker 16:  from each party there can be. So there's somewhat of a balance
Speaker 16:  there and it's hard for a chair to just
Speaker 16:  unilaterally lead an agency in a certain direction.
Speaker 16:  But in this way it seems like the president is trying to
Speaker 16:  assert this kind of oversight over these independent agencies
Speaker 16:  to, it seems, make sure that their agenda is in
Speaker 16:  line with what he wants. So that's really contrary
Speaker 16:  to how these agencies have worked in the past. You know,
Speaker 16:  obviously he's already installed people that he seems to think
Speaker 16:  align with him and his political values. If you look at
Speaker 16:  Andrew Ferguson at the FTC and Brendan Carr at the FCC
Speaker 16:  and some of the recent statements they've made,
Speaker 5:  They have been just thrilled to talk about how much they love doing Donald
Speaker 5:  Trump's bidding. Like if anything you're, you're underselling the extent
Speaker 5:  to which he already has lackeys in charge and has decided that was not enough.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 7:  I'm confused why he would even need to do this. Like, is Brendan car gonna
Speaker 7:  go rogue and be like, eh, neutrality is pretty good.
Speaker 16:  Yeah, I, I think, you know, obviously I think this applies to many
Speaker 16:  more agencies than just those two. I think it would apply to
Speaker 16:  agencies like the SEC for example, but,
Speaker 16:  you know, I think it just is another way of Trump asserting his power
Speaker 16:  and asserting his influence over as much of the federal government
Speaker 16:  as he can. And I don't know exactly what it will look like
Speaker 16:  for this to be executed. You know, it seems like
Speaker 16:  he kinda wants these agencies to run by what
Speaker 16:  he calls significant regulatory actions by the executive office of the
Speaker 16:  president. What does that entail?
Speaker 16:  I guess it remains to be seen, but basically
Speaker 16:  it's just another way to exert the sort of influence and,
Speaker 16:  you know, whether that's gonna be through
Speaker 16:  official or unofficial communications with these
Speaker 16:  agencies. I think there's going to be some level of,
Speaker 16:  of kind of trying to get these agencies to work in a way that's in line
Speaker 16:  with the president's values.
Speaker 5:  Clearly there is no pretense of separation of
Speaker 5:  powers anymore. Like that's not the, the Trump administration has let go
Speaker 5:  of the idea that they even need to pretend they're interested in the separation
Speaker 5:  of powers. I mean, you have, you have Trump saying, well was
Speaker 5:  it when when someone saves his country, no laws are broken.
Speaker 5:  They're all saying they're just gonna ignore the judges. Like it's, it's
Speaker 5:  pretty straightforward what is happening here. It's just been interesting
Speaker 5:  to see Jake, to your point where they feel like they need to actually put
Speaker 5:  pen to paper on this stuff and where Trump can
Speaker 5:  just like truth social it into existence and hope that that works.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, everything's just like yo Loing, like seeing how far they can go with
Speaker 7:  it.
Speaker 16:  Well I think a lot of these executive orders, it's, you know, we've seen
Speaker 16:  an executive order, I think on maybe the first day of his
Speaker 16:  presidency where he kind of just said, yeah, the first Amendment exists
Speaker 16:  and we can't censor. And it's like, yeah, that already,
Speaker 16:  it already said that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that one's been there a while,
Speaker 16:  But I think there's just this sense of wanting to assert via executive
Speaker 16:  order, here are my values as president and here's how
Speaker 16:  I am going to lead this office.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, makes sense. Alright, last one. Tariffs. We got
Speaker 5:  tariffs going so well for everyone. I would say have
Speaker 5:  gone just swimmingly for everyone involved. No
Speaker 5:  strangeness. So we're doing more of them. We're doing more tariffs now.
Speaker 16:  Yeah. So Trump was threatening a
Speaker 16:  25% and higher tariff on chips
Speaker 16:  and we've already seen at Acer saying that
Speaker 16:  it's going to raise laptop prices
Speaker 16:  10% in response to the 10%
Speaker 16:  tariff on income goods from China. So, you know, this is,
Speaker 16:  they're kind of saying, alright, we see you're raising this, we're gonna
Speaker 16:  raise our prices. And I think that's exactly the thing
Speaker 16:  that a lot of economists have feared is that this is really going to
Speaker 16:  raise prices for consumers. I think the Trump administration would say in
Speaker 16:  the long run, this is going to be better for consumers, it's going to make
Speaker 16:  things more fair, it's gonna provide more opportunity within the
Speaker 16:  us But that's a pretty big gamble here.
Speaker 7:  I love Acer's response here where they're just like, it's 10. Like yeah,
Speaker 7:  price can go up 10%. Like what? Like it's 10% tariff, 10% price, act like
Speaker 7:  it's kind of it, that's
Speaker 5:  Literally how it works. Like,
Speaker 7:  Like we just been like, wait, like we've been waiting for somebody to say
Speaker 7:  this and, and finally, you know, as your CEO came out and was just like,
Speaker 7:  that's Yeah, it's math. Yeah. Like
Speaker 5:  That's it. Your government made it 10% more expensive, so now it's 10% more
Speaker 5:  expensive.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's just science. What is your sense, Lauren, of how this is
Speaker 5:  working as a political move? 'cause I think it's like,
Speaker 5:  there, there are all kinds of complicated economic rationales
Speaker 5:  behind all of this, but I think one thing Trump has always said is that this
Speaker 5:  is like a, a move of power and strength for the Trump administration and
Speaker 5:  it is like a statement of purpose in The world. And with Mexico
Speaker 5:  and Canada, they were kind of like, we're doing it too. And then Trump was
Speaker 5:  like, nevermind. And it doesn't feel like it's working. Is does it,
Speaker 5:  is it working?
Speaker 16:  That probably depends who you ask. I think maybe
Speaker 16:  he is thinking all along, this is a negotiation tactic and I'm gonna start
Speaker 16:  from this really strong stance on how we're going to do
Speaker 16:  trade policy
Speaker 16:  and you know, land somewhere in the middle.
Speaker 16:  But you know, on the other hand, you're talking about
Speaker 16:  putting tariffs on who a, a historical
Speaker 16:  ally like Canada, that has really changed
Speaker 16:  the dynamic with that country. So I, I think
Speaker 16:  it, it's really, I don't know if it would necessarily be the way that Trump
Speaker 16:  anticipated it would work out. Maybe it is, but it it's
Speaker 16:  certainly causing a lot of chaos around The world.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And I just feel like I, I, I keep reading all this stuff that Trump
Speaker 5:  says about like, you know, they'll just build factories and plants in the
Speaker 5:  United States and it's like, oh that's that it's fine. That just takes like,
Speaker 5:  what's that like two weeks? Like my guy, you're a real estate developer,
Speaker 5:  you know how long buildings take and then it's like, Intel's over here, we
Speaker 5:  gave them all the money in The world and they still can't build chips that
Speaker 5:  anybody wants. Like maybe this stuff is hard and maybe, maybe
Speaker 5:  that's not the fight that we should be fighting, but I digress. Anything
Speaker 5:  else, Lauren? What, what else is top of mind in the, in the Trump and
Speaker 5:  DOGE and Musk universe right now before we get outta here?
Speaker 16:  I mean there's, there's just so much. I think, you know, I'm
Speaker 16:  just gonna be continuing to track all of this and
Speaker 16:  you know, continuing to see where DOGE goes next, what sort of
Speaker 16:  data they're trying to get and hopefully eventually get an understanding
Speaker 16:  of what they're going to use it for. I don't know if that's something
Speaker 16:  that even they know right now, but yeah, I think that's the thing that we
Speaker 16:  really want to understand. Ultimately,
Speaker 5:  What's your read on how the pushback is going? 'cause like you said, the,
Speaker 5:  there have been some court decisions stopping things that have gone.
Speaker 5:  I would say the, those court decisions have been some degree of respected
Speaker 5:  and disrespected over time, but the, there's definitely been more energy
Speaker 5:  on the other side of the aisle fighting back against this stuff. How is that
Speaker 5:  going on that side?
Speaker 16:  Yeah, I think we've seen a, a little bit of success from
Speaker 16:  the opposition. You know, we've seen some court
Speaker 16:  orders that, you know, at least put some sort of
Speaker 16:  pause on, you know, accessing or
Speaker 16:  changing data or you know, further firings.
Speaker 16:  But it's definitely been kind of all over the place. We saw that the
Speaker 16:  Treasury Inspector General said that they'd investigate
Speaker 16:  doer's access to the payment system and that was in response
Speaker 16:  to Senate Democrats who had asked for that
Speaker 16:  kind of investigation. So, you know, we're starting to see
Speaker 16:  a little bit of this opposition gained some traction.
Speaker 16:  That said, you know, like I mentioned earlier, there's a lot that it
Speaker 16:  seems like DOGE is already doing that could, you know,
Speaker 16:  mess up some systems or access data
Speaker 16:  or lead to layoffs that are really hard to undo
Speaker 16:  later on.
Speaker 5:  Totally. Alright, Lauren, thank you for coming and doing this with us.
Speaker 5:  This was extremely helpful and, and I think we're gonna have to do this more.
Speaker 5:  We need to get out of here. I have officially made Jake late for a meeting
Speaker 5:  that I promised I was not gonna make him late for We've gone way over. Thank
Speaker 5:  you both for doing this. This was incredibly fun. Hopefully Neli just stays
Speaker 5:  on vacation. We don't, we don't need that guy. We'll be back next time.
Speaker 5:  Lots of stuff left going on. Thank you both. Thank you all. That's The Vergecast
Speaker 5:  rock and roll.
Speaker 10:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 10:  you. Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one.
Speaker 10:  The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network.
Speaker 10:  Our show's produced by Will Pour Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer.
Speaker 10:  And that's it. We'll see you next week.