# Transcript
ID: 7a3d2749-2792-4b8f-bc5f-db1346e3adf5
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/4161081232188617450/5249983859168374524/s93290-US-5114s-1738664450.mp3
Description: Today on the show, it’s all about the future of phones… and your data. The Verge’s Allison Johnson joins the show to talk about the new Samsung Galaxy S25, what’s new in this high-end phone, and what it means for all the other smartphones coming this year. After that, Cooper Quintin, a senior staff technologist at the Electronic Frontier Foundation, talks us through how to think about the privacy implications of RedNote, TikTok, DeepSeek, and all the other tech that puts us in contact with China. Finally, we enlist The Verge’s Jennifer Pattison Tuohy to help us answer a question from the Vergecast Hotline all about the Meta Portal. Remember the Meta Portal?? If you’re missing yours, we have some ideas.
Speaker 2:  Welcome To The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of minor
Speaker 2:  smartphone camera upgrades. I'm your friend David Pierce, and I am
Speaker 2:  sitting here once again, repacking my travel electronics
Speaker 2:  bag. I've been traveling a bunch. I've had a lot of like 36 hour trips
Speaker 2:  recently, which is a weird and sort of unique packing challenge, but I've
Speaker 2:  gotten very good. I can do the whole thing in a backpack now, even if I have
Speaker 2:  to bring a camera. And the trick, the key for me has been
Speaker 2:  that I turned this whole gigantic bag full
Speaker 2:  of cables and other assorted crap into two things. I
Speaker 2:  bought these things from Amazon. They're these retractable
Speaker 2:  USB cables. I got one that's six feet long and
Speaker 2:  black, and one that's blue and three feet long. And these are now the only
Speaker 2:  USB cables I carry with me. Anywhere I can plug into walls, I can plug into
Speaker 2:  other devices, I can plug them into almost everything I this thing where
Speaker 2:  everything is USBC. It's great. Like, to be clear, I don't care how you
Speaker 2:  feel about the eu, I don't care how you feel about like Apple wanting to
Speaker 2:  do lightning, whatever. It's better that there's one port for everything.
Speaker 2:  And I'm finally to the point where, actually, other than my AirPods, which
Speaker 2:  I haven't upgraded in a long time, every gadget I own is USBC,
Speaker 2:  and it's fabulous. So now instead of a giant bag, I just have this and it
Speaker 2:  has made everything a whole lot easier. I'll link these in the show notes.
Speaker 2:  They're on Amazon. I don't know if there's any like specific reason to buy
Speaker 2:  this brand over any other, but they're great.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, we are not here to talk about USB cables, although we're a little
Speaker 2:  bit here to talk about USB cables on every single episode of this show. Today,
Speaker 2:  we're gonna do two things on the show. First, we're gonna talk about the
Speaker 2:  Galaxy S 25 and all of the phones coming up this year.
Speaker 2:  What we think is gonna happen in maybe not the
Speaker 2:  most interesting year ever in smartphones, but in a year where a lot of smartphone
Speaker 2:  companies are going to make the case that your phone can be different
Speaker 2:  and new because of ai. So we're gonna get into that. We're
Speaker 2:  also gonna talk about China. With all of this stuff happening with TikTok
Speaker 2:  and RedNote and DeepSeek, this question of how we as internet users
Speaker 2:  should think about China and the Chinese government and apps that come from
Speaker 2:  China and products that come from China is just complicated. And we're gonna
Speaker 2:  try to sort through it with somebody who actually knows what they're talking
Speaker 2:  about. We also have a question from The Vergecast hotline. Lots of fun stuff
Speaker 2:  to get to. This is a particularly fun hotline question, and I feel like I
Speaker 2:  say that a lot, but I really enjoyed this one because it made me think about
Speaker 2:  a gadget I haven't thought about in a long time. All that is coming up in
Speaker 2:  just a sec. But first I'm just gonna can do you see how
Speaker 2:  fun this looks? This look, it just, it's a long cable and you pull
Speaker 2:  and it goes back in. This is what The Vergecast is here for.
Speaker 2:  Retractable USBC cables. This is the dream, this is The Vergecast.
Speaker 2:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's talk about some gadgets. So last week,
Speaker 2:  Samsung announced the Galaxy S 25 lineup. There's the S
Speaker 2:  25, the S 25 plus the S 25 Ultra.
Speaker 2:  By and large, I think these phones are not the most interesting
Speaker 2:  things that have ever been launched, but they're gonna be very popular and
Speaker 2:  they are the first kind of big mainstream.
Speaker 2:  Lots of people are going to buy them phones that we've seen this year,
Speaker 2:  which makes it a fun moment to, I think look at the rest of the year
Speaker 2:  ahead. We know pretty much what we're gonna get. We're gonna get new pixels,
Speaker 2:  we're gonna get new iPhones, we're gonna get more foldables, we're gonna
Speaker 2:  get more flippable. We're gonna have a lot of new ideas about what a
Speaker 2:  smartphone should do and how AI should figure in. And so I figured
Speaker 2:  Alison Johnson and I should just get into what we think 2025 is
Speaker 2:  going to look like and maybe a little bit what we're hoping for from
Speaker 2:  smartphones in the year to come. So let's talk S 25.
Speaker 2:  Let's talk 2025. Let's get into it. Alison Johnson. Hello.
Speaker 2:  Hello. It's phone time again are, it's January 31st as we're
Speaker 2:  recording this and somehow it's already phone time. It's
Speaker 7:  Phone season baby.
Speaker 2:  This is just the rest of your year. Now this is, you got, oh, don't say that.
Speaker 2:  You got two weeks between CES and right now. And now it's just phones forever.
Speaker 7:  Phones for the rest of time.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So, okay. So because it's January, I kind of wanna do two things. I
Speaker 2:  wanna talk about your review of the Samsung S 25 Ultra
Speaker 2:  A phone. I find both deeply boring and thoroughly fascinating and
Speaker 2:  I want to peel that apart a little bit. And then I wanna look ahead to the
Speaker 2:  year to come a little bit. I think it's gonna gonna be a really interesting
Speaker 2:  year of phones. And I just wanna talk about that a little bit. But let's
Speaker 2:  start with the S 25. You, you've reviewed the thing, you tried it.
Speaker 2:  I would not say based on the little bit I've heard about your review, you
Speaker 2:  seem wildly enthusiastic about this phone. Is that fair to say?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, that's fair. And I'm, I've been using
Speaker 7:  the, the S 25 Ultra first for the past week.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it's complicated. It's like, it is a great phone. It's a, it's
Speaker 7:  a very good phone. It's been a good phone, you know, for the past couple
Speaker 7:  of generations. But it just feels like
Speaker 7:  Samsung is kind of losing the plot on, like, they call this
Speaker 7:  phone the ultra, like it should be the everything you
Speaker 7:  could ever want from a phone. And it kind of is. But every, it
Speaker 7:  feels like the past couple years they've just been taking away little things
Speaker 7:  of like, it used to have the 10 x dedicated Zoom
Speaker 7:  and then they're like, well, people didn't really use it that much, so we
Speaker 7:  do a five x and you're like, fine. And then
Speaker 7:  this time around they're like, we took away the, the Bluetooth and the
Speaker 7:  stylus and you can't do the little magic wand things anymore. 'cause no one
Speaker 7:  was doing them. And it's like, fine, I guess I can,
Speaker 7:  I, I'm not gonna miss them. But then you end up with like, what have
Speaker 7:  they been adding? And it's just kind of like
Speaker 7:  stalled out. I feel like we've got all these AI features,
Speaker 7:  which are a real mixed bag still. And they're on
Speaker 7:  every other phone. They're like on all the Samsung phones, right?
Speaker 7:  They're on older Samsung phones, they're on Android phones. So
Speaker 7:  I'm just sort of sitting here like, this is a great phone. Sure. But like,
Speaker 7:  why? What makes it so special? I don't know.
Speaker 2:  So I'm of two minds about all of this, which is part of what I wanna
Speaker 2:  talk through with you. I think on the one hand, the thing that Samsung
Speaker 2:  is describing where it's like, let's take all the confusing and
Speaker 2:  complicated stuff out and just give you a phone that is
Speaker 2:  good and is full of things that people like to do. I think it's good,
Speaker 2:  right? Like it's, it's a thing we ask for in product design all the time.
Speaker 2:  Like stop shipping weird shit and just make a good phone
Speaker 2:  that does things. People like, I think is like a not wrong path.
Speaker 2:  But then on the other hand, I do feel like either
Speaker 2:  Samsung is, like you said, kind of losing the plot and running out of ideas
Speaker 2:  or this is just a sign that there is absolutely nothing left to do
Speaker 2:  in smartphones and, and that maybe our phones are what they
Speaker 2:  are and they're, they have hit laptop territory of like, we pretty
Speaker 2:  much know how this is supposed to go the end. And then I think if you're
Speaker 2:  Samsung continuing to sell a phone that you call the ultra
Speaker 2:  just feels bonkers. Like my, the more I think about
Speaker 2:  your review and your experience, the less I even understand why this phone
Speaker 2:  exists. Because like you're saying, this is supposed to be the one that does
Speaker 2:  all the things. And it's supposed to be the place where Samsung tests its
Speaker 2:  weirdest ideas. And I kind of love Samsung for that. And you, for years they
Speaker 2:  were like, oh, most people don't want a stylists, but some people do.
Speaker 2:  And so we make a note and it's gonna blow up on a plane.
Speaker 7:  Right?
Speaker 2:  But like they, they did that for people. And there's something about that
Speaker 2:  that I actually really appreciate about Samsung that they're like, this is,
Speaker 2:  this is the one where we just said yes to everything.
Speaker 2:  And now that it's not that I'm not super clear on what it even is
Speaker 2:  anymore.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And it's like I am generally o like of
Speaker 7:  the mind that phones are boring now and that's okay. It's like
Speaker 7:  we've, we just kind of landed on like what a phone is shaped like
Speaker 7:  and what it does. We're not doing a bunch of wacky things anymore with like
Speaker 7:  cameras that pop up or like little things that flip around,
Speaker 7:  you know? Bless lg.
Speaker 2:  Those were fun days though. Yeah. I missed those
Speaker 7:  Times. I know. They were fun. What was the
Speaker 2:  LG one that the, the screen like turned 90 degrees? I think
Speaker 7:  That was the wing.
Speaker 2:  The wing. Ugh. I wish that had been successful.
Speaker 7:  You know, LG was
Speaker 2:  That, I don't think any person on earth bought that phone, but I loved that
Speaker 2:  it existed.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Bless them.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah. It's like we're just landed on like the basic
Speaker 7:  idea of like what a phone is shaped like what it does
Speaker 7:  and it's fine. And people, we use it for so many things in our lives.
Speaker 7:  You don't want a bunch of have to learn a bunch of different stuff every
Speaker 7:  time you buy a new phone.
Speaker 7:  So I think that's okay. But yeah, I think the problem comes when
Speaker 7:  Samsung is like, here's the ultra phone
Speaker 7:  and it costs 1299 and you
Speaker 7:  definitely should pay that much money for it. And you're like, okay, what
Speaker 7:  do I get? And it's like, well, you know, you get a
Speaker 7:  five x zoom, but you could get that on a pixel phone. You get a
Speaker 7:  little stylus that like used to do some special stuff and
Speaker 7:  it does it now. Like, I don't know, like give us something like
Speaker 7:  do do something. Make it a little bigger and double the
Speaker 7:  battery life for, I don't know. You know? I'm sure it's that easy,
Speaker 7:  you know, designing engineering phones. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I feel like there's something like, there has to be something and Samsung
Speaker 7:  is just kind of like stalled out.
Speaker 2:  I know, I, I do think, I'm glad you mentioned the battery life 'cause I was
Speaker 2:  thinking about it and I'm like, okay, what, what would work as ultra for
Speaker 2:  me? And it's like twice as thick, twice the battery would do it, right? I
Speaker 2:  think, I think you could, you could feasibly be like, this phone is like
Speaker 2:  a thick boy with two C's,
Speaker 2:  but it lasts for five days. And I actually, I, I think that is like an
Speaker 2:  incredibly interesting idea about a smartphone. Yeah. Then
Speaker 2:  on the flip side, I think the other one they could have done is really gone
Speaker 2:  after durability and, and like, yeah, Motorola,
Speaker 2:  I feel like was really the last company to take a big swing at. Like, we
Speaker 2:  are going to make a phone that you can't break. And it didn't, it
Speaker 2:  didn't really work. But I think that's more for like Motorola reasons than
Speaker 2:  it being a good idea of reasons. Yeah. Right. And so I think if I'm Samsung,
Speaker 2:  like I, I would've been interested to see if Samsung had poked it either
Speaker 2:  of those two and been like, is this, is this a thing people will upgrade
Speaker 2:  for? Because I think it is, but we have no evidence for it because no one
Speaker 2:  has ever really tested it. Like I think if I could say to somebody,
Speaker 2:  here's a phone that will last you from Monday to
Speaker 2:  Thursday reliably, or here is a phone that you
Speaker 2:  slippery handed goofs you, you can't even break.
Speaker 7:  Right.
Speaker 2:  That works. That is the most interesting new idea about a smartphone I've
Speaker 2:  heard in a very long time. And I like, I wish Samsung had picked something
Speaker 2:  like that to do here.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I feel like we're gonna end up with like the
Speaker 7:  fold, the z fold in the ultra like merge into
Speaker 7:  like here is the ultimate phone that
Speaker 7:  does other things and it's like cut somehow comes with the stylus and
Speaker 7:  folds in half and like if they upgraded the cameras
Speaker 7:  on the fold, like that would be an ultra phone
Speaker 7:  I think. Yeah. If, if such a thing exists. But yeah, as far
Speaker 7:  as things that people actually want in their lives, like battery life
Speaker 7:  would be an easy one.
Speaker 2:  Like Yeah, I totally agree. So the two things I'm particularly curious about
Speaker 2:  on the S 25 Ultra in particular, but kind of the S 25 line in
Speaker 2:  general is as ever the AI and the cameras
Speaker 2:  brand new-ish version of Gemini shipping first on this
Speaker 2:  device is supposed to be the like multi-step multi app
Speaker 2:  action things supposed to be kind of the next AI
Speaker 2:  experience on your phone. You've gotten to test it, how'd it go
Speaker 7:  Good and bad. So I'll start with the good, I finally
Speaker 7:  did the thing where it's like you have something on your screen and you wanna
Speaker 7:  put it on your calendar and that has just not been a thing that Gemini are
Speaker 7:  like any other technology in the world can do apparently.
Speaker 7:  But it finally happened. You like Summon
Speaker 7:  Gemini, which is now the default assistant on Samsung phones,
Speaker 2:  Which we agree is like an extremely good upgrade, right? Yeah. That is the
Speaker 2:  correct. Okay. It
Speaker 7:  It should be this way. Excuse like hanging around in the settings menu,
Speaker 7:  like doing some stuff and that's fine. Like that's, yeah, that's where Bixby
Speaker 7:  belongs.
Speaker 2:  I don't wanna kill Bixby. I just don't wanna like think about Bixby very
Speaker 7:  Often. Yeah. Bixby can just be hanging out. Yeah. Yeah. I had something on
Speaker 7:  my screen, I summon Gemini and there you get a little chip
Speaker 7:  that's like, ask about this screen or get help with the screen. And I was
Speaker 7:  like, add this to my calendar and it frigging did it
Speaker 7:  and it was like the best thing. It was like, finally,
Speaker 7:  this is all I've been wanting, but the, it,
Speaker 7:  it kind of falls apart in other ways when you're like,
Speaker 7:  I am, I'm, I'm a Sudoku now I am
Speaker 7:  in my Sudoku era and I was like asking
Speaker 7:  Gemini for some Sudoku solving. I was like, find some
Speaker 7:  videos on YouTube to help me learn Sudokus
Speaker 7:  and add them to a note and it can do that. Like, it, it
Speaker 7:  follows instructions. It's like, okay. And it goes and gets some videos
Speaker 7:  and then opens a note app. It's like that is all cool to see that
Speaker 7:  happening. But what it created in the notes app was just
Speaker 7:  a list of video, like headlines with, with
Speaker 7:  no link.
Speaker 2:  I I did the same thing. I tried it when, when it first came out just
Speaker 2:  like on Gemini web and was I did the same thing. Mm. I forget it was oh it
Speaker 2:  was, it was like GPU explainers and it pulled, it pulled like
Speaker 2:  five different Google Keep notes that were just the title
Speaker 2:  of the video and nothing else.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, no. He was
Speaker 2:  Like, what, what are we
Speaker 7:  Accomplishing here? I know. Yeah. I was even like add
Speaker 7:  hyperlinks to the videos and it did not do that either.
Speaker 7:  It's rough. Yeah. I have so many examples of just like
Speaker 7:  you guys talked about last week too on, on the Friday verse
Speaker 7:  cast of like, when you're fighting with the tool, it
Speaker 7:  you're just done. Like I had to fight with Gemini so many times
Speaker 7:  that I was like, I don't care that I can, you know, take
Speaker 7:  this detail and have it email my husband or whatever. Like I can't
Speaker 7:  convince it that I am leaving that my flight leaves from
Speaker 7:  San Francisco and not San Jose. Right. It was like
Speaker 7:  arguing with me for five minutes about this.
Speaker 2:  And there's so many things in all of that that it feels
Speaker 2:  very obvious that Gemini should be able to do it. And
Speaker 2:  like I remember back when Siri could tell you some
Speaker 2:  sports scores, but not other sports scores. And there's a thing about that
Speaker 2:  that just feels broken because it's like, well If you know the football scores,
Speaker 2:  why don't you know the baseball scores? And I forget which order it was,
Speaker 2:  but it was, there's just something about that that is like, okay, this, this
Speaker 2:  thing doesn't work and I don't, I I should not have
Speaker 2:  to understand which specific like feature flags have been turned on. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It just doesn't feel like it works. And I think in reading your review, the
Speaker 2:  experience you had of asking when the someone's flight was
Speaker 2:  landing was one of those where I was like, this ob this so obviously should
Speaker 2:  work that it is just infuriating that it doesn't.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And it's one of those things that's like, I know I can go to Google
Speaker 7:  and just type in like Alaska Airlines, flight
Speaker 7:  Detroit to Seattle, when does it land? And it's like, boom, gonna be there.
Speaker 7:  Gemini does this whole dance of like, oh, I don't know, I'm a large language
Speaker 7:  model and I'm yelling at it to Google it. I'm like,
Speaker 7:  I'm not going to use this tool Yeah. Anymore.
Speaker 2:  It's like you're Google like if, if, if at the very least it would
Speaker 2:  just fall back on a Google search. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Exactly.
Speaker 2:  Like the thing that Siri does that sucks is it's like, here's what I found
Speaker 2:  on the web, but it's like always wrong. But like Google is Google.
Speaker 7:  Like I know just, just
Speaker 2:  Be like, oh, I don't know, but here's a Google search for all the words that
Speaker 2:  you just said. Even that we would be somewhere.
Speaker 7:  Yep,
Speaker 2:  Yep. But it can, okay. Yeah. I feel like this is, this just continues to
Speaker 2:  be the Gemini experience like that, the thing with the, the dates and the
Speaker 2:  screen is like amazing. And there are just enough moments like that for me
Speaker 2:  with even things like visual intelligence and, and a lot of these tools are
Speaker 2:  getting good at that kind of thing where it's like, I'm like, here's a list
Speaker 2:  of stuff. Can you add everything on this piece of paper to my grocery list?
Speaker 2:  And like it works and it feels like magic. But then for
Speaker 2:  every one of those I have found three that it's like, this is actually easier
Speaker 2:  than the thing that you did that works and it doesn't work. Yeah. And I
Speaker 2:  can't figure out why and it just makes me want to use the tool less and less.
Speaker 7:  I know. Yeah. It feels like it does a good job when it has very specific
Speaker 7:  parameters where like on the ultra
Speaker 7:  it does a good job with like note summarization. I
Speaker 7:  just was like,
Speaker 7:  my kid was sick and I was trying to type out that note you make for yourself
Speaker 7:  before you go to the pediatrician to be like, here's when
Speaker 7:  symptoms started, blah blah, blah fevers and, and it was all just kinda like
Speaker 7:  blah. And I used the summer, the like
Speaker 7:  rewrite tool to like make it make sense. Oh that's neat.
Speaker 7:  And it did great and it picked up on the fact that it was like
Speaker 7:  a child's illness progression and it kind of like gave it a title
Speaker 7:  like that. I was like, this is good, this is fine
Speaker 7:  that, you know, I I wasn't asking it to go ask three other
Speaker 7:  apps to do anything, but you know, we're we're getting the handle on
Speaker 7:  stuff like that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That's something I'll, I'll take that. Yeah. So the other one on the
Speaker 2:  S 25 Ultra is the camera. And I think Samsung made,
Speaker 2:  as far as I understand it, two trades on the
Speaker 2:  camera. It got rid of the 10 x zoom and it added a
Speaker 2:  50 megapixel ultra wide lens. My immediate read of that is
Speaker 2:  I'm very into one of those changes and I am very unhappy about the other
Speaker 2:  one. But what's your experience?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, the 10 x was actually last year. So the S 24 Ultra
Speaker 7:  is when they did the swap.
Speaker 2:  Oh,
Speaker 7:  Okay. Yeah. And they, they added the five x and they're like, well you can
Speaker 7:  just do, you know, digital zoom re
Speaker 7:  mosaic zoom to 10 x, which
Speaker 2:  Is not correct. It's called cropping digital zoom is called cropping.
Speaker 2:  Anyone who says otherwise is selling you something
Speaker 7:  Cropping without upscaling, which is something.
Speaker 7:  Sure. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  But I do think, so I like, I I bring this up in part because I, for the first
Speaker 2:  time this year went from an iPhone pro to an iPhone and so I lost the, the
Speaker 2:  five x zoom and I miss it terribly. Yeah. And I, I'm
Speaker 2:  consistently surprised at how often I miss the five x zoom.
Speaker 2:  And so I guess this is to some extent now a year old question, but
Speaker 2:  do you miss the 10 x or does the five X feel like it does the job for you?
Speaker 7:  I miss it because I am, I'm a sicko
Speaker 7:  and I can see the difference. Like there's just, I think the
Speaker 7:  difference is that you just amplify the fact
Speaker 7:  that you're using a crappy little lens and you can see some of the
Speaker 7:  aberrations from the lens more than you could see it with
Speaker 7:  the 10 x. This is interesting. Sure. This is my theory. I
Speaker 7:  can see a slight difference. Does this matter to most people? Like No,
Speaker 7:  probably not at all. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I mean, I guess I guess from Samsung's perspective where it's like, okay,
Speaker 2:  we can either add this very expensive thing that makes the
Speaker 2:  phone bigger and all that stuff, or we can get rid of it and people can pinch
Speaker 2:  with their fingers if they really want to. Yeah. I I guess I get that trade,
Speaker 2:  but I absolutely unequivocally do not buy that they're the same
Speaker 2:  thing. Yeah. And, and they aren't. And Samsung is lying and should feel bad
Speaker 2:  about itself. But tell me about the ultra wide, because this seems like it's
Speaker 2:  a, it's a good trade.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah. They just kind of upgraded it from a,
Speaker 7:  I believe a 12 megapixel to a 50 megapixel now
Speaker 7:  it's got wider aperture, so it's an F1
Speaker 7:  0.9. Oh, I like
Speaker 2:  That.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So does that in theory mean that with a 50 megapixel Ultra
Speaker 2:  wide you could shoot a lot more often in ultra wide and then just
Speaker 2:  crop as you need to? Like that's actually an interesting use case of like
Speaker 2:  you just shoot the most you can. Hmm. And then
Speaker 2:  because you have more pixels to play with, but then like the, I don't know,
Speaker 2:  the ultra wides always get a little fish ie. For me. So maybe that's not
Speaker 2:  a perfect solution.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I think you still get a little bit of that and even like, even in
Speaker 7:  kind of like dim light, the main camera is so much better for
Speaker 7:  like yeah. Getting freezing action and all
Speaker 7:  that. But the ultra wide like, you know, apples to apples with the
Speaker 7:  previous ultra wide, it definitely is better and low light it can,
Speaker 7:  it'll complete like a, a night mode exposure
Speaker 7:  like a little quicker Hmm. Than the previous one.
Speaker 7:  There's a little more detail. It's like just kind of like check, check, check
Speaker 7:  all the things you would expect from like a more modern
Speaker 7:  nice pixel bin sensor. So it's like, yeah.
Speaker 7:  Good.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I'll take that. Okay. So the, the S 25
Speaker 2:  ultra and I think we will reserve judgment in case one of the other S 20
Speaker 2:  fives blows your mind. But I think the story of these is going to be, they're
Speaker 2:  very good phones. If you're in the market for a Galaxy phone, these are the
Speaker 2:  best ones, but there's nothing here that's gonna like blow
Speaker 2:  your socks off or change your life forever. What I'm wondering
Speaker 2:  is, is that just the story of 2025, like is this, is this what
Speaker 2:  we're in for? Because the thing that worries me is that this is supposed
Speaker 2:  to be the year that AI does everything for all of our funds forever. Mm.
Speaker 2:  And I think we can say with pretty strong confidence that that's not this
Speaker 2:  year. It might happen someday. I'm not willing to rule out that maybe someday
Speaker 2:  AI will get very good. I think it's very unlikely that it's gonna happen
Speaker 2:  this year.
Speaker 2:  So what else are we in for this year?
Speaker 7:  I think, yeah, it's gonna be a lot of, I think we're just in this,
Speaker 7:  this like head space of we're so focused
Speaker 7:  on the, the hardware launches and a phone is
Speaker 7:  released, it does X, y, and z new things. And then the next
Speaker 7:  year, new phone, you know, and we're in such a
Speaker 7:  different space now of like the hardware is just
Speaker 7:  the less interesting thing almost. And it's about the
Speaker 7:  software updates that are happening throughout the year. And like in Samsung
Speaker 7:  especially is like, they put a lot of the AI in the software
Speaker 7:  in previous phones. So it's even less important If you have
Speaker 7:  an S 24 and S 25 presumably.
Speaker 7:  So I think that's just gonna be an, an adjustment for all of us and
Speaker 7:  just kind of how we think about these things and even how we cover them
Speaker 7:  and use them. 'cause it's, it's gonna be a lot more like,
Speaker 7:  what does this phone do six months later that it didn't do,
Speaker 7:  you know, when it came out? So seeing things
Speaker 7:  like Gemini getting better
Speaker 7:  at a somewhat slow rate, but like being able
Speaker 7:  to do more for us and trying those things out is going to be like,
Speaker 7:  that's gonna be my focus for the year, honestly. But like
Speaker 7:  in the other corner is the weird, like the
Speaker 7:  slim phone thing, which is, it's like, okay,
Speaker 7:  like we, we've reached a conclusion I guess, and in one side
Speaker 7:  it's like the phone is here is phones look like this.
Speaker 7:  And then they've kind of, they're kind of doing a lateral move of like,
Speaker 7:  what if a phone was really slim? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I'm, I'm into it honestly. Like any kind of
Speaker 2:  new idea about what a phone should look like, I am psyched about right now.
Speaker 2:  Where's your head on Foldables and Flippable coming into this year? I mean,
Speaker 2:  Samsung kind of teased the trifold thing, I
Speaker 2:  think in that we saw like a outline and that's about all we saw.
Speaker 2:  But you know, we've been on the show for a while talking about is this,
Speaker 2:  is this the time these things are gonna come mainstream? And I do think
Speaker 2:  it's possible to gin up some real excitement about one of
Speaker 2:  those this year specifically because there is
Speaker 2:  not a ton of like wild other cool stuff coming
Speaker 2:  that's gonna blow people's minds. Like Apple intelligence is not going to
Speaker 2:  convince the hundreds of millions of people to run out and get new
Speaker 2:  iPhones. But like, so does that mean there is potential for Google
Speaker 2:  or Samsung or somebody to like do the flip phone thing well enough
Speaker 2:  to pull people in? Like could could this be the year that these things start
Speaker 2:  to really take off? Or am I just wishful thinking?
Speaker 7:  I don't know. I feel like I've kind of said that the past three years where
Speaker 7:  I'm like, you know, I don't know, this could be the year. And I, I
Speaker 7:  just have so many like interactions with people when I'm carrying a
Speaker 7:  folding phone or one of the flip phones. So many people will be like, oh,
Speaker 7:  that's that, you know, Samsung phone or a Google phone. They're like, I almost
Speaker 7:  bought that, but then I just got the whatever, like regular
Speaker 7:  slab phone. Yeah. I think there's like, there's a, there's interest,
Speaker 7:  but there's still like a real hesitation from people. 'cause I
Speaker 7:  like, I kind of chalk it up to the durability. I know,
Speaker 7:  I know someone who has like the third generation
Speaker 7:  Samsung flip and that thing
Speaker 7:  doesn't look great. Like the inner screen is all like
Speaker 7:  peeled and gross. I'm like, girl, you need to trade that in.
Speaker 7:  But yeah, that's the kind of thing I'm like, yeah, if I am,
Speaker 7:  like your phone just has to take so much abuse throughout the day. And
Speaker 7:  I think there's a certain person who's willing to be like, yeah, I
Speaker 7:  want all the benefits of this and I'm willing to like, accept the risks of
Speaker 7:  the inner screen. Might do something wonky.
Speaker 7:  IDI don't know how they, how the manufacturers like really
Speaker 7:  address that. I think they've been pushing forward as much as they can with
Speaker 7:  the, the waterproofing. Dust proofing. Is that even
Speaker 7:  possible? Like with a hinge? You know, I think they mitigate it as
Speaker 7:  much as they can and they're kind of like been beefing up
Speaker 7:  their, their repair programs like Samsung,
Speaker 7:  If you buy their like Care plus plan, they'll just repair
Speaker 7:  the inner screen as many times as you want for free. Or like, oh, that's
Speaker 7:  cool for not extra money,
Speaker 2:  But never a great sign that that's a thing they have to offer though. I know.
Speaker 2:  To your point. Yeah, yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah. They weren't exactly shouting that from the rooftops either.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Ask a few questions. Yeah. I
Speaker 2:  Will say the, the z flip six has
Speaker 2:  appeared in the wild around me more than I
Speaker 2:  would've expected. Hmm. And I think part of it is like, I notice everyone
Speaker 2:  because it's so different looking. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  But they're out there. Like I saw, I saw one in a coffee shop this morning.
Speaker 2:  It's just a person sitting there eating a bacon, egg and cheese. And they
Speaker 2:  had a flip phone on the table. Oh wow. And
Speaker 7:  I was just like, let's
Speaker 2:  Go. I love that. I love they were almost certainly an Amazon employee 'cause
Speaker 2:  I was like at HQ two at this coffee shop. Okay. So make of
Speaker 2:  that, which you will. But I think, I think if it's gonna be anything this
Speaker 2:  year, it's there, there might be a folding phone that gets
Speaker 2:  closer.
Speaker 2:  That's it. It, I I have no particular reason to bet on that, but it feels
Speaker 2:  like that is pushing towards being the right size and
Speaker 2:  shape faster than the foldable phones are. And I say that the, the
Speaker 2:  Pixel nine pro fold stupid name kicks ass. Like
Speaker 2:  it's a great phone. Yeah. Yeah. There's so many good things about it. But
Speaker 2:  the problem with those is they're still $1,800. And so I, I
Speaker 2:  wouldn't be shocked to see Samsung come out and like
Speaker 2:  try to knock that price down substantially. Yeah. But
Speaker 2:  also the fact that these phones now didn't go down
Speaker 2:  substantially doesn't necessarily give me great faith that that's gonna come.
Speaker 7:  I know. And they've been so stagnant on the, the fold.
Speaker 7:  It's like every year for the past three years has been like, well
Speaker 7:  it's like two millimeters wider. Right.
Speaker 2:  Just this is it very slowly pulling at the edges of the thing. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  They're
Speaker 7:  Just stretching it a little bit. Yeah. I don't know. That's the only thing
Speaker 7:  that's making me pessimistic about the
Speaker 7:  foldables, particularly Samsung's foldables
Speaker 7:  is I, I haven't seen it. I don't know.
Speaker 7:  Is there, is there really like a fire there to, to go out and
Speaker 7:  capture the, the market for it? Or they just kinda like, eh, I don't know.
Speaker 7:  People aren't buying these things like we thought they would.
Speaker 2:  It sure seems like it's that, but I think there is a chicken and egg thing
Speaker 2:  going on there. Last question and then I'll let you go. If there was going
Speaker 2:  to be one phone company that shocks us this
Speaker 2:  year, does something no one would've expected, who would you bet it's gonna
Speaker 2:  be?
Speaker 7:  I feel like, well, I feel like the wild card is nothing.
Speaker 7:  That's what I was gonna say too. Yeah. Okay. Yeah, because they've been kind
Speaker 7:  of like not on the radar for a minute and I'm like, what, what they, what
Speaker 7:  might they be doing? I feel like it's a company with like
Speaker 7:  enough interesting ideas and enough kind of like
Speaker 7:  they, they've established connections in supply
Speaker 7:  chains and I think maybe they're gonna be in a place to like
Speaker 7:  flex a little bit. I I would be really interested. I don't have any
Speaker 7:  specific idea of what that could be. It just sort of feels like
Speaker 7:  yeah, they could do something.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. Carl pay nothing's. CEO has has always said that
Speaker 2:  they did not exist to be a phone company. And it does seem like
Speaker 2:  they're, they're not like a real competitor in this
Speaker 2:  space yet next to, you know, apple and Samsung. But like, they're, they're
Speaker 2:  like you said, they're established. Like that company has proven they can
Speaker 2:  do the thing. And I kind of hope this is the year that
Speaker 2:  they're like, okay, here's, here are our actual ideas. Yeah. I
Speaker 2:  I, I'm, I'm with you. I think if anybody's gonna do it in a way that is like
Speaker 2:  cool and exciting, I would, I would bet on nothing. I have high hopes on
Speaker 2:  that
Speaker 7:  One. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  All right, Alison, thank you as always. There's gonna
Speaker 2:  Alright, we're back. So one of the questions that has been swirling
Speaker 2:  really in the last few weeks, but also over the last few years
Speaker 2:  is this question about how we should think about China's role
Speaker 2:  on the internet. As we've talked about the TikTok ban, we've talked kind
Speaker 2:  of ad nauseum about this idea of the Chinese government being able to
Speaker 2:  get our personal data from TikTok and do
Speaker 2:  something with it. Then people left TikTok and went to
Speaker 2:  RedNote, which is an app that is much more straightforwardly connected to
Speaker 2:  China. There have been all these questions about DeepSeek connection to China
Speaker 2:  and how we should think about using an AI model
Speaker 2:  from China or an AI model from a company from China.
Speaker 2:  This question of what we should be thinking about China,
Speaker 2:  not like big macro politically, but like as people on the
Speaker 2:  internet, is a thing that I have struggled with and would love to have somebody
Speaker 2:  just talk me through. So that's what we're gonna try and
Speaker 2:  do in the next little while here. I asked Cooper, Quentin, who's a
Speaker 2:  senior staff technologist at the EFF, The Electronic Frontier Foundation
Speaker 2:  to come on and just walk me through how he thinks about all of this. Cooper
Speaker 2:  does things like help activists think about security training,
Speaker 2:  and he works with nonprofits and vulnerable populations,
Speaker 2:  all thinking about how to operate online in a
Speaker 2:  safe and productive and private and useful way. And he's
Speaker 2:  also somebody who's been thinking about China specifically a lot for a long
Speaker 2:  time. And he is just going to walk me through
Speaker 2:  how we're supposed to think about all of this, how it should weigh on our
Speaker 2:  decisions about what we use and what data we reveal and whether we want
Speaker 2:  TikTok to be banned or sold or whatever. We're just gonna try to make sense
Speaker 2:  of it all. So let's just dive in. Cooper, welcome to the show.
Speaker 2:  So I guess maybe the easiest place to start is like, let's just lay the land
Speaker 2:  a little bit in terms of like what are you thinking about
Speaker 2:  and researching and talking to folks about right now as it pertains to
Speaker 2:  China in particular, but also just kind of the internet more broadly. Like
Speaker 2:  what's your angle on this space right now?
Speaker 8:  So for me, there's two topics that I'm interested in and that I think
Speaker 8:  both come up when we're talking about this.
Speaker 8:  One is surveillance capitalism and this
Speaker 8:  sort of industry of data brokers and
Speaker 8:  selling your data and like all of this industry that
Speaker 8:  the internet has really been built on, right? And how
Speaker 8:  your data flows and like whether you have control of it and what can be done
Speaker 8:  with that, right? And there's some really interesting things in there
Speaker 8:  like law enforcement buying access to that data so that they
Speaker 8:  don't have to deal with pesky things like warrants, right?
Speaker 8:  So that's all really interesting to me. The other thing that I've studied
Speaker 8:  pretty extensively in my time at EFF is malware
Speaker 8:  and spyware, specifically the types of spyware they're used to spy
Speaker 8:  on, activists, journalists, human
Speaker 8:  rights defenders, and you know, people who are trying to exercise
Speaker 8:  free expression and trying to, you know,
Speaker 8:  improve their lives and fight against, you know, their
Speaker 8:  governments or governments, you know, of countries which they used to be
Speaker 8:  a part of oftentimes, right? Like oftentimes these are people who, who have
Speaker 8:  left their countries for fear of oppression and are still though doing the
Speaker 8:  work of, you know, fighting against corruption in the country that they left.
Speaker 8:  And so in the conversations around TikTok and around Red Book and around
Speaker 8:  DeepSeek, I see echoes of all of these topics.
Speaker 2:  Interesting. How so where do you, what, what echoes are you seeing right
Speaker 2:  now?
Speaker 8:  To go back a little bit, right? Like I, I think that the
Speaker 8:  reaction to TikTok going away and people starting to
Speaker 8:  join Little Red Book right, is really
Speaker 8:  funny.
Speaker 2:  The fact that RedNote is actually technically called Little Red Book is one
Speaker 2:  of my favorite discoveries of 2025. Enjoyed that to no end.
Speaker 2:  It is the funniest and most like direct beyond parody thing
Speaker 2:  we could have possibly done in that moment.
Speaker 8:  Should we break that down? Because it's, I think it's a, I think it's really
Speaker 8:  interesting, like sure, please, little Red Book is, is
Speaker 8:  Mao's little Red book. This was like one of the main tracks of
Speaker 8:  Maoism that was given out to people in
Speaker 8:  revolutionary China, right? Like this is, this is like
Speaker 8:  the, you know, it'd be, it'd be like calling an American social network the
Speaker 8:  Federalist Papers or something like that, right? Like it's so on the
Speaker 8:  nose, right? Like this is, you know, this, this is an
Speaker 8:  application of the ccp, right? Like absolutely
Speaker 8:  100% we're not, you know, we're not pretending otherwise,
Speaker 8:  right? But the, the reaction to me was so funny. It's such a
Speaker 8:  like, like a prototypical reaction of like a 13-year-old,
Speaker 8:  right? To, to like, well, you know, we're gonna have to ban
Speaker 8:  TikTok because we don't want your data going to China
Speaker 8:  and there's some serious privacy issues and national security issues here.
Speaker 8:  And people's reaction was, oh, you don't want me to like
Speaker 8:  China, you don't want me to like China, guess what? I
Speaker 8:  love China, right? I am gonna give China all my data. I
Speaker 8:  am mailing a copy of my birth certificate to Xi Jinping
Speaker 8:  right now. Like, and I saw videos of people doing like putting,
Speaker 8:  pretending to like, put data in an envelope and like mail it to the Chinese
Speaker 8:  government. Like, and this is, it's a
Speaker 8:  really funny reaction because people are like, yeah,
Speaker 8:  I know, I know that they're taking all my data.
Speaker 8:  I don't care. Why should I care? You took all my
Speaker 8:  data anyway. US companies took all my data, meta took all my
Speaker 8:  data, right? Twitter took all my data. The US government
Speaker 8:  has an, and like it has all my data and is constantly being leaked. So
Speaker 8:  why do I care if China has it? Like, and in fact because you
Speaker 8:  don't like that, it makes me wanna do it even more, right?
Speaker 8:  And that's, it's so interesting to me.
Speaker 2:  I'm forever somewhat compelled by that
Speaker 2:  argument. Like, I, I think it, it's, it's so easy in this time that we
Speaker 2:  live in to fall into that particular brand of nihilism, which is like,
Speaker 2:  look, if, if China wants to know information about me, China has so many
Speaker 2:  ways that are more efficient than developing a social network that
Speaker 2:  like, right? I I I struggle with this personally of like how much
Speaker 2:  is the a how much of this is sort of real threat versus like
Speaker 2:  potential, maybe possible several steps down the road
Speaker 2:  threat and what does it mean in
Speaker 2:  a practical sense that someone in the Chinese government can theoretically
Speaker 2:  find out what I watch on TikTok? Like who cares? Right?
Speaker 2:  I like, I sort of intellectually know that that's an argument that will
Speaker 2:  lead only to ruin and trouble, but I kind of understand how people
Speaker 2:  land there.
Speaker 8:  It's, yeah, definitely. I mean, like, it it is a form of privacy
Speaker 8:  nihilism, right? Yeah, yeah. At the end of the day, absolutely.
Speaker 8:  But like, it's understandable that people have
Speaker 8:  come to privacy nihilism, right? Like we don't, we,
Speaker 8:  we don't have anything that anybody can do in like a,
Speaker 8:  you know, like in terms of laws, in terms of
Speaker 8:  litigation, in terms like there are no legal protections for people's data,
Speaker 8:  right? Zero. Unless you happen to live in California, right?
Speaker 8:  Where there's like some okay. Privacy laws, right?
Speaker 8:  That's still like, don't, don't seem to prevent this
Speaker 8:  data from ending up in the hands of these corporations. It just means that
Speaker 8:  you can go request your data and remove your data, which is better than nothing
Speaker 8:  for sure. But like people, I think it's, it's understandable why
Speaker 8:  people end up with this sort of privacy nihilism, right?
Speaker 8:  And because we've just, like, we've accepted as
Speaker 8:  a, I don't, maybe accepted isn't the right word, but like we've, we have,
Speaker 8:  as a society, this is where we're at, right? Like, you will give up your
Speaker 8:  data in exchange for some kind of crappy
Speaker 8:  services from Facebook and like, there's nothing you can do about
Speaker 8:  it because If you wanna participate in society, you have to be on these kind
Speaker 8:  of crappy services.
Speaker 2:  So how do you understand the difference between what
Speaker 2:  it means to do that to a company like Google or Meta
Speaker 2:  and doing that with a
Speaker 2:  country or a, a government like the Chinese Communist Party? Like are,
Speaker 2:  are those meaningfully different things? I think we have a hard time talking
Speaker 2:  about what China is and what that threat looks like
Speaker 2:  and why that is dangerous in a way that having it in Google servers
Speaker 2:  isn't, or is differently dangerous. Like how do you think through the difference
Speaker 2:  there?
Speaker 8:  I always say it depends on your threat model, right? Like If
Speaker 8:  you have family in China, If you have friends in China, right?
Speaker 8:  Like, or If you, I don't know, work in
Speaker 8:  national security, right? Or if your work is like related to something that
Speaker 8:  has historically been a target of Chinese espionage,
Speaker 8:  right? Then that's one very specific threat model, right? Sure. Where like
Speaker 8:  the CCP actually should be in your threat model, right? Like, you
Speaker 8:  don't want to search for Taiwan
Speaker 8:  and have that or Tiananmen Square and have that come back
Speaker 8:  to investigation of your family in China,
Speaker 8:  right? And like, you know, If you're, if you're in an industry that is
Speaker 8:  the target of Chinese espionage, right? Like this, like information that
Speaker 8:  you give could be used for, you know, phishing or,
Speaker 8:  or you know, other sort of targeted, more targeted
Speaker 8:  espionage attacks, right? Right.
Speaker 2:  Phishing is a really interesting one by the way. I think I've,
Speaker 2:  I've, I've heard a couple of folks mention that in this context in a
Speaker 2:  way that I have actually found really instructive because that's a good example
Speaker 2:  of things, you know, about what I watch on TikTok
Speaker 2:  become ways in which to appear to be someone I know
Speaker 2:  or have information about me that you can then use to get other more
Speaker 2:  dangerous information about me. Sure. And I think like for sure, that to
Speaker 2:  me is, is 'cause it's like if I'm not taking a picture of my bank
Speaker 2:  account information and posting it on TikTok, like the, the sort of
Speaker 2:  direct threat there is lesser, but there's this, this data you can use to
Speaker 2:  understand me better, right? Which you can use to get other information out
Speaker 2:  of me is like, that's the kind of step I think people often fail to understand.
Speaker 8:  But it's still hard for me though to see actually a meaningful difference,
Speaker 8:  right? Like, because this data already exists anyway, right?
Speaker 8:  Meta has this data, Google has this data, right? And like, and so do
Speaker 8:  a dozen data brokers, right? Like you can,
Speaker 8:  you know, journalists keep showing that, that you
Speaker 8:  can get people's location in near real time just
Speaker 8:  from the advertising bid stream, which is where like
Speaker 8:  when you are using an app or whatever, and ads are showing up though, people
Speaker 8:  are bidding in real time on who gets to sell you ads. And that
Speaker 8:  data is like, and there's data in there about like your demographics,
Speaker 8:  how old you are, what kind of phone you have, what your interests are, there's
Speaker 8:  data about your location, right? Like all of this data is just flowing
Speaker 8:  around the internet all the time, and there's no reason that the
Speaker 8:  CCP can't just get that data from that source, right?
Speaker 8:  Like there's no reason that they can't get it by taking out ads
Speaker 8:  in meta, right? Like there's no reason they can't create a US
Speaker 8:  cutout and make a partnership with Meta or, or with
Speaker 8:  Google to get this data so like they can
Speaker 8:  get it directly from, you know, little Red Book or,
Speaker 8:  you know, possibly from, from TikTok. There are
Speaker 8:  easier ways to get the data actually, right? Like yeah, the target audience
Speaker 8:  for Little Red Book was not like data collection of Americans, right?
Speaker 8:  Like this was an, this was like a p kind of Pinterest
Speaker 8:  like application, like a kind of an intersection between like Pinterest and
Speaker 8:  TikTok, right? That was primarily targeted at like
Speaker 8:  people in women in China and people like
Speaker 8:  talking to relatives or whatever in China, right? Like this was targeted
Speaker 8:  at Chinese people in China, right? So like there
Speaker 8:  are other ways to get this data and it's all like, none
Speaker 8:  of it is good to be clear. Right?
Speaker 2:  I was gonna say, you sound an awful lot like a privacy nihilist,
Speaker 8:  Right? No, yeah. I
Speaker 8:  it's so, it's so easy to go into privacy nihilism talking about this, right?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. But like, and I think people are correctly frustrated
Speaker 8:  with Silicon Valley oligarchs and like US surveillance capitalism,
Speaker 8:  right? It's a bad industry
Speaker 8:  that should not exist, right? Like this is not a good thing.
Speaker 8:  I don't think that trading in that
Speaker 8:  for CCP surveillance is going to make
Speaker 8:  anyone's lives meaningfully better. Sure. Like they are
Speaker 8:  both bad. Two things can be bad, right? They are both
Speaker 8:  bad in different ways and, and in a lot of the same ways,
Speaker 8:  right? Like in the end, the most useful, like for
Speaker 8:  99% of people, the most lucrative use of this data
Speaker 8:  is going to, for the CCP, is going to be to sell
Speaker 8:  it and sell advertisements off it the same way that it is for Silicon
Speaker 8:  Valley, right? Right. Like surveillance capitalism cuts both ways for
Speaker 8:  Bo you know, for, for both organizations, right? Yeah.
Speaker 2:  So I guess if, if, if the, if the way of thinking about it is
Speaker 2:  it's, it's definitely not a better choice to give that data to the CCP
Speaker 2:  instead of to Google or meta, is it a substantially worse
Speaker 2:  choice to do that? Again, I I think we, we should, we should
Speaker 2:  carve out the people who have, like you were saying, the sort of obvious
Speaker 2:  threat models. I think there, there's a set of people who
Speaker 2:  should think about all of this like minute to minute and day to day more
Speaker 2:  carefully, right? And, and we can talk about those people, but I think for,
Speaker 2:  for the people who ask you questions like, who cares? I have nothing to hide.
Speaker 2:  Is it that different a trade?
Speaker 8:  I really don't think that it is. Like I don't see any good argument
Speaker 8:  that it's that different of a trade, right? Like, and what we,
Speaker 8:  what we need, and maybe I'm, I'm stop me if I'm jumping the gun here, but
Speaker 8:  like we need desperately federal
Speaker 8:  privacy law. We desperately need federal laws that let
Speaker 8:  us control our data, that stop our, that let us stop
Speaker 8:  our data from being sold that let us actually have meaningful
Speaker 8:  opt-in consent and to, into who we give our data to an
Speaker 8:  understanding of what's being done with that data and a private right of
Speaker 8:  action to sue when companies misuse our data or take our data
Speaker 8:  without our consent. This would go a long way to solving
Speaker 8:  the problem of the CCP stealing people's data.
Speaker 8:  This would go a long way to solving the problem of Silicon Valley surveillance,
Speaker 8:  capitalism and meta and Google stealing people's data, right? This would
Speaker 8:  go a long way to solving the problem of the like constant background noise
Speaker 8:  of data breaches, right? And, and data being breached and
Speaker 8:  then used in phishing campaigns and everything else, right? Data
Speaker 8:  breaches are another angle, like argue one could argue
Speaker 8:  that like, you know, Google and Meta have pretty good
Speaker 8:  security teams and like your data is safer from a data breach
Speaker 8:  with them than it is in, you know, in the hands of some of
Speaker 8:  these Chinese apps. Right? But I don't, I don't know that that's a, I
Speaker 8:  don't think that that's a strong argument because data breaches still happen
Speaker 8:  all the time in the US Yeah. Right? Like there's all sorts of data breaches
Speaker 8:  every day and you know, even if, even if Google and
Speaker 8:  Meta themselves aren't getting breached yet, and I think, you know, on a
Speaker 8:  long enough timeline, the probability approach is a hundred percent that
Speaker 8:  there will be a data breach from one of these companies, right? But
Speaker 8:  like, even if those haven't been data like breached yet, they still have
Speaker 8:  that data and they still sell it in the form of ad targeting, right?
Speaker 8:  So like it doesn't need to be breached when you can just buy it.
Speaker 2:  Right? So I is is it possible then that one
Speaker 2:  reason to
Speaker 2:  think about keeping this data in the United States is that, you know, in
Speaker 2:  theory we live in a democracy that can, in theory pass laws and that
Speaker 2:  I, if we are able to regulate this, at least we can like
Speaker 2:  retroactively make some of this stuff better in a way that whatever you're
Speaker 2:  dumping onto RedNote is, is gone and lost and there's nothing you can do
Speaker 2:  about it. I feel like I just said like 11 glass half full things
Speaker 2:  in a row to get to that point. Yeah. But is that at least, is that at least
Speaker 2:  an argument that sort of makes sense?
Speaker 8:  I think it's a very optimistic argument.
Speaker 2:  Yeah,
Speaker 8:  I would agree.
Speaker 2:  Listen, I said theoretically a bunch of times,
Speaker 8:  But yeah, I mean, you know, certainly
Speaker 8:  if we one day have a functioning congress
Speaker 8:  and you know, certainly if we were ever to
Speaker 8:  get any sort of federal privacy law, right?
Speaker 8:  Domestic privacy law. So yeah, it, it is possible that that could apply to,
Speaker 8:  to retroactively gather data about you. And that is, I guess that is
Speaker 8:  one, one reason it's not, I mean, I think you yourself would
Speaker 8:  admit it's not the most compelling reason. No.
Speaker 2:  Right? It's not. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  There's another compelling reason not to have any of these apps on your phone,
Speaker 8:  which is just that, like what, and the compelling reason is
Speaker 8:  who do you trust to run code on your phone, right? Like, who do you
Speaker 8:  trust to have control of your phone? And I think a lot of people
Speaker 8:  will say, I don't care if Meta or the CCP
Speaker 8:  has control of my phone, right. As a form of, again, privacy nihilism.
Speaker 8:  I don't know. It's, it's, I think each person needs to do a little bit
Speaker 8:  of threat modeling and think about that, right? Like for, for
Speaker 8:  whatever it's worth, Google and Facebook have pretty good
Speaker 8:  security engineering, right? And like people have looked at these apps, whereas
Speaker 8:  like some of these other apps don't have as good a security engineering
Speaker 8:  necessarily, right? So like the, the possibility that you'll be
Speaker 8:  be putting an app on your phone, which is poorly programmed
Speaker 8:  and is not using things like https is not using, you know,
Speaker 8:  is not using other, other kind of standard technologies and is therefore
Speaker 8:  like leaking your data and causing, you know, potential security issues.
Speaker 8:  Right? Like that is a, that is a, a thing that I think people should
Speaker 8:  consider.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that makes a lot of sense. Can you walk me through how you think about
Speaker 2:  kind of the average person's threat modeling? I mean, you, you, you mentioned
Speaker 2:  kind of that, that first rung of people who have, have some
Speaker 2:  direct threat in, in some like, sort of the one degree removed
Speaker 2:  from like a, a real possible threat. But I think
Speaker 2:  that that's a big group of people. I think that's a bigger group of people
Speaker 2:  than we often give it credit for, but that's not
Speaker 2:  everybody. And I think there are lots of people who are not even sure how
Speaker 2:  to think about those threat models. Like how do you talk people through how
Speaker 2:  to think about that stuff?
Speaker 8:  Sure. Unfortunately, for a large percentage of Americans,
Speaker 8:  the US government is, is a very big
Speaker 8:  obvious threat, right? Like anybody, anybody who is
Speaker 8:  an immigrant here, right? Anybody who is a, you know, not a
Speaker 8:  born citizen, but a, you know, a a a on a visa
Speaker 8:  or a citizen, you know, through a green card or
Speaker 8:  anybody who is trans right? Or
Speaker 8:  gender non-binary, right? Like the, the obvious
Speaker 8:  threats from the American government, unfortunately are
Speaker 8:  much more real than any, you know, sort of perceived threats.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. You know, future threats from the ccp. But like, the way that I,
Speaker 8:  I would kind of walk people through this is to,
Speaker 8:  you know, first think about like what you know, where you work, what access
Speaker 8:  you have, that could be interesting to other people, right? Like for
Speaker 8:  example, If you work in telecom, right? Like If you work at at and
Speaker 8:  t or Verizon, right? Like, or one of those phone companies, look
Speaker 8:  at what just happened with Salt Typhoon, right? Like, you are definitely
Speaker 8:  a potential target for espionage. You know, anybody who works for
Speaker 8:  the government is a potential target for espionage, right? You know, obviously
Speaker 8:  people that have family there, we kind of went over that, right? Like that's
Speaker 8:  a, that's a pretty obvious threat metal there. I think
Speaker 8:  some of the less obvious threat metals are like industry, right? Like,
Speaker 8:  like anybody in any industry can, obviously we target,
Speaker 8:  like we know that, you know, there've been espionage from China
Speaker 8:  on like, you know, the medical or you know, the, the sort of drug industry
Speaker 8:  in America, right? And like aviation industry and things like that.
Speaker 8:  You might also not really care about that, right? Like, you
Speaker 8:  might look at your situation being paid poorly in the drug industry and be
Speaker 8:  like, what do I care If, you know, if if Chinese
Speaker 8:  spies want to use me to get to, to get to patent
Speaker 8:  documents,
Speaker 2:  Fish away friends. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Right? Like, they should pay me more if they want me to care about that.
Speaker 8:  And that's pretty understandable. The, the consequences for you, you
Speaker 8:  could actually be pretty severe, right? Like even If you were an
Speaker 8:  unwilling participant. So it's, I don't, I don't think it should be
Speaker 8:  actually treated that cavalierly overall. I think that most people
Speaker 8:  like don't face that severe threat of like
Speaker 8:  Chinese espionage. And If you do, I don't think it's going
Speaker 8:  to significantly matter whether you use TikTok or a little Red book or
Speaker 8:  not, right? Yeah. Like the CIA existed long before
Speaker 8:  the internet did. Right. Espionage can be done just fine
Speaker 8:  without, without this sort of data. This sort of data does help.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, for sure.
Speaker 2:  So, so you think there are people who could do a, a
Speaker 2:  pretty rational threat modeling of their own life and
Speaker 2:  come out of it and say,
Speaker 2:  I'm good. Let the CCP have my data, it's gonna be fine.
Speaker 2:  Like you think that's, that there are people for whom that is a, like a reasonable
Speaker 2:  rational outcome.
Speaker 8:  I don't think that that is totally a reasonable, that is a, that is
Speaker 8:  a rational outcome in the lens of privacy nihilism, right?
Speaker 8:  Sure. That's fair. Yeah. Like the rational outcome is I don't want anybody
Speaker 8:  to have my data, right? Like my data is mine, I want to control it. Nobody
Speaker 8:  needs to know what I, what I enjoy thinking about
Speaker 8:  and looking at. Right? Like that's actually just not data that needs to be
Speaker 8:  out there because I don't trust the CCP to handle it any more responsibly
Speaker 8:  than I trust Facebook to handle it. Right? But for
Speaker 8:  somebody who's looking at it through the lens of privacy, nihilism is saying
Speaker 8:  like, Facebook already has all my data anyway. How is it different?
Speaker 8:  I think that there's a large percentage of people out there for whom a reasonable
Speaker 8:  answer is there's not a meaningful difference. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  That, that's totally fair. So given that, then, why do
Speaker 2:  you think kind of societally, we talk about
Speaker 2:  China and data privacy and security so differently
Speaker 2:  than we talk about companies like Meta and Google, and I do think
Speaker 2:  there are maybe more examples than often get credit for
Speaker 2:  of us talking about them the same way, right? Like, I think that the
Speaker 2:  idea that these things are all collecting data they shouldn't be and using
Speaker 2:  it in ways they shouldn't be is, is pretty true across
Speaker 2:  the board. But e even now, like the, the way
Speaker 2:  that people have worked themselves up about the
Speaker 2:  personal data being shared on TikTok and collected by the CCP
Speaker 2:  hit a fever pitch that I don't remember with Google or
Speaker 2:  Facebook or really anything. Why do you think China is so different?
Speaker 8:  I mean, I think there's a couple of reasons. One is
Speaker 8:  the sort of the openness of government
Speaker 8:  surveillance in China, right? Like government surveillance
Speaker 8:  and like control of speech
Speaker 8:  is done openly in a way that
Speaker 8:  makes Americans very uncomfortable with a strong
Speaker 8:  First Amendment history, right? Like we, we are, I I think Americans are
Speaker 8:  definitely uncomfortable with, you know, anytime the government
Speaker 8:  says, like, you're not allowed to say these things, right?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Anybody who's ideologically consistent right. Should say that
Speaker 8:  right off. Oftentimes people are comfortable with the government
Speaker 8:  truncating speech they don't like, right? Like, people want to
Speaker 8:  make it legal to run over protesters on highways. Right? Or
Speaker 8:  like to, you know, not to seem partisan here. People, you know, aren't comfortable
Speaker 8:  with people talking about guns. Right. But for the most part, we tend to
Speaker 8:  not want the government to curtail that, right? For sure. We also, I
Speaker 8:  think as Americans, like our government surveillance
Speaker 8:  kind of hidden from us, right? Yeah. Like, we don't, we don't
Speaker 8:  really want it in your face, right? We're okay with police having license
Speaker 8:  plate readers and we're okay with, you know,
Speaker 8:  you know, whatever the NSA has to do as long as it's to get the bad
Speaker 8:  guys, you know, in China, the surveillance is very much more in the open,
Speaker 8:  right? It's, it's, it's sort of targeted at
Speaker 8:  everybody, right? And I think that that, even If you could argue like
Speaker 8:  surveillance in America is just as bad, right? Or is just as prevalent, at
Speaker 8:  least I think that there's a, there's a difference in
Speaker 8:  how it feels to Americans. And then the other part of this
Speaker 8:  is of course just, you know, good old fashioned xenophobia,
Speaker 8:  right? Right. China is scary. Like, you know, just,
Speaker 8:  just all this sort of old, you know, like, well you don't
Speaker 8:  wanna be like China, right? Like, this is America, this isn't China.
Speaker 8:  We don't do things like that here. You don't want China to have your data,
Speaker 8:  right? Like it's, it's just kind of like, well that's those
Speaker 8:  other guys and like, you can trust us, but you can't trust them. I honestly,
Speaker 8:  I think it's that, right? Like I think, I think that's a big part of it.
Speaker 8:  At my most cynical, I'd say a big part of it is just is
Speaker 8:  is being mad that they're not
Speaker 8:  getting a cut of the data or a cut of the profits, right? Hmm.
Speaker 8:  Like, you're like, we are, we are okay with
Speaker 8:  Facebook collecting this data and then China
Speaker 8:  buying it from Facebook or buying ad targeting or whatever from Facebook
Speaker 8:  because us companies are getting a cut. We're not, we're not
Speaker 8:  okay with it just going straight to China, right? Like
Speaker 8:  that's, that would be my most cynical take on it, right? Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Like, we gotta get our cut.
Speaker 2:  That's a good take. I had, I hadn't heard that one, but that, that rings
Speaker 2:  truer than I would like it to.
Speaker 8:  It does, and I hate it.
Speaker 2:  It it does. I don't, I don't like it. But I'm gonna keep hearing that in
Speaker 2:  my head for a while. Let's end on a, on a positive and
Speaker 2:  productive note here. Yes. We wanna keep people out of privacy
Speaker 2:  nihilism. I think it is, it is an understandable place to go, but it
Speaker 2:  is a place we should all do our best to avoid going. What, what
Speaker 2:  in, in the absence of these kind of big structural improvements you're
Speaker 2:  talking, talking about that I think we, we absolutely are in agreement ought
Speaker 2:  to exist.
Speaker 2:  What can people do? Like, what's a, what's a useful thing that people
Speaker 2:  can do to start pushing this stuff at least a little bit in the right direction
Speaker 2:  for themselves?
Speaker 8:  So the privacy nihilism is so rampant right now. I think
Speaker 8:  it's more rampant than I've ever seen it. And
Speaker 8:  I'm gonna, I'm gonna say clearly and unequivocally, privacy is
Speaker 8:  not dead. You can still have privacy, right?
Speaker 8:  Surveillance capitalism is not an inevitability. And there
Speaker 8:  are, are lots of things you can do, right? Getting off of
Speaker 8:  meta products is a great place to start, right? Like,
Speaker 8:  you know, uninstall Instagram from your phone, unin, get off Facebook, right?
Speaker 8:  See, see if this improves your life, right? There are a lot of really
Speaker 8:  interesting social networks, which are popping up right now, which are not
Speaker 8:  based on the, the model of surveillance capitalism and which are not owned
Speaker 8:  by tech oligarchs, right? So things like blue
Speaker 8:  sky things like Mastodon I think are really
Speaker 8:  interesting models for what social media
Speaker 8:  without surveillance capitalism could look like. And doing things
Speaker 8:  like looking at what apps are on your phone, right? Like,
Speaker 8:  do you, like If you can uninstall most of the apps on your phone
Speaker 8:  and you can, right? That's a great place to start, right? Like, do I really
Speaker 8:  need an app from my grocery store? No, no, I don't. And I don't need it and
Speaker 8:  I don't want it, right? Like, I think pushing back on those things, right?
Speaker 8:  Like there are so many, so many places now which want us to
Speaker 8:  install an app just to get basic services and just kind of
Speaker 8:  refusing to do that. I'm, I'm with the Boomers on this one, man. No, I refuse
Speaker 8:  to install an app to eat at a restaurant. I refuse to
Speaker 8:  install an app to shop at CVS. Yeah, I will not be doing this.
Speaker 8:  I think that that's a good place to start, right? Installing ad blockers.
Speaker 8:  There are, there are some, some really good ad blockers out there. EFF makes
Speaker 8:  one called Privacy Badger. There's another one called you Block Origin. Those
Speaker 8:  are both great ad blockers, right? If you're a bit more technical,
Speaker 8:  there's a, there's a project called Pie Hole that
Speaker 8:  lets you set up your own sort of ad blocking DNS
Speaker 8:  on your, on your network. You can, so like this is something you can set
Speaker 8:  up on your home network to prevent a lot of the tracking that goes on.
Speaker 8:  If you want to go even a little bit more down the rabbit hole there, like
Speaker 8:  things like turning off location services on your phone, unless you're using
Speaker 8:  it for navigation. Hmm. This is a great way to stop your location from ending
Speaker 8:  up in these, in these sort of data broker
Speaker 8:  repositories, right? There are a lot of services which will delete your
Speaker 8:  data off the internet and try to scrub your data wherever possible. Things
Speaker 8:  like delete me. Hmm. They all have pros and cons, but
Speaker 8:  checking one of those out can definitely be worth it. If you're in California
Speaker 8:  doing things like requesting copies of your data from companies using
Speaker 8:  the California Privacy Rights Act, the CPRA
Speaker 8:  laws, right? Like this can be, this can be really interesting too, right?
Speaker 8:  Request request copies of your data request to delete your data.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. There's lots of things you can do, right? And
Speaker 8:  also the biggest long term that you can do, because these are all bandings,
Speaker 8:  right? Like, I, I wanna acknowledge that these are all
Speaker 8:  kind of similar to telling people to like, turn off the lights to stop
Speaker 8:  climate change, right? Sure. Like the privacy problem that we have is a
Speaker 8:  systemic problem that's not going to be solved by like individual
Speaker 8:  piece meal action. We need a systemic solution for this, right? And that
Speaker 8:  is comprehensive federal privacy law.
Speaker 8:  And so a good thing you can do is call your representatives,
Speaker 8:  right? Call your senators, call your congressmen and
Speaker 8:  explain to them how important this is, how important it is to you, why it's
Speaker 8:  so important, right? And, and get them to understand that this
Speaker 8:  is important. Get them to understand that this is important to their constituents,
Speaker 8:  right? So that maybe one day we actually can have
Speaker 8:  this systemic real solution to this problem instead of
Speaker 8:  just, and, you know, having everybody try to solve it for themselves.
Speaker 8:  But the important takeaway here is If you
Speaker 8:  do give, If you give up on privacy, they win. Right?
Speaker 8:  These companies win If you give up on privacy. And if,
Speaker 8:  if it was impossible to have privacy, they wouldn't spend so much money
Speaker 8:  on trying to convince you that it was impossible to have privacy and that
Speaker 8:  it was a great thing to give up on your data.
Speaker 2:  I, I I like that. That's a, that's a good place to end on
Speaker 2:  that. I also, you've just made me realize it's been a really long time since
Speaker 2:  I did like a full delete of all the apps on my phone. It's time to
Speaker 2:  get rid of some apps. Yeah. This is, this is good advice. This is now my
Speaker 2:  weekend project.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's get to the hotline as always. The number is
Speaker 2:  8 6 6 VERGE one one. The email is vergecast at The Verge dot com.
Speaker 2:  We love all your questions. Thank you again to everybody who has been emailing
Speaker 2:  and calling about how you use AI in your regular day-to-day
Speaker 2:  life. It's been so interesting. I have enjoyed every single one that we've
Speaker 2:  gotten. Please keep all your responses coming on that and on everything else.
Speaker 2:  This week we have a question about a somewhat surprising
Speaker 2:  gadget that I haven't thought about in a very long time. Let's hear it.
Speaker 13:  Hey Vergecast, it is Rob. I might be the only
Speaker 13:  power user of this device, kind of a pandemic holdover, but
Speaker 13:  around the pandemic, I had children and thus was calling
Speaker 13:  my parents, my kids' grandparents quite often using the
Speaker 13:  Facebook now meta portal. That device is kind of part of Facebook's push
Speaker 13:  into hardware and they've since deprecated it. It worked for about a year
Speaker 13:  after the announcement was made, but has recently started dying. And
Speaker 13:  the main use case for us is literally just calling my parents
Speaker 13:  at dinner when we're with our kids. Kind of a nice hand free
Speaker 13:  FaceTime type experience. And I was wondering If you all have any
Speaker 13:  recommendations for other dedicated portal
Speaker 13:  calling type devices I could use for my kids and, and me to call
Speaker 13:  my parents their grandparents. Yeah, that's pretty much it.
Speaker 13:  Thanks so much. Appreciate what y'all do.
Speaker 2:  All right. Jen Tui is here to help me. Hi Jen.
Speaker 14:  Hi David.
Speaker 2:  Did you ever have a portal?
Speaker 14:  I, I tested the portal. Go. I never owned one
Speaker 14:  myself. I do have several friends who owned one though. 'cause it really
Speaker 14:  did, I think it appealed to a lot of non-techie people
Speaker 14:  during the pandemic. Yeah. So I'm sad to hear that they're
Speaker 14:  pretty much dead and dying now that that's, that's really sad.
Speaker 2:  It is a real bummer. I bought the portal TV during the pandemic. Oh.
Speaker 2:  And we used it a ton. It was, I was so shocked at how good that thing
Speaker 2:  was for like, as a, as a microphone especially like, we would just sit
Speaker 2:  on the couch and we would like play games with our friends over Zoom, which
Speaker 2:  is a like insane to remember and think about all of the time that
Speaker 2:  we spent doing that. Mm. But like the thing kind of worked. Yeah. And I'm
Speaker 2:  sure bummed to hear that I, I frankly have not plugged mine in in a long
Speaker 2:  time. But like I'm sad that they're going away and I will say I looked this
Speaker 2:  up and meta claims that it is continuing to support existing ones.
Speaker 2:  So Right. The the first thing you can do is, is reach out to Meta there as
Speaker 2:  a, yeah, I would say small but non-zero chance. They
Speaker 2:  might do something for you. But I'm curious where, where
Speaker 2:  your head goes as far as replacement devices. I, I think of a
Speaker 2:  couple of possibilities that we can get into and I'm curious if there's anything
Speaker 2:  that immediately comes to mind for you. Yeah,
Speaker 14:  Well I think the most obvious alternative and
Speaker 14:  probably the one I would actually have recommended to people rather than
Speaker 14:  buying this in the first place, except for one reason
Speaker 14:  is an Echo show. Because Amazon really has kind of
Speaker 14:  perfected the Alexa calling experience as much as
Speaker 14:  it, it does still have some rough edges, but it is very universal.
Speaker 14:  Like the other person doesn't have to have an Echo show for you to use
Speaker 14:  it as a calling device. They just have to have the Alexa app on their phone.
Speaker 14:  So they know you don't, you're not limited by hardware and
Speaker 14:  it works very well. And the new Echo show devices have the kind of
Speaker 14:  tracking, so If you are sitting having your kids talk to your, to their
Speaker 14:  grandparents, you know, you don't have to like make sure they're sitting
Speaker 14:  right in front of the camera. And the portal had a good, had that too. Has
Speaker 14:  that kind of the, what is it? It's got a technical term.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. It's like the automatic pan in Zoom that keeps you in in frame.
Speaker 2:  Which I find sort of unnerving in a lot of cases. It can be. But for this
Speaker 2:  one use case I think is like Exactly, yes. Like chasing a child around is
Speaker 2:  the one good use case for this technology?
Speaker 14:  It is. And the Echo Show eight and Echo Show 10 would be sort
Speaker 14:  of my go-tos. The Echo Show eight is the less expensive, similar
Speaker 14:  size to the portal, similar features, you know, you could, if it doesn't
Speaker 14:  sound like he used any of the other features of the portal, but you can,
Speaker 14:  you know, it works as a photo frame. There are other things you can do with,
Speaker 14:  it obviously has the voice assistant built in and
Speaker 14:  the Echo show, the current one has the
Speaker 14:  framing, the auto framing and then the Echo Show 10 is actually on a robotic
Speaker 14:  arm and will follow you around. So like If you are having a conversation
Speaker 14:  Oh that's handy in the kitchen, it will follow you as you go.
Speaker 14:  It's an older device now and it's still quite expensive though. It's
Speaker 14:  $250, so,
Speaker 2:  Okay. I mean the portals are pretty expensive too, so I think on that front,
Speaker 2:  yes. That's not so terrible. Yeah, yeah. Like it's definitely like a hundred
Speaker 2:  dollars more than I'd like it to be. But I feel like that's still in the
Speaker 2:  realm of like, if it solves this problem, so be it. Okay. I have,
Speaker 2:  I have two questions about the Echo show though. One is like,
Speaker 2:  convince me that Alexa calling is actually good because A, I used Alexa calling
Speaker 2:  when it first came out and it was not good. Like not good to the point that
Speaker 2:  I kind of stopped trying and B, I do occasionally have to use Chime,
Speaker 2:  which is Amazon's like, oh, don't do that own video calling
Speaker 2:  service. And like the people that's bad who make Chime think
Speaker 2:  Chime sucks. Like, like that is reporting. Like they, they
Speaker 2:  don't like it, it's bad. Everyone agrees. But you're telling me Alexa calling
Speaker 2:  now is, is good.
Speaker 14:  Yeah, I, I I mean it's, is there a really good video calling
Speaker 14:  service out there? I mean maybe FaceTime, that's fair. But the problem with
Speaker 14:  FaceTime is everyone has to have an Apple device and you know, and if grandparents
Speaker 14:  have an Apple device and you know everyone has an Apple device, maybe
Speaker 14:  use an iPad. If you don't already have one that's, that's a good choice.
Speaker 14:  We are hearing rumors that there's going to be an iPad on an arm that we'll
Speaker 14:  move around one day. Right. So you know, If you can wait, wait and see if
Speaker 14:  that comes out, if you're an Apple household, but you know, you're limited
Speaker 14:  with iPads to people that can use FaceTime and
Speaker 14:  Alexa calling with its universal aspect, I feel like
Speaker 14:  is, is is a good bet and they've been refining it and making it better
Speaker 14:  over the years. You can also use your Echo show to make phone calls too.
Speaker 14:  So you can just call someone's landline or cell phone,
Speaker 14:  not video calling but you know, it's, it's like a phone for your home, which
Speaker 14:  you know is kind of weird because we don't have those anymore.
Speaker 2:  It's true. And there is something to the, like the phone that is just in
Speaker 2:  a place on a table. Right. But you kind of go to when you want, particularly
Speaker 2:  for kids. Yes. And it's like having them, it's one thing, like I try to
Speaker 2:  hand my two-year-old, my phone and he just like throws it on the ground and
Speaker 2:  runs away. But there's something too. It's like this is where the phone is.
Speaker 2:  Yes. And they go to it like that actually kind of works for
Speaker 14:  Sure. And when you have young, young, older than you but younger than my
Speaker 14:  kids who don't have phones but are maybe old
Speaker 14:  enough to be home alone for 30 minutes. Sure. They don't have a phone.
Speaker 14:  So if something happened, you know, now you can actually use Alexa to
Speaker 14:  call like you can, they can say call mom and call you
Speaker 14:  or call nine one one. You know that it, having not having landlines
Speaker 14:  in our homes has kind of opened up this kind of weird gray
Speaker 14:  area. Especially when you have kids at home. So I think, I feel like an
Speaker 14:  echo show is a good solution here. If you aren't a fan of the
Speaker 14:  Amazon side of things,
Speaker 14:  I, you know, I think the I the Apple option, that iPad is probably your
Speaker 14:  best other choice. Yeah. Video calling as a whole has kind of
Speaker 14:  dropped off the cliff since the end of the pandemic.
Speaker 14:  You know, when Port the portal launched, it had like seven different services
Speaker 14:  you could use. So it had Zoom, you had WhatsApp, Facebook, all of that.
Speaker 14:  I don't think there is any other way you can use WhatsApp or Facebook
Speaker 14:  on video calling device today that I can think of.
Speaker 2:  That's right. I've done a fair amount of research on this now 'cause I assume
Speaker 2:  the, the people like a, I think there are a lot of people out there
Speaker 2:  whose main connection to family is through one of those two apps,
Speaker 2:  messenger or WhatsApp. Yes. And I also think there's a strong chance that
Speaker 2:  If you are still now a portal user, it's because it
Speaker 2:  works of those
Speaker 14:  Yes.
Speaker 2:  Or because of those two things. Right. So my assumption, Rob, our
Speaker 2:  caller didn't say, but my assumption is that the reason this is hard to replace
Speaker 2:  is because of WhatsApp and Messenger and Right on that front
Speaker 2:  you're just hosed. No, like there's just, there just isn't a good answer.
Speaker 14:  No a a laptop.
Speaker 2:  Yeah a laptop works fine. Yeah. An iPad works fine. Like
Speaker 14:  IPad. Yeah you could do it an iPad for WhatsApp video calling. They're just
Speaker 2:  Such overkill and I kind of feel like it's
Speaker 14:  Overkill. Yeah. And movable.
Speaker 2:  Well yeah, true.
Speaker 14:  An iPad, If you think it's hard to take, take a cell phone outta your kid's
Speaker 14:  hand, try taking an iPad. I mean it'll get used for other things.
Speaker 14:  Again, this is why I'm kind of excited about whatever Apple is gonna come
Speaker 14:  up with in terms of a home device. Because yes, you could use an iPad
Speaker 14:  as a WhatsApp calling device if it was fixed somewhere in your
Speaker 14:  house for children. Obviously you can use it if it moves too. But the
Speaker 14:  kid aspect is a tablet isn't going to stay fixed. Although
Speaker 14:  speaking of as, as we've mentioned this, I'm sitting here staring at my
Speaker 14:  Pixel tablet, which could be another
Speaker 14:  option and you could do WhatsApp calling through that.
Speaker 14:  Again, it's not fixed, but you can take it off the speaker.
Speaker 14:  But that would, that would be another option. I just don't
Speaker 14:  feel that comfortable recommending Pixel hardware right now.
Speaker 2:  That is, that is very fair. Well I have another Google question which we
Speaker 2:  should come to in a second. But I, I will say I think a non, a non
Speaker 2:  ridiculous answer to sort of solving this problem
Speaker 2:  is just to find the cheapest Android tablet you possibly can. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Because like the camera will be fine. Yeah. It will run all these apps on
Speaker 2:  Android, which is I think the way to solve your, your compatibility problem.
Speaker 2:  It's not gonna be nearly as like clean and useful and dedicated as something
Speaker 2:  like the portal was. No, but if you're just like, I just need a thing I can
Speaker 2:  prop on a coffee mug and put in front of my kid like a, a cheap Android tablet
Speaker 2:  will do that job fairly successfully.
Speaker 14:  Yes. Yes, that's
Speaker 2:  True. So I think that's one, one way to go. But I do think the dedicated
Speaker 2:  device experience is real. Like there's a reason people gravitated to things
Speaker 2:  like the portal. Yeah. In the first place. You have not mentioned a
Speaker 2:  Nest Hub one single time. Oh
Speaker 14:  No.
Speaker 2:  Why? Yeah. Okay. Because they don't, that was
Speaker 14:  What I figured. They don't do that. They don't, they had some kind of calling
Speaker 14:  feature at some point, but it keeps changing and going away and
Speaker 14:  is not helpful. I mean the Pixel tablet would be better than a Nest hub
Speaker 14:  at this stage. Definitely the Pixel tablet with its doc,
Speaker 14:  speaker doc too is is is a nice little device.
Speaker 14:  I think it's about ready for an upgrade and there were quite a few rumors
Speaker 14:  that p that Google wasn't going to upgrade it. So yeah,
Speaker 14:  again, I just, if you've been burned by one device dying
Speaker 14:  and losing support, it's so true. I honestly feel like an echo show
Speaker 14:  is probably or an iPad are gonna be, you know, those aren't going anywhere.
Speaker 2:  Right. Yeah. With Google it's like, can I interest you in another dead product
Speaker 2:  that it's company doesn't care about it at all.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. I mean what, how you talk to the person on the other end is the ultimate
Speaker 14:  decision here. And he didn't mention that, but as you say, but if they were
Speaker 14:  using WhatsApp and
Speaker 14:  Facebook Messenger, you know, Alexa app is gonna work in the same way on
Speaker 14:  your phone. It'll call, it comes through like a call on their end when
Speaker 14:  you call them. I think I I do think, yeah, that's the simplest,
Speaker 14:  most straightforward. Sorry, I
Speaker 14:  have like seven of them around and I thought I muted most of them, but apparently
Speaker 14:  not.
Speaker 2:  What went wrong? So clever.
Speaker 14:  Oh, it's, it's okay. I know why because you made me get the Echo Show 10
Speaker 14:  out. So this, we didn't we didn't come up. Yeah, we did not
Speaker 14:  discuss this. But I should mention in case Zoom was the way you were calling
Speaker 14:  'cause you could zoom through the portal, you can zoom
Speaker 14:  through Echo Show devices. So if that was the way that they were
Speaker 14:  communicating with the grandparents, although only
Speaker 14:  the Echo Show 10 works with Zoom or the
Speaker 14:  first or second Gen Echo Show eight, the third Gen
Speaker 14:  Echo show the most new one, which you would expect to go by if
Speaker 14:  that's what you were hoping to buy. You know, or by the latest gen
Speaker 14:  does not support Zoom. So what
Speaker 2:  A perfect explanation of Amazon's entire product strategy. It's
Speaker 14:  Just like no idea why
Speaker 2:  They have a, they have a grab bag of things that it does and they just, somebody
Speaker 2:  just reaches in and pulls out a bunch and that's what their devices are.
Speaker 14:  And actually the Zoom experience on the Echo shows is quite good. I tested
Speaker 14:  it, I did a how to on our site If you wanna check it out. And
Speaker 14:  it was a good experience. We stopped using Zoom for work calls, but I actually
Speaker 14:  used it for work a lot because it would just pop up and say, are you ready
Speaker 14:  for your call? And I could just press it and it would be there. And that
Speaker 14:  was like what I used the portal for too. It was, it was a, a good integration.
Speaker 14:  It had, it had a similar experience on the portal as it did on the show.
Speaker 14:  So if that was the way you were going then the show is definitely
Speaker 14:  the best option. Just don't get the latest Echo Show eight. 'cause it won't
Speaker 14:  work with Zoom. Right.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I think I I'm increasingly convinced as you talk that the
Speaker 2:  Echo Show Alexa calling is the way to go because
Speaker 2:  the, the Echo show microphones are gonna be better. Yes. Especially for like,
Speaker 2:  people moving around a room Yeah. Than even something like an iPad is gonna
Speaker 2:  be the, the speakers are very good. The calling stuff is
Speaker 2:  very, like, the technology for calling is very good inside of those devices.
Speaker 2:  And I think the pitch to family members of like, all you need is the
Speaker 2:  Alexa app is probably doable.
Speaker 14:  Not so bad. Yeah. It's not
Speaker 2:  Great, but it's, it's doable and it gives you the opportunity of like
Speaker 2:  Christmas 2025 gift here is your own box
Speaker 2:  for calling your grandchildren. Yeah. Which is like a, a spectacular victory
Speaker 2:  of a, of a device. I will put all pictures of your grandchildren and you
Speaker 2:  can press this button and call them. Yeah. So is a win.
Speaker 2:  Okay. For sure. I think that's it. So which if, if we're doing calling
Speaker 2:  it means you can get any, any echo show you want. We're doing this all through
Speaker 2:  Alexa. Which echo show would you recommend for our caller here?
Speaker 14:  I think the 10 because of its rotating
Speaker 14:  arm. I think the Echo Show 10, it, it is
Speaker 14:  $250 though. And if, and the Echo show eight
Speaker 14:  Second Gen would be a perfectly acceptable
Speaker 14:  alternative and about half the price. So it just has
Speaker 14:  it, I think the camera's not as good. The speakers aren't gonna be quite
Speaker 14:  as good, but it will work in the same, the software is the same.
Speaker 14:  So I would, yeah, I I mean the Echo show 10 would be more fun,
Speaker 14:  especially if your kids are moving around a lot. Right. They can't run away
Speaker 14:  from grandma as easily. Right. The show 10. True.
Speaker 2:  But If you can convince your family to download the Alexa app, pick your
Speaker 2:  favorite gun.
Speaker 14:  Yes. Yes. Okay. Well I wouldn't, I wouldn't do the five. That's a bit too
Speaker 14:  small. And then there's new yeah, the five huge ones. There's like the 21
Speaker 14:  just came out
Speaker 2:  Now you're talking. Put that on your dining room table, see what happens.
Speaker 2:  Yes, I'm into that. It's,
Speaker 14:  It's a bit large.
Speaker 14:  I think these are better. All right. So
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I think the, the eight or 10 seems like the right place to live. Alright
Speaker 2:  Jen, thank you. I hope this
Speaker 14:  Helps. You're welcome.
Speaker 2:  Alright, that is it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to everybody who came
Speaker 2:  on the show and thank you as always for listening. There's lots more on everything
Speaker 2:  we talked about in this episode from our S 25 reviews to the rest of our
Speaker 2:  phone coverage, to all the stuff with TikTok and RedNote and DeepSeek and
Speaker 2:  everything China at The Verge dot com. I'll put lots of links in the show
Speaker 2:  notes, but as always, read the website, Lord help us. There is a
Speaker 2:  lot going on right now. As always, If you have thoughts, questions, or feelings,
Speaker 2:  you can email vergecast at The Verge dot com or call the hotline. It's six
Speaker 2:  six VERGE one one. I've terrible news for you. The slack room broke,
Speaker 2:  but it also comes to the email and we're getting the slack room fixed so
Speaker 2:  the hotlines keep coming. Don't you worry. And we love hearing from you.
Speaker 2:  This show is produced by Will Poor Eric Gomez and Brandon Kiefer. The Vergecast
Speaker 2:  is a VERGE production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neli and
Speaker 2:  I'll be back on Friday to talk about all the politics, all the
Speaker 2:  news, whatever weird stuff is happening at the FCC Mor
Speaker 2:  gadgets that are still to come and everything else. We'll see you then. Rock
Speaker 2:  and roll.