# Transcript
ID: d0c8e50a-071d-4b85-8cde-60fb50e011bb
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-4597631793488673735/-2903794557931901334/s93290-US-4410s-1748222731.mp3
Description: Kids these days, you know? They love the '90s, they want everything to be colorful and bold and bouncy, and they really, truly love Snapchat. And the tech world is listening. On this episode, The Verge's Allison Johnson joins to talk about her review of the new Razr Ultra, the new-look Android 16, and why she thinks we're getting ever closer to a true flip phone resurgence. (Also: why we're not quite there yet.) After that, The Verge's Alex Heath explains what's going on with Snapchat, and how it's possible that the app is more popular than ever but still can't figure out how to cash in. It all makes us wonder: is there a business in chat at all? Finally, we answer a question on the Vergecast Hotline (call 866-VERGE11 or email vergecast@theverge.com!) about a possible outcome for Chrome after the Google search trial ends.
Speaker 2:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of really important
Speaker 2:  technology with absolutely no business model. I'm m your friend David Pierce,
Speaker 2:  and I am somewhere in the woods in the mountains of Virginia.
Speaker 2:  This is the week every year. That is Mother's Day, my wife's
Speaker 2:  birthday, our wedding anniversary, and this year her grad school
Speaker 2:  graduation. Congrats Anna. All in the span of seven days. So we try to get
Speaker 2:  away, we try to have some fun, and this time it was go sit in the woods
Speaker 2:  and just be quiet. It's been lovely. Can't recommend it enough, but that
Speaker 2:  is not what we're here to talk about today. Today we're gonna do two things
Speaker 2:  on the show. First, we're gonna talk about a couple of really
Speaker 2:  important new devices, and by new devices, I mean flip phones.
Speaker 2:  The new Motorola, Razr Ultra is out. Alison Johnson reviewed it. We're gonna
Speaker 2:  talk about that. And we're also gonna talk a little bit about whether this
Speaker 2:  is finally the year of flip phones. Then Alex Heath is gonna come on
Speaker 2:  and we're gonna talk about Snapchat. We're gonna talk about WhatsApp and
Speaker 2:  we're gonna talk about whether letting people talk to each other is actually
Speaker 2:  a tech business that even exists. We also have a really fun question on The
Speaker 2:  Vergecast hotline. Lots of stuff to do. All of that is coming up in just
Speaker 2:  a sec. But first I have, I'm gonna be honest, just like a tiny bit more celebrating
Speaker 2:  to do. And also I have not yet baked cake, So I gotta go bake a cake.
Speaker 2:  Wish me luck. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. Allison Johnson is here. Hi Allison.
Speaker 4:  Hello.
Speaker 2:  I've seen a lot of you recently for reasons I both can and cannot explain
Speaker 2:  yet. Yeah, and it's, this is very exciting. It's, it's nice to
Speaker 4:  See you again. It's good. It's a good addition to my life. I don't, I don
Speaker 4:  Dunno.
Speaker 2:  So there are two Android things I wanna talk about.
Speaker 2:  One is kind of the like big picture Android 16
Speaker 2:  material three cool kid, young people design.
Speaker 2:  But first I wanna talk about the razor. Yes. Because you and I might
Speaker 2:  be the only people on earth who believe in flip phones, but I still believe
Speaker 2:  in flip phones.
Speaker 4:  Yes, I do too. You
Speaker 2:  Reviewed the new Razr Ultra, which is like the high end flip
Speaker 2:  phone.
Speaker 2:  What was the verdict? How'd you feel?
Speaker 4:  It's so beautiful. Like, I can't emphasize this enough,
Speaker 4:  like I don't get to say this a lot. They're shaped like phones. They look
Speaker 4:  like phones, you know, we've like settled on a, a thing
Speaker 4:  for phones. This is a gorgeous phone. So the ultra
Speaker 4:  comes in the, the like fancier finishes. They're all kind of
Speaker 4:  fun. There's the regular razor and then the razor plus this one has the
Speaker 4:  wood panel back. Maybe because I made such a stink about it,
Speaker 4:  Motorola knew that that's the one I wanted.
Speaker 4:  It's gorgeous. It's not a huge departure or
Speaker 4:  huge evolution of the razor. I would say from last year.
Speaker 4:  Like there's some upgraded specs. You get the Snapdragon eight
Speaker 4:  elite processor, which is just the most amount of firepower
Speaker 4:  you can throw at a phone. Right now. It has like a slightly bigger
Speaker 4:  interior screen than the other two. It has a seven inch display, it's
Speaker 4:  a little bit higher resolution and you get
Speaker 4:  upgraded cameras. There's an upgraded like 50 megapixel main
Speaker 4:  camera, an ultra wide and then a 50 megapixel selfie camera.
Speaker 2:  The cameras by the way, seems like a super big deal to me 'cause I think
Speaker 2:  one of the reasons I was excited about this phone in the first place is it's
Speaker 2:  one of the first flip phones I can think of where you
Speaker 2:  don't look at the spec sheet and immediately see some glaring deficiency.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That It is like in theory, this is just a very good phone that
Speaker 2:  also happens to be a flip phone. It's not like the Samsung stuff. It always
Speaker 2:  has worse cameras than the, the normal candy bar phones. There's
Speaker 2:  always some issue and the ultra seems like
Speaker 2:  it's, it's the first one with like a feature complete spec sheet,
Speaker 2:  which is very exciting to me.
Speaker 4:  It is. I would say it's like it has closed the gap more than
Speaker 4:  any other flip phone for sure,
Speaker 2:  But it's not all the way there.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Just the thing is like they, they called it Ultra, which already,
Speaker 4:  you know, you're, you're setting, you're making your bed
Speaker 4:  when you call a phone ultra fair. Yeah. And the Samsung Galaxy S 25
Speaker 4:  Ultra exists. It costs $1,300 and if
Speaker 4:  you want to get into like what, how much phone can you get
Speaker 4:  for $1,300? You can get a phone with so many cameras,
Speaker 4:  you know, and like an amazing display. Like if you
Speaker 4:  wanna get into that, there's still kind of, we're not quite at like
Speaker 4:  parody I guess, but this does feel like they're like, we
Speaker 4:  shoved as much as we can in here. I found the battery life was
Speaker 4:  like real good, honestly. Which is nice. Yeah. Is a
Speaker 4:  concern for a flip phone. 'cause they are secretly just like two small
Speaker 4:  phones like strapped together. Yeah. It, it feels
Speaker 4:  more than ever before. Like if you have been thinking about
Speaker 4:  a flip phone and kind of put off by like Yeah, you know, but I want a little
Speaker 4:  more, I don't wanna give up so much this, you don't have to give up
Speaker 4:  quite so much this time around.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Or, or or having just increasingly
Speaker 2:  more ideas. Yeah. Some of those ideas seem to be good
Speaker 2:  and some of them seem to be bad, but I feel like the, the two pieces of it
Speaker 2:  that I most wanna talk about are the outside screen, which I think
Speaker 2:  my impression has been, Motorola has kind of done the most of the flip
Speaker 2:  phone manufacturers in terms of like what you can actually do on the outside
Speaker 2:  screen and then we have to talk about ai. But let's talk about that later
Speaker 2:  because I don't want to
Speaker 2:  the outside screen. What has, has Motorola like continued to kind of
Speaker 2:  dial in what you can do with the phone closed?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, and, and I think for my money they, they're
Speaker 4:  ahead and I have to apologize to the flip phones that are not sold
Speaker 4:  in the us. I don't really get to play with those. So I'm really kind
Speaker 4:  of basing this on experience versus the Samsung Z flip six.
Speaker 4:  Sure. Motorola just makes it super inviting and really easy
Speaker 4:  to enable apps on the outer display. There's little
Speaker 4:  games which I normally shrug off. I was like, I, I don't
Speaker 4:  wanna play a little marble game, but I handed the marble game to my
Speaker 4:  child, to my three-year-old and he frigging loves it
Speaker 4:  and he's actually kind of good at it. So like
Speaker 4:  that's been a weird little bonus feature where I just hand him the phone
Speaker 4:  and it's closed and he has a little marble game moment,
Speaker 4:  but they, they make it really easy. There's a new like widget panel so you
Speaker 4:  can kind of get even more like into
Speaker 4:  customization for it. The, just like, the media
Speaker 4:  player is cute. You can make it a tape deck and the, the little
Speaker 4:  tape reels. I like that like move as the music is playing.
Speaker 4:  I just, it it's fun. Yeah. I love it. The,
Speaker 2:  The thing I've been trying to decide with all of the outside screens on
Speaker 2:  flip phones is whether their job is to be like a
Speaker 2:  worse phone or if their job is to be more like a smartwatch where
Speaker 2:  it's like simple controls but you can't actually
Speaker 2:  do very much. Right. Like, you, you, you hit one button at a time and that's
Speaker 2:  kind of it. Yeah. What's what's your read on sort of in
Speaker 2:  day-to-day use? How you want the outer screen to work?
Speaker 4:  I think it's somewhere in the middle. Okay. I kind of started with like,
Speaker 4:  the flip phone has a little smart watch on the front and that's cool and
Speaker 4:  fun and you can do quick things. I end up doing a lot
Speaker 4:  more than that on this phone. I actually had my digital boarding pass
Speaker 4:  for my flight on there and I pulled it out and had the,
Speaker 4:  the gate agent scan it and he was like, that's a cute little phone.
Speaker 4:  I was like, oh, he doesn't know it's two phones in one.
Speaker 4:  But I like, I enable a lot of apps
Speaker 4:  So I can just fully open up Strava. I can choose
Speaker 4:  my activity, start my bike ride, and then just like put the phone away in
Speaker 4:  my pocket. Have I saved some kind of amazing amount of time
Speaker 4:  or is it that much more convenient? I think it's like a, an
Speaker 4:  an emotional like mental thing where I don't feel like I,
Speaker 4:  I had to like dive into my whole phone and look at every notification.
Speaker 4:  So for me it's really, it's really somewhere in the middle. I respond to
Speaker 4:  text, I'll use the little keyboard. It's kind of janky, but it's perfect
Speaker 4:  for just like, hey, on my way or, or those kind of things. So
Speaker 4:  it can be less if you want it to be, but for me I've, it kind of crept towards
Speaker 4:  like it's a cute little phone when I want it.
Speaker 2:  Hmm. Can you do things like open settings
Speaker 2:  and get to the notification shade and like if you want sort of the full
Speaker 2:  phone experience on the front screen, can you get it?
Speaker 4:  You can get a lot. Yeah. Okay. It has its own kind of built in UI for,
Speaker 4:  there's a, the notifications panel and
Speaker 4:  you can swipe through that like you normally would. There's quick
Speaker 4:  settings and, and all that stuff. You can run any app
Speaker 4:  you want on it and you just have to tap through a, an alert
Speaker 4:  that says like, Hey, this might suck. And sometimes
Speaker 4:  it really does.
Speaker 4:  But Yeah. It's like Motorola is very like, it's your world.
Speaker 4:  You can do what you want with this and I love that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. That feels like mostly the right answer. There is a little part of
Speaker 2:  me that is like, there should be a set of things that it
Speaker 2:  protects you from in a certain way where it's like
Speaker 2:  the, the notification shade is an interesting one Right. Because I feel like
Speaker 2:  it should, I want it to show me the notification that like just
Speaker 2:  buzzed in my pocket. Mm. But I actually feel like I want to have to open
Speaker 2:  the phone in order to go get the rest of my notifications. Oh. Because there,
Speaker 2:  there's just that, that little tiny bit of added friction feels like it's,
Speaker 2:  yeah. Useful. And again, it's, it's the thing you're describing that I think
Speaker 2:  I find so charming about flip phones in the first place is that like when
Speaker 2:  I go to a text message, making it a literal physical
Speaker 2:  activity I have to do in order to then go open Instagram is going to
Speaker 2:  prevent me from opening Instagram. Oh yeah. And I, I think like that, that's
Speaker 2:  probably still true in this case just because the front screen is small enough
Speaker 2:  and not quite good enough to really be a good Instagram experience. But I
Speaker 2:  do feel like dialing in that sort of, how do we give you all the things to
Speaker 2:  do without then just sort of letting you into your phone
Speaker 2:  unless you open the phone feels like that's the balance. I don't know that
Speaker 2:  anybody has quite dialed in. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And it's a little bit of like personal responsibility
Speaker 4:  because Instagram is a hundred percent the one I will like
Speaker 4:  mindlessly tap on a notification from the outer screen and
Speaker 4:  it'll be like, you wanna open Instagram? Like, I haven't enabled it for
Speaker 4:  the outer screen. And I'm like, oh no, no, no. I, I don't actually. And I
Speaker 4:  like back away like the social media apps
Speaker 4:  really, I, I've kept off the front screen and it would be a bad
Speaker 4:  experience using them. You could if you wanted to. But
Speaker 4:  I have maintained that as my, my barrier of like, I'm not
Speaker 4:  gonna cross this line. I'm gonna have to make a conscious decision to open
Speaker 4:  the phone if I wanna check on Instagram.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And that's an okay balance that you can set that up for yourself. Feels
Speaker 2:  like a good, that's an okay way to do it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Tell me about the AI stuff. I think Motorola, again has just a lot of
Speaker 2:  ideas about what AI is supposed to do on your phone.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It was a little overwhelming. I, I'm still like
Speaker 4:  reserving a little bit of judgment 'cause I wanna live with some of this
Speaker 4:  stuff a little bit longer. But, so they have introduced something
Speaker 4:  called Modo ai, which is really just, there's an app on the phone
Speaker 4:  and it's kind of a dashboard for all the, these AI features
Speaker 4:  that, that live alongside Gemini in every
Speaker 4:  piece of AI that Google had shoved into Android.
Speaker 4:  But Modo AI is, is like a handful of things. There's
Speaker 4:  Catch me up, which will summarize your recent notifications
Speaker 4:  from messaging apps.
Speaker 2:  Is Motorola better at this than Apple is?
Speaker 4:  Yes. You know what? I think it's really, it's a good co Well, yes and no.
Speaker 4:  Okay. 'cause it can only do the messaging apps. So I'm like, catch me up
Speaker 4:  and I have a bunch of emails that I really need to get into and it it's just
Speaker 4:  like you didn't get any texts in the last hour. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Is that even solving a, I don't feel like my notification overload is my
Speaker 2:  messaging apps. Like that's not the problem I'm having.
Speaker 4:  That's where I'm hung up on it. I like that it's you opt in,
Speaker 4:  you you're like, sure I need this at this moment. And it makes me more
Speaker 4:  irritated with the Apple alternative, which is like, we're gonna give you
Speaker 4:  a weird little summary of every single notification. It might be wrong too.
Speaker 4:  You gotta double check it. So there's that. There is
Speaker 4:  something called, remember this, which you can, it's
Speaker 4:  a little pixel screenshots ish. 'cause you can screenshot a, a
Speaker 4:  website, you can take a picture of something, you can just write yourself
Speaker 4:  a little text note and it'll save it and kind of catalog it
Speaker 4:  in the way of AI reading it and tagging it.
Speaker 4:  And then you, you ask the Moto AI later like, Hey, what time is
Speaker 4:  my flight tomorrow? And in my experience,
Speaker 4:  it was good with that stuff. It didn't go halluc and eat
Speaker 4:  another flight out of another airport. That's good. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But has that catch where you have to remember to add stuff to it.
Speaker 2:  Right. But I will say I think that is a very cool sort of
Speaker 2:  overall idea. This idea of like, you just need a place to
Speaker 2:  dump stuff that you encounter on your phone. Yeah. You know, you, you screenshot
Speaker 2:  a text message or you see a recipe or whatever and you just sort of dump
Speaker 2:  it all somewhere that you can like access and query later I think is the
Speaker 2:  right idea. Yeah. I'm not super sold on the idea that every phone
Speaker 2:  manufacturer should make this for themselves. I feel like this is better
Speaker 2:  as like a cross-platform thing tied to an account that I already have
Speaker 2:  instead of all living on my phone. But this still feels like
Speaker 2:  that in terms of like phone AI stuff actually feels sort of directionally
Speaker 2:  correct to me. Yeah. In the same way that I think pixel screenshots is like
Speaker 2:  a very good idea.
Speaker 4:  Exactly. There's so many times I end up with a thing where I'm like, where
Speaker 4:  do I put this? Like this? I don't wanna just leave it. I don't
Speaker 4:  like wanna put it in a weird chrome bookmarks folder that I've
Speaker 4:  forgotten exists and Right. Yeah. So that's one
Speaker 4:  of the things that like this feels promising, wanna use it a little more.
Speaker 4:  And then, then there's like a, an AI voice, you know, recorder.
Speaker 4:  Then it makes a transcription just sort of like, you want it to pay attention
Speaker 4:  in a meeting
Speaker 4:  you do that kind of thing.
Speaker 2:  Motorola really just trying to do pixel stuff here it sounds like A
Speaker 4:  Little bit. Yeah. Yeah. And it, it gets a little AI overload
Speaker 4:  with the, the fact that Gemini and all that stuff is on
Speaker 4:  here, but also like, they've tried to make it like very
Speaker 4:  obvious how to interact with their ai. So there's like a little
Speaker 4:  floating bubble on the screen that will get you to the ai.
Speaker 4:  There's the Moto AI app, which is like right in the middle of the home screen.
Speaker 4:  The Ultra has an AI button on the side. So you like
Speaker 4:  long press it or short press it and get into the ai.
Speaker 4:  There's also ways to like prop up the phone, have the front
Speaker 4:  screen kind of facing you and you can like approach it and the
Speaker 4:  AI will start listening
Speaker 2:  Weird.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It was all a little much, I di I tried the propping up thing
Speaker 4:  and then I just felt like the phone was watching me. So I,
Speaker 2:  Yeah. So the idea is like you have it on your desk or whatever and then you
Speaker 2:  walk up to it like the, what was it? The Echo show does this right. Where
Speaker 2:  it'll, it'll change the interface when you get close to it. Right. But instead
Speaker 2:  it's an AI assistant being like, what's up?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah. I like that. And there's a little, the little glowing borders
Speaker 4:  going. I'm like, what does that mean? Is it listening? Is it waiting for
Speaker 2:  Me? No, thank you. No, no.
Speaker 4:  Didn't super love it.
Speaker 2:  I do feel like Motorola is in
Speaker 2:  a category I would put a lot of other companies in that I, I don't
Speaker 2:  necessarily blame it for, but they're just so deep on
Speaker 2:  the AI thing that it's like we have to overplay our hand on this that
Speaker 2:  it's like we can't be chill about the ai. We can't just have you discovered
Speaker 2:  over time. We have to just put it in
Speaker 2:  front of you no matter where you are all the time. And this is like early
Speaker 2:  Samsung mistakes, right. Where for years, every time you would do anything,
Speaker 2:  the little popup would appear and Samsung would be like, did you know that
Speaker 2:  milk music exists? And you'd be like, I don't care. Samsung. Like, I'm, I'm
Speaker 2:  good. I do know this and I'm not interested in knowing this information and
Speaker 2:  my hope is give it another generation or two and
Speaker 2:  they will stop feeling the need to beat you over the head with AI
Speaker 2:  exists in quite the same way, but It is, everybody
Speaker 2:  is kind of overshooting their actual usefulness with a lot
Speaker 2:  of this stuff. Yeah. That said, I do think the button is a good idea.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. The button I don't hate, I wish you could reprogram it to do
Speaker 4:  something else. They don't let you do that. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  It should be like the iPhone's action button. Yeah. Like even if you start
Speaker 2:  it as an AI thing, but sort of let me turn it into something else. Fine.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, yeah. Like we would like you to use it for ai but you know,
Speaker 4:  it's your world. Yeah. And I, I kind of sympathize with
Speaker 4:  Motorola in that like, it, they're asking you to like create
Speaker 4:  some new behaviors with your phone and you have to take a minute and think
Speaker 4:  like, how do we get to the ai? Or if I wanna put this and
Speaker 4:  remember this, what am I doing? So they've kind of put it everywhere. I feel
Speaker 4:  like an attempt to be like, here you go. But yeah, it,
Speaker 4:  it just gets a little bit like AI overload pretty quickly.
Speaker 2:  That's fair. So I'm gonna ask you the question I ask you every year around
Speaker 2:  this time, is this the year, the flip phone
Speaker 4:  Man, I,
Speaker 2:  We're gonna get at least another one from Samsung. Yeah. Sounds like the,
Speaker 2:  the flip iPhone, which is probably gonna be a fold iPhone, which I would
Speaker 2:  like to be on the record as saying is a bad decision. Oh is, is a ways
Speaker 2:  out. But like it, it feels like at the very least we are getting to the point
Speaker 2:  where you can credibly say this phone is as good
Speaker 2:  as the other phones you might buy. And also it's a flip phone. Like we're,
Speaker 2:  we're almost there. And that feels important.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's closure than it's ever been. I think if you've been on the fence
Speaker 4:  about a flip phone and you're pretty sure it's a good idea for you, actually
Speaker 4:  someone in the comments had a good suggestion that you could get
Speaker 4:  one of the like low end razors on a
Speaker 4:  prepaid number for like 250 bucks or
Speaker 4:  something. Oh, that's a good idea. Like try that out, see if you like it
Speaker 4:  and then that might be a good way to, you know, get
Speaker 4:  your feet wet without jumping into a $1,300 phone.
Speaker 4:  That, like the couple of things that I hesitate about
Speaker 4:  on the Motorola and all the flip phones right now there,
Speaker 4:  there's no dust protection. There's like teeny tiny
Speaker 4:  particle protection. It's IP 48, but it's still
Speaker 4:  kind of like, I would be a little more careful with this phone than a
Speaker 4:  regular slab phone. I handed it to my 3-year-old and he put his
Speaker 4:  fingers all over the inner screen. Like I was, I didn't go easy on this thing,
Speaker 4:  but that's a little bit of a hesitation. I am also a little
Speaker 4:  annoyed with Motorola as software policy. They haven't been like
Speaker 4:  super great about rolling out software versions in a
Speaker 4:  timely fashion. They support it for not quite as many
Speaker 4:  years as Samsung. I think they do three OS versions and then
Speaker 4:  four years of security updates, which is like,
Speaker 2:  Which is not as good as its competitors. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  It's okay. Like it'll it'll get most people as far as they wanna go
Speaker 4:  with this phone probably. But yeah, we're getting there. Yeah. I'm like
Speaker 4:  if you, if you are pretty sure a flip phone is for you, like It
Speaker 4:  is a great year for the flip phone.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I was excited to, I got to try yours for a minute.
Speaker 2:  And we're also still at the point where like there is a crease
Speaker 2:  if you look for it in the inside screen, but it's,
Speaker 2:  it it continues to go away. Yeah. Like it, which is, which is nice. Like
Speaker 2:  even after a couple minutes of using it, I didn't really notice it anymore.
Speaker 2:  It's still very tall and It is still not quite as good a screen as you get
Speaker 2:  when it's just a regular pane of glass. But like you said, we're getting
Speaker 2:  there. The, the gap gets smaller and smaller every year it seems.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I'm very excited to see what Samsung does because from a hardware perspective,
Speaker 2:  Samsung has been out in front of this for a long time and I think
Speaker 2:  might might still be the one to get us there.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. But we'll see. That's coming later. So before I let you go, let's talk
Speaker 2:  about the, the Android 16 stuff for just a minute. What do you make of
Speaker 2:  this? We talked a little bit about this on Friday show, but there's a, a
Speaker 2:  new design language for Android. It's very like vibrant and bouncy
Speaker 2:  and colorful. There's a new font.
Speaker 2:  What do you think? What do you make of all this?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I think it's fun. They're calling this material three
Speaker 4:  expressive. It's a big update that's gonna be in the Android in
Speaker 4:  Android 16. It's gonna be in the beta later this month. And
Speaker 4:  we got kind of a little preview of it when Google
Speaker 4:  accidentally posted a blog kind of explaining the
Speaker 4:  rationale behind the designs. You know, Google leaking Google stuff
Speaker 4:  is a, a tale as old as time.
Speaker 2:  That's a true tradition of this time of year. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Right. But there's just a real emphasis in the
Speaker 4:  kind of the appearance of it. It's very, like, they talk about
Speaker 4:  the springy animations and the, the fonts are
Speaker 4:  bolder, the colors are bolder,
Speaker 4:  you know, there's new icon shapes and everything about It is
Speaker 4:  just screams like youth, like
Speaker 4:  hello fellow kids kind of thing.
Speaker 2:  Do you think that's the right call? I mean put that next to everything we've
Speaker 2:  seen about what's coming in iOS, which is like very paired
Speaker 2:  down and simple and they're, they're doing a similar kind of like
Speaker 2:  layered three dimensional thing, but it's much more like
Speaker 2:  spaceshipy and glassy and pristine.
Speaker 2:  Android is going all the other way and they're just like, get really weird
Speaker 2:  with what all of this looks like. Do you think that, is that the right
Speaker 2:  call for Android? These things were, we're pushing towards each other for
Speaker 2:  so long. iOS and Android we're looking more and more like every year and
Speaker 2:  now it feels like in a pretty big way. They are absolutely breaking back
Speaker 2:  apart.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I think it, you know, maybe It is kind of just the nature and
Speaker 4:  they're gonna split apart and come back together again at some point. But
Speaker 4:  I, in my mind, I think yeah, make it look different.
Speaker 4:  iOS has such a stranglehold on the US market
Speaker 4:  and especially among young people. I think we all read a study
Speaker 4:  last year where like 88% of teenagers have an
Speaker 4:  iPhone or something like that. So this feels like an attempt
Speaker 4:  to address that market. And there's a little bit of like inherent
Speaker 4:  cringiness I think when a big company sort of
Speaker 4:  approaches a younger demographic and is like, look, we speak your
Speaker 4:  language.
Speaker 2:  How do you do fellow kids is such a sick burn. But also like Exactly Right,
Speaker 2:  right. You are correct about that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. But, but not, not to kind of dismiss it all as like, oh, they're just
Speaker 4:  trying to like pander to Gen ZI think it's,
Speaker 4:  it's good to refresh things and it seems like they've put a lot of
Speaker 4:  thought into like how do we make this more usable for
Speaker 4:  everybody? And, and I think making something that looks like an
Speaker 4:  an iOS clone is wouldn't be a smart
Speaker 4:  move right now. I think leaning into the difference of like,
Speaker 4:  yeah, this is not an iPhone, this is something else. It, you
Speaker 4:  can make it purple and pink if you want and it looks cool.
Speaker 2:  Are you a customizer, by the way, one of the things I've been thinking about
Speaker 2:  a lot with this is that there is this big push toward
Speaker 2:  letting you do whatever you want with your phone. And I, I keep trying to
Speaker 2:  figure out how to put that next to the thing that we have known and said
Speaker 2:  for forever, which is that defaults are the only thing that matter, right?
Speaker 2:  And So I'm like, is this, am I giving these companies too much credit
Speaker 2:  for giving people more customization tools that statistically
Speaker 2:  speaking they're never going to use? Or is there something to the
Speaker 2:  idea that actually these things are becoming more personal and more versatile
Speaker 2:  and what we should be giving people is more knobs and buttons and options
Speaker 2:  to mess with.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Maybe it's a good moment to try it, I think. 'cause yeah, I think
Speaker 4:  in the past, like I don't super customize
Speaker 4:  my phone. I play around with all the options. I
Speaker 4:  pick one of the color palettes and material you, and,
Speaker 4:  and then I, I'm like, this looks weird. And I just go back to the regular
Speaker 4:  one. But maybe kind of as the, as the hardware has
Speaker 4:  just hit a point where, you know, flip phones and folding phones
Speaker 4:  side, they all look the same. Like a Samsung phone, looks like
Speaker 4:  an iPhone, looks like a Yeah. Pixel. Unless you're looking at the camera
Speaker 4:  bump. So maybe that's kind of ripe for
Speaker 4:  like, we'll do something fun and different in the software and people might,
Speaker 4:  might actually try these things out if they're like, you know, I, I
Speaker 4:  would like a different color palette. I see more like
Speaker 4:  colorful fun lock iOS lock screens. You know, since Apple made
Speaker 4:  that change. I don't believe I've seen anyone
Speaker 4:  outside of the, my my fellow like,
Speaker 4:  you know, phone sickos tinting the icons on their
Speaker 4:  home screens. Like Normies are not doing that. I don't think
Speaker 2:  Phone sickos is is the exact correct description of who does that.
Speaker 4:  Yes. And I put myself in that category love lovingly with all, all
Speaker 4:  of my fellow phone sickos. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  With all of these personalizations. My problem is like, and it's like what
Speaker 2:  you said with the material, you colors like 60% of it. I'm like, this looks
Speaker 2:  awesome. I love it. It's so cool. And then like four times a day you
Speaker 2:  open a screen and it just like, it just feels and looks awful
Speaker 2:  and everything is bad. And I'm like, I'm just gonna go back to the way that
Speaker 2:  it was. And So I think, like my hope is if these
Speaker 2:  companies, and Google in particular can stay committed to this idea that
Speaker 2:  it'll actually get developers and users and like wallpaper makers and everybody
Speaker 2:  to buy into this way of thinking about what a phone should look like
Speaker 2:  and start to solve some of those edge cases. 'cause right now it's like half
Speaker 2:  the icons on my screen look great in whatever color I've chosen. Yeah. And
Speaker 2:  the other half look like butts. Yeah. And you're like, you gotta fix that.
Speaker 4:  Right. Fix the buts, please
Speaker 2:  Fix the buts and then Android will be perfect. Is my takeaway. Exactly.
Speaker 2:  So Android 16 coming this year seems like it, it might be the
Speaker 2:  most interesting Android in a minute. Like it's been a while since we had
Speaker 2:  an Android that you sort of update your phone and look at it and go, oh,
Speaker 2:  it's different now. This feels like it might do it. And I'm excited about
Speaker 2:  that.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, me too. And there's, there's other stuff. They've got kind of like
Speaker 4:  a, a live activities thing. There's gonna be
Speaker 4:  new haptics and all that. It's gonna look and feel and do different things.
Speaker 4:  So Yeah, it's been a minute. I I'm excited for that.
Speaker 2:  Me too. All right, well we gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back.
Speaker 2:  We're gonna talk about Snapchat. Allison, thank you as always.
Speaker 4:  Thank you.
Speaker 2:  All right. I made a mistake. I hung up on Allison before we did one thing
Speaker 2:  that Allison asked. So Allison's back. Hi Allison,
Speaker 4:  I'm back.
Speaker 2:  You, you had a special request for the people.
Speaker 4:  I do.
Speaker 2:  What's up?
Speaker 4:  I have the great honor of hosting a couple episodes of The
Speaker 4:  Vergecast this summer and something I wanna do is
Speaker 4:  ask all of you to let me know your phone buying
Speaker 4:  conundrums. I wanna hear from people who are
Speaker 4:  considering a new phone who are stuck between two phones
Speaker 4:  who don't wanna upgrade their iPhone mini.
Speaker 4:  I see you, I am one of you. This can be
Speaker 4:  a pep talk, this can be therapy. I can help you talk through a buying decision.
Speaker 4:  I spend all day thinking about what phone people should buy. So
Speaker 4:  this is like, I'm just like itching to provide this service. So
Speaker 4:  send me your, your questions, your, your troubles. I would
Speaker 4:  like to hear them.
Speaker 2:  I love this. I'm gonna call and ask you if it's actually time
Speaker 2:  for me to give up on the iPhone and switch to Android. If I should go through
Speaker 2:  the pain of leaving iMessage once and for all. That's mine.
Speaker 4:  Okay. That'll be a a 60 minute segment. So
Speaker 2:  Cool. And so yeah, same way as always. Call the hotline. Eight six six version
Speaker 2:  one one email Vergecast The Verge dot com. Yeah, you and a
Speaker 2:  bunch of folks are gonna have a lot of fun on this show over the summer and
Speaker 2:  I'm very excited.
Speaker 4:  It's gonna rule. I'm so excited.
Speaker 2:  Sweet. All
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Alex Heath is here. Hi Alex.
Speaker 5:  Hey Devon.
Speaker 2:  So as we do from time to time, you and I need to talk about Snapchat.
Speaker 2:  It's possible that you and I are the only people in the news business who
Speaker 2:  care about Snapchat, which is I think part of the point. But I care deeply
Speaker 2:  about Snapchat and I wanna talk about it. So I think we should probably
Speaker 2:  start like last fall because Snapchat launches
Speaker 2:  this big or announces that they're doing this big redesign, kind of a
Speaker 2:  whole new way of thinking about Snapchat. I think they called it simple Snapchat.
Speaker 2:  And you, you like understood what was going on at the time. And I think we
Speaker 2:  talked about it a little bit but refresh our memory a little bit. Like what
Speaker 2:  was Snapchat trying to do with this big change last fall?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, Snapchat started as a pretty simple disappearing messaging app
Speaker 5:  and over the years they added on a lot of stuff. There's a
Speaker 5:  map where you can see where your friends are in the app. There's
Speaker 5:  memories, which is essentially their own camera roll experience. There's
Speaker 5:  Discover, which was their really early take on
Speaker 5:  how a publishing environment can work in a visual messaging
Speaker 5:  application. And then they were doing Spotlight, which was their
Speaker 5:  TikTok video, you know, full screen swipe up and down
Speaker 5:  competitor. And it was just a lot. That
Speaker 2:  Is a lot of stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They're also scaling beyond their core
Speaker 5:  demographic of young people and I think
Speaker 5:  older people and don't want a ton of tabs. And so the idea was,
Speaker 5:  let's condense all of this. They really need their content business,
Speaker 5:  the video business spotlight and discover to get bigger
Speaker 5:  and be more culturally relevant. And the idea was let's just
Speaker 5:  simplify everything to three tabs messaging the camera Snap always
Speaker 5:  opens to the camera and then on the right you would have
Speaker 5:  all of the video content and publish or content merged together into just
Speaker 5:  one feed like Reels or TikTok. And this was, you know, meant
Speaker 5:  to not only appease investors by making the video business more front and
Speaker 5:  center, but hopefully make the app more intuitive and encourage
Speaker 5:  more people to not just message their friends on Snap but
Speaker 5:  watch video, watch stuff from creators, watch stuff from
Speaker 5:  publishers.
Speaker 2:  The theory of that still, even as you describe it, strikes me as a good
Speaker 2:  idea. Yeah. That I think like Snap's whole thing has been
Speaker 2:  trying to do all of this in one place makes sense. Right? And I think we,
Speaker 2:  you, you can sort of litigate that forever if the messaging app and the content
Speaker 2:  business should have been fully separate products. But Snap
Speaker 2:  has believed that they should be at least next to each other for a very long
Speaker 2:  time. And the idea of like camera in the middle, talk to your friends
Speaker 2:  on one side, public facing video feed on the other
Speaker 2:  side like that, that makes sense to me. That is like, that is the Snapchat
Speaker 2:  that seems like it could work and yet, and
Speaker 2:  yet they, they in an earnings report just recently, they just
Speaker 2:  bailed on that whole entire idea what is happening here.
Speaker 5:  I think Snap is really struggling to execute, especially over
Speaker 5:  the last, I would say five years really.
Speaker 5:  There was a moment where it seemed like they were inventing all these new
Speaker 5:  formats, really looking ahead to where social media was going. Everyone was
Speaker 5:  copying them. And lately It is just been a lot of
Speaker 5:  executional business strategy
Speaker 5:  mishaps. And what happened with this simple Snapchat rollout was
Speaker 5:  that it was really hurting engagement with the
Speaker 5:  audience that consumes content the most, which was the opposite of what they
Speaker 5:  wanted to happen. And because Snap is so already
Speaker 5:  financially on the rocks, they can't
Speaker 5:  take huge swings like they used to, like when they redesigned
Speaker 5:  the app right after they iPod and then Kylie Jenner posted about how it sucked
Speaker 5:  and you know, the stock tanked and all of that. Right.
Speaker 2:  You can't really afford another one of those. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They stuck with it at the time and now they're just so beholden
Speaker 5:  to Wall Street and quarterly earnings and proving that they can actually
Speaker 5:  be a real business that they can't afford to tank
Speaker 5:  their business with a redesign like this even if they think it's the thing
Speaker 5:  that's gonna work in the long run. So yeah, it was a big swing and a miss.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, it and it does feel like that tension you describe
Speaker 2:  might be just unsolvable at some point for Snapchat because It is the, the
Speaker 2:  two things that keep happening are like, especially for young users,
Speaker 2:  they're growing up and continuing to use Snapchat and there is like a, there
Speaker 2:  is a world in which Snapchat is more and more sort of culturally
Speaker 2:  important to vast numbers of people
Speaker 2:  than ever. Like It is, It is a, a communication tool that like
Speaker 2:  several generations of people now use all day every day.
Speaker 2:  And that is very important and very powerful. And yet Snapchat cannot figure
Speaker 2:  out how to make a single nickel off of that entire thing. And
Speaker 2:  so it just seems like it's, it's now stuck in this
Speaker 2:  business of trying to be TikTok or reels
Speaker 2:  when TikTok and reels exist.
Speaker 5:  Well let's give them a little credit. They make more than a nickel.
Speaker 5:  How, how much revenue do you think they made last quarter?
Speaker 2:  Well that's an interesting question.
Speaker 5:  I wanna ask you that. And then how many users do you think they have?
Speaker 5:  I think the audience will be surprised by both of these.
Speaker 2:  I'm gonna guess there's more users than revenue. It
Speaker 5:  Would be actually no, but they're close. Okay.
Speaker 2:  I think I'm give the numbers. I'm I'm gonna bet it's, I'm gonna bet it's
Speaker 2:  less than I would've thought a
Speaker 5:  Annually. Yes. But quarterly. So they're, they're doing about 1.3 billion
Speaker 5:  a year in Rev in a quarter in revenue
Speaker 2:  That's higher than I would've guessed. I was gonna guess like high hundred
Speaker 2:  millions.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And they've surpassed 900 million monthly active users.
Speaker 5:  So they're rapidly approaching a billion users. Over
Speaker 5:  460 million of those are daily.
Speaker 2:  That's huge like that that those are giant numbers
Speaker 5:  Significantly larger than X. It's in the same ballpark is like
Speaker 5:  Telegram maybe bigger, obviously Meta's
Speaker 5:  platforms are are larger, but in terms of like independent
Speaker 5:  social media, it's by far the biggest. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And at the same time,
Speaker 5:  snap stock price, if you pull it up from when they went public, God
Speaker 5:  what is it like 10 ish years ago is, is negative.
Speaker 5:  So this is a business that has gone sideways over the last decade while at
Speaker 5:  the same time scaling its user base by a dramatic,
Speaker 5:  you know, percentage. And I think that just goes to show that
Speaker 5:  maybe the thesis of this conversation too, that maybe you can't make money
Speaker 5:  off of messaging. I dunno.
Speaker 2:  Well yeah, I mean I guess is it, would you chalk that
Speaker 2:  up to like you said, sort of pure executional failure? Like is this
Speaker 2:  just a function of not having a very good sales team or like, or is
Speaker 2:  there something kind of fundamentally different about what
Speaker 2:  Snapchat is and who it's reaching that
Speaker 2:  just doesn't work the same way that it has for other companies?
Speaker 5:  I think it's a mix of all of that. Okay. I think it's really hard to compete
Speaker 5:  with a platform like Meta that has over 10 million advertisers
Speaker 5:  platforms with billions of users and it's just been grinding on the ads
Speaker 5:  stuff. And now ai which is increasingly
Speaker 5:  getting intertwined with ads for much longer at a much larger
Speaker 5:  run rate. And you know, I think Snap also has been
Speaker 5:  kind of precious about things for far too long. It is now finally
Speaker 5:  realizing it needs to be a real business. And I think that
Speaker 5:  delay in getting there really cost them.
Speaker 5:  And you know, snap, I, I've been covering Snap since before they
Speaker 5:  went public when they were a very small startup. The headlines like,
Speaker 5:  is Snapchat dead? Is Snapchat cooks? You know,
Speaker 5:  Snapchat's almost dead have been written many times. I've written them many
Speaker 5:  times the company has still held on, but
Speaker 5:  it's definitely not what everyone hoped it would be. And
Speaker 5:  you know, they've tried ways to monetize. They've got
Speaker 5:  Snapchat Plus now, which is a subscription that has 15 million
Speaker 5:  subscribers where you get a bunch of extra things in the app. Their ads
Speaker 5:  business is meaningful. It's nowhere near Meta or Google's, but it's, it's
Speaker 5:  meaningful. It's nothing to completely thumb up, but
Speaker 5:  they're just still really struggling to figure out how to
Speaker 5:  monetize the app effectively. And for the longest time they just weren't
Speaker 5:  monetizing the main way people use the app, which is messaging.
Speaker 5:  And recently they started putting ads in chat and they're testing that, but
Speaker 5:  they don't want to tank the metrics of messaging either. 'cause that's their
Speaker 5:  core business. So there's just a lot of, they're, they're trying to
Speaker 5:  do a lot because messaging and
Speaker 5:  all of that that it entails and really talking to friends is
Speaker 5:  just really hard to put ads in.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Well and then next to all of that is, is this thing
Speaker 2:  that Snap has been trying to sell itself as for years now, which is that
Speaker 2:  Snap is a camera company, right? That, that actually we're not about messaging,
Speaker 2:  we're not about Spotlight, we're not about any of this other stuff. We're
Speaker 2:  about camera. And I think I bought that
Speaker 2:  for a long time and I think still to this day, like if you wanna talk about
Speaker 2:  who is doing the most interesting ar camera stuff, I think it's probably
Speaker 2:  still Snap. The problem is just no one cares.
Speaker 2:  And I think, I think either we're still too early and this is happening more
Speaker 2:  slowly than we realized.
Speaker 2:  And I mean the, the first generation of spectacles was 10 years ago and like
Speaker 2:  Snap has just been at this a long time and the the world
Speaker 2:  has not caught up to Snap. And either it's gonna happen slower than anybody
Speaker 2:  bet on or it's just not gonna happen at all. And I, I
Speaker 2:  used to think with confidence that it was just that it was happening
Speaker 2:  slower. And I'm starting to wonder more and more if it's just not gonna happen
Speaker 2:  at all.
Speaker 5:  You know, they don't call themselves a camera company anymore.
Speaker 2:  Did that change?
Speaker 5:  They dropped it, yeah. Interesting. They dropped around the time they were
Speaker 5:  redesigning the app and trying to really become an ads business. Now they're
Speaker 5:  just a regular old tech company.
Speaker 2:  They're just Snapchat again. Yeah. That feels very telling to me. Well
Speaker 5:  I mean they, they, they still open to the camera and spectacles is still
Speaker 5:  very much to the chagrin of their investors. A serious
Speaker 5:  bet that Evan Spiegel the CO is very focused on.
Speaker 5:  But yeah, they're, they're playing in a land of giants there. Right.
Speaker 5:  And gosh, you think back to like the yellow vending
Speaker 5:  machines, the first spectacles drop, how buzzy that was
Speaker 5:  and it kind of is Snap in a nutshell. They created a lot of buzz. They did
Speaker 5:  something pretty early that was foreshadowing what was
Speaker 5:  to come right now with the meta Ray bands camera glasses finally
Speaker 5:  taking off 10 years later. But at the same time
Speaker 5:  they wildly overshot the demand and ended up
Speaker 5:  costing them like 40 million in unsold inventory because they bought way
Speaker 5:  more spectacles thinking this thing was gonna scale way faster. Right. And
Speaker 5:  then it didn't, and then they've like reset that division like 14
Speaker 5:  times since then. Yeah. So it's just this repeat
Speaker 5:  pattern of good ideas that are probably too early
Speaker 5:  and then messing up on the execution. I don't know how else to say it. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And when you look at how messaging apps are
Speaker 5:  monetized, meta is probably the best example.
Speaker 5:  They actually monetize it through ads on their other apps. So Meta has this
Speaker 5:  conglomerate where ads that point people to me
Speaker 5:  with businesses and WhatsApp and Messenger is a 10 billion a year
Speaker 5:  business. And those ads don't show up in
Speaker 5:  WhatsApp or Messenger. They show up on Facebook and Instagram and they point
Speaker 5:  people to those apps. So Meta has built this flywheel with these
Speaker 5:  products that serve different purposes that point to each other and
Speaker 5:  that's how they're monetizing messaging. And then the only other really
Speaker 5:  meaningful way that someone has ma monetized
Speaker 5:  messaging besides that would be like a Discord or a
Speaker 5:  Telegram, which is, they're smaller still pretty
Speaker 5:  subscription based. Most of the revenue Telegram made last year was actually
Speaker 5:  from crypto, from its crypto holdings. It has this weird cryptocurrency
Speaker 5:  that you can use in the app.
Speaker 2:  Sounds right.
Speaker 5:  So no one has figured out ads in a messaging environment. Yeah. And for years,
Speaker 5:  up until the last couple years when they started testing ads in chat on Snapchat,
Speaker 5:  all the people at Snap I would talk to would be like, we are never going
Speaker 5:  to really crack revenue growth until we figure out how to
Speaker 5:  monetize that messaging tab. And they're trying now. But,
Speaker 5:  you know, we'll see, I think rolling back the, the discover the content piece
Speaker 5:  back to where it was is a sign that that video business
Speaker 5:  and the ads that could go in there, which are make a lot of money for Instagram
Speaker 5:  and TikTok are also gonna be a slower
Speaker 5:  role for Snap. So yeah, it's just a challenging time for them.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Well, and I think you, you, you bring up a broader point about sort
Speaker 2:  of consumer messaging apps that I've been thinking about a lot because it
Speaker 2:  keeps coming up in this meta trial too, where on the one hand, you
Speaker 2:  know, there's all these conversations about Instagram and whether Meta helped
Speaker 2:  or hindered Instagram. And then on the WhatsApp side it's just like, it was
Speaker 2:  just this tiny lifestyle business that had no interest in making money and
Speaker 2:  no plans to make money and was never gonna make any money. And then Meta
Speaker 2:  bought it and like supercharged it as a business, but, but like not really.
Speaker 2:  And for a long time Meta didn't make any money and they spent a ton of money
Speaker 2:  on WhatsApp and now they're just starting to, like you said, sort
Speaker 2:  of turn the screws on how to make money off of this giant platform that you
Speaker 2:  have. And it's just made me wonder like we are at a moment
Speaker 2:  right now where I think you could argue that
Speaker 2:  messaging like person to person messaging, group chats and
Speaker 2:  and texts and whatever is like the single most important thing
Speaker 2:  we do in, in our online lives right now. It is, It
Speaker 2:  is how we communicate in, in so many ways and it just
Speaker 2:  isn't a business for anybody. Like I, as far as I can tell, no one
Speaker 2:  has figured out how to directly monetize letting you and I talk to each other
Speaker 2:  on the internet. No one, you either have to subsidize it
Speaker 2:  by making me buy an iPhone and making it really hard for me to leave. You
Speaker 2:  have to find some, like you said, sort of ancillary way to
Speaker 2:  like you, you sell ads where you put your
Speaker 2:  number that I can text you, which is not the same, but, so I'm like, I've
Speaker 2:  reached a point now where it's like, is this, is there just not a business
Speaker 2:  in chat? And if that's true, is that a problem? And
Speaker 2:  it feels like downstream from this that feels like it might be because then
Speaker 2:  you look at somebody like Snap who is like, oh, what we have to do is we
Speaker 2:  have to actually just ruin the experience for you in order to make any money
Speaker 2:  off of this.
Speaker 5:  I think it's a problem for people who can't build something around it like
Speaker 5:  Snap right now you're right. Like Apple doesn't make money off iMessage,
Speaker 5:  but iMessage helps 'em sell iPhones
Speaker 5:  and Google with its many, many messaging apps I'm
Speaker 5:  sure makes money indirectly from those
Speaker 2:  Messaging apps. Maybe I don know
Speaker 5:  Maybe who knows, but they probably don't even know. But yeah, it's, I mean
Speaker 5:  do you remember when Snap was doing mini games and a little mini app store
Speaker 5:  and they were trying to be WeChat and have all these
Speaker 5:  apps and they bought like gaming studios and
Speaker 5:  you could That's right. Yeah, you could and you could transact to these mini
Speaker 5:  apps
Speaker 2:  And all that was gonna be stuff you could like invoke inside the chat, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And they shut that down too. And so they've tried,
Speaker 5:  I mean they've tried a lot of things.
Speaker 5:  I think for them they have to get the content piece down. They have, I mean
Speaker 5:  they have creators that are huge on Snap, you know, David Dorich, people
Speaker 5:  like that that have millions of followers make a lot of money, but it's
Speaker 5:  just not culturally relevant like TikTok or even reels. And
Speaker 5:  that's a problem for them. Maybe they don't see it that way, but I think
Speaker 5:  It is. And they also have this
Speaker 5:  relationship with publishers where they share ad revenue with a bunch of
Speaker 5:  publishers. Vox Media was in this at one point. I'm not sure if we still
Speaker 5:  are. And that also just feels
Speaker 5:  like that entire chess board of publishers
Speaker 5:  relationships with platforms is fraught.
Speaker 5:  So I think the real hail Mary
Speaker 5:  bet is that spectacles will work, eventually Snap
Speaker 5:  will be able to transition to what Spiegel and to his
Speaker 5:  credit, Tim Cook, Merck Zuckerberg, Senator Pacha also agree is
Speaker 5:  maybe the next platform AR glasses. Sure It
Speaker 2:  Is the bet for sure.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And that, that will be the thing that gives them
Speaker 5:  their next 10 to 20 years. Now I've written about this,
Speaker 5:  I'm very skeptical of their ability to compete. I would love to see a smaller
Speaker 5:  player, especially one like Snap that's been pretty innovative with the products.
Speaker 5:  It does stay in the space and challenge the the Giants,
Speaker 5:  but with their financial profile right now it's such a
Speaker 5:  capital intensive business to do hardware well at scale.
Speaker 5:  It's very hard. It's a very hard uphill thing. I'm like, their last spectacles
Speaker 5:  that I tried last year, you know, they're not even for sale, right? They're
Speaker 5:  just letting developers try them and you know, I think they'll do a consumer
Speaker 5:  version in maybe the next year or two, but
Speaker 5:  you know, it's gonna cost a lot. They're not gonna be able to make a ton
Speaker 5:  of them. It'll still be an early adopter thing. Meanwhile, their investors
Speaker 5:  don't really have patience for them to not be growing their ads business
Speaker 5:  the way they are. So they're still not profitable either. You know,
Speaker 5:  Snap's not made a annual profit ever. So
Speaker 5:  that's if, if they could really like change the way the company runs
Speaker 5:  and be leaner and make money and be content with being a
Speaker 5:  smaller business, even though they have a huge user base that's highly engaged,
Speaker 5:  you know, maybe they'll be able to hang in there. They also, I mean they
Speaker 5:  have the benefit, I guess you could call it a benefit or a curse of their
Speaker 5:  founder controlled, you know, like Meta, like Evan Spiegel can't be fired.
Speaker 5:  He controls the company with Bobby Murphy, the co-founder. And that's
Speaker 5:  why stuff like spectacles exists. So yeah, it's a complicated,
Speaker 5:  fascinating company. You know, when I'm out and about, I still see Snap
Speaker 5:  open on phones, you know, like on an airplane I'll still see people using
Speaker 5:  it. It's still very much like in the culture,
Speaker 5:  especially like among college students. A thing I've heard is that
Speaker 5:  as the pressure on how kids and teens
Speaker 5:  use these platforms and the a specific, you know, attacks on
Speaker 5:  Snap, the anonymity of it, the ephemerality,
Speaker 5:  which leads to things like drug dealing and like sextortion and like, there's
Speaker 5:  just inherent things in the product that can be really bad, especially for
Speaker 5:  young people with the way it's designed. They're starting to feel that a
Speaker 5:  little bit in terms of not only just the regulatory scrutiny, but like the
Speaker 5:  way that people and parents especially think about the product.
Speaker 5:  And I think that could be a huge potential problem for their
Speaker 5:  continued growth, especially with young people. They've got a lot to navigate
Speaker 5:  and they've got Meta and all these other companies also betting
Speaker 5:  and spending way more money on this new hardware platform that they're trying
Speaker 5:  to invent.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean it seems like even on the messaging side, I mean I give Snap
Speaker 2:  a lot of credit. I think it has been the most innovative
Speaker 2:  messaging app for a very long time. And in terms of like
Speaker 2:  how people talk to each other, It is, It is always been the most interesting
Speaker 2:  one, right? Everything else is, is either stealing features from Snapchat
Speaker 2:  or just less interesting, right? Like we have a million text messaging
Speaker 2:  platforms and nothing else that is even trying to do the thing that Snapchat
Speaker 2:  does really well. But I think you're right, It is, It is such a
Speaker 2:  double-edged sword. This idea that everything goes away is both very sort
Speaker 2:  of compelling in a, in a way right now in that like what we're learning is
Speaker 2:  that more things should go away on the internet, but also it comes with huge
Speaker 2:  downsides. And I think we are reckoning with that in
Speaker 2:  new ways. What is your sense of how big and maybe how
Speaker 2:  desperate a swing ads in chat is?
Speaker 5:  I think it's big. They're, they haven't fully rolled it out to my
Speaker 5:  knowledge, but they are starting to put ads in chat.
Speaker 5:  They just have to, it's just where people spend the most time in the app.
Speaker 5:  It always has been. And it, like I said, It is always driven certain
Speaker 5:  people in the company crazy that they're not able to monetize that engagement,
Speaker 5:  right. And that's why they did stuff like Discover and Spotlight and all
Speaker 5:  these other things and AR is like, maybe we can find a way to monetize through
Speaker 5:  that. So they have to do it. I think
Speaker 5:  they, they, they don't want to tank engagement though at the same time.
Speaker 5:  Like they found that they did with the redesign last year that they're rolling
Speaker 5:  back.
Speaker 2:  It is an interesting test. I mean you think about, we talk a lot about how
Speaker 2:  sticky messaging is and it's one of those things like if you can, if you
Speaker 2:  can build this sort of network of people talking to each other, people will
Speaker 2:  stay on like almost anything else. But I also feel like the minute you put
Speaker 2:  a pre-roll ad on me opening my group chat, I'm
Speaker 2:  out. Right? Like that's, that's, there are very few things that are gonna
Speaker 2:  unstick you like that. And So I think I'm,
Speaker 2:  again, Snapchat is a, a, an app that has really interesting and
Speaker 2:  in many ways ahead of its time design ideas. And So I think this question
Speaker 2:  of like, what, what are ads supposed to look like in chat?
Speaker 2:  I just don't know because I'm like a banner ad in between
Speaker 2:  every four messages again, I'm out. Like, I just, I don't know, I don't
Speaker 2:  even know how to imagine what a successful version of this looks like,
Speaker 2:  but I also understand why at some point Snap and
Speaker 2:  everybody else is gonna have to figure out what it looks like.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I I think they have to, you know, this conversation has me
Speaker 5:  reminiscing about, you know, 10 years ago, like using Snap with
Speaker 5:  my wife, who's my girlfriend at the time, and like how we would just like
Speaker 5:  share things throughout the day with each other in a way that was very like
Speaker 5:  fluid and like goofy and like just a simple photo of something or
Speaker 5:  like, yeah, you felt more connected to people through that visual messaging
Speaker 5:  thing. And there's no product that really has captured that since then.
Speaker 2:  No, nothing.
Speaker 5:  And network effects are real. And when you, you know, this happens,
Speaker 5:  I bet a lot of people listening to this can relate. You get older, you leave
Speaker 5:  college, you and people are using iMessage instead or they're using WhatsApp
Speaker 5:  or like Signal or, and your network's fracture
Speaker 5:  and SNAP is just not a place where I have
Speaker 5:  my friends anymore. Yeah. And I kind of miss that. Like, I miss, I miss those
Speaker 5:  early days of it where you felt like you could be yourself and you could
Speaker 5:  share just more frequently because it felt casual and
Speaker 5:  depressurized in a way that Instagram definitely does not,
Speaker 5:  or you know, some of these other services and yeah, them
Speaker 5:  putting ads in that experience feels just like it inherently screws it
Speaker 5:  up. So yeah, it's gonna be a, a tricky balance for
Speaker 5:  them.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's a tough one in the way that like, I think one of the reasons you
Speaker 2:  do something like Discover is that actually it's really obvious how
Speaker 2:  to do the ads there, right? It's like that's a thing we know how to do and
Speaker 2:  it works and people are used to it and it's you, you can understand why all
Speaker 2:  of that works. And even ads in stories and stuff like that, like that stuff
Speaker 2:  feels natural in a way that there just is no version of that
Speaker 2:  in in human to human chat that I think is ever gonna
Speaker 2:  feel good to people. To your point about the, the
Speaker 2:  growing the user base outside of kind of the core Snapchat people,
Speaker 2:  what's your sense of how much they even care about that anymore? I mean,
Speaker 2:  like you said, the user base is enormous. I, I am, I don't know a single
Speaker 2:  person my age who uses Snapchat, but maybe it doesn't matter, like maybe
Speaker 2:  I'm old and lame now.
Speaker 5:  No, it matters. It matters. If you're running an ADS business it matters
Speaker 5:  because teenagers can't buy a lot of stuff. So
Speaker 2:  Fair. Which has always been a Snapchat problem.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You really need people in their thirties and forties, fifties even
Speaker 5:  where, where a lot of the growth is happening is outside of the US and
Speaker 5:  even Europe. Their users actually slightly declined in
Speaker 5:  North America last quarter, which is a bad sign.
Speaker 5:  You really have to be strong and growing in North America as one of these
Speaker 5:  social networks that's ad supported for investors to believe in you
Speaker 5:  for your stock price to continue to grow. Which the reason I
Speaker 5:  focus on that is like the stock price is a trickle down of a lot of things
Speaker 5:  that lets you hire better people. It gives you stability to make
Speaker 5:  more strategic long-term decisions that cost you in the short term
Speaker 5:  what we just talked about with the redesign. So it matters. And
Speaker 5:  I think they're struggling to break out of that college team
Speaker 5:  market and they always have. But
Speaker 5:  yeah, I mean maybe the ship has sailed. You know, I've been, when you
Speaker 5:  cover social media long enough, you just realize like network effects are
Speaker 5:  all that matters. Once something tips in one direction, it's really
Speaker 5:  hard, if not impossible to tip it the other way. And once
Speaker 5:  all of your friends have decided that they use other apps to talk to you,
Speaker 5:  how do you get them back on Snap? If I had to guess, there's
Speaker 5:  millions and millions of people just in the US that they
Speaker 5:  would love to, you know, quote unquote resurrect, like bring back to the
Speaker 5:  app. Yeah. And how do you do that? Like what is the, it used to be like
Speaker 5:  viral AR filters, you know, that would turn you into a baby or
Speaker 5:  something like that, right? And now it's like, that's Chad GBT. It's like
Speaker 5:  people doing that with AI and it's like Snap did that eight years ago
Speaker 5:  and it, and it gave them these super viral moments where people came to the
Speaker 5:  app and they just haven't had moments like that anymore. And so the thing
Speaker 5:  that I watch was Snap is like, is the product
Speaker 5:  innovation still there? Are they still shipping things regularly that
Speaker 5:  kind of wow the industry and that pace has definitely slowed as they're
Speaker 5:  trying to fix the business. And so, you know, the thing that
Speaker 5:  may hurt them is like focusing too much on the business. They have to save
Speaker 5:  in spite of the product that they have to keep relevant.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Yeah. It's, I mean it's kind of a vicious cycle at some point, right?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. You, you can't take the big swings without the money to take the big
Speaker 2:  swings, but without big swings you don't get the money to take the big swings.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, we should give them credit for this scale they've hit it's, yeah, it's
Speaker 5:  still is next to impossible. You know, I remember I was in DC when
Speaker 5:  Zuckerberg was on the stand for the meta FTC trial and he was talking about
Speaker 5:  how to his knowledge, no independent company has hit a billion users.
Speaker 5:  They all either get bought by a bigger conglomerate
Speaker 5:  or you know, taken out and Snap is about to hit a billion users.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And that's a very hard thing to do.
Speaker 2:  I mean that, that's why I'm so interested in this company, right? Like yeah,
Speaker 2:  I cannot stop rooting for Snapchat like sort of against
Speaker 2:  all reality and evidence. I
Speaker 2:  think Snapchat is doing a lot of smart good correct
Speaker 2:  things and it's just like the, the fact that it just,
Speaker 2:  if it could solve the ad business that would open up everything
Speaker 2:  else it wants to do is such a frustrating reality to me
Speaker 2:  that It is like what, what this company is not short of is good product
Speaker 2:  that people like, right? Like It is, It is actually over and over able to
Speaker 2:  make good products that people like It just can't make enough money for any
Speaker 2:  of that to matter. I mean, and I even think about like the pixie drone
Speaker 2:  was cool. Yeah. And interesting and exciting and there just wasn't, that's
Speaker 2:  not the kind of thing you can do when you don't have an ad business, right?
Speaker 2:  It's the kind of thing you can do when you're Mark Zuckerberg and you have
Speaker 2:  just a money fountain coming outta Facebook all the time. Snap just can't,
Speaker 2:  literally can't afford to do that. And it's so frustrating because there
Speaker 2:  is such good product in that company and there always has been
Speaker 2:  and It is just like the reality of being a company in the world has
Speaker 2:  prevented Snapchat from I think being what it actually could have been,
Speaker 5:  Man, RIP Pixie. That one lasted less than a year. I think
Speaker 2:  I know one of the cooler videos you've made, I think. Yeah. Going through
Speaker 2:  like a warehouse. Yeah, like an arcade looking thing. That
Speaker 5:  Was good stuff. That was a fun one. Yeah, there's so many things in the last
Speaker 5:  few years that Snap has announced and then killed. Within a year they were
Speaker 5:  gonna do this huge shopping play where they, they were gonna literally put
Speaker 5:  like big vending machines with AR displays on them in
Speaker 5:  stores. I, I remember doing this at their event a couple years ago
Speaker 5:  and it was gonna like let their ads be more targeted. They were gonna hook
Speaker 5:  into all these retailers and do ar try-on stuff and like reduce
Speaker 5:  the amount of trade-ins that stores need to do with physical goods. Like
Speaker 5:  you could just wear the stuff on you really cool, innovative, kind of weird
Speaker 5:  wacky idea. Killed it within a year because they had to focus on
Speaker 5:  getting the business turned around, right? And that back and
Speaker 5:  forth that we've been talking about where they try a thing and then they
Speaker 5:  realized they can't do it either because it doesn't work or it's hurting
Speaker 5:  the business. They gotta focus on the business has just been a pattern for
Speaker 5:  the last like five years and are for them to really
Speaker 5:  come through this, they've gotta get outta that cycle. And I'm not sure how
Speaker 5:  they do,
Speaker 2:  Should Evan have just taken the 6 billion from Mark Zuckerberg all those
Speaker 2:  years ago?
Speaker 5:  I don't know. I mean if it was mostly Facebook stock, which I
Speaker 5:  think a good healthy chunk of it was, yeah, everyone at Snap
Speaker 5:  would be a lot richer right now. Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I mean 10 years ago everyone should have taken the deal if it included
Speaker 2:  Facebook
Speaker 5:  Stock Snap has had so many offers, you know Google Yeah. Many
Speaker 5:  times Facebook again before they went public, other
Speaker 5:  companies and other parts of the world. It's a very valuable asset. Like
Speaker 5:  I said, there's very few scaled social networks to get to a billion users
Speaker 5:  that have this kind of engagement. It's just can this
Speaker 5:  team that's running it make it a huge business?
Speaker 5:  And so far the answer is no.
Speaker 2:  Right? It does make you wonder, I mean again, back to the like, can you make
Speaker 2:  a messaging business a business? You, you wonder at some
Speaker 2:  point if this is just a like structural mismatch if like the thing that is
Speaker 2:  great about Snapchat is never going to be its business.
Speaker 2:  And that is a really hard problem to solve because it then
Speaker 2:  means you have to go do another thing really well. Yeah. And very few
Speaker 2:  companies have actually successfully done that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, we'll see, I mean, spectacles is the bet. That's like the big bet
Speaker 5:  outside of Snapchat. It's gonna take a long time. And I feel like I was
Speaker 5:  saying that 10 years ago, so this has been like the story of air
Speaker 5:  glasses is
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's do a question from The Vergecast hotline. As
Speaker 2:  always, you can call 8 6 6 VERGE one one. You can email Vergecast at The
Speaker 2:  Verge dot com. Send us all of your thoughts and feelings and questions about
Speaker 2:  everything. Recently, it seems a lot of you have questions about places you've
Speaker 2:  found ants, which I find extremely delightful. But also you continue to have
Speaker 2:  questions about the Google trial and in particular for now, let
Speaker 2:  me just play you one of the questions I've actually gotten a few versions
Speaker 2:  of over the last couple of weeks and see if I can answer it here. It's,
Speaker 6:  Hey David, my name is Rag and I had a thought about
Speaker 6:  the code rolling and the ongoing
Speaker 6:  remedies trial for Google and Google Chrome and the talk about
Speaker 6:  splitting it off into or like having it sold to a separate company.
Speaker 6:  But I haven't seen in any of the discussions so far folks
Speaker 6:  considering that why won't Google just turn down the project
Speaker 6:  altogether? Why would they have to consider selling it? Like sure they could
Speaker 6:  make some billions of dollars by selling it,
Speaker 6:  but they probably stand to lose more, especially if they're selling it to
Speaker 6:  OpenAI. The value gain that OpenAI can have over the
Speaker 6:  long term and like the immediate market share that they would have, the six,
Speaker 6:  the whatever browser market share that Chrome has. It seems
Speaker 6:  like unless this number is extremely high,
Speaker 6:  which I'm sure the DOJ will not let it be, then
Speaker 6:  why Google should even consider selling it and instead just be like, well,
Speaker 6:  chromium can go open source, we will not contribute to it anymore
Speaker 6:  and Chrome as a project will just turn it down and we'll,
Speaker 6:  you know, consider some open source project as like the default browser and
Speaker 6:  Android going forward. Yeah, I'm just curious about your thoughts and
Speaker 6:  why do you think that this is a bad idea or a good idea? And if Google
Speaker 6:  should or Google will actually consider doing this. Thank you.
Speaker 2:  Okay, So I think the thing about this question is
Speaker 2:  it speaks to all of what's happening in this trial in a way that I actually
Speaker 2:  find really fascinating. I, I asked a bunch of people this question like
Speaker 2:  isn't the better idea if you want to take away Google's dominance to just
Speaker 2:  shut Chrome down altogether, right? Just remove the project open, source
Speaker 2:  it something, right? Like just take it away from Google, it doesn't
Speaker 2:  matter who gets it. You don't even necessarily want to sort of King make
Speaker 2:  some other company just make Google, get rid of something, push
Speaker 2:  the project away, make it nobody's. I think what I've
Speaker 2:  come to realize is that's actually not the goal from the DOJ
Speaker 2:  in this case. So if you look at it there, there's sort of two things going
Speaker 2:  on, right? What they wanna do is they wanna undo some of Google's
Speaker 2:  dominance. You have this company that has built this whole system by
Speaker 2:  which it remains the biggest and most important thing in search, has all
Speaker 2:  the market share, and you wanna sort of systematically stop that from
Speaker 2:  happening, right? But the way that the DOJ
Speaker 2:  frames it, it's not just enough to sort of level the playing field
Speaker 2:  starting now, if you say, okay, beginning today,
Speaker 2:  may of 2025 or whenever this trial actually ends,
Speaker 2:  we are all playing by the same rules. Google has
Speaker 2:  this gigantic, essentially insurmountable lead. And even if you take away
Speaker 2:  Chrome, all you're doing is taking Google's lead and
Speaker 2:  moving it around, right? Like what the DOJ wants
Speaker 2:  is to engineer a fairer fight. And that means not
Speaker 2:  just slowing Google down but actually speeding others up.
Speaker 2:  And this is one of the things about this trial that I have found really complicated.
Speaker 2:  So if you take something like Chrome and you say, okay, what we need is we,
Speaker 2:  we wanna give this to somebody in order to make them a viable
Speaker 2:  competitor. This is what Google is facing with a lot of its search stuff,
Speaker 2:  by the way, the do j's big plan to essentially white label Google search
Speaker 2:  and force Google to give away all of the data and all
Speaker 2:  of the search results and all of the query information that it gets from
Speaker 2:  its search engine in order to let others make better search engines.
Speaker 2:  It's the same idea here, right? It's not just you can't do X,
Speaker 2:  Y, and Z anymore. It's you Google have to do the work to bring a
Speaker 2:  competitor or several competitors or hundreds of competitors up to your level.
Speaker 2:  That's what the DOJ wants. And when it comes to Chrome, you have this thing
Speaker 2:  that could just be put into an open
Speaker 2:  source world and everybody could maintain it. But I have to say
Speaker 2:  Google's argument has been that actually building a browser is hugely
Speaker 2:  expensive and hugely complicated. And Chrome is only as good as It is because
Speaker 2:  Google has been the only company willing to invest this much time
Speaker 2:  and this many resources into it. I find that very compelling and I think
Speaker 2:  the judge does too. And so the idea that you would just
Speaker 2:  release it to everybody and Chrome would continue to be great, I think is
Speaker 2:  just wrong. And so you end up in a position where you're saying, okay,
Speaker 2:  we're either going to kill Chrome entirely for everybody,
Speaker 2:  which I don't think is actually plausible or even maybe possible
Speaker 2:  given what Chrome is and where It is, you'd essentially just like blow
Speaker 2:  up half of people's devices. Nobody I think wants that. So
Speaker 2:  then you have to say, we have to put this in someone's hands who
Speaker 2:  also has the resources and incentives and finances to take care of this.
Speaker 2:  There aren't that many companies that can do that. There are a bunch of companies
Speaker 2:  out there that would very much like to buy Chrome. Perplexity has said
Speaker 2:  it once, it, Yahoo said it once, it open AI said it once it, I mean
Speaker 2:  anybody with the resources would happily buy Chrome. It's one of the most
Speaker 2:  popular and important things on the internet. I've heard from a lot of companies
Speaker 2:  who are like, you don't understand having this kind of browser data is
Speaker 2:  hugely important to almost any business on the internet. If I know what
Speaker 2:  4 billion people are doing online, I can figure out how to make money off
Speaker 2:  of that. It's just that it's gonna be really expensive to buy Chrome. So
Speaker 2:  there aren't that many companies that can actually afford the thing. And
Speaker 2:  doing that is going to be challenging. So the
Speaker 2:  flip side though is that whoever does get it immediately becomes
Speaker 2:  enormously powerful, right? It, it's like if you just let someone buy
Speaker 2:  Instagram, hugely powerful because now you own Instagram. It's not,
Speaker 2:  it's not like you're, you're bringing somebody up. You've given somebody
Speaker 2:  the most powerful version of this product
Speaker 2:  on the market. And so far it seems like the company that makes the most
Speaker 2:  sense would be OpenAI. It has the resources, it has the ability
Speaker 2:  to raise infinite money in order to be able to do stuff like this. It has
Speaker 2:  a real incentive to have a browser, to have all this data to be able to put
Speaker 2:  chat two PT more directly in front of you all the time. It is the one
Speaker 2:  closest to the same set of incentives and resources that Google has. But
Speaker 2:  then if you give open AI Chrome or even let
Speaker 2:  open AI buy Chrome, I think all the money is sort of immaterial. It's just
Speaker 2:  money.
Speaker 2:  Now, open AI is vastly powerful and It is in a position of
Speaker 2:  huge authority over a lot of what we do online too. And the question I
Speaker 2:  think in front of the judge in this case is, is it better
Speaker 2:  to have two sort of giant
Speaker 2:  superpowers of the web than one? And the problem is that
Speaker 2:  we've had one, and it's been Google, but does two solve the problem
Speaker 2:  is, is Google and AI enough competition that it's
Speaker 2:  okay that we have two companies that are, you know, a thousand miles ahead
Speaker 2:  of everybody else in the race? Or is the goal to have
Speaker 2:  dozens, hundreds, thousands of other companies that can do the kind of stuff
Speaker 2:  that these companies are doing too. And if that's the goal,
Speaker 2:  I don't think you can allow Google to sell Chrome to open ai.
Speaker 2:  I don't even know who you have to allow Google to sell Chrome two,
Speaker 2:  if what you're trying to do is raise a whole industry chromium, the,
Speaker 2:  the open source browser stack underneath a lot of this is very
Speaker 2:  important and is one of the things that lets a lot of people roll other browsers.
Speaker 2:  But Chrome won like in, in every meaningful way Chrome won the browser
Speaker 2:  wars and everybody else is just kind of nibbling around the edges. So the
Speaker 2:  question in front of the court in this particular case is, do we want to
Speaker 2:  King make one other company in order to make them
Speaker 2:  as powerful as Google, or at least close to it in the way that the internet
Speaker 2:  works? And is that competition, like, does that count? Did we do
Speaker 2:  the job or is there some other remedy that we're gonna have to figure out
Speaker 2:  here? And I think that's why the DOJ is pursuing this
Speaker 2:  idea of both kind of making Google White label all of
Speaker 2:  its search stuff such that any other search engine can get it, but also
Speaker 2:  take away Chrome and give it to somebody else. And So I think where we might
Speaker 2:  land is instead of one giant, we have two, whether it's OpenAI or somebody
Speaker 2:  else. And then the hope is if you can also have
Speaker 2:  dozens or hundreds or whatever of other Google quality
Speaker 2:  search engines, that that market becomes the solvable
Speaker 2:  thing. I don't know if that's the right answer, but I do think that's why
Speaker 2:  Google isn't going to be allowed to just get rid of Chrome.
Speaker 2:  There are a bunch of business reasons Google wouldn't do it, right? Like,
Speaker 2:  it, it, it makes a certain kind of like logical sense to say Google
Speaker 2:  would rather just shut the whole thing down. But if you offer the company
Speaker 2:  the chance to have, you know, tens of billions of dollars or nothing,
Speaker 2:  they're pretty much always gonna choose the tens of billions of dollars.
Speaker 2:  And Google wants Chrome. Google wants
Speaker 2:  this thing to continue to work, so It is going to hold onto it for dear life.
Speaker 2:  And I think the idea that it would just sort of voluntarily shut it down,
Speaker 2:  it, it makes a certain kind of abstract sense, but I don't think it's realistic
Speaker 2:  for Google. And it's also not what the DOJ wants because if it goes away,
Speaker 2:  all it does is make Google the same kind of powerful, but in sort
Speaker 2:  of a different direction. I hope that makes sense. I think it's a really
Speaker 2:  interesting question and there's a lot of this left to litigate. There's
Speaker 2:  a lot of decisions for Judge Meta left to make about what competition looks
Speaker 2:  like and what it means to bring Google down versus bring others up
Speaker 2:  and what sort of middle point there
Speaker 2:  counts as success. There's a bunch left of this trial. We have closing arguments,
Speaker 2:  we have the, the decision. We're months away. There's gonna be appeals.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's gonna be a while before we start this out, but I think we're,
Speaker 2:  we're starting to see what it might look like and I find it totally fascinating.
Speaker 2:  All right, that is it for the first cast today. Thank you to everybody who
Speaker 2:  came on the show and thank you as always for listening. Like I mentioned,
Speaker 2:  if