# Transcript
ID: 9e8328b3-e1a5-47cd-bd97-a7b686b55cdd
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-8621159635500505288/-8742694857511658866/s93290-US-7310s-1743155668.mp3
Description: In this episode, we do a Studio Ghibli-like rendition of The Vergecast. First, Nilay and David discuss some big news in the gadget world, from the mysteriously viral midrange Canon camera to the upgrades we're expecting out of Apple in the next few months. Plus, is it over for Amazon's Echo brand? After all that, The Verge's Kylie Robison joins the show to discuss everything happening at OpenAI: the company launched a new image generator inside of ChatGPT, and it immediately became both a huge hit and a big mess. (Par for the course with OpenAI, really.) Kylie also explains why Perplexity is probably not buying TikTok, no matter how much it might want to. Finally, in the lightning round, it's time for everyone's favorite segment, Brendan Carr Is a Dummy, followed by the latest on the Signal attack-planning chaos in the government, some news about Elon Musk pressuring Reddit CEO Steve Huffmann, and what's next for the car industry with huge tariffs looming. Oh, and a little bit of exciting e-bike news
Speaker 1:  Now
Speaker 6:  Hello and welcome to Red Chest, the flagship podcast with viral cameras from
Speaker 6:  five years ago.
Speaker 7:  This has all made me feel really good because I have a, the only camera I
Speaker 7:  have is from like 2012. It's a, it's a Sony a
Speaker 7:  6,000 and it sucks. And I'm like, give it, give it 18 more months. And this
Speaker 7:  is gonna be the camera everybody wants.
Speaker 6:  I'm your friend Neli David Pierce is here. First of all, I wanna point out
Speaker 6:  that everyone thought I was gonna make a joke about Signal, right? You all,
Speaker 6:  you all thought it. I said the flagship podcast of, and you all thought
Speaker 6:  of something, right? Adding somebody to a group chat, you all thought it
Speaker 6:  and I went another way and I just wanna take the credit for that.
Speaker 6:  We're gonna talk about Signal later in the show. Do you have
Speaker 7:  Any good, I've been added to a group chat
Speaker 6:  Stories. I have a good, I didn't know
Speaker 6:  how deleting a message worked. So like
Speaker 6:  I, this is a long time ago, actually. This is a really good story. Okay.
Speaker 6:  A long time ago, the night before Uber
Speaker 6:  fired Travis Kanick from this, from being the CEO, do you remember this?
Speaker 6:  It is like a big deal. Yeah, sure. Everyone heard about it? I can't, I
Speaker 6:  got a message from, let's just say a
Speaker 6:  dancer
Speaker 6:  and the dancer said, there's a VC crying in my lap
Speaker 6:  right now because they're gonna fire Travis Knick. Whoa. And I
Speaker 6:  had, what am I gonna do with this? Like, right. I'm like,
Speaker 6:  this is weird. I dunno. Like, can you take a picture? Like this is a
Speaker 6:  true story. A hundred percent true story. And so I went to Slack or transportation
Speaker 6:  editor Andy Hawkins being like, I think dudes, I think it's gonna happen.
Speaker 6:  Like here's we all, this noise is happening. And I just got this insane message.
Speaker 6:  And in the middle of that, I accidentally texted her what I meant to text
Speaker 6:  Andy. And I went to delete it. And it doesn't, it didn't delete right?
Speaker 6:  Because it works. It's like locally, so you can hide your cheating from like
Speaker 6:  your wife. But the person who got the message to has it,
Speaker 6:  I thought I was being so smart. I was like, oh, I deleted it. And later,
Speaker 6:  like she, the, the person was like, did you,
Speaker 6:  please don't, please don't mention my name. And this why i's like, I don't
Speaker 6:  have the story. That's, we don't know. It's true. This all It is all years
Speaker 6:  later, we, we did not have the story at a single source the next morning.
Speaker 6:  It turned out to be true. But you know, we have standards here,
Speaker 6:  right? We, we need multiple sources to run a story of, of that nature. And
Speaker 6:  so we could, I, so I knew it and the next morning I was like, God damnit,
Speaker 7:  Does our ethics policy cover how many dancers have to
Speaker 7:  corroborate the VC crying in their lap before it's portable
Speaker 6:  Journalism? This was also, this was happening like at
Speaker 6:  7:00 PM East Coast time, right? So it was like,
Speaker 6:  I had to, I had to call like everyone was home. So they'd be like,
Speaker 6:  I need you to walk away from your children. I need you to tell you a story
Speaker 6:  about a t. He was like, what are you talking about? So he
Speaker 6:  changed it for a while and then the next morning it happened and I was like,
Speaker 6:  I should have done something that I couldn't figure out what to do. That's
Speaker 6:  my, that's my texting fail story. What's yours? Good stuff.
Speaker 7:  I like that. I don't really have a good one, to be honest. I have, I've had
Speaker 7:  a lot of very near misses. Most of mine are actually more
Speaker 7:  dangerous in Slack than in messages where
Speaker 7:  in Slack everything looks the same. And I have sent, I have almost sent
Speaker 7:  like truly alarming things to the person
Speaker 7:  I was talking shit about.
Speaker 7:  And I don't think I have ever actually done it. And it's a real like there,
Speaker 7:  but for the grace of God kind of situation, watching all of this unfold.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Like It is, It, is it out of the realm of possibility that I have
Speaker 7:  accidentally invited the editor in chief of the Atlantic to a group chat?
Speaker 7:  It's not, but luckily I never have. As far as,
Speaker 6:  The thing that gets me the most often is clipboard fails
Speaker 6:  where I hit, I paced and I hit return. Like before I
Speaker 6:  verify that I've pasted the thing I wanna paste. Yep. And that happens to
Speaker 6:  me all the time. Like just random sentences from old documents just show
Speaker 6:  up. Like
Speaker 7:  That's right for me always. It's always a really, it's always a link. I didn't
Speaker 7:  mean to post. Yeah. Like I, I copied the, the wrong tab out of Chrome
Speaker 7:  instead of the right one. And so I'm like, Hey, here's a cool thing
Speaker 7:  we should do. And then it's just like a, a weird like cheat code for a video
Speaker 7:  game that I should not be thinking about at work. It's good times.
Speaker 6:  This happens to me all the time with TikTok, which is my segue. Ooh,
Speaker 7:  Okay.
Speaker 6:  Right. Because I'm always like, I wanna share TikTok, but I always have to
Speaker 6:  double check. It's not a totally bananas TikTok.
Speaker 7:  Right? There's a real, like you have to watch the whole thing through just
Speaker 7:  in case. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Is this creator secretly like a milkshake duck situation? It's like a real
Speaker 6:  thing. So here's the mystery I wanna start with, which explains the joke
Speaker 6:  at the top of the show. My TikTok feed for the past three days
Speaker 6:  has just been people talking about the Canon G seven X mark
Speaker 6:  three. And this to me, this is a gadget mystery.
Speaker 6:  So the Canon G seven X mark three is a camera from 2019.
Speaker 6:  It's just old. It is an old camera.
Speaker 7:  Oh, I remember this camera.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's just, it's a G seven X. Like it, you know, there's the RX 100,
Speaker 6:  which I talk about on the show all the time. 'cause I have one and it's competitors,
Speaker 6:  sort of the G seven X, but like, they're different. I dunno it whatever pop,
Speaker 6:  it's got
Speaker 7:  Aon pop. It's fun. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  This thing is apparently mega popular with influencers and people wanna take
Speaker 6:  be better pictures. They're all taking flash photos with it,
Speaker 6:  which is bonkers. But they're, that's what they're doing. And
Speaker 6:  It is selling out every day. Like I have gotten
Speaker 6:  TikTok videos from people who are like, here's how to get a G seven X mark
Speaker 6:  three, or even a mark two, which is even older. And the answer is like,
Speaker 6:  wait up until 5:00 AM until Target restocks, its online like a
Speaker 6:  PS five drop.
Speaker 7:  Wow.
Speaker 6:  So we've assigned the story, the virtue. I think it's Alison Johnson's like
Speaker 6:  working on what, where, what's happening here. Like why,
Speaker 6:  why is the G seven X mark three A camera again from 2019?
Speaker 6:  Why is it going viral and why isn't Canon making enough of them?
Speaker 7:  The second question I think is super fascinating. The, the macro
Speaker 7:  mystery of this is, is pretty straightforward, right? This, this like
Speaker 7:  resurgence in digital cameras and point and shoots in particular
Speaker 7:  is a thing, right? We're in this very like, turn of the century
Speaker 7:  nostalgia moment in so much of culture and like
Speaker 7:  crappy pre-Instagram photos are like
Speaker 7:  the thing everybody wants, which is very funny because they're bad. But that
Speaker 7:  is like, there's something in that look that a lot of people are after. And
Speaker 7:  so we, we've talked about this before with like there, there was a run on
Speaker 7:  like the Nikon Cool picks from 2004 Yeah. For a long time. But
Speaker 7:  it's very weird that it's this particular camera.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The Nikon cool picks is like very cheap, right? This is an
Speaker 6:  $800 camera normally, right? And right now the
Speaker 6:  secondary market or the demand for It is so high that
Speaker 6:  on Amazon it's like over a thousand dollars. Well
Speaker 7:  That's the thing. It's weird that it's like this, this would actually make
Speaker 7:  more sense to me if this camera was from 2009 than from
Speaker 7:  2019. Do you know what I mean? Like, it's, it's, it doesn't satisfy
Speaker 7:  the, this is a sort of pre-internet digital camera. And that's fun
Speaker 7:  to play with, with my high school friends. It's also too expensive
Speaker 7:  to, and like for $1,500 you can buy a way better camera than the G seven
Speaker 7:  X. Like, do not let TikTok lie to you. You can do much, much
Speaker 7:  better than a G seven X mark three. So It is, it's very strange to me that
Speaker 7:  It is this camera in particular that people are obsessed with.
Speaker 6:  It is a phenomenon.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Oh, it really is.
Speaker 6:  We looked at an unboxing TikTok that has almost a million likes Oh
Speaker 6:  my gosh. Of a 5-year-old camera. And this unboxing was just recently posted.
Speaker 6:  So I don't know what's going on if you know what's going on. This is a gadget
Speaker 6:  mystery. Like I said, we're reporting on it. We're gonna, you know, talk
Speaker 6:  to people who are using it and figure out if Target is actually restocking
Speaker 6:  like six G, seven x mark threes at 5:00 AM every morning, which would be
Speaker 6:  just deeply hilarious. So we're, we're poking at it. If you know anything
Speaker 6:  or you have one or you're, you know, just
Speaker 6:  like foaming at the mouth trying to get a 5-year-old camera, like let us
Speaker 6:  know. Hit up the, hit up the hotline, send us an email. Like I'm,
Speaker 6:  I'm sort of very curious about it. 'cause it, you are right. Sometimes old
Speaker 6:  gadgets come back and certainly cameras go through these waves,
Speaker 6:  right? Like X one hundreds. This is a thing like Right.
Speaker 6:  It's hard to get them, but those are kind of bleeding edge. They're hard
Speaker 6:  to manufacture. This is a five-year-old camera that Canon should just be
Speaker 6:  able to fart out at will.
Speaker 7:  And if memory serves, this was not like a set the world
Speaker 7:  on fire kind of camera. Like the, that not 100 makes sense to me. Right.
Speaker 7:  That is like an unusual camera with a particular style that people really
Speaker 7:  gravitate to. Like that I fully understand. Even like the RX 100 was like
Speaker 7:  the first of this kind of thing. And so it got a lot of shine for it. And
Speaker 7:  they've had got what, seven or eight revs of that thing since like, I
Speaker 6:  Honestly think, I think one of the answers why the canon is succeeding right
Speaker 6:  now is it's impossible to understand which RX 100 to buy.
Speaker 6:  They sell all of them at once and then the zv ones also exist right next
Speaker 6:  to them, which are the same camera in a shittier case for cheaper with better
Speaker 6:  video features. And none of that makes sense to anyone. And the only difference
Speaker 6:  is between like the four and the five and the six and the seven
Speaker 6:  is like focal lengths of lenses. And so like
Speaker 6:  I, any normal person just like looks at the available set of RX one hundreds
Speaker 6:  and is like, nope. And then someone's like, have you thought about the G
Speaker 6:  seven X mark three? And it's like right there.
Speaker 7:  You're like, thank God I'll have it. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like this, this is way simpler than whatever. So did. Yeah. Anyway, it's
Speaker 6:  a mystery. It, I will, I drove our team crazy with
Speaker 6:  this mystery this week because I was like, why is this camera going viral?
Speaker 6:  And they were, I've already had all these reactions. Well, we're gonna do
Speaker 6:  it. We're gonna do, we're gonna figure out this story, let us know. I'm,
Speaker 6:  it's, it's like a culture story. It's not
Speaker 7:  A tech story. Yeah. So there is, I should just say before we move on that
Speaker 7:  like, there's a, there's a sort of truism in journalism that like news
Speaker 7:  is whatever your editor cares about that day, there's a real thing
Speaker 7:  that happens in our Slack in particular where Neli will just parachute in
Speaker 7:  after hanging out on TikTok for an hour and be like, the kids are into this.
Speaker 7:  What's that about? And it, it brings up some of my
Speaker 7:  very favorite stories that we do.
Speaker 6:  As you can imagine, my TikTok for you algorithm is ludicrous.
Speaker 6:  It's like trucks jumping over stuff. We're doing a story on like AI
Speaker 6:  image enhancers. So now it's just weird AI porn that makes me feel bad
Speaker 6:  about myself. Like literally like we've done
Speaker 6:  searches for some of these tools that are available and
Speaker 6:  I'm just sending some of the worst shit in the world to these songs. So
Speaker 6:  that's really bad. And then it's like, ca like 5-year-old cameras that have
Speaker 6:  gone viral. I need to reset my a maybe they're gonna ban it in time
Speaker 6:  for me to regain some semblance of
Speaker 7:  Identity. Yeah. What you need is for it to go dark, new algorithm,
Speaker 7:  new neli, just start it all over.
Speaker 6:  I wanna be a different person. I just, I'd like to get back to Trump's jumping
Speaker 6:  over stuff. Please. That feels good. It's gone. All right. There's actual
Speaker 6:  gadget news this week, not just 5-year-old mysteries. What's sort with
Speaker 6:  Facebook, which is also in an identity crisis.
Speaker 6:  Have I told you my, my deepest theory of meta as a company
Speaker 6:  right now? No. Which is Mark Zuckerberg just desperately wants
Speaker 6:  to beat Elon Musk.
Speaker 7:  Oh, interesting.
Speaker 6:  Right? Like Elon has everything Mark wants, like he's got the president,
Speaker 6:  he gets to say stuff whenever he wants
Speaker 6:  and people are scared of him. He's got fans, like
Speaker 6:  actual fans. He's the rockets and cars guy, whether you like the rockets
Speaker 6:  and cars or not. Like some people perceive him to be deeply evil and some
Speaker 6:  people perceive him to be ruling the world. And Mark Zuckerberg just has
Speaker 6:  like a gold chain and mostly people yelling at him.
Speaker 6:  And I don't think he has the other set of things.
Speaker 7:  That's interesting. And he is, I mean, it, it's a, it's a funny segue into
Speaker 7:  Facebook because like going all the way back to the beginning of Facebook,
Speaker 7:  mark Zuckerberg has always been like big and powerful, but never cool. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Like even when Facebook ruled the world, Twitter was cooler. It was
Speaker 7:  like culturally central in a way that Facebook never was.
Speaker 6:  Twitter was cooler, Instagram was cool, but Instagram had distance.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And I weirdly, I don't think people associate Mark with
Speaker 7:  Instagram the same way. Like, do you remember I, this was years
Speaker 7:  ago at this point, so I'm sure it's different now, but there was a pretty
Speaker 7:  strong subset of people in a study that they did that had no idea that Facebook
Speaker 7:  owned Instagram.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah, we did that. We did that. That was us.
Speaker 7:  Oh, that was us. There you go.
Speaker 6:  Cool. Ages ago. It's a good study.
Speaker 7:  Love that. Yeah. But that is like, I don't think, I don't think he got the
Speaker 7:  shine from Instagram in the way that he would've wanted to.
Speaker 7:  And so, and there was a minute where he was like, he thought Threads was
Speaker 7:  gonna make him really shiny. And then he was like, I'm gonna be a personality.
Speaker 7:  And then Elon Musk just ate all of that airspace completely out away
Speaker 7:  from him. That's a good theory. I feel like if I mark, I want
Speaker 7:  that less and less every single day, but I don't know.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The baggage of that is enormous, right? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But you kind of look at a bunch of these moves. We, we'll talk
Speaker 6:  about the, what they're doing with Facebook, the Blue app proper, but you're
Speaker 6:  like, oh man, A lot of this is like positioning him as an inventor or like
Speaker 6:  the product person, not the guy who just steals all the ideas from Snapchat.
Speaker 6:  All right, what are they doing with Facebook?
Speaker 7:  So it was, was it last fall or earlier
Speaker 7:  this year that Mark first was like, we want to get back to
Speaker 7:  OG Facebook. We wanna bring back the thing that makes Facebook great, which
Speaker 7:  is people hanging out with their friends. That was a long time
Speaker 7:  ago, and I'm not sure that was ever actually what made Facebook great, but
Speaker 7:  that was like, there is that, that is the perception of old Facebook. And
Speaker 7:  they're making the first turn of that now, which is
Speaker 7:  essentially they've added a tab to Facebook
Speaker 7:  so far, at least for me, it's just in the mobile app, not on the website
Speaker 7:  that It is just your friends and it gets rid of all of the other,
Speaker 7:  you know, publications and AI slap and all of the like, recommended
Speaker 7:  crap that is all over everybody's feeds now and is designed to just be, it's
Speaker 7:  literally called a Friends tab. And It is designed to just be the people
Speaker 7:  you are friends with on Facebook, which for me is a very funny experience
Speaker 7:  because none of my friends on Facebook are still using Facebook except the
Speaker 7:  people who need it for like branding reasons. Yeah. Like
Speaker 7:  it's, if you wanna like be an influencer on Facebook, you keep posting to
Speaker 7:  Facebook. So I like, I have a few friends who are like outing themselves
Speaker 7:  with like many, you know, large albums of photos of them and
Speaker 7:  their family at Disney World. But other than that, my Friends tab is totally
Speaker 7:  dead. But this is like, this is the first turn in, I think
Speaker 7:  trying to make Facebook in particular, the thing, it was
Speaker 7:  a long time ago and I'm just not convinced A, that's gonna work.
Speaker 7:  And b, that's even possible. Like, it just feels like we've left that idea
Speaker 7:  of like, I'm hanging out with my friends on a social network. We left that
Speaker 7:  behind a long time ago, didn't we?
Speaker 6:  I think we did. But this is, this is, by the way, I'm gonna relate this to
Speaker 6:  Elon.
Speaker 6:  Elon made X into whatever cesspool It
Speaker 6:  is, but It is very influential in its tiny sphere.
Speaker 6:  I actually believe that X is less influential outside of its sphere.
Speaker 6:  Like it used to be influential in culture. It used to be influential in sports
Speaker 6:  media. It used to be influential in tech. Now, now it's kind of influential
Speaker 6:  in MAGA politics and that's it. But It is
Speaker 7:  Very influential in that world.
Speaker 6:  It is, it it It is expanded, its influence in, in one way and reduced it
Speaker 6:  in another way. And that's a trade. And you can have a lot of feelings about
Speaker 6:  that trade and I certainly do. But It is a trade. You can just look at it
Speaker 6:  and evaluate it however you want. But people are posting to it,
Speaker 6:  right? Like that's a still a thing that's happening. Yeah. Like people are
Speaker 6:  posting to it, they're sharing stuff. It is not a creator
Speaker 6:  platform. And like it has creator platform dynamics. It doesn't have any
Speaker 6:  revenue. So it's like, it hasn't been gamed quite in that way.
Speaker 6:  Facebook is turn turned into a creator platform. This is what you're saying
Speaker 6:  about people are acting like influencers on it, right? Like it's all pages.
Speaker 6:  Most of the individual activity happens in groups, like every school,
Speaker 6:  every parents group at every school's on Facebook in groups, and
Speaker 6:  no one's just like posting their regular stuff. Right? And so this turned
Speaker 6:  back to, oh, I just want people to share with their friends is like, it's
Speaker 6:  a product decision, but it's also a where do you post decision?
Speaker 6:  Like where should this stuff live? And I
Speaker 6:  I, you get the sense that like if Facebook turns into
Speaker 6:  Yahoo email lists, that's the end of that. You know,
Speaker 6:  like,
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  If it's just where people go to complain about their car, like I'm in a lot
Speaker 6:  of car groups on Facebook and it's just people being like, the tires fell
Speaker 6:  off my car. Right. Does
Speaker 7:  This happen to anyone else? And that's the thing, Facebook I think is, is
Speaker 7:  desperately trying to rectify here, right? Like groups is still hugely
Speaker 7:  successful. Marketplace by all accounts is hugely successful. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  But the like core Facebook thing is just
Speaker 7:  kind of gone. And I feel like for me,
Speaker 7:  I think I am me plus like plus or minus four
Speaker 7:  years I would say. So like sort of our age range and a little younger was
Speaker 7:  like, that was the Facebook generation, right? Like there are albums that
Speaker 7:  I posted that are just like 125 pictures of me drunk because I
Speaker 7:  took every picture on my camera and put it on Facebook and tagged all my
Speaker 7:  friends. And that was like peak Facebook that's
Speaker 7:  gone. Like we learned the hard way that that is a
Speaker 7:  terrible way to interact online with our friends. And that there are all
Speaker 7:  kinds of problems that come with that. And that like, the whole
Speaker 7:  idea of sort of harmless low stakes hanging out with your friends on
Speaker 7:  Facebook is just wrong. Younger generations never learned that in the first
Speaker 7:  place, right? Like they, they gravitated to Snapchat because stuff disappears.
Speaker 7:  Because it doesn't stick around because It is this like ephemeral thing.
Speaker 7:  Group chats have become really important. Like to me, the, the very idea
Speaker 7:  of like posting what I'm doing that day on Facebook so my
Speaker 7:  friends can see it just feels weird now. Yeah. Like I don't, that muscle
Speaker 7:  is gone and I don't think it's ever coming back for people.
Speaker 6:  And that's what I mean by just like turning this product knob, like
Speaker 6:  wanting to be influential in this specific way. You can
Speaker 6:  see that it's getting away from like Threads is not that platform they lost
Speaker 6:  to Blue Sky in a very real world. They have a much bigger number. More people
Speaker 6:  are using it 'cause of the juiced against their entire graph. But like
Speaker 6:  Blue Sky is where a whole conversation is happening. X is where a whole conversation
Speaker 6:  is happening. Yeah. Instagram is a creator platform.
Speaker 6:  Like I, I know lots of regular people who just like do stories or whatever,
Speaker 6:  but the vast majority of the content is creators doing stuff that gets shared
Speaker 6:  into a group chat or a dm. And then that's, that's the
Speaker 6:  action there. So you just see like, oh, these platforms are really
Speaker 6:  big, but they're losing influence in a very specific way. And I'm telling
Speaker 6:  you, there's, there's jealousy there that I think is, you can just see it.
Speaker 6:  He really needs the metaverse to work.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, no, I I I buy it. And I think what's weird about Facebook is it
Speaker 7:  seemed like Facebook's fate was to be sort of the,
Speaker 7:  the overall repository for everything, right? Like you make a reel
Speaker 7:  on Instagram and it, it accrues back to Facebook and becomes a thing. But
Speaker 7:  you didn't make it for Facebook. Yeah. Threads posts show up on Instagram
Speaker 7:  and Facebook. So it was like Facebook became this thing with a huge
Speaker 7:  kind of unengaged user base that is doing other stuff on the platform. And
Speaker 7:  then you just show them a bunch of content and that it's not an exciting
Speaker 7:  product, but as a product strategy actually kind of makes sense to me. And
Speaker 7:  so the only reason I can think that this friends thing is so
Speaker 7:  important is because it's important to Mark for exactly the reasons you're
Speaker 7:  describing. It's like, It is, It is the thing people like about
Speaker 7:  Facebook. Yeah. Not the thing that people tolerate in order to get to
Speaker 7:  marketplace. And like, especially as they, they continue
Speaker 7:  to promote AI stuff all over the feed. They continue to juice
Speaker 7:  engagement and publisher stuff like the, the,
Speaker 7:  they have to have something that people like about being on Facebook or it's
Speaker 7:  just gonna keep getting worse. And it really does feel like, this is Mark
Speaker 7:  in particular saying, this is what I want back. Yeah. It's like that he is
Speaker 7:  nostalgic for this thing so he can build it into Facebook.
Speaker 6:  I can't wait to start posting ai. I slap to all my friends. I'm just gonna
Speaker 6:  AI generate some new children. Like here they're first day of school for
Speaker 6:  my AI generated
Speaker 7:  Baby. That, that would do numbers.
Speaker 6:  Huge engagement. Did I mention this last week? Last week there was the Nvidia
Speaker 6:  conference we talked about a little bit and there was one segment in it that
Speaker 6:  I think will form the basis of yet more editor in chief assigning
Speaker 6:  stories in Slack. 'cause he saw, oh, goodie. But Nvidia is part of their
Speaker 6:  conference demoed this thing that I've been calling Infinite Creative. I
Speaker 6:  think they actually titled it Infinite Creative. See ad agencies make creative,
Speaker 6:  right? That's, that's what Mad Men does. They're like, here's an ad. Like
Speaker 6:  here's the ad, the creative of an ad and the creative of ad is like
Speaker 6:  made of components. It's made of photos of the product, it's made of tagline
Speaker 6:  and copy. And then there's targeting, right? So like
Speaker 6:  you send it, you open Facebook Ads Manager and you're like
Speaker 6:  18 to 30 5-year-old men who like shampoo get 'em. Right? You
Speaker 6:  know, and like it shows people those ads
Speaker 6:  Nvidia demoed infinite creative. So they th they AI
Speaker 6:  generate the shampoo bottle. Then they AI generate the copy. They AI
Speaker 6:  generate the tagline. They AI generate the photo shoot of the shampoo bottle.
Speaker 6:  And then they, when you say target these people, it starts remixing all of
Speaker 6:  the elements in an infinite way until it starts converting.
Speaker 6:  So everyone gets their own ad and like if you thought AI slap on
Speaker 6:  Facebook was bad, now wait until there's real money
Speaker 6:  behind it and it's already here. Like they're, that this is why these big
Speaker 6:  companies like Google and and Meta in particular are chasing AI video generation
Speaker 6:  so hard, right? Because that's the promise is as you're scrolling
Speaker 6:  an AI generated video ad will pop up that's perfectly targeted to you.
Speaker 6:  And then you will buy the shampoo.
Speaker 7:  I I wonder a lot about whether that actually becomes
Speaker 7:  the thing that sort of viscerally turns
Speaker 7:  everybody against ad targeting. 'cause until now it's been like,
Speaker 7:  you know, we're gonna serve you better ads. And I I think
Speaker 6:  Until now it's been, are you listening to me?
Speaker 7:  Well, fair. But like the, the promise of ad targeting
Speaker 7:  is we will, we will send you an ad for something you want instead of something
Speaker 7:  you don't. Right. Which is fine, but I don't think people actually want that.
Speaker 7:  But like, if you're gonna serve me an ad, serve me a good one. Sure. But
Speaker 7:  the idea of like an ad coming up in my feed that's like, Hey David, do you
Speaker 7:  want these shoes? That's it's coming frightening. And like that,
Speaker 7:  that makes a thing plain to people in a way that I think has not
Speaker 7:  been clear before. Like, that is all the data about me that you have
Speaker 7:  being spoken aloud to me and that feels really different from, oh,
Speaker 7:  this ad is a thing I like. Yeah. Do you know what I mean? There's, it connects
Speaker 7:  different neurons somehow in a, in a way that I think might backfire.
Speaker 6:  I would just argue that it already has ad targeting either works
Speaker 6:  so well that you think Mark Zuckerberg is listening to you or
Speaker 6:  it works so poorly that it shows you an ad for something you've already bought.
Speaker 6:  Like there's no middle ground. That's everyone's experience to with advertising
Speaker 6:  today. Right. And most people think Mark Zuckerberg is listening to you
Speaker 6:  and it's like, well not really. 'cause you you bought those shoes
Speaker 6:  and he was like, show 'em more shoes.
Speaker 6:  Like I don't think he's listening to you closely
Speaker 7:  So he closely enough
Speaker 6:  So he like shoes, but sure. Like he he's listening to you. This is gonna
Speaker 6:  turn the he's listening knob all the way like
Speaker 7:  Yeah, that's fair.
Speaker 6:  All the way up to not only is he listening to me, he's talking back to me.
Speaker 6:  Right.
Speaker 7:  Mark Zuckerberg is in my house. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And maybe, you know, and you make all the arguments for why they're
Speaker 6:  not listening. Like Apple would never allow it. It's actually easier to do
Speaker 6:  the, the data fusion about what wifi network you were on at what time and
Speaker 6:  what location because you're not as special as you think, which is really
Speaker 6:  the core argument to they're not listening to you is you're not as special
Speaker 6:  as you think you are.
Speaker 6:  Like every other 18-year-old in this city Googled these shoes
Speaker 6:  at this time. Like we we just guessed that you probably did too. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And that's, that's the heart of the argument is it's simpler to guess Right.
Speaker 6:  And be right some of the time. This is gonna be something else entirely.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The all the cost curves have, but Nvidia did demo.
Speaker 6:  Infinite creative TikTok has demoed variations on infinite creative.
Speaker 6:  It's coming. And I, I think some of this push to do friends again is very
Speaker 6:  much, we need more surface area for these experiments
Speaker 6:  that is out of the creator's end. They
Speaker 7:  Need people to look at their feeds again. And if I'm in, if I'm in marketplace
Speaker 7:  and groups, I'm not looking at my feeds. Yeah. That's like, it's that's
Speaker 7:  a real thing.
Speaker 6:  It's coming. It's, I we're gonna do a lot of stories in this stuff over the
Speaker 6:  coming year, but you We'll, I'll, I'll link, I'll put a link
Speaker 6:  to this TikTok in the show notes. How's that? Just like everyone else
Speaker 6:  can experience the absolute insanity of my TikTok feed. We'll do it in the
Speaker 6:  show notes by
Speaker 7:  2027. We're gonna have a version of this podcast that is individualized to
Speaker 7:  every single person who listens to it. And
Speaker 6:  It's gonna be, that is the Dream Sick
Speaker 7:  Can't,
Speaker 6:  That's our final subscription tier for
Speaker 6:  $5 million a year. David will just call you, talk
Speaker 7:  To your, does just make you a podcast. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  All right. There's actual Gadget news, some, some a little stuff. A bunch
Speaker 6:  of Apple stuff. Really. AirPods Max with USPC, they're updating it
Speaker 6:  to support Lossless audio, which is way overdue like way, way
Speaker 6:  overdue. And they're gonna cut some latency down. I have no idea why this
Speaker 6:  took so long.
Speaker 7:  It It is a strange one. And the AirPods max
Speaker 7:  for me kind of goes in the category of products that Apple seems to forget
Speaker 7:  about for years at a time. It's like the MAC Pro, the
Speaker 7:  AirPods Max, the iPad mini. It's just like every, every 18
Speaker 7:  months the company forgets it exists. And it was like, oh crap, we should
Speaker 7:  do something with that. And here we are. But yeah, this one, they, they
Speaker 7:  put back wired playback through USBC when they switched to the connector,
Speaker 7:  they dropped wired playback, which I had forgotten about and was so weird
Speaker 7:  at the time, you just couldn't play audio over a wire. Like
Speaker 7:  just weird stuff. But now that's back. So that's good. And like you said,
Speaker 7:  super low latency stuff and when we were hearing rumblings
Speaker 7:  about there maybe being an announcement a along these lines,
Speaker 7:  I was like, oh my God, are we gonna get new AirPods Max? I I
Speaker 7:  want them. And that's very exciting. And what's interesting about this is
Speaker 7:  this suggests to me that Apple is pretty happy with the
Speaker 7:  hardware of the AirPods Max. And It is like this, this is very much
Speaker 7:  like a meaningful software update on top of a
Speaker 7:  piece of hardware. They have no intention of updating. Yeah. Imminently.
Speaker 6:  So I wanna be clear here, the Lossless audio is only if you use the cable.
Speaker 6:  Like I Oh
Speaker 7:  Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 6:  And so you get 24 bit 48 kilohertz lossless audio, you get personalized
Speaker 6:  spa audio musicians cannot mix in it using these headphones. You have to
Speaker 6:  use the cable, which is wild because Apple
Speaker 6:  owns their Bluetooth stack. They own the chips on both sides of this. These
Speaker 6:  headphones cost $550. What are we doing?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, what are we doing? Did you also see the real reason I wanted to talk
Speaker 7:  about It is I wanted to see if you had seen the new
Speaker 7:  USBC to 3.5 millimeter cable that Apple is selling. It's very
Speaker 6:  Nice.
Speaker 7:  It's $40. Yep. So for four, for for $40,
Speaker 7:  you can approximate having a headphone Jack. Again, congratulations to you.
Speaker 7:  And It is, It is 1.2 meters, which is what, like four feet.
Speaker 7:  You can just have a four foot long adapter cable.
Speaker 7:  I think this is just for airplanes, right? Isn't that This is just for plugging
Speaker 7:  into the, the seat back thing on
Speaker 6:  The air. No, this is the thing you need for everything, for all these new
Speaker 6:  features. So you're wanna plug this in your Mac and do Lossless
Speaker 6:  personalized spatial audio mixing. Okay.
Speaker 6:  I don't
Speaker 7:  Know man, I'm calling this right now. iPhone 17 headphone Jack is back.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, there we, there was a entire like blue
Speaker 6:  sky kerfuffle about the headphone jack being in stratification. I was like,
Speaker 6:  like I wrote about this to the iPhone seven. Like this has always been what's
Speaker 6:  coming. They've compressed the audio and now pendulum swing back and people
Speaker 6:  are like, what if my music sounded good? And the answer is Dongle Town.
Speaker 6:  That's just the way it goes. And it's weird. And the the, the bad thing
Speaker 6:  happened. I I, I made a prediction when I wrote that piece, taking the headphone
Speaker 6:  jack off of phones as you draw also and stupid, which Apple hated at the
Speaker 6:  time. I wanna be very clear about this one
Speaker 7:  Of your better headlines. It was,
Speaker 6:  It was very direct, but my prediction was that we would get DRM audio
Speaker 6:  where only approved headphones would work with certain streaming services.
Speaker 6:  That did not happen. What did happen is arguably weirder
Speaker 6:  and worse, which is that every phone
Speaker 6:  works best with the headphones from the same company. Right? So Pixel
Speaker 6:  Buds work best with the Pixel Galaxy Buds work best with your Samsung phone.
Speaker 6:  AirPods work best with your Apple phone. And then they all have weird proprietary
Speaker 6:  extensions like spatial audio head tracking. And that is ar it's
Speaker 6:  arguably worse than here are some headphones that have the DRM trip for Spotify
Speaker 6:  and we're all, maybe it's not. Maybe, maybe it, maybe it's all just
Speaker 6:  equally bad, but that, I got my prediction wrong in that way. But
Speaker 6:  the thing happened where the headphone market contracted Yeah. And now
Speaker 6:  everyone's kinda has the ecosystem locking on headphones.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It is just purely platform based now, which is, which
Speaker 7:  is a weird outcome. Yeah. In, in a lot of ways.
Speaker 6:  Speaking of ecosystem lockin, there's some Apple Watch rumors. What's going
Speaker 6:  on here?
Speaker 7:  So we've been talking a lot about AI gadgets in general.
Speaker 7:  And a thing that Allison Johnson keeps floating to me is that actually the
Speaker 7:  AI gadget that should exist is the Apple Watch. Like that's
Speaker 7:  the one, forget the humane pin, forget the rabbit. Just make a smart watch
Speaker 7:  that does AI things. And it turns out Apple appears to
Speaker 7:  agree with that. I think it was over the weekend, mark Kerman at Bloomberg
Speaker 7:  reported that Apple is trying to put visual
Speaker 7:  intelligence and thus cameras inside of the Apple Watch
Speaker 7:  in the next two years. And I think I actually need you to help me visualize
Speaker 7:  this because the, the way he reported It is on the regular models, the
Speaker 7:  camera is going to be inside of the display, which I would assume means it's
Speaker 7:  pointing kind of up off your wrist. But then on the
Speaker 7:  ultra it's gonna be on the side between I guess the,
Speaker 7:  the crown and the action button, which would indicate that
Speaker 7:  it's pointing out the side of the watch. So I like, I've been spending all
Speaker 7:  week trying to figure out like, what is this thing gonna be looking at and
Speaker 7:  how are you gonna use it? But I'm like,
Speaker 7:  there's a real energy within Apple, it appears to
Speaker 7:  figure out how to put cameras both in your watch and in your AirPods
Speaker 7:  as a, as a like visual intelligence AI input system.
Speaker 7:  The AirPods one kind of makes sense to me, right? Like you just, you just
Speaker 7:  put a camera here, it faces this way. Like you have the sort of Ray band
Speaker 7:  meta visual and that makes sense. This one I can't quite wrap my
Speaker 7:  mind around. Like I get the idea. I just don't get how you do it in the product
Speaker 6:  Or like truly where it goes. Like fundamentally,
Speaker 7:  Literally. Yeah. What
Speaker 6:  Is it? If you're wearing a watch be like you're gonna beep.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It really is like a, like an old school like Dick Tracy
Speaker 7:  kind of thing where you're just, you're gonna hold it up and like shoot lasers
Speaker 7:  at the side of your watch
Speaker 6:  And then if you do the face, you're always kind of like,
Speaker 7:  This is, yeah, this is looking
Speaker 6:  At stuff. And then where is the shutter button here? You got a weird problem
Speaker 6:  there.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Just
Speaker 7:  Can you just imagine like we're two years away from just walking around and
Speaker 7:  just like shoving our wrist and people's faces being like, look at this.
Speaker 6:  I don't even use, I know a lot of people who do use Apple Wallet on their
Speaker 6:  watches and they're just like, beep. And I find that to be awkward and I
Speaker 6:  use my phone all the time. I get it. I, I like if you've got a
Speaker 6:  big wearable and you've, you've got your own proprietary Bluetooth link
Speaker 6:  back to a phone with a big battery or a bigger battery, more processing
Speaker 6:  power, it makes sense to have this thing be the thing.
Speaker 6:  I don't know. I I I don't know why you would put a camera on it. I I think
Speaker 6:  that would, unless you want it to be totally separate from the phone,
Speaker 6:  which runs directly into
Speaker 6:  a classic of the David Pierce genre, which is when you profiled the Apple
Speaker 6:  Watch for Wired and you set it, its goal was to get away from the, the phone.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And Apple basically yelled and said that wasn't
Speaker 6:  true.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  They told me on the record it was true. And then told me off
Speaker 7:  on the record it wasn't true.
Speaker 6:  Sure. But like, this has been the problem with the watch forever. Like, can
Speaker 6:  it be independent of the phone and maybe AI is the thing that makes it independent
Speaker 6:  of the phone
Speaker 7:  Maybe. But I also think I I I think one of the other stories of the Apple
Speaker 7:  Watch is another thing that I reported in that story that Apple hated, which
Speaker 7:  is that they decided to build a watch way before they decided why to build
Speaker 7:  a watch. And I think you still see that in the watch. Like they
Speaker 7:  figured out one thing, this is a, a health device, but that has a
Speaker 7:  ceiling for both. Yeah. What they can like literally do
Speaker 7:  scientifically and the number of people who are gonna be interested in it.
Speaker 7:  So you need another thing if you want this thing to sort of continue to grow
Speaker 7:  and become a huge business, which it obviously already is.
Speaker 7:  Now the bet obviously is that it's an AI thing and
Speaker 7:  you, you either need a ton more processing inside of it, which is very hard
Speaker 7:  to do on a watch or you need some new input thing that it can do.
Speaker 7:  And I think that's how you get to, oh, the way we do this is to is to make
Speaker 7:  it a camera somehow.
Speaker 6:  Or you give it AI voice
Speaker 6:  Siri, you know, that's confusing
Speaker 7:  Everyone. Yeah. That's going really well for Apple.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The, the thing that's currently confusing this entire
Speaker 7:  Industry, honestly, if Siri were good, it would've solved an enormous number
Speaker 7:  of problems like this for Apple because, because it, the watch would've been
Speaker 7:  much closer to the thing that Apple originally wanted it to be if Siri was
Speaker 7:  good because you would've been able to do stuff on your watch and thus not
Speaker 7:  do it on your phone, which was the goal.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. But then you run, you run into that serial problem also. You probably
Speaker 6:  have to wear headphones all the time. Right. It's like the combo platter
Speaker 6:  of AirPods and an Apple Watch replaces your phone is a dream I think
Speaker 6:  they've hinted at. Right? You get some AR glasses in the mix there. That's
Speaker 6:  a lot of stuff.
Speaker 7:  It is a lot of
Speaker 6:  Stuff, you know, on, on the, the chart of wearable bullshit that's a lot
Speaker 6:  of gizmos to care for that does not necessarily deliver more value than
Speaker 6:  having a giant phone.
Speaker 7:  Right.
Speaker 6:  In case you're wondering Eli's theory of wearable bullshit is that you have
Speaker 6:  a Y axis that's FIDS and an X axis
Speaker 6:  that's like value, like utility.
Speaker 6:  I change the axes every time we talk about this and you have a a a
Speaker 6:  a huge penalty for a face on fis. Right? And so
Speaker 6:  regular glasses are like a perfect device. You don't have to care for 'em
Speaker 6:  a lot, a little bit. You have to care for 'em, but they're so valuable, they
Speaker 6:  overcome the, it's on your face penalty and then the Apple
Speaker 6:  Watch had to curve up. It wasn't useful enough at the beginning and now it's
Speaker 6:  pretty useful. You don't have to care for it a lot. 'cause battery less a
Speaker 6:  long time. And the Vision Pro is all the way at the bottom where it's really
Speaker 6:  fiddly has an external battery pack, it doesn't have enough apps, it's on
Speaker 6:  your face and it doesn't do a
Speaker 7:  Lot. It is the most penalty. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And like many people have sent us vari variations on this
Speaker 6:  chart. Please by all means, send us where you think the combo platter of
Speaker 6:  Apple Watch plus AirPods plus glasses lives
Speaker 6:  compared to phone.
Speaker 6:  Because you, you just see that math doesn't math.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So I just reviewed the, the light phone three this week and we shouldn't
Speaker 7:  talk about it. I'm gonna talk about it a bunch with Allison next week. But
Speaker 7:  one of the things that kept striking me in the course of doing this is like,
Speaker 7:  intellectually I would like to use my phone less, but then every time
Speaker 7:  I am given a, a thing that would maybe make me use my phone
Speaker 7:  less, I'm like, you know what kicks ass is my phone. Yeah. Like my phone
Speaker 7:  is so good at so many things. It's really,
Speaker 6:  And it's a real problem for this whole industry. Yeah. And
Speaker 7:  Like what I like to do some of those things less. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  But I'd, I still wanna do I still wanna look at Reddit sometimes. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  The screen is really big in this internet connection's pretty fast. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  It's
Speaker 6:  Real problem. The camera's pretty good. Speaking of Apple WWC was
Speaker 6:  announced, it starts June 9th. We're expecting a, a big overhaul to
Speaker 6:  iOS. There's some notion that I
Speaker 6:  know inside of Squares will have circles for icons.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Speaking of the Vision Pro
Speaker 6:  Aas will finally come to iOS.
Speaker 7:  I will say two like old head internet references that we've made
Speaker 7:  in the last couple of weeks. One was Arrow glass on Windows. We got like
Speaker 7:  an email or two from people who were like, oh, I remember that. And then
Speaker 7:  just offhandedly a drinking outta cups references. And we got an absolute
Speaker 7:  outpouring of support from people who were like that you are my people
Speaker 7:  drinking outta cups.
Speaker 6:  I don't, it
Speaker 7:  Was amazing.
Speaker 6:  Many people on YouTube comments record, I'd love to get this joke. What?
Speaker 6:  And I, the video doesn't hold up.
Speaker 7:  It was funny to watch again, but if you've never seen it, it won't be funny.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like it's an old video. You can Google it. It's a
Speaker 6:  animated, it's it's, I'm not even gonna explain it. Whatever. It's just,
Speaker 6:  if you were drunk with your friends at a particular moment in your history,
Speaker 6:  this was the funniest thing you'd ever seen in your life.
Speaker 7:  A hundred percent.
Speaker 6:  And that DNAI think is shared with a great many for chess
Speaker 6:  listeners. Yes. Johnny Hammer sticks over here.
Speaker 7:  But on the, on the WWDC front, it, it seems like
Speaker 7:  there there's been a bunch of hype about a huge redesigned iOS 19 and I
Speaker 7:  would say every little bit we learn about it makes it seem like a less and
Speaker 7:  less huge redesign of all the time. It's just gonna
Speaker 7:  be slightly glassier and that'll be
Speaker 7:  it. Well,
Speaker 6:  I mean this is what, three months away, right? Yeah. Not even two months
Speaker 6:  away. Think about all the things that aren't gonna
Speaker 6:  get paid off at this WWC Apple intelligence with Smart
Speaker 6:  Siri not gonna get paid off at this WWE c like we already
Speaker 6:  know they've announced it next generation CarPlay
Speaker 6:  50 years after they announced it. Yep. Not gonna get paid. Last
Speaker 6:  year they were insistent like this is happening. Like big
Speaker 6:  car companies were meant to like didn't happen. Porsche, which actually
Speaker 6:  did announce it, not, hasn't shipped to card yet with the
Speaker 6:  next generation CarPlay. It's still not paid off. What are they gonna say
Speaker 6:  in, in two months? Is will there, will there be an auto industry in America?
Speaker 6:  Who knows? But it's not there.
Speaker 6:  Then iOS is conceptually, if you're reorienting it around Apple
Speaker 6:  intelligence, what are you gonna pay off? Right? Right. Even
Speaker 6:  marketing these phones is having Apple on top. Like I think there's a lot
Speaker 6:  of pressure. And then you've got just angry developers in general,
Speaker 6:  right? Like this has been the story forever. So I'm curious to see what they
Speaker 6:  say actually. Wwc.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it's, it's very funny because last year right about now there was
Speaker 7:  this sense of, okay, apple has not talked enough
Speaker 7:  about ai. AI is the thing, it's all anybody wants to talk about.
Speaker 7:  But we know WWDC is coming and it's gonna be the time Apple takes its big
Speaker 7:  swing and sort of announces the perfect productization of AI
Speaker 7:  and Apple like attempted to do that. And here we
Speaker 7:  are and I think this time Apple is coming into it
Speaker 7:  on its back foot in a way that It is not accustomed to that it Apple
Speaker 7:  is going to have to explain itself in a way that It is not used to having
Speaker 7:  to explain itself and it's not going to because
Speaker 7:  that's just not what Apple does. Apple is better than any company on Earth.
Speaker 7:  It just pretending everything is fine and posting through it.
Speaker 7:  But, but that is where It is right now. Like this, this,
Speaker 7:  at some point It is going to have to look people in the face and be like,
Speaker 7:  Hey, remember that Siri thing we told you about that That one's on us.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Sign up for app Intense where we commoditize your app, right.
Speaker 6:  For a product that doesn't work. We'll see, speaking of
Speaker 6:  AI and agents, we're kind of waiting on next
Speaker 6:  generation Alexa to hit. It's like any minute now. And then there's a rumor
Speaker 6:  that Amazon will rename the entire echo line to just Alexa,
Speaker 6:  what
Speaker 7:  Do you think of this? I've been thinking about this for like two days now
Speaker 7:  since Jen Tui first saw this and, and I think got a tip
Speaker 7:  about it and wrote, wrote a story. And some people on our team were seeing
Speaker 7:  Alexa. Like when you go to the Amazon listing, we're seeing Alexa show other
Speaker 7:  people were seeing echo show.
Speaker 7:  What do you think of that switch? If they just go full on Alexa everything,
Speaker 6:  I think they should go full on Alexa everything. I
Speaker 7:  Kind of think so too.
Speaker 6:  It's the name of the pla It's the argument was always that Alexa is Windows
Speaker 6:  and then you had to have this ecosystem of products that run Alexa and
Speaker 6:  Amazon's products would be called Echo.
Speaker 6:  Even just explaining it that sounds stupid, right? Like it was not the right
Speaker 6:  idea and no one knows the difference. No one's like, I better buy an
Speaker 6:  Echo and not a Lenovo voice operated Alexa
Speaker 6:  bot. Well, and
Speaker 7:  I think the other part of It is that stuff never really materialized. Like
Speaker 7:  there isn't a giant third party universe of Alexa
Speaker 7:  speakers. Like they just are echos
Speaker 6:  Because Alexa is not useful enough, right? So just to be, to, to hammer that
Speaker 6:  home that never took off because Alexa itself was never useful enough. Like
Speaker 6:  when car makers are like, there's Alexa integration in the dash, it's like,
Speaker 6:  why? To do what? Set a timer
Speaker 6:  in my car. Like I'm, I'm not doing that. Maybe play music, but you don't
Speaker 6:  need Alexa to do all that. Like the promise of this brand name hasn't meant
Speaker 6:  anything. Now it means something or it's supposed to mean something,
Speaker 6:  which is all this age agentic AI actual assistant stuff. And I think you
Speaker 6:  need to reclaim that. 'cause I don't think they're gonna run this new Alexa
Speaker 6:  on third party devices the way they were in the past. I think they want you
Speaker 6:  to buy a screen. They, like Panas has said, I want you to buy
Speaker 6:  an Alexa show and then there's gonna be new hardware. And I think you gotta,
Speaker 6:  that's the brand.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, no, I think that, I think that's right. And it actually, it makes a
Speaker 7:  lot of sense to me too. 'cause I think, I would bet most people who own
Speaker 7:  an Echo device don't know that it's called an Echo device. It's just, it's,
Speaker 7:  it's the Alexa. That's how almost everyone I know who has one of these
Speaker 7:  refers to it as it's the Alexa. You
Speaker 6:  Don't, you don't talk to your Dell XPS 500 Alexa bot.
Speaker 7:  What was the Harmon Cardin one that had,
Speaker 7:  that was good stuff.
Speaker 6:  I mean, we'll see. It, it, the it Alexa, the new Alexa is gonna start hitting.
Speaker 6:  If you have access to us, let us know. We're everyone on
Speaker 6:  our team is sort of like, are you useful now?
Speaker 6:  We're back. Kylie Robinson's here. Hey Kylie. Hello. Big
Speaker 6:  week of AI News. Big week of AI Feelings. Yes.
Speaker 6:  Mostly centered around OpenAI says the, I would say the most emotional of
Speaker 6:  the AI companies. Right?
Speaker 7:  That's really true, isn't it? I never really thought about it like that,
Speaker 7:  but that is true. There are a lot of feelings inside that company.
Speaker 6:  Just big feelings all over the place.
Speaker 11:  Big feelings
Speaker 6:  Like Microsoft as a company is not like a big feelings company, you know?
Speaker 6:  No, no. Anthropic, you know, they're sort of like dead ahead. They're like,
Speaker 6:  here's some stuff. It writes code and then open eyes. Like, I'm feeling all
Speaker 6:  of 'em. Yeah,
Speaker 11:  We're creating God, please save us.
Speaker 6:  Like it's just like a lot like, it's like I tell my daughter like it's, you
Speaker 6:  have to feel all of your feelings so you can get over them. You know? I was
Speaker 6:  like, I'm feeling all of them.
Speaker 7:  I feel like there's like two things we need to talk about here. But yeah,
Speaker 7:  before we get way into the inevitable
Speaker 7:  Studio, Ghibli Weeds, which I would very much like to do, there was some
Speaker 7:  like business leadership stuff that happened at OpenAI
Speaker 7:  says. And speaking of companies that are unusual,
Speaker 7:  nobody does a C-suite quite like OpenAI says, does a C-suite, right?
Speaker 7:  What do you make of this whole like shift? What, what happened this weekend
Speaker 7:  and do we need to actually care about it?
Speaker 11:  No, I don't think people need to care about it. But for their information,
Speaker 11:  the CEOO, Brad lcap, he's expanding his role.
Speaker 11:  He's taking over day-to-day operations, basically becoming a CEO.
Speaker 11:  And Sam Altman, who is the CEO, is gonna shift to a more
Speaker 11:  product research focus, which to me, my reading is
Speaker 11:  he wants to focus more on Stargate. He wants to more like focus more on
Speaker 11:  shaking hands and making these deals. And he can't exactly
Speaker 11:  do all that and be the leader. Opening AI knees right now is my
Speaker 11:  take, but it's like an ever shifting thing. They're gonna become
Speaker 11:  a for-profit soon. Brad seems like a nice person to put at the top and be
Speaker 11:  like, this is the guy running things right now and Sam is just tinkering
Speaker 11:  with robots and a GI
Speaker 6:  Are they gonna become a for-profit soon?
Speaker 11:  Great question. Great question. I think they would like to,
Speaker 11:  but I don't know how this lawsuit with Elon and all of
Speaker 11:  that will, you know, totally change the trajectory if at all.
Speaker 11:  That remains to be seen. I think they have to get through that first.
Speaker 7:  How far are we into the two year window that they had to do it? We're not
Speaker 7:  at a year yet, right? No.
Speaker 11:  No, I don't think so. Okay. Please fact, check me. But I, I think off
Speaker 11:  the top of my head, it was supposed to happen like mid midway through this
Speaker 11:  year around the summer. Okay.
Speaker 6:  It does seem like the boring part of changing the corporate structure
Speaker 6:  is what they want Brad to do. Yes. Like do this paperwork so
Speaker 6:  Sam can say he's building God. Right? Is that, is
Speaker 6:  that all, is that all that is?
Speaker 11:  I've had a lot of people ask me about this and I think, you know, you know
Speaker 11:  how Elon was like, I'm leading Twitter and now he just put someone as
Speaker 11:  CEO so he doesn't have to fucking deal with it. That's sort of like you've,
Speaker 11:  he's been running this company long enough, clearly he wants to do other
Speaker 11:  things and he's like, can somebody else deal with the logistics?
Speaker 11:  Is my read.
Speaker 7:  I also wonder if Neil, I, we were talking about Mark Zuckerberg in
Speaker 7:  the last segment and one of the pivots that Mark made pretty aggressively
Speaker 7:  was, I don't wanna be the person required to apologize for this stuff
Speaker 7:  anymore. And so he made like Nick Clegg, the person who had to go
Speaker 7:  apologize for Facebook all the time and he just got to go like announce new
Speaker 7:  products. And I, I keep thinking about, and, and this is where we should
Speaker 7:  get to the images and ChatGPT stuff, but there was a, there was a, a Sam
Speaker 7:  tweet this week where he was basically like, you know, be me,
Speaker 7:  build in silence for a long time. Nobody cares. And then it was like, and
Speaker 7:  then we do images and now everybody's being weird and it's like, oh you,
Speaker 6:  You just didn't wanna say the word that he said. What
Speaker 7:  Did he say? I honestly don't remember what that was. Lemme tell
Speaker 11:  You. I know the exact sequence hit me. So, you know, for a few years
Speaker 11:  building in silence then for two and a half everybody hates me and then
Speaker 11:  wake up today and everyone's saying, haha, I made you into Twink Studio
Speaker 11:  Ghibli. That's right.
Speaker 6:  That's exactly what he said. Yeah. To be clear, Sam is a gay man. I think
Speaker 6:  he's allowed to use that word in a way. Yes. That David and I are not. Yes.
Speaker 6:  But that, I mean that this is the thing, like he's the product person now.
Speaker 6:  He's the face of the product. He's still the CEO famously. He was
Speaker 6:  not the CEO EO for about 20 minutes last year. Yeah. Yes. So I don't think
Speaker 6:  he's allowed to step down as CEO EO again after that flight. He has to say
Speaker 6:  the CEO e Right. But the like operate the company, be the corporate person.
Speaker 6:  Okay. We're shift down somewhere else. I will not be the face of the product
Speaker 6:  and the fundraising and the hype and then that face
Speaker 6:  quite literally this week is image generation.
Speaker 11:  Right. Not to take away from Studio Ghibli, but I think the strangest thing
Speaker 11:  is that they don't have a CTO and they've said they have no plans to replace
Speaker 11:  Mirati anytime soon, which would probably help Sam in
Speaker 11:  his product research mode to have a CTO. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And Sam notably does not have a reputation as like a great
Speaker 6:  product person. Like he has an incredible reputation as a fundraiser
Speaker 6:  and a guy who can build hype and talk about the story of the product and,
Speaker 6:  and, and you know, he used to run Y Combinator like he's a great
Speaker 6:  spotter of things, but like are you the great
Speaker 6:  product visionary? I think there's a reason that Johnny Ive is building
Speaker 6:  whatever he's building for them, right? Like he, he, he hires that talent
Speaker 6:  so he doesn't have the CTO building that, now that said the image generator
Speaker 6:  come out in four Oh this week has led to a wide variety
Speaker 6:  of reactions.
Speaker 11:  Yes.
Speaker 6:  I, there's no other way to say that. A wide variety of reactions. What's
Speaker 6:  going on there?
Speaker 11:  Is this where I bait neli into talking about fair use because I was really
Speaker 11:  hoping
Speaker 7:  I could let, let's do that in a minute. First, what I would like you to do
Speaker 7:  is describe every single interaction that you personally have had within
Speaker 7:  the chat J pt.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, perfect. The first thing I tried to do is to break it
Speaker 11:  and make pictures of CEOs. And that worked pretty
Speaker 11:  well actually. I described, this is in the piece about Ghibli. I described
Speaker 11:  like this social media executive that everybody knows and he went in front
Speaker 11:  of congress and you know, there's this fictional movie about him and he
Speaker 11:  wears gold chains now. And they're like, oh that's interesting. Okay, let
Speaker 11:  me generate that. And it's literally Mark Zuckerberg. So it's not super
Speaker 11:  hard to get around the whole like make a famous person thing. And then I
Speaker 11:  put him in a VERGE brand hoodie and things started to get weird. It, it
Speaker 11:  started amalgamate into average tech CEO across whatever
Speaker 11:  its data is and then the Ghibli trend kicked off.
Speaker 11:  And I did not expect that when this, when I got the
Speaker 11:  embargo and I talked to the team, I thought, okay, this is a cool upgrade.
Speaker 11:  And I really think the auto regressive approach instead of
Speaker 11:  the diffusion approach, so it goes from left to right top to bottom
Speaker 11:  instead of generating it all at once. I think that has made like
Speaker 11:  the craziest difference in the fidelity and the accuracy, which is
Speaker 11:  was wild to see. And people glbb onto that really fast. What you
Speaker 7:  Mean it generates the pixels of the image lesson, right? Yes. Top to bottom
Speaker 7:  instead of Okay.
Speaker 11:  Instead of just like the whole thing at once. So I think that probably helps
Speaker 11:  with hallucinations, the lead for the project. He said
Speaker 11:  I am speculating that that's the case. Which is funny 'cause it's like that
Speaker 11:  unknown to them as well. Right. So
Speaker 11:  I think people globbed onto that pretty quickly and one person was like,
Speaker 11:  I've made a Ghibli version of my wife and my family and then the
Speaker 11:  internet said, oh my god, I can make nine 11 with this and then it got crazy.
Speaker 7:  I do love a that those are the two steps, right? And that b
Speaker 7:  that is precisely of course how it was going to happen. Yeah. So I'll say
Speaker 7:  my impression and I, I have not personally played with this at all. So all
Speaker 7:  I've seen is what other people have made from it. It is remarkably
Speaker 7:  better than yes. Basically any other image
Speaker 7:  generation tool that I've seen, it does text really well. It seems like you
Speaker 7:  have to pretty carefully describe the text that you
Speaker 7:  want where if you're just like, just put a logo, it'll do some of the sort
Speaker 7:  of insane gibberish that we've seen. But if you're like, no, replace that
Speaker 7:  with Marlboro, it'll do it. Yeah. But the stuff is
Speaker 7:  more accurate, it's more realistic. It is more like true to
Speaker 7:  whatever style you ask for than basically anything I have seen Certainly
Speaker 7:  that is like available to people at any kind of scale. And
Speaker 7:  some of the stuff people are making is wild. And it does feel like we're
Speaker 7:  gonna get into all the fair use of this all in a minute because It is the
Speaker 7:  most straightforward. You just say like, make a Rick and Morty and it just
Speaker 7:  makes a Rick and Morty that now looks like Rick and Morty.
Speaker 7:  Yes. And it's, it's nuts. But like Kylie, I know you made a bunch of stuff
Speaker 7:  and I did like was it, was it different to make stuff
Speaker 7:  with this than you've had experience with image generators before? Like you,
Speaker 7:  you used a bunch of selfies to make Yes. Images of yourself.
Speaker 11:  Yes. 'cause I don't wanna feed it pictures of my family
Speaker 11:  actually it's inevitable, but I just don't wanna start there.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. I uploaded this mirror selfie I took in a bar bathroom in San Francisco
Speaker 11:  and was totally shocked by how it got the depth
Speaker 11:  and the lighting correct. And then it got, it didn't get the small text
Speaker 11:  of the graffiti Correct. It said like lost lever instead of like
Speaker 11:  dirty, hairy or something. So,
Speaker 7:  But like the vibe was right? Like it felt like the, you, it was
Speaker 7:  that bathroom that you were in it,
Speaker 11:  It got the style of my shirt. Correct. It knows that it opened on one side
Speaker 11:  and I was, I was totally sur I was totally
Speaker 11:  surprised. And then I asked it to combine some photos. I took an
Speaker 11:  Amsterdam and add Toro, I add a Toro like character
Speaker 11:  to see if it works. Sure. And then sure enough I got Toro and we put that
Speaker 11:  in the article as the lead image and I was like, are we gonna get sued over
Speaker 11:  this? I can't tell. You know, and that's the fair use of it
Speaker 11:  all. My first question is, where the fuck did you get all of
Speaker 11:  this data? Is, is my first question. What are these people going
Speaker 11:  to do when they see Homer Simpson doing, you know,
Speaker 11:  nine 11? Like, like what happens? I don't know. I
Speaker 11:  actually was, this might dismay some listeners and
Speaker 11:  maybe even Neli, but I, I wanted to argue with Chad Petit this morning through
Speaker 11:  voice mode about fair use in this context. And it did not,
Speaker 11:  it did not have really great responses. It was like, oh yeah, this does
Speaker 11:  seem bad. I'm like, oh,
Speaker 6:  Okay. No, that's the right answer. I just wanna be clear. It, it seems
Speaker 6:  bad. Yes. Like the, the fatal flaw
Speaker 6:  at the heart of this entire over-hyped industry is
Speaker 6:  the amount of copyright infringement that is occurring. Yes. Like obvious,
Speaker 6:  not subtle. Right out in the open, did you copy a bunch
Speaker 6:  of Studio GLI stuff so that you can generate Studio gli art y
Speaker 6:  You sure did. It's ob it's obvious, like it's not
Speaker 6:  a question mark. And then you have OpenAI says, and Google going to the
Speaker 6:  United States Congress and the White House being like, can you write us an
Speaker 6:  exception to the copyright law? So this isn't a problem that destroys our
Speaker 6:  business because that's how bad It is. Copyright law is stupid. I say this
Speaker 6:  on the show all the time. It's not, it's not some sophisticated legal
Speaker 6:  doctrine. It's did you make a copy? Did you have permission to make a
Speaker 6:  copy if you didn't have the permission? Does it fall into one of these narrow
Speaker 6:  categories where we say, we know you made a copy without permission,
Speaker 6:  but that's okay because of x. And those categories are like scholarship,
Speaker 6:  right? Like commentary parody. Like it's not make
Speaker 6:  more of it, make more copies of it
Speaker 6:  and like, I don't know, like I truly do not know how any judge looks
Speaker 6:  at all of this and says, oh this is fine. I can shoehorn this
Speaker 6:  into that legal doctrine.
Speaker 7:  Well, and this is why it's become so important for all these companies to
Speaker 7:  obfuscate where the data is coming from. Right? Because if you boil it all
Speaker 7:  the way down to did you make a copy of this? They're trying very hard to
Speaker 7:  convince everybody that the answer is like, we don't know.
Speaker 11:  Right?
Speaker 7:  The internet is a mysterious place. Can
Speaker 6:  I just underline again how stupid copyright law is as a, as a
Speaker 6:  legal doctrine?
Speaker 11:  I'm glad we've gotten here.
Speaker 6:  It's not smart, it's not like sophisticated. We had to
Speaker 6:  litigate as a society moving images across
Speaker 6:  the internet and making all of the copies on the ram of all of the
Speaker 6:  routers is okay. Those are called ephemeral copies. We
Speaker 6:  that, that's lawsuits we had to litigate. This is a real lawsuit.
Speaker 7:  Kylie, you asked for this. I just want you to know, Kylie, you asked for
Speaker 7:  this. I did,
Speaker 11:  I did.
Speaker 6:  MAI versus Peak. This nation had to litigate
Speaker 6:  and decide that loading software from a hard drive onto
Speaker 6:  the ram of the computer was fair use if you didn't have
Speaker 6:  permission to do it. 'cause It is a copy. 'cause it's just a copy. That's
Speaker 6:  how dumb copyright law is as doctrine. It is so
Speaker 6:  blunt as an instrument. It is used for all kinds of
Speaker 6:  purposes because it's so blunt and so stupid. It is the only speech regulation
Speaker 6:  that exists in this country for real. Because you, you don't have the moral
Speaker 6:  component of speech. You're just like, did you make a copy jail? And like
Speaker 6:  that's the end of that. Like you don't have to do all the work, but like
Speaker 6:  that's how dumb copyright law is. And so you, with all of this, like maybe
Speaker 6:  you can get all that fair use, but you start with did you make a copy?
Speaker 6:  And like Yeah, you sure did. Like, without
Speaker 6:  question they did.
Speaker 11:  I was reading this Anthropic lawsuit sent to me by shout out Crans
Speaker 11:  and I was reading through it and it, the judge
Speaker 11:  seemingly threw out the case and their one thing was like, okay, you
Speaker 11:  have to create guardrails to prevent it from spitting out
Speaker 11:  actual copies of copyrighted work. But
Speaker 11:  otherwise it seemed fine. And I thought, okay,
Speaker 11:  I'm not a a legal expert, but in this case I can get
Speaker 11:  Rick and Morty's face on just about anything. So that seems like a problem.
Speaker 11:  OpenAI says, has surprisingly lacks guidelines. I was waiting for them to
Speaker 11:  respond with comment and they gave me a ton of very interesting guidelines.
Speaker 11:  I thought it would be more like we do not depict, you know, copyrighted
Speaker 11:  material. We do not depict Totoro or Donald Trump, but they say
Speaker 11:  it's fine for artistic endeavors. The long and short just don't shrink.
Speaker 11:  'cause you can upload a photo and be like, do this in studio Gibble. Don't
Speaker 11:  upload photos that you don't own the copyright to, which is basically what
Speaker 11:  everyone is doing. But otherwise they say you own
Speaker 11:  whatever it generates. And I, I feel like this is going
Speaker 11:  to end up being a nightmare that that's the only answer. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And there's some amount of this that I think you depend on the volume,
Speaker 6:  just overcoming the objection, right? There's so much infringement
Speaker 6:  that it can't be stopped. Right. You'll be perceived of as the bad guys
Speaker 6:  music industry, you're gonna shut down Napster, Lars,
Speaker 6:  Lars Ulrich is the bad guy now that, and that's basically how that playbook
Speaker 6:  worked. That's how the playbook works against Google. We scanned all the
Speaker 6:  books and made Google Books search and the evil authors Guild does not want
Speaker 6:  you to have it. And the judges were like, but these goofballs have slides
Speaker 6:  in their office. Right? Like YouTube is okay, even though you copied all
Speaker 6:  of South Park onto YouTube. Right? And the utility was so
Speaker 6:  high and the, the industry was so new and young and cute
Speaker 6:  that like they, they kind of, like Google in particular wrote a lot of the
Speaker 6:  fair use law here. Like they just litigated their way through a lot of fair
Speaker 6:  use law. And you can see that reflected, like Eric Schmidt
Speaker 6:  like gives talks at Stanford, which he tried to get taken down. We
Speaker 6:  wrote about it and he got tried to get taken down, but it's still up on YouTube.
Speaker 6:  We can go find it. He's like, here's what I would do. I would start an AI
Speaker 6:  company. I would fire out products until one hit and then when the lawsuits
Speaker 6:  came, I would just pay off the lawsuits. And it's like, oh, that's good.
Speaker 6:  You did, you would do Google. That's what Google did. And I
Speaker 6:  just don't think these companies are positioned the same way as Google in
Speaker 6:  the early two thousands. Right? Like this is,
Speaker 6:  here's anime nine 11 is just not the same product as
Speaker 6:  YouTube at first impression. And I, I don't know, I don't know what's gonna
Speaker 6:  happen here. I will like agree with David. The amount of usage
Speaker 6:  is off the charts. Like people love this shit. They love it.
Speaker 6:  And there's something to that that I, we talk about all the time.
Speaker 6:  You're in it, you're like, you're reporting on the companies, the
Speaker 6:  gap between how much the audience says they hate the tools and then
Speaker 6:  how much people are using the tools seems to get bigger every day.
Speaker 11:  Yes, yes. The commenters on my Ghibli posts are
Speaker 11:  so fun because they're arguing so intensely about, my favorite
Speaker 11:  comment is someone talking about fascism and then another
Speaker 11:  person who's like, I just think it's pretty That's perfect. That's perfect.
Speaker 11:  It's like the perfect VERGE audience comment section. But I think
Speaker 11:  that, yeah, it does get wider and you know,
Speaker 11:  this is a very silly thing, but I was just at a doctor's appointment and
Speaker 11:  all my doctors now use this AI scribe. So it takes notes and they
Speaker 11:  ask for permission and it just feels like this has become
Speaker 11:  truly like, permeated into our society. There's no way to
Speaker 11:  stop it. That's sort of the argument with the Ghibli thing. Like, artists
Speaker 11:  can't stop this, this is here, this is now we just
Speaker 11:  have to adapt. I'm not sure that's a fair argument. I would love Eli's legal
Speaker 11:  take. I was gonna ask what do you think happens? But you already said you
Speaker 11:  don't know.
Speaker 6:  Well, I think two things happen. I, I have this theory every time AI art
Speaker 6:  comes up this way and people use it and they go crazy for it. Like open eye,
Speaker 6:  their line is like the GPUs are melting. You know, like yes, they have all
Speaker 6:  this usage. First of all, they're not making a dollar on this usage, right?
Speaker 6:  Like they're just giving this away at 20 bucks a month. Like they're losing
Speaker 6:  money on this. Especially now that they're melting the GPUs. Like they're
Speaker 6:  already losing money now we're using even more compute.
Speaker 6:  You're we're losing more money. So I don't know what happens there, like
Speaker 6:  on its own. I don't know what, what's happening. I do have this like broader
Speaker 6:  like vergeer thesis that all of this technology is meant for us
Speaker 6:  to make art with and like the most human possible instinct
Speaker 6:  is to somehow communicate art and try to get people
Speaker 6:  to, to feel things. Yeah. Like Becky has like live laugh,
Speaker 6:  love ants, you know, like you go in the Midwest. Yeah. And I, I always
Speaker 6:  think about those. It's like, oh, they, this is a command. Like they
Speaker 6:  just want me to go in their kitchen and they're like laugh and like that's
Speaker 6:  how they want me to feel. Yeah. Right. Yeah. And like I have a lot of empathy.
Speaker 6:  I'm like, I, it's kind of blunt force like love, like
Speaker 6:  do it And they have a sign that says eat over the dining room table.
Speaker 11:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Eat. These are just instructions on like what to feel and ever
Speaker 6:  sleepy. You know, like that's all It is. Like it's, it's so human
Speaker 6:  to try to communicate what you want other people to feel. And
Speaker 6:  it's pretty hard to do that. Like, I don't have a 6-year-old and
Speaker 6:  like mostly what she wants me to feel is pain, I guess. Like, I don't know.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. There's something there. She's very sweet.
Speaker 6:  She kicks hard. That's all I'm saying.
Speaker 6:  But like, you see people get access to these tools and they're
Speaker 6:  able to communicate that emotional thing so much
Speaker 6:  easier and then they're into it.
Speaker 11:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And that to me that's the point. That's like you watch the original Steve
Speaker 6:  Jobs demo of Garage Band. That's the argument he's making about all
Speaker 6:  this stuff. Right? Right. And so people have cameras on their phones and
Speaker 6:  so like there's something very important there, but then there's also,
Speaker 6:  you shouldn't steal it from the people who figured out how to do it well.
Speaker 6:  Right. And that is by far the tension that I see.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I think make it easy for people to make things
Speaker 7:  is a very different argument from Make Rick
Speaker 7:  and Morty do nine 11. Right. Like I just, I I think the AI
Speaker 6:  Companies, I mean, did did make you feel feelings, David? I think
Speaker 7:  Love,
Speaker 7:  But I think, I think the AI companies would like you to believe that those
Speaker 7:  are the same thing. Right? Yeah. And that this is, and I think this really
Speaker 7:  comes also back to a lot of OpenAI says like running away
Speaker 7:  from guardrails. Like Yeah. The, all of these companies are basically like,
Speaker 7:  all we make is is sort of underlying technology. And what you do with this
Speaker 7:  good and bad is up to you. And that is, that is a thing they have to
Speaker 7:  put on society so that they don't have to put it on themselves. That like
Speaker 7:  the results of this black box are not our fault. All we built is the box.
Speaker 7:  What you do with It is up to you. Right. And that's very clearly what OpenAI
Speaker 7:  says is doing here. Like they've, they've tried to set up guardrails, they've
Speaker 7:  tried to do the right thing, they write long documents and then people make
Speaker 7:  Rick and Morty do nine 11 and now OpenAI says is like, that's your problem.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. You, you typed in the words what comes out is not our responsibility.
Speaker 11:  I saw someone say that the larger story isn't that you can make Ghibli.
Speaker 11:  Now the larger story is that they've just dropped their guardrails. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  And they're walking away from those guardrails very publicly and
Speaker 11:  like where does that line stop? Because clearly it hasn't,
Speaker 11:  you know, we were just talking about grok not that long ago,
Speaker 11:  making Kamala Harris with a gun and that was a bad thing. And
Speaker 11:  I just saw like a depiction of Korean Americans in the eighties holding
Speaker 11:  guns on rooftops, stirring the LA riots. Like,
Speaker 11:  I mean, like where is the line? It's, it seems
Speaker 11:  to blur more and more as they think that maybe this will make them
Speaker 11:  more money and get them more users. I'm not, I'm not sure.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I mean I, this is the same thing as meta walking away from content
Speaker 7:  moderation. Right? Like it's, it's just easier to say, this isn't our problem
Speaker 7:  than to take any kind of responsibility for it.
Speaker 11:  Right.
Speaker 6:  And this is where I will remind you once again, the only functional speech
Speaker 6:  regulation in this country is copyright law. It's the only thing that
Speaker 6:  regulates the internet. 'cause when Disney shows up and says, you stole the
Speaker 6:  Avengers, the court system is like, yep, jail. And it works
Speaker 6:  every time. Like without question, if, what is
Speaker 6:  the most, what is the most effective regulation on
Speaker 6:  YouTube that is built its own culture? Is copyright strikes Disney?
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's copyright strikes. It's using the music wrong. It's why is TikTok
Speaker 6:  full of weird sped up movies with that line down the center
Speaker 6:  to avoid the copyright filters that everyone agrees should exist. There's
Speaker 6:  no moral outrage about that filter. But if you do actual content moderation,
Speaker 6:  then there is moral outrage. And so you just, here's this problem,
Speaker 6:  right? Where OpenAI says isn't gonna make these choices,
Speaker 6:  this government is certainly not gonna make these choices. Or if
Speaker 6:  they do, it will be in the, the worst possible way and you'll be abducted
Speaker 6:  to El Salvador in the dead of night. That's weird. That's a thing
Speaker 6:  that we're comfortable doing. But like content moderation is not, so
Speaker 6:  the thing that will step in will be these copyright fights and they are
Speaker 6:  existential and everyone kind of glosses over them.
Speaker 7:  I had never thought about this until you said YouTube copyright strikes.
Speaker 7:  But I, I almost wonder if what these AI companies are gonna want is
Speaker 7:  a version of the same thing for these AI tools that doesn't say
Speaker 7:  OpenAI says is guilty of copyright problems. I am, when I
Speaker 7:  upload the, when I ask for a Studio Ghibli that's in their guidelines style
Speaker 7:  image's, right? I think OpenAI says, would really like that to be my problem.
Speaker 7:  And, and that Studio Ghibli or Disney or whoever can come after me and
Speaker 7:  not OpenAI says,
Speaker 11:  You can go to a copyright page at OpenAI says and report copyright and
Speaker 11:  infringers mul like people who have done it multiple times, they will
Speaker 11:  ban their account. That's what it says. So I mean, that is already in
Speaker 11:  motion.
Speaker 7:  I was just about to say that's one of the things that has been really successful
Speaker 7:  on YouTube is the like chilling effect that the possibility of copyright
Speaker 7:  strikes has every creator worries about this
Speaker 7:  all the time. Even like, even the possibility of of an incorrect copyright
Speaker 7:  strike can be a huge problem because it takes a long time to
Speaker 7:  litigate these things can be overzealous sometimes like it, and it's a huge
Speaker 7:  problem if you, if you get copyright strikes, you get demonetized, you get
Speaker 7:  kicked off the platform. Like you lose your living in a lot of ways. And
Speaker 7:  I, a system like that for AI content, boy
Speaker 7:  does that benefit the AI companies at the cost of everybody else.
Speaker 6:  But that's all rooted in the digital Millennium Copyright Act like
Speaker 6:  the safe, literally it's called the safe harbor in the
Speaker 6:  DMCA where by having notice and take down and copyright
Speaker 6:  strikes and all this system, YouTube doesn't have the liability for the
Speaker 6:  infringement. Right. The law says if you can build this mechanism where things
Speaker 6:  get taken down, you will avoid the liability for the cop infringement on
Speaker 6:  your platform. That doesn't make the same sense for OpenAI says, 'cause they
Speaker 6:  don't distribute it. Right? Like it's, it's weird to be like, I
Speaker 6:  will report this Mickey Mouse to OpenAI
Speaker 6:  says like, why you're, you're gonna distribute it on some other platform,
Speaker 6:  right? Yeah. So like they're using the law in a way, a way that doesn't make
Speaker 6:  any sense and none of that has anything to do with how much data have they
Speaker 6:  trained on? How much did they ingest to do the training, which is a real
Speaker 6:  problem. Yeah. With meta is getting in trouble every day because in
Speaker 6:  their court cases it's coming out, they tore into books to put
Speaker 6:  into the in Salas training and like that's just
Speaker 6:  copyright. Like, did you make a copy? Yes. Did you have permission? Definitely
Speaker 6:  not.
Speaker 11:  And the researchers are scared of it in the lawsuit. The researchers are
Speaker 11:  like, we shouldn't be doing this. Especially on company laptops.
Speaker 6:  It's like, yeah, I'm just, again, it's a copyright a stupid flow chart.
Speaker 6:  Did you make a copy? Yeah. Did you have permission? Well, it, you knew
Speaker 6:  you didn't, does it fit into one of these exceptions in fair use?
Speaker 6:  The judge has to decide and you're not exactly like a friendly
Speaker 6:  cuddly little kid anymore. Mark Zuckerberg, you're Mark Zuckerberg.
Speaker 6:  Like, good luck.
Speaker 11:  So the move is like, break the law until it changes for us. Is that
Speaker 11:  sort of the vibe,
Speaker 6:  The move? And I think I I I think this is just a a, a law of The
Speaker 6:  Vergecast. If you're young and cute, you should break the law as much as
Speaker 6:  you can. And then later on in life you should stop
Speaker 11:  Incredible. Both
Speaker 7:  As a, as a person and a company. I
Speaker 11:  Have some felonies I can pick up. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Exactly. You got time. If you're under 30, go nuts. You know, like, have
Speaker 6:  a good time. Perfect. And then later on in life, you know, settle down. I
Speaker 6:  think that's,
Speaker 7:  You buy a suit and, and you testify in front of Congress. That's,
Speaker 6:  And that's why whenever people get caught now they're like, he was young
Speaker 6:  and you're like, he's 45 years old. I dunno what you're talking about. That
Speaker 11:  Is a grown man.
Speaker 6:  Like that's just an adult. Like he, that's a house and
Speaker 6:  two kids and a mortgage. Like that's an adult. I don't know. I I don't know
Speaker 6:  what's gonna happen. I I I think the economic pressure on OpenAI says
Speaker 6:  is high. Like they, they have to be losing more money than they were yesterday
Speaker 6:  because of this tool. Yes. Right.
Speaker 7:  Are we sure that's true, Kylie? I I actually wanna know what you think about
Speaker 7:  this Kylie. Yeah. Because one of the other things that happened this week
Speaker 7:  was OpenAI says, said it expects to earn, was it $12.7 billion in
Speaker 7:  revenue? Yeah, that's a big number. I'm sure it comes underneath a much
Speaker 7:  bigger cost number because that's what OpenAI says is doing.
Speaker 7:  But this company seems to essentially be able to raise as much money as it
Speaker 7:  needs whenever it needs for any purposes whatsoever.
Speaker 7:  And I'm sort of at a point now where I'm like, maybe this company can just
Speaker 7:  capitalize itself forever. And, and all these numbers are fake and none of
Speaker 7:  it really matters. Where is your head with this stuff?
Speaker 11:  I agree because I'm more of an AI expert, the expert than I am
Speaker 11:  a finance expert. So when I see those numbers, I'm like, how, how is this
Speaker 11:  company not totally crumbling? Some of these AI leaders
Speaker 11:  will point to Amazon. They never turned a profit, but I mean they were doing
Speaker 11:  something more useful. I think
Speaker 11:  honestly,
Speaker 7:  Amazon took all of the money that it made and put it back in the company.
Speaker 7:  They didn't lose money on every single thing that they shifted That was not,
Speaker 7:  that was not the Amazon way.
Speaker 11:  Right. And I, I genuinely do think that OpenAI says
Speaker 11:  is okay with losing this amount of money. Maybe the new CFO
Speaker 11:  isn't, but it seems like Sam Altman is totally fine with it. And
Speaker 11:  I, I don't know where that stops and what happens to a company.
Speaker 11:  I've never seen a company like this. Their, their new valuation would be
Speaker 11:  $300 billion and they're not even close to profitable. They're losing billions
Speaker 11:  and billions every year and they only want to keep losing
Speaker 11:  more money for studio Ghibli renderings. That doesn't
Speaker 11:  make a ton of sense to me. And it does make me nervous, especially what
Speaker 11:  we saw with the deep seek moment and what that did to the markets. And Nvidia,
Speaker 11:  I, I worry that the OpenAI says bubble
Speaker 11:  will be really destructive, but I don't wanna scare anybody. I'm not sure.
Speaker 6:  Well, it's funny, I don't like, you know, the new image generation
Speaker 6:  features, they're not the promise. Right. The the promise is
Speaker 6:  in the reasoning models and the agentic stuff and the replace all of your
Speaker 6:  employees with, with this system and image generation might
Speaker 6:  be some component of that. But you see, it's not like the interest in
Speaker 6:  it and the hype around it. It has nothing to do with what might ultimately
Speaker 6:  justify the valuation. Right. And that seems like as big of a
Speaker 6:  disconnect as anything like, oh, this costs more money than it did yesterday.
Speaker 6:  It doesn't meaningfully bring us closer to earning all that money back.
Speaker 11:  Right. You still need users though. And they don't, the average person does
Speaker 11:  not care about a GI, they wanna make their daughter into a Studio Ghibli
Speaker 11:  character. Like they, they've gotta get somebody to subscribe and, and care.
Speaker 11:  And I feel that way about, you know, OpenAI says for a while it's like no
Speaker 11:  one cares about, you know, a very small sect of people in Silicon Valley
Speaker 11:  care about it being the best coder and, and getting a PhD in mathematics.
Speaker 11:  And I think these are important endeavors, but you know, Google is
Speaker 11:  baking it into every product. Meta is baking it into every
Speaker 11:  product. Whether that's a good thing or not, I'm not sure, but it, it seems
Speaker 11:  more real than a GI So make something people
Speaker 11:  want to use right now. Seems to be studio gli.
Speaker 7:  It's also like sneakily a really mainstream use case. Yeah. Like
Speaker 7:  it, it's, we've talked a lot about like none of these products are things
Speaker 7:  regular people are actually gonna want to do all the time. But you're right.
Speaker 7:  Like I can take my family portrait and make it into any style I want and
Speaker 7:  It is like compelling That's interesting to everybody.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I don't think a many people will pay 20 bucks a month for that for
Speaker 7:  the rest of their lives. But that is like, that is a genuinely mainstream
Speaker 7:  use case for AI in a way that even like helped me write my emails
Speaker 7:  isn't
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Also you can see it, right? That's, yeah, It is like we we're doing
Speaker 6:  the pixels left to right up to down is like a meaningful visual
Speaker 6:  improvement over regular diffusion. Yeah. I would just compare that to this
Speaker 6:  other headline which says, Google says its new reasoning, Gemini Am models
Speaker 6:  are the best one yet. It's like most people can't evaluate slightly better
Speaker 6:  reasoning.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. They
Speaker 6:  Can say that it looks different. Like Microsoft is adding
Speaker 6:  reasoning to copilot AI for research and data. Like great. Is it
Speaker 6:  better than it was yesterday? Right.
Speaker 7:  This is, this is one of the things Kylie and I always enjoy talking about
Speaker 7:  is this like endless race where every 15 minutes somebody makes the best
Speaker 7:  model that has ever been made in history. Yes. And It is, it wins
Speaker 7:  all It is at the top of every leaderboard for somewhere
Speaker 7:  between an hour and a week and then It is not anymore. And I think
Speaker 7:  this, this week was there, there were like three of them that they were like,
Speaker 7:  this is the best model we've ever made. Right. And Google, Google and Open,
Speaker 7:  is it Google and OpenAI says that are obsessively trying to like front run
Speaker 7:  each other's announcements. Yes. With an It's so fun.
Speaker 11:  It's so fun. It's so fun. When I saw, you know, I got the OpenAI says
Speaker 11:  announcement and then the Google announcement came in, I thought, oh my
Speaker 11:  God, they're back at it again. What? Like it's the most pointless thing.
Speaker 11:  And what's even funnier is I have all these people's tweet notifications
Speaker 11:  turned on and I was watching Demis do some
Speaker 11:  retweets that were like Subtweeting OpenAI says and saying like, oh, well
Speaker 11:  we already had image generation and blah blah blah before they had even
Speaker 11:  properly announced it. And I thought, wow, you guys are petty. And it's,
Speaker 11:  it's like such a useless, the average consumer does not notice this
Speaker 11:  does not care, you know?
Speaker 6:  No, but It is good to know that you can be a billionaire Nobel Prize
Speaker 6:  winner and still be just furiously subtweeting your competition
Speaker 7:  On that. Turns out Twitter breaks your brain no matter who you are. Yes.
Speaker 7:  Like that is, that is the great lesson of our times is that Twitter will
Speaker 7:  destroy you no matter who or what you are.
Speaker 6:  When we get to a GI, we'll finally take this app off our phones.
Speaker 7:  That's the goal. I do think I, there's one trend inside of all of this that
Speaker 7:  I think is really interesting, which is that everybody is getting really
Speaker 7:  comfortable making slower products. And we were on this
Speaker 7:  race for a while where everything had to be fast and everybody was obsessed
Speaker 7:  with latency and everybody was like, how do we make, you know, smaller, better,
Speaker 7:  quicker models, everything should be instant. And feedback is, and now everybody's
Speaker 7:  like, we're gonna build a deep reasoning model that is going to take its
Speaker 7:  time and it's gonna think and it's gonna show you that it's thinking and
Speaker 7:  it's gonna take a while and it's gonna happen step by step. But then at the
Speaker 7:  end it's gonna say true things and not lies. And
Speaker 7:  that is we've just like hard turned into, it's okay if this takes a
Speaker 7:  while because the product is going to be better. And that is like so completely
Speaker 7:  different than the conversations I was having with AI people even like a
Speaker 7:  year ago who were like, speed is everything. Yes. We have to make this stuff
Speaker 7:  real time. It has to be fast or else nobody's gonna use it. And It is like,
Speaker 7:  we've just gone all the way away from that.
Speaker 6:  Right. 'cause lying fast turned out to not be a great product. Right. Right.
Speaker 6:  I think they, they we'll come back to speed once they solve the, like, is
Speaker 6:  it good enough?
Speaker 11:  Right.
Speaker 7:  That might be true. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But I, I think that this is useless. Does not being useless fast
Speaker 6:  does not get you what what anybody needs to keep the promises that
Speaker 6:  they're, they're making.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I just always enjoy, every time somebody talks about deep reasoning,
Speaker 7:  I just hear slow. Yes.
Speaker 11:  And it's, that's when they, when they ask me about the, like the new reasoning
Speaker 11:  powering images, my first question was like, is this slower? And they said
Speaker 11:  Yes, but I think people are gonna enjoy the product and it, it won't matter
Speaker 11:  was their answer. And it's Yeah. Wild.
Speaker 7:  It turns out it's fine. Right. Like turns out it's, and and, and they're
Speaker 7:  learning how to build product that like shows you the slowness, right. Where
Speaker 7:  they're like, it, it, it shows you the turns in its thinking. And part of
Speaker 7:  that is, is to like help you understand whatever. But part of that is also
Speaker 7:  to like give you something to do while it's slow and all of the
Speaker 7:  sort of affordances these things are getting so that they can be slow so
Speaker 7:  that they can not lie to you all the time is just fascinating. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  The the best part though is people putting in a prompt that it
Speaker 11:  should not generate and it starts generating and you see a sliver of
Speaker 11:  the, the band content before it stops. And that makes for
Speaker 11:  incredible means. Unfortunately. That's,
Speaker 7:  That's very good.
Speaker 6:  Well that's happening less and less apparently.
Speaker 11:  Right.
Speaker 6:  Do you think Open Eyes is gonna react to this? Right? Like Sam Altman is
Speaker 6:  saying, yeah, this is, I shouldn't be this person. Like
Speaker 6:  all my life's work has ended with this picture. And then Opening Eye had
Speaker 6:  some reactions saying we should, we don't want this to happen as much. There
Speaker 6:  is the looming copyright threat. Do you think they're gonna to pull back
Speaker 6:  on this a little bit?
Speaker 11:  Right. Someone made the joke about how he's like doing the legal back flips
Speaker 11:  He did after the Scar Joe stuff. The Scarlet Johansson stuff.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. I think that they're seeing, you know, Sam made this, his profile
Speaker 11:  picture. He made a Studio Ghibli profile picture and he said, can everyone
Speaker 11:  make me a better one so they're not shying away from it. And, and the email
Speaker 11:  they sent me, they're like, we encourage and we love to see all these renditions
Speaker 11:  and something that was really weird and their statement was,
Speaker 11:  you know, we don't allow the recreation
Speaker 11:  of art from living artists. And I'm like, the Studio
Speaker 11:  Ghibli co-founder is still alive.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Miyazaki's alive and he hates ai. Yeah. He's so just tweeting about
Speaker 6:  how much he,
Speaker 7:  This
Speaker 11:  It's, so, I so putting that aside,
Speaker 11:  I think that they are leaning into this until they get a seasoned desist
Speaker 11:  is my guess.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I mean they have to right, they have to keep saying this is okay. Yes. 'cause
Speaker 7:  if if they start apologizing it all falls apart.
Speaker 11:  Exactly. Exactly. It's much like what's happening with signal
Speaker 11:  messages if we start admitting things. Indeed.
Speaker 7:  Which, which we'll get to. But there is one, one more AI thing I wanna talk
Speaker 7:  about and then we should probably take a break because we all need a break
Speaker 7:  before we get into Signal. Is Perplexity gonna buy TikTok?
Speaker 11:  Oh wow. You know, I've, I've gotten not
Speaker 11:  so nice notes saying that I should really believe that they're
Speaker 11:  doing that. No. Can you imagine TikTok taking
Speaker 11:  Perplexity seriously? Some analysts think that
Speaker 11:  TikTok, their US operations will sell between 30 to
Speaker 11:  $50 billion in TikTok or in Perplexity is valued at
Speaker 11:  about 18 billion. And also those are
Speaker 11:  kind of made up numbers when it comes to a startup that's a GPT wrapper.
Speaker 11:  I'm, I'm not trying to be mean, but like realistically, how, how would they
Speaker 11:  actually buy TikTok? It would be great for them. Much better for Perplexity
Speaker 11:  than I think TikTok ultimately. We'll see, I
Speaker 11:  would be, that would be the best day on my job on
Speaker 11:  the internet if that actually happens.
Speaker 6:  True.
Speaker 6:  I mean I've definitely seen other companies be like, we're gonna put this
Speaker 6:  on the blockchain. Like, you know, everyone's got dreams.
Speaker 11:  Sure. Everybody's got dreams.
Speaker 7:  I mean, It is funny 'cause in a, in a more normal
Speaker 7:  political moment, it would be much more likely that TikTok
Speaker 7:  would just quickly buy Perplexity and then make it like it's search
Speaker 7:  products be like, we're really leaning into search on TikTok.
Speaker 7:  Just do that.
Speaker 6:  Do you think the Perplexity CEO is sitting there searching like, how to get
Speaker 6:  TikTok to do reverse buyout or I become CEO EO of TikTok.
Speaker 6:  Like if you got the AI product, you might as well just ask the question.
Speaker 7:  That's true. Yeah. It, it might know
Speaker 6:  How to end up CEO of TikTok.
Speaker 7:  I mean it turns out if, if you say things out loud enough, sometimes
Speaker 6:  They happen. Make Studio Glibly picture of me, A CEO of TikTok.
Speaker 11:  I too am seeking $40 billion to be this TikTok.
Speaker 6:  CEOI would, I think I'd be a great TikTok, CEO just based on my algorithm
Speaker 6:  at one. All right. We should take a break. I, Kyle, I think you're,
Speaker 6:  you're on the side of this is not happening for Perplexity.
Speaker 11:  No, I don't think so.
Speaker 6:  But if you have a document that says It is, if you have a document that says
Speaker 6:  JD Vance has seriously considered Perplexity buying
Speaker 6:  TikTok 'cause apparently he's in charge of the deal, Kylie's email is available.
Speaker 6:  Send send it to us. We're
Speaker 7:  Just hit, hit up JD on Signal and let us know. Nobody says we gotta
Speaker 6:  Take a break.
Speaker 11:  Add me to your group chats.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, please. All right. We'll be back. Lightning around
Speaker 6:  All right, we're back. The lightning round unsponsored
Speaker 6:  for flavor.
Speaker 7:  Thank you to everybody who has sent us t-shirt designs. Some of them have
Speaker 7:  been very good. We will make this t-shirt. I like. I don't know when,
Speaker 7:  I don't know how much it'll cost, but like I, I'm willing to say on the record,
Speaker 7:  we will make this t-shirt. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It's a lot. It's it just the word putting the word flavor on a t-shirt just
Speaker 6:  opens you up to all kinds of situations and we'll just,
Speaker 6:  we'll just figure it out. I will say, I would like to continue reminding
Speaker 6:  people that even when we are sponsored, the whole point of our ethics policy
Speaker 6:  is you can't tell us what to do. Which I would compare to
Speaker 6:  the universe of brand deals that happen elsewhere in the media
Speaker 6:  where people often get told what to do and you just can't do that. You no
Speaker 6:  amount of money will, will make me say nice things about you. I'm
Speaker 7:  Sorry. Well, that's the important thing about being unsponsored for flavor
Speaker 7:  is that it actually doesn't mean anything. Nothing changes. Right.
Speaker 6:  I I do like that it implies that some people are sponsored for less flavor.
Speaker 6:  Sure, sure. Right. Like there's an, there's
Speaker 6:  an implied comparison there that says, oh, less flavor when
Speaker 6:  you have, when you have the brand deals. So
Speaker 7:  Maybe our t-shirt comes with stickers that you can, it covers the UN
Speaker 7:  and then adds a less when you
Speaker 6:  Do get sponsored. Right. I think instead of, you know, those like boring
Speaker 6:  social media badges that are like PON may contain
Speaker 6:  advertising. It should just say sponsored with less flavor.
Speaker 6:  Like that might communicate more about what's happening to the media industry.
Speaker 7:  Well I kind of like the idea that actually we go the other way and everything
Speaker 7:  that's not sponsored has like a blinking red light that says flavor
Speaker 7:  and everything that is sponsored doesn't get to have cool light that says
Speaker 7:  flavor. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Alright, well speaking of flavor and spiciness,
Speaker 6:  it's time. David.
Speaker 7:  Oh my god. America's favorite. It's a top two podcaster than a podcast.
Speaker 7:  Based on the emails that I get from people every single week,
Speaker 7:  it's time for Brendan Carr Is a Dummy
Speaker 6:  By the way. People are starting to send us theme music. If you have ideas
Speaker 6:  for Brendan Carr Is a Dummy theme music, send 'em in, we'll start running
Speaker 6:  'em. Absolutely. We need some variety. But I'm, I'm, I'm happy to see that
Speaker 6:  the podcast within a podcast is beginning to take on a life of its own.
Speaker 7:  And it has real momentum. It does real momentum. Brendan Carr Is a Dummy.
Speaker 6:  So does Brendan in his unconstitutional nonsense that he does
Speaker 6:  every single week. Brendan Carr, chairman of the FCC this week
Speaker 6:  outta nowhere said he was gonna investigate Disney.
Speaker 6:  That's everybody wants
Speaker 7:  To investigate Disney.
Speaker 6:  That's what I got for you. He gave an interview to Punchbowl News.
Speaker 6:  It's on YouTube, it's just like a podcast interview. And he says
Speaker 6:  he's, he's putting the finishing touches on a letter announcing his efforts
Speaker 6:  to investigate Disney's DEI practices, which similar to his
Speaker 6:  efforts against Comcast and Verizon. This is because Disney
Speaker 6:  had a shareholder vote on continuing its DEI practices. And the
Speaker 6:  shareholders voted to continue them because it
Speaker 6:  turns out having a wide applicant pool for your open roles
Speaker 6:  at things like parks is good. Just like I
Speaker 6:  I, and again, I will point this out, Comcast investor in rock mute, they
Speaker 6:  do not like me. This is not a thing, but there's your disclosure. They invest
Speaker 6:  in our company, Comcast being remaining committed to
Speaker 6:  DEI is because it has a huge physical plant. Like it has wires in the ground,
Speaker 6:  it hires installers like it needs a big net of how it
Speaker 6:  hires and who it puts in the field is customer service. 'cause its
Speaker 6:  customers are everyone Disney's customers. The parks are everyone. Like it
Speaker 6:  makes sense that you would wanna keep the applicant
Speaker 6:  pools wide open at the top of the company, at the bottom of the company,
Speaker 6:  all the way up and down. It makes sense. And so Brendan just
Speaker 6:  wants to chill the speech of Disney, which owns a b, C news. Right.
Speaker 6:  Which already settled a case with Donald Trump
Speaker 6:  about definition saying they were gonna give $15 million to Trump's presidential
Speaker 6:  library.
Speaker 7:  That was the, was that the George Stephanopoulos case? Yep.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Which George Stephanopoulos did not want to settle, but Disney
Speaker 6:  caved. So you just see, even when you cave to these
Speaker 6:  bullies, the pressure remains. And that's happening right now with
Speaker 6:  universities and law firms. Right. You, you see Columbia caved and the pressures
Speaker 6:  still on you. You can see that Paul Weiss, the law firm caved and
Speaker 6:  the pressure is still on. It doesn't work. You, you gotta hit the bully
Speaker 6:  back and Brendan is nothing if not a bully. And
Speaker 6:  so just saying gleefully, I'm gonna
Speaker 6:  investigate Disney for no reason and saying gleefully, any
Speaker 6:  businesses that are looking for FCC approval, I would encourage them to get
Speaker 6:  busy ending any sort of their invidious forms of DEI discrimination.
Speaker 6:  So he's already saying is that a,
Speaker 7:  That's a quote quote that's like a real thing he said out loud.
Speaker 6:  That's what said, he said that out loud. And what he's saying is,
Speaker 6:  before I even evaluate the legality of your merger or the ideas
Speaker 6:  that you might have about what you might wanna do with your companies, if
Speaker 6:  you need my approval, I need you to do some racism. Right. Like
Speaker 6:  straightforwardly. Yeah. And that's power. That's chilling speech. That
Speaker 6:  is just inappropriate. And then on top of that, this week when I say
Speaker 6:  he's a bully,
Speaker 6:  he's investigating CBS for the 60 minutes edit, which we have
Speaker 6:  talked about before. Which is a very straightforward, they did a long interview
Speaker 6:  with Kamala Harris. They edit it one way for one program, they edit it another
Speaker 6:  way for another program that's normal. And you now the whole clip is out
Speaker 6:  and you can see that it didn't actually make any substantive edits and you
Speaker 6:  can disagreeing on it.
Speaker 7:  There's a lot of stupid cases on the, in this universe. This
Speaker 7:  this is one of the stupidest ones if you ask me.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And you know, Brendan bullied CBS, they released the full unedited
Speaker 6:  clip and you can see with your own eyes, you don't have to agree with me.
Speaker 6:  You can see that no substantive change was made of that answer. Yep. They
Speaker 6:  just cut it differently for two different programs. Right.
Speaker 7:  They used one part over here and one part over there. Yeah. Which is called
Speaker 7:  editing.
Speaker 6:  That's
Speaker 7:  Like what if, what if movie trailers were illegal?
Speaker 6:  I assure you that editing occurs. Right. If only we edited the show
Speaker 6:  this week because that case is open as a pending investigation at the
Speaker 6:  FCC. A bunch of former FCC commissioners
Speaker 6:  from Republican and Democratic presidential administrations have written
Speaker 6:  a letter they put into the docket. This is inappropriate.
Speaker 6:  So Oliver Darcy, who's front of The Verge front of the show report on this,
Speaker 6:  we'll link link to it, but he is got Alfred Sykes. But
Speaker 6:  he notes that in this letter, Alfred Sykes, who's the former Republican
Speaker 6:  chairman of the SEC Irvin Dugan, who is a democratic commissioner appointed
Speaker 6:  by George HW Bush, Gloria Tristani, who Bill Clinton appointed,
Speaker 6:  and Tom Wheeler, who I know who served under Barack Obama is the chairman.
Speaker 6:  We've all signed on this letter and they say it's highly unusual for Carr
Speaker 6:  to take the case up against CBS. He opened the matter without any real
Speaker 6:  explanation for reconsidering his prior decision and said,
Speaker 6:  this sets a chilling precedent. Here's a quote by reopening this complaint.
Speaker 6:  The commission is signaling to broadcasters that it will indeed act at the
Speaker 6:  behest of the White House by closely scrutinizing the content of news coverage
Speaker 6:  and threatening the licenses of broadcasters whose outlets produce coverage
Speaker 6:  that does not pass muster in the president's view. That is
Speaker 6:  a big bipartisan spanning time set
Speaker 6:  of former SEC commissioners and chairs saying, you're doing some illegal
Speaker 6:  chilling of speech, you're doing some censorship. Okay, maybe you disagree
Speaker 6:  with him. Maybe you don't agree with me. But I'm telling you b Brendan Carr
Speaker 6:  Is a Dummy and a bully. And this is how he responded to
Speaker 6:  Oliver Darcy asking him for comment on this. He sent him a Doctor evil
Speaker 6:  meme that just says, how about no Jesus but Dr. Evil
Speaker 6:  from Austin Powers. It's just a gif. It says, how about no,
Speaker 6:  not a substantive response to former chairs of the
Speaker 6:  FCC former commissioners of the FCC saying, we're worried about this.
Speaker 6:  The chilling of speech, the precedent you are setting by reopening
Speaker 6:  this case without any explanation. He's sending out doctor evil memes.
Speaker 6:  'cause he is a fundamentally unserious piece of shit.
Speaker 7:  Yep. It's such useful proof that all of this stuff is happening in bad faith.
Speaker 7:  Right. Like it's, it, I am endlessly willing to
Speaker 7:  entertain arguments made in good faith. And this administration has made
Speaker 7:  so abundantly clear that none of this shit is being done in good
Speaker 7:  faith. No one, they're not trying to do the right thing. No one believes
Speaker 7:  any of this. They just, it's some combination of their idiots and they think
Speaker 7:  it's funny and they want to Yeah. And that's it.
Speaker 6:  And it there there's just this endless search for power and how to use it
Speaker 6:  and how to make other people feel bad. And I look,
Speaker 6:  we've wrestled with who should do the content moderation. How should you
Speaker 6:  do it? How do you keep kids on the internet safe? Is it even appropriate
Speaker 6:  for the government to have these rules? I have looked Barack Obama in the
Speaker 6:  eye on decoder. You can go watch the video and said, aren't you trying to
Speaker 6:  get around the First Amendment? And had him try to answer that question.
Speaker 6:  I don't think he gave a very good answer.
Speaker 6:  We we're in it. We've been covering this stuff for years and to
Speaker 6:  have real concerns about government overreach into
Speaker 6:  speech regulations met with Dr. Evil memes is
Speaker 6:  just wildly inappropriate. It is disrespectful to the American people. It
Speaker 6:  is on the line of you are a trader to the constitution. So Brendan,
Speaker 6:  every week I say this. I know, I know you're listening. I know, I know. You
Speaker 6:  get the notes. Come on the show. Come on this show. Come on decoder.
Speaker 6:  You can argue with an AI if you want to, you will lose because you are wrong.
Speaker 6:  But the, the door is always open because I,
Speaker 6:  I think you should be held to account for the decisions you're making and
Speaker 6:  the fundamental unseriousness with which you are taking the first amendment.
Speaker 6:  That's been Brendan Carr had done
Speaker 7:  Hit us up on signal. Brendan we'll be here.
Speaker 6:  Alright.
Speaker 7:  We we're like a hundred years into this podcast and we have not talked about
Speaker 7:  the only thing anyone has been talking about, the joke
Speaker 6:  That we open the show with.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Should we just talk about this briefly?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean there's, there's a lot to say. There's almost nothing to say.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 7:  That's, that's where I'm at too. So just
Speaker 7:  to like, if I can just very briefly recap what happened here. So Jeffrey
Speaker 7:  Goldberg, the editor in Chief of the Atlantic, got added in
Speaker 7:  some way that I am still desperately trying to figure out to a signal
Speaker 7:  group chat that included a bunch of people very high up in the government,
Speaker 7:  including Secretary of Defense, Pete Hegseth and Vice President JD Vance,
Speaker 7:  and a bunch of other people in which they just planned
Speaker 7:  attacks. And, and Jeffrey Goldberg writes this story being like,
Speaker 7:  they planned attacks and signal and they added me to it. Everyone in the
Speaker 7:  government denied it was like, this isn't classified. None of that happened.
Speaker 7:  We didn't do any attack planning and signal. He's a liar.
Speaker 7:  So they just posted the chats. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  By the way, the move here just editor in chief wise
Speaker 6:  gold. Like gold, right?
Speaker 7:  Oh, spectacular.
Speaker 6:  You say I I didn't publish everything. 'cause I know it's classified sensitive
Speaker 6:  military information. The government says, screw you, nothing sensitive,
Speaker 6:  nothing classified was shared. And you say here's all of it. And you just
Speaker 6:  know he had that in his backlog.
Speaker 7:  Yes. So, which I will give him credit for because one of the things that
Speaker 7:  a lot of people have been talking about this week is, why did my man leave
Speaker 7:  the group chat? Which I agree with. Frankly, I would've stayed
Speaker 7:  in that group chat. I would've just, you just sit quietly and just, just
Speaker 7:  watch the group chat happen. But he did take some screenshots before he left
Speaker 7:  the group chat. And, and I I respect the hell outta that. You gotta take
Speaker 7:  your screenshots.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean I think you leave once you think that you have information that
Speaker 6:  would be illegal for you to have,
Speaker 7:  Is it illegal if they add you to the group chat.
Speaker 6:  So this is, this is the complication here. Right. And
Speaker 6:  you know, we're, we're all the way down to this story where the President
Speaker 6:  Trump is like, maybe signal is defective and he keeps using the word defective,
Speaker 6:  which is like very funny in
Speaker 7:  This context. I'll say everything that President Trump says suggests to me
Speaker 7:  that he has no idea what has actually,
Speaker 6:  At one point he referred to this group chat as a call. He said he got added
Speaker 6:  to the call
Speaker 7:  And he keeps referring to the signal being bad. And it's like my guy that's
Speaker 7:  not,
Speaker 6:  This is how he keeps putting black people and his, his secretary of housing
Speaker 6:  in Urban Development says, urban in It is true. That's real.
Speaker 6:  He thinks the signal's bad. And why he keeps mentioning Hannibal
Speaker 6:  Lecter in the context of asylum because he thinks it's saying it's very good.
Speaker 6:  Trump notably in this context, the most like
Speaker 6:  dead ahead, trustworthy person talking. 'cause he
Speaker 6:  is like, that was bad. I had nothing to do. Yeah, it's true. He's like, I
Speaker 6:  dunno what they're talking about. That wasn't me. And he, you're like, yeah,
Speaker 6:  that wasn't you. I, I don't think you know how to use signal, but he has
Speaker 6:  claimed that it's defective. There's some amount of like what Signal hacked
Speaker 6:  is a deflection. Elon Musk now is gonna investigate how this
Speaker 6:  happened. And the answer is, Mike Waltz added Jeffrey Goldberg
Speaker 6:  to the signal chat. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  It's right there. That's happened
Speaker 6:  In the screenshots. Yeah. 'cause it's in the screenshot. Yeah. And maybe
Speaker 6:  he shares in initial roles with somebody else. Maybe he got the wrong
Speaker 6:  2 0 2 area code number. 'cause everyone's in DC and
Speaker 6:  that's the area code. I don't know how it happened, but he did it. It's not
Speaker 6:  a mystery.
Speaker 7:  Right?
Speaker 6:  Like that's how Signal works. And maybe signals interface could be clear.
Speaker 6:  But he did it. He did the thing and then they had that conversation, which
Speaker 6:  is inappropriate to have in Signal. I think that much is clear as well. There
Speaker 6:  are are classified systems that are meant for that kind of communication.
Speaker 7:  Potentially illegal to have in signal No,
Speaker 6:  Potentially illegal. Right. To not use the classified systems for the,
Speaker 6:  the kind of conversation they're having now. There's this very tired semantic
Speaker 6:  argument about the difference between war plans and attack plans. Right.
Speaker 6:  But all of this is like, yeah, it's a tech story. 'cause it's a, it's signal.
Speaker 7:  They just did it in a group chat.
Speaker 6:  Well, I'm saying the, the, the term that I'm worried about is they're gonna
Speaker 6:  be like, signal's not safe. We're we need to break its encryption.
Speaker 7:  Oh, interesting. Right.
Speaker 6:  That, that's the term that I've just been on Red Alert for. That makes it
Speaker 6:  like really a story.
Speaker 7:  Well, it's, it's tricky though because It is, It is clearly
Speaker 7:  a thing that they are using on purpose because A, it's encrypted and b it
Speaker 7:  disappears. Right? Like they, they had, yeah, they had message retention
Speaker 7:  limits in the group chat on purpose, which is again, not a thing you're allowed
Speaker 7:  to do as a government official doing official business. But It is like, clearly
Speaker 7:  what's going on here.
Speaker 6:  And there's another part of this that's, you know, you can make the argument
Speaker 6:  that signals safer than it used to be because they have to keep making the
Speaker 6:  argument that it was safe because it's encrypted and can't be backdoored.
Speaker 6:  And, and now you can't go and attack it.
Speaker 7:  Oh, interesting. So they, they've kind of painted themselves into a corner.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So I don't, I don't know. But the, the thing that I'm always nervous
Speaker 6:  about is how will governments find ways to attack encryption?
Speaker 6:  And here you have this thing, here's this mess.
Speaker 6:  And then the person with the big hammer, like the FBI with the big hammer
Speaker 6:  that says we shouldn't have encryption. Well, it could be up like, do you
Speaker 6:  have a nail that looks like a huge nail?
Speaker 6:  That's, it's just always a thing that's on the back of my mind that I should
Speaker 6:  be worried about. Like, will the government try to get rid of encryption
Speaker 6:  because of this?
Speaker 7:  So the argument is like Jeffrey Goldberg hacked his way into signal. Thus
Speaker 7:  signal is not safe anyway. Thus we
Speaker 7:  should break the encryption.
Speaker 6:  Or the argument is we can't know because signal's encrypted and that's the
Speaker 6:  law enforcement problem. Oh, I, we have, we can't possibly arrest Jeffrey
Speaker 6:  Goldberg because there's no evidence because of this encryption.
Speaker 7:  Our buddy big balls at DOS couldn't figure it out because he couldn't get
Speaker 7:  by the encryption.
Speaker 6:  It's very bad. The, this whole situation's very bad. And then like the Trump
Speaker 6:  administration, like just trying to power through it by
Speaker 6:  saying the things that are obvious are not obvious. Right. It's bad.
Speaker 6:  Like all of that's bad. And It is all centered on this app. That, that
Speaker 6:  I hope the Signal Foundation can withstand the pressure.
Speaker 7:  It, I will say the Signal Foundation so far has responded to this very well.
Speaker 7:  Which is like, they, they have mostly been very funny about it. And
Speaker 7:  also it sounds like downloads have spiked. I think I, in a, in
Speaker 7:  a funny way, one very possible outcome of this is that if the
Speaker 7:  government's gonna use it to do attack planning, it's probably pretty
Speaker 7:  safe. Like they're, if if they're in here doing the
Speaker 7:  group chats, they, that's a lot of trust to have from a lot of very senior
Speaker 7:  people. But then at the same time, this is a fundamentally unserious group
Speaker 7:  of people. And the other thing Wired went and found that Mike
Speaker 7:  Waltz's Venmo friend list was public. And it's like,
Speaker 7:  this is just, this is not a group of people who is smart and
Speaker 7:  thoughtful and doing a good job. No.
Speaker 6:  Like, can we just run the Marco Rubio audio because
Speaker 6:  you know, they all do press conferences and I think the Atlantic timed
Speaker 6:  this stuff when they knew that t Gabbard and Mike
Speaker 6:  Waltz would be in front of Congress. 'cause they had hearings in the Senate
Speaker 6:  in the house. So there was just all these moments for people to talk.
Speaker 6:  But it's Marco Rubio who was in the chat, who I think his
Speaker 6:  response, It is just such a perfect, it just run the audio. You,
Speaker 6:  you'll see what I'm saying.
Speaker 15:  And you know, so I can speak to myself or my presence on it. I think my,
Speaker 15:  my role I on it was just speaking for my role. I,
Speaker 16:  That's it. That's the, that's just, just
Speaker 6:  A primal scream of like help,
Speaker 16:  Like I'm in danger.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that's good. Look, the story's gonna keep playing
Speaker 6:  out. The, the thing that I think we're, we're gonna stay focused on, it's
Speaker 6:  like encrypted messaging is important. Encryption is important.
Speaker 6:  Elon Musk is gonna somehow investigate this. Now I do love
Speaker 6:  that they've landed on, Elon will fix It is though
Speaker 6:  he's good at computers. It is like that, that's how they're treating it here.
Speaker 6:  And it's like, I think the military is good at keeping its
Speaker 6:  information.
Speaker 7:  This ends with like e Elon telling lies about dms
Speaker 7:  on X and suddenly that's where the war planning happens. That's where
Speaker 7:  this goes. I just wanna shout out to our friends at 4 0 4 media who wrote
Speaker 7:  a story about all this and their headline is when your threat model is being
Speaker 7:  a moron. And I think that sums it up all pre
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think that's correct. Speaking of Elon, we got a big Alex Heath scoop
Speaker 6:  that we should mention briefly in the lightning round. We kind of knew this
Speaker 6:  was happening, but Alex nailed it down. Elon is very mad
Speaker 6:  about content moderation on Reddit. He's mad about two things. One which
Speaker 6:  is totally justified. He is mad that there are death threats about him on
Speaker 6:  Reddit. And he apparently has been communicating those
Speaker 6:  directly to Steve Hoffman, Reddit to you. The other thing he is mad about
Speaker 6:  is many, many subreddits have banned links to X Right.
Speaker 6:  Which Reddit hasn't done anything about yet, but there's a lot of, I would
Speaker 6:  say user drama, moderator drama about what Reddit might be doing, how it
Speaker 6:  might be promoting these subreddits, how it might be coming and doing moderation
Speaker 6:  over the top against this perceived pressure. So far it
Speaker 6:  doesn't seem like they've made any subreddits have links to X
Speaker 6:  like that hasn't been the line they've crossed, but there's a lot of ing.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. How much pressure is Elon putting on the top and how much is that pressure
Speaker 6:  being reflected on the user experience of Reddit? And that's
Speaker 6:  as always, that's bad.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And I would say a, it's not at all surprising and b It is very
Speaker 7:  funny because this is like, like for a man who styles himself a free
Speaker 7:  speech warrior, like here It is. Yeah. It's, it's like, this
Speaker 7:  is so of a piece for me with the thing that Elon Musk has decided,
Speaker 7:  it's, it should be illegal not to advertise on X. That It is just
Speaker 7:  like, we're just so deep down all of these rabbit
Speaker 7:  holes where it's like you can't possibly think what you
Speaker 7:  just said out loud that it's like every subreddit should be required to
Speaker 7:  link to X. It's like, no, that's not how
Speaker 7:  any of this
Speaker 6:  Works. That's
Speaker 7:  Just not how any of this works. And, and yeah, and I think
Speaker 7:  the, the Reddit side of It is interesting because I think there is a sort
Speaker 7:  of ongoing fundamental mistrust on those three levels. Like the
Speaker 7:  users don't trust the mods and the admins, the mods don't trust the
Speaker 7:  admins. And the admins don't trust anybody. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And so
Speaker 7:  It's just like, this has always been a group of people who are all suspicious
Speaker 7:  of each other. So as soon as things like this come up, everybody is looking
Speaker 7:  for like any little thing that happens. And
Speaker 7:  like there was a, was it white people Twitter that that got,
Speaker 7:  that was like briefly banned. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  72 hour
Speaker 7:  Ban because of that was a place that a lot of the, the conversation about
Speaker 7:  Doge employees and the threats were being made. And there's, there's now
Speaker 7:  pretty clearly a link back to Elon Musk from that.
Speaker 7:  This is just, it's, it's both absurd in exactly the way you would expect
Speaker 7:  and like a truly terrible look for everyone involved.
Speaker 6:  There's also just some real fear of Elon here. Like if you run a
Speaker 6:  competitor to Twitter, which by all accounts, you know, Reddit is
Speaker 6:  you, your answer should be go run your own social network. That's the answer.
Speaker 6:  We're gonna run ours our way and you run yours.
Speaker 7:  I mean, I think back to like the first Trump administration when
Speaker 7:  there was so much happening because people were afraid
Speaker 7:  that if they didn't do it or did do it or whatever, Donald Trump would tweet
Speaker 7:  about it. And I think Elon Musk wields that same thing now,
Speaker 7:  right? Like there there's been a Trump's like
Speaker 7:  truth social presence, social people pay attention to it, but it doesn't
Speaker 7:  carry the weight that his, his Twitter account once did. But Elon Musk sure
Speaker 7:  does. Like yeah, he tweets a million times a day. But It is like, he is
Speaker 7:  somebody who can direct a lot of attention toward whatever he
Speaker 7:  wants. And that is like, it, it just feels like a behavior he learned by
Speaker 7:  watching Donald Trump in his last campaign and administration.
Speaker 6:  But I feel like if Elon was like Reddit is being mean to me, go attack Reddit,
Speaker 6:  Reddit's users would be capable of waging their own fight.
Speaker 6:  So like that's true of all the communities in the United, they would be like,
Speaker 6:  no, we're we're very capable on our own. Right.
Speaker 7:  Like come at me bro. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. We're, we're good actually. We'll see. I just, you just see that pressure.
Speaker 6:  It's good scoop from Alex. Yeah. We'll see how that, those dynamics keep
Speaker 6:  playing out. Speaking of social networks that have problems
Speaker 6:  to TikTok still in the news, David, you keep pointing out that
Speaker 6:  April is is like tomorrow basically. And it's
Speaker 7:  So soon
Speaker 6:  Man. A lot of things come due in April including the
Speaker 6:  TikTok ban
Speaker 7:  Next Saturday. Yeah. And there It is.
Speaker 7:  We were talking about with Kylie about the Perplexity thing, which is not
Speaker 7:  gonna happen. The Oracle thing
Speaker 7:  Burs along Walmart is gonna, you know, come in off the top rope
Speaker 7:  and buy it according to Eli. But now
Speaker 7:  that, the interesting thing is, and I think one of the questions we have
Speaker 7:  been asking over and over is essentially who gets to
Speaker 7:  decide what constitutes a deal here, right? Like
Speaker 7:  it, who, who is the one who gets to say that satisfies the brief,
Speaker 7:  TikTok gets to remain. And what happens now
Speaker 7:  is a, a bunch of members of Congress basically reminding the
Speaker 7:  Trump administration that actually they do.
Speaker 7:  And I just, I'll just read you the, the quote here. He
Speaker 7:  says, to the extent that you continue trying to delay the divestment deadline
Speaker 7:  through executive orders, any further extensions of the TikTok deadline will
Speaker 7:  require Oracle, apple, Google, and other companies to continue risking ruinous
Speaker 7:  legal liability. A difficult decision to justify in perpetuity. So they're
Speaker 7:  basically like, figure this out or it's going to happen
Speaker 7:  and we are not going to continue to play these shenanigan games with you.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So the interesting thing here is the actual text of the bill, which
Speaker 6:  we should read, which says here's what a
Speaker 6:  qualified divestiture is. So the bill said you have to sell it or be banned.
Speaker 6:  Right? Banned. And everyone was like, this is a band 'cause Byan will never
Speaker 6:  sell and they didn't sell and they did their little stunt and they shut it
Speaker 6:  down for a minute. Then Trump said, you're fine until next Saturday. Right.
Speaker 6:  Which is weird 'cause that's not how law enforcement's supposed to work,
Speaker 6:  but here we are in the Trump administration
Speaker 7:  And Congress is trying very hard to remind him that that's not how law enforcement
Speaker 7:  works.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You can't just delay. This went to the Supreme Court, this supreme
Speaker 6:  the, this is weird, but constitutional, you, the government is allowed to
Speaker 6:  ban TikTok in this way. So what by chance was supposed to do was enact a
Speaker 6:  qualified divestiture, which is sell TikTok. And so
Speaker 6:  here's how it's defined in the bill. The term qualified divestiture means
Speaker 6:  a divestiture or similar transaction that a, the president
Speaker 6:  determines through an inter-agency process would result in the
Speaker 6:  relevant foreign adversary controlled application no longer being controlled
Speaker 6:  by a foreign adversary. So that President Donald Trump has to go through
Speaker 6:  an inter-agency process that results in
Speaker 6:  TikTok no longer being controlled by by chance. That's a big
Speaker 6:  one. What is this process? Is the Trump administration capable of a process?
Speaker 7:  No.
Speaker 6:  Who are the agencies? But the
Speaker 7:  Trump administration seems very confident that an executive order counts
Speaker 7:  as an inter-agency process,
Speaker 6:  I guess. Right? I mean PE the they have to a, a bunch
Speaker 6:  of agencies including our national security agencies have to weigh in. Right?
Speaker 6:  We don't know if that's gonna happen by Saturday. And we don't know if
Speaker 6:  the sort of moves that they have on the table like Byan will reduce
Speaker 6:  its share of this to X amount of dollars and
Speaker 6:  Oracle will increase its share will satisfy this process.
Speaker 6:  And all we've got is like JD Vance being like, we'll have the high level
Speaker 6:  structure of a deal by the deadline. I don't know.
Speaker 7:  So my guess would be, and we're gonna find out in eight days, but
Speaker 7:  my guess would be they're going to use that because there was, there was
Speaker 7:  a provision that if there was a deal in the works, they could do
Speaker 7:  another 90 day delay in order to finish that deal. But
Speaker 6:  That's over, that's over. That was in the te original text. There was that
Speaker 6:  but
Speaker 7:  Wasn't the 75 day delay that we just did something else?
Speaker 6:  No. 'cause the deadline passed. This all matters if you believe the rule
Speaker 6:  of law in America still matters. Right. And what matters is, did
Speaker 6:  Donald Trump tell the attorney general to enforce this law? And the answer
Speaker 6:  right now is he said to her, don't do it. So she's not doing it.
Speaker 6:  Right. And will that matter on, on Saturday? Maybe
Speaker 6:  he'll, maybe he'll say it again and like that's where you have letters from
Speaker 6:  Congress saying, Hey, we passed this law. Your job is to enforce it not to
Speaker 6:  delay it. Right. And we gave you this grace period basically
Speaker 6:  because the law went into effect on the first day you were in office.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Grace periods up, enforce the law, don't. Right. And we,
Speaker 6:  I just dunno, there's gonna be a deal. There's this other part that says
Speaker 6:  like, maybe you can get the algorithms out. I I the goal of this law is
Speaker 6:  for them to sell It is to get by dance out of
Speaker 6:  social media Right. In the United States. And at least
Speaker 7:  As far as I can tell,
Speaker 7:  there is not a lot of indication coming from anywhere other than the Trump
Speaker 7:  administration that a deal is happening
Speaker 6:  Because I think everyone is except for Perplexity,
Speaker 6:  which I think tells you a lot about the status of their efforts here. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  There's the, what is it, Frank McCort thing, project Liberty? Is that what
Speaker 7:  it's called? Like that's, that's out there.
Speaker 6:  That's the one where Alexis Hanney and, and Mr. Beast wanna put it on the
Speaker 6:  blockchain. Oh
Speaker 7:  God, yeah, sure, sure. Why not put TikTok on the
Speaker 7:  blockchain? Like it's whatever that's the same as banning it.
Speaker 7:  It'll be fine.
Speaker 6:  Everything's in NFT now. Yeah. We're gonna light the ocean on
Speaker 6:  fire. Some other lightning round items here. This one's real quick.
Speaker 6:  The Google antitrust trial, the remedies phase
Speaker 6:  where they already determined that Google had a monopoly in search and now
Speaker 6:  it's what do we do about it? That's set to kick off in April as well. Right.
Speaker 6:  The government, including Trump's administration, wants them to get rid of
Speaker 6:  Chrome. Right. That was the approach of
Speaker 6:  the DOJ under the Biden administration who won the trial. The Trump DOJ is
Speaker 6:  sticking to it. Yep. We won the case. The DOJ won the case. The United States
Speaker 6:  won the case. You're a monopoly. We also think the remedy is you getting
Speaker 6:  rid of all this stuff. Google has filed an answer. The news here is that
Speaker 6:  Apple moved to intervene in that case and you should basically be like,
Speaker 6:  don't take our money away. And the court ruled that they were too late.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Which is really interesting.
Speaker 6:  So they're not allowed. So that's 20 billions of Apple's revenue on a calendar
Speaker 6:  error. Basically.
Speaker 7:  Apple was like central to that case. I mean there was so
Speaker 7:  much Apple in that case and it's, it's fascinating to see it
Speaker 7:  just totally looped out of the last part of this.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, well see the, that that case is coming up by the way, the, the FTCs
Speaker 6:  case against meta in which the government is asking for
Speaker 6:  Instagram and WhatsApp to sort off also comment in April. You're
Speaker 7:  Very excited about that case.
Speaker 6:  I think that is the most legible case to the biggest audience. The
Speaker 6:  government wants Mark Zuckerberg to get rid of Instagram. There's not another,
Speaker 6:  I don't have to say more words, right? Yeah. I I everyone
Speaker 6:  understands exactly what means. Like I I I honestly think Google
Speaker 6:  is a monopoly in search and so the government wants it to get rid of Chrome
Speaker 6:  is totally opaque.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like you have to explain a bunch of hoops.
Speaker 7:  Well, which is why it's funny, like Google pays Apple
Speaker 7:  $20 billion a year to be the search engine in
Speaker 7:  Safari is actually more legible than Google is a
Speaker 7:  monopoly because of Chrome. And even though I think both are sort of equally
Speaker 7:  true, but you're right. Like It is meta a monopoly and thus should
Speaker 7:  it have to get rid of Instagram is it's just, it's It is as perfectly simple
Speaker 7:  a monopoly case as I think you'll find. But they're gonna spend seven weeks
Speaker 7:  making it really complicated.
Speaker 6:  Oh. So you can ask every celebrity in the world if Mark Zuckerberg shown
Speaker 6:  on Instagram, like I, I think about the local TV news test,
Speaker 6:  you know, like, is this a local TV segment and it's just like whoever, like
Speaker 6:  man on the street should mark Zuckerberg on Instagram. They're like, no.
Speaker 6:  And like there you go. Like that's great TV like that's coming
Speaker 6:  up as well. It's big April. And then the other thing that's happening is
Speaker 6:  tariffs hit in April, Trump yesterday announced
Speaker 6:  25% tariffs on cars and car parts.
Speaker 6:  If they're not manufactured in the United States, this is gonna be a huge
Speaker 6:  problem for every car maker. Yep. Most cars are made of parts from
Speaker 6:  all kinds of places. There are some like
Speaker 6:  U-S-M-C-A trade carve outs here. The whole audio industry is like
Speaker 6:  sort of reorganizing around this problem. Hmm. There might be some benefit
Speaker 6:  to Tesla because Tesla makes so many of its cars in the United States,
Speaker 6:  but it's coming like tariffs are here. He, he got
Speaker 6:  held off on them once he got held off on them. Again.
Speaker 6:  I don't think he's gonna blink this time.
Speaker 7:  It doesn't seem like it,
Speaker 6:  The tariffs on Chinese products are like 45%. So I think we're just
Speaker 6:  gonna see a bunch of consumer electronics prices go up. We're gonna see a
Speaker 6:  bunch of car prices go up. I will say that there's
Speaker 6:  a lot of a lot of memes of people trading in their Teslas for rivian,
Speaker 6:  which is really interesting. Yeah, I've seen a cyber truck with the Rivian
Speaker 6:  logo on the back. I've now seen a cyber truck with the Toyota logo on the
Speaker 6:  back that's floating around New York City. That
Speaker 7:  Has been my favorite meme. The people putting like Honda and BMW
Speaker 7:  logos where the, the Tesla thing used to be. It's
Speaker 6:  Very funny. I've also seen a picture of a cyber truck where they just have
Speaker 6:  put like huge fender flares on it to make it look like a different
Speaker 7:  Car. I was just gonna say the cyber truck famously easy to make look like
Speaker 7:  other cars.
Speaker 6:  It's like no, it's a cyber truck bro. And one big wiper really
Speaker 6:  sells it every time. And then, you know, there's just the general
Speaker 6:  angst around Tesla BYD the Chinese company is
Speaker 6:  outselling Tesla right now.
Speaker 6:  I did BYD to 107 billion in revenue for 2024, which
Speaker 6:  is way over Tesla's 97.7 billion
Speaker 6:  BYD ships more than double the vehicles of Tesla if you can at hybrids. And
Speaker 6:  then they're investing in charging tech. Their, their new bods, new
Speaker 6:  charging tech is twice as fast as Tesla's. You can get 250 miles range in
Speaker 6:  like five minutes. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And we talked about like the, the ongoing boom in
Speaker 7:  like excitement about Chinese EVs coming to the us
Speaker 7:  Like the cars are not but the, the the like talkers and YouTubers are reviewing
Speaker 7:  them. A lot of UID stuff starting to show up.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Andy Hawkins is working on a story on that. I'm, we should have him
Speaker 6:  on when he does that story.
Speaker 7:  Oh, there you go. Yeah. And the, the like supposed
Speaker 7:  biggest day of Tesla take down is this weekend.
Speaker 7:  And so I think we're gonna, we'll we'll have Andy on next week maybe. We'll
Speaker 7:  we'll talk through a lot of this stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I know people get, there's whatever noise about Tesla take down where it's
Speaker 6:  all just like domestic terrorism, first of all, domestic terrorism, very
Speaker 6:  fuzzy concept in American law. It is just true. It has been for a long time.
Speaker 6:  It's not illegal on its own. Like the things you do are illegal
Speaker 6:  and there are some definitions but there's not like a law. So like the
Speaker 6:  government keeps saying this thing and it's like cheat codes to get
Speaker 6:  surveillance warrants. It's very, it's very weird
Speaker 6:  and like a lot of the Trump administration is invoking
Speaker 6:  powers that are reserved for special circumstances. Like
Speaker 6:  we're at war with Canada. Say you just like say these words
Speaker 6:  to, to justify even like tariffs are, they're being justified under emergency
Speaker 6:  powers. Right. So there's some weird stuff with the Tesla protests that we
Speaker 6:  will cover. But yeah, there's big protests coming. Tesla's under a lot of
Speaker 6:  pressure. These tariffs might benefit Tesla. So there's some back and forth
Speaker 6:  there. And then last little, little one, which I think we should end on
Speaker 6:  a high note, but Cars Rivian had a secret e-bike
Speaker 6:  company that it's spun out called also, which is pretty cool.
Speaker 7:  I'm pumped about this. The, the idea of rivian
Speaker 7:  taking its tech into like they, at first
Speaker 7:  they were like micro mobility and I was like dope, we're gonna get some scooters
Speaker 7:  'cause you, you know, I love a scooter startup, but it sounds like it's gonna
Speaker 7:  be bikes, but they're gonna use some of the rivian tech. They're gonna, they're
Speaker 7:  gonna use a lot of rivian like manufacturing capabilities. And
Speaker 7:  one of the things that RJ, the CEO said is that he thinks It is
Speaker 7:  ridiculous how expensive these great e-bikes are. And I
Speaker 7:  also think It is ridiculous how expensive they are. And so that made me very
Speaker 7:  happy. Yeah. Like if Rivian can figure out how to economies of scale
Speaker 7:  its way into good e-bikes for like half what they currently cost.
Speaker 7:  Great. Forget cars. Just do that. I'm good.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I'm super down with that. I am looking at an R one s like every day
Speaker 6:  right now. Yeah. Yeah. I I've,
Speaker 6:  I've test driven one a million times. They, RJ was on de coder, they gave
Speaker 6:  me one for a weekend. It was cool. It's like they're not
Speaker 6:  as nice on the inside as our Jeep, but they're obviously better cars
Speaker 6:  because Jeeps are made by STIs.
Speaker 6:  I dunno what else to say about that. Like you want a 3-year-old SUV for your
Speaker 6:  family and you want a bunch of range. Like the R one s is the thing that
Speaker 6:  exists. Yeah, but they're pretty spartan on the inside.
Speaker 6:  They're also expensive. I just, I'm just like, oh these tariffs are coming,
Speaker 6:  all these cars are gonna get more expensive
Speaker 7:  So buy it now. That's the only answer. Right. And
Speaker 6:  Like, I'm like, am I just gonna pull the trigger on this car for kind of
Speaker 6:  no reason except I think the tariffs will make it expensive a year from now.
Speaker 7:  I'm sure that's a case Becky will buy. Listen, I don't need this car now,
Speaker 7:  but it'll be more expensive in two weeks.
Speaker 6:  By the way, if you have a Jeep four by eight, if you got one of the hybrids,
Speaker 6:  you need to go to the dealer today. Because they just issued the software
Speaker 6:  update for the recall. They had where the, they
Speaker 6:  told everyone to not charge their cars because they might start on
Speaker 6:  fire. Oh boy. And part of that was not just don't charge your car,
Speaker 6:  it was leave it outside in case it starts on fire.
Speaker 6:  This is a real thing. They had defective Samsung batteries in them. So the
Speaker 6:  recalls out. You could go to the dealer, they do the software upgrade. Part
Speaker 6:  of the software upgrade is just making the software know if there's gonna
Speaker 6:  be fire. Like these numbers are outta spec. Like there's gonna be
Speaker 6:  fire. And then another part of the software upgrade is after they do it,
Speaker 6:  they drive your car around and there's like some specific set of miles you
Speaker 6:  have to drive at specific speeds
Speaker 7:  To see if it does fire, to
Speaker 6:  See if it hits the threshold that requires a battery call. You can understand
Speaker 6:  where I'm like, I should get a different car 'cause we did all the things
Speaker 6:  and a car was fine. But like once that happens you're like, I don't
Speaker 6:  like you anymore.
Speaker 6:  I'm, I, you know, I just, I have uncomfortable feelings about you specifically.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You
Speaker 7:  Don't get that trust back, I don't think. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And I, yeah, so I dunno if you, if you can talk me into an R one s,
Speaker 6:  you know, send me a note. There we go. I'm also open to a 2002 Escalade,
Speaker 6:  which you can buy at any point for $2,000.
Speaker 6:  It's all, every time we talk about a computer on the show and we're like,
Speaker 6:  it's $1,500, we're like a new iPad. I'm like, I could get a
Speaker 6:  2002 Escalade.
Speaker 7:  That's the dream. All right. We need to get outta here. We
Speaker 6:  Got it. Let me know if you have a 2002 escalate. That's awesome. If you've
Speaker 6:  got one, you know, let's make a deal. Let's talk. All right. That's it.
Speaker 6:  That's Vergecast. Fuck all.
Speaker 10:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 10:  you. Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one.
Speaker 10:  The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network.
Speaker 10:  Our show is produced by Will Por, Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer. And
Speaker 10:  that's it. We'll see you next week.