# Transcript
ID: 2a699c14-38d0-4e3d-87bb-1c61dbed0600
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-7477606883169224852/-7220491696513646380/s93290-US-7484s-1749561036.mp3
Description: Apple spent 90 minutes talking about the future of its software, and we're pretty sure only said the word "Siri" once. Nilay and David are joined by The Verge's Victoria Song and Allison Johnson, both of whom were with Nilay at the keynote, to talk about all the news of the day. They talk about the Liquid Glass design language, and why Apple decided to redesign all its software. They talk about Spotlight on the Mac, the new multitasking features on the iPad, the typing indicators on the iPhone, Workout Buddy on the Watch, personas on the Vision Pro, and everything else that Apple announced — or, in a few cases, pointedly didn't announce — on stage. We're just starting to try out some of this software, and it's all likely to change a lot before it hits your devices this fall. And we'll have lots of thoughts along the way.
Speaker 6:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Liquid Glass.
Speaker 6:  And you have to say it like that every single time. I'm m your friend David
Speaker 6:  Pierce. Neli Patella is here. Hi Neli.
Speaker 7:  Hello. Here I am.
Speaker 6:  Neli is doing great. Everybody we're having a day. Allison
Speaker 6:  Johnson's also here. Hi Allison.
Speaker 8:  Hello.
Speaker 6:  You guys are in Cupertino for ww DC Keynote
Speaker 6:  was today V Song who was also there is gonna join us in a little bit. She's
Speaker 6:  still at some meeting, but it's gonna show up. But it was today was
Speaker 6:  ww DC day. I found myself sadder not to be there than I expected.
Speaker 6:  So just gimme the vibe. Check-in. How's the day been? How do you guys feel?
Speaker 6:  Are you alive? Are we okay? We're alive.
Speaker 7:  Okay. It was, it was a loose day. There was like not a lot
Speaker 7:  going on,
Speaker 7:  right? Like the number of new ideas that we have enforced to contend with
Speaker 7:  are fairly limited. There's a lot of new feature ideas
Speaker 7:  and a lot of, a lot of stuff to talk about, but there's no grand
Speaker 7:  big thing that we all have to be like, let me wrap my head around
Speaker 7:  this. There's a menu bar on the iPad, David,
Speaker 6:  So a, I would argue that is very much a big thing, but B
Speaker 6:  like last year, that thing was Apple intelligence, right? They were like,
Speaker 6:  this is, this is the grand new way of thinking about technology that is going
Speaker 6:  to change everything forever.
Speaker 6:  This year. There was, there wasn't even all that much Apple
Speaker 6:  intelligence this year, which we should talk about. Allison,
Speaker 6:  what, how did you feel? What were the, what were the vibes like in the room?
Speaker 8:  The vibes are kind of like, there was a lot of
Speaker 8:  curiosity I think, about how Apple would handle or like
Speaker 8:  address any of the Siri Apple intelligence
Speaker 8:  stuff, which was, it was interesting. They didn't shy
Speaker 8:  away from saying Apple Intelligence, which was
Speaker 8:  a little surprising to me. Yeah. They kind of sprinkled it in throughout
Speaker 8:  rather than the big, like it's an Apple intelligence show,
Speaker 8:  but we did not hear Siri's name I don't think a single time,
Speaker 8:  correct me if I'm wrong.
Speaker 6:  I think the answer is once
Speaker 8:  Maybe. Yeah. Okay.
Speaker 6:  I would not swear to this, but I think ironically right at the beginning,
Speaker 6:  basically explaining why they weren't going to talk about Siri more. I think
Speaker 6:  Craig Federighe said Siri once. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 7:  At the very beginning they said it, you know, all of our plans will come
Speaker 7:  true
Speaker 6:  Right?
Speaker 7:  In the coming year. Here's what I can tell you, just based on vibes on the
Speaker 7:  ground, they are furious that people think that last year
Speaker 7:  they showed a fake Siri.
Speaker 6:  Oh, interesting. Wow.
Speaker 7:  So they, they want people to know
Speaker 7:  that they're gonna do it. It's coming
Speaker 7:  and like what they, they showed was real
Speaker 7:  and they just weren't happy with it. And so it's coming.
Speaker 6:  But, so it's actually, I feel like it's worse if it worked, right? Because
Speaker 6:  it's one thing to be like, here's a cool concept video we think we can make.
Speaker 6:  It's another to be like, here is the product, it's done, we've made it. And
Speaker 6:  then
Speaker 6:  at some point somebody's like, nevermind, actually it sucks. Like that's
Speaker 6:  that it all, it's it's, it's weird either way.
Speaker 7:  I don't like, again, the vibes, right? What are the vibes? The vibes are,
Speaker 7:  everyone knows that this is the elephant in the room that last year they
Speaker 7:  announce this thing. They didn't ship. They were gonna talk about Apple Intelligence
Speaker 7:  is here. You know, apple is the royal family. Never complain,
Speaker 7:  never explain. Like that's just how they roll. Yeah. And so
Speaker 7:  they confidently muscled their way through their, their presentation. They,
Speaker 7:  they showed off Liquid Glass, all the stuff they're gonna show off. They
Speaker 7:  showed off a bunch of artificial intelligence features that are expanding
Speaker 7:  and the fact that they didn't ship Siri, they are willing to own up to, but
Speaker 7:  they're, the answer is it wasn't good enough. And we only ship
Speaker 7:  things that are good enough. Right. And what I would connect that to is the
Speaker 7:  fact that no products that have made the same promises about
Speaker 7:  being able to do stuff on your phone for you are good enough.
Speaker 7:  Like we haven't seen the smart assistant be good enough anywhere in the
Speaker 7:  industry. Right. And whether or not you think that connects to whether like,
Speaker 7:  whether AI as we understand it today can actually do it,
Speaker 7:  or whether you think everyone is just kind of dumb. There's a little bit
Speaker 7:  of column B and a little bit of column B at at work here. But
Speaker 7:  like, they're, they're, they, they want you to
Speaker 7:  know that their goal is making great products and that's what they're gonna
Speaker 7:  do. And that I saw some, you know, some folks in the press just like milling
Speaker 7:  around and they're like, there's some quiet tension and uncertainty here
Speaker 7:  because no one knows how they're gonna address it. And then they just muscled
Speaker 7:  through their thing.
Speaker 6:  I mean, I was, I I will say I was sort of impressed that they at least like
Speaker 6:  half acknowledged it at the beginning. The like, we're still working on
Speaker 6:  it. It's taking longer than we thought in the coming year is like, even that
Speaker 6:  is more than I expected Apple to do. Like traditionally Apple would just
Speaker 6:  memory hole the whole idea that it had ever spoken the word Siri
Speaker 6:  aloud in history and just keep going. And we'd all be like,
Speaker 6:  do you know that Siri exists?
Speaker 7:  Well, you know, they walked right, I'm sure we're gonna talk about this,
Speaker 7:  but they walked right up to the line of all the things they said Siri would
Speaker 7:  be able to do, but in like other formats. So if you
Speaker 7:  look at Spotlight search and what it can and can't do now,
Speaker 7:  you know, like, oh, why wouldn't I just talk to this? That's the
Speaker 7:  Siri you want. And they're, it's not, they have, they just didn't connect
Speaker 7:  the dots.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Or they'll like, take a screenshot and add something to your calendar.
Speaker 8:  I'm like, that's that's Siri, right? We're just calling it
Speaker 8:  something else. Or I, it feels like they were a little bit
Speaker 8:  hesitant to kind of be like, look, look at this intelligence. They were
Speaker 8:  sort of like sprinkling it throughout rather than making
Speaker 8:  such a big show of it this time. Maybe just they felt
Speaker 8:  burned by how everything went last year.
Speaker 7:  It is fair to say they feel burned.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I would, I could feel that from 3000 miles away. But also,
Speaker 6:  Allison, I was thinking about you all day today because y
Speaker 6:  you and I have been arguing about AI devices for like two years
Speaker 6:  and you keep being like, I don't care about any of the rest of it because
Speaker 6:  phones exist and phones are good at doing phones things and phones
Speaker 6:  exist and it's fine if you wanna do AI stuff, do it on your phone. And there
Speaker 6:  was so much of that energy today to that point, like you're talking about
Speaker 6:  Apple was like, we, we didn't, everybody else is out here being like, we've
Speaker 6:  invented a, a new paradigm for everything. Johnny, Ivan, Sam Altman, like
Speaker 6:  own San Francisco together now. And Apple's just like, do you know as cool
Speaker 6:  as your iPhone, what if your iPhone could do more stuff? Did have you heard
Speaker 6:  of the iPhone? And there's like, it's like guys, you, where was this
Speaker 6:  energy last year? Like you, the iPhone also existed then, but it's like
Speaker 6:  this was, it was sort of a very aply way of thinking about this stuff
Speaker 6:  again. Yeah. After such a weird diversion last year,
Speaker 8:  I think like the, not to jump the gun, but like the,
Speaker 8:  the screenshot kind of visual intelligence things is like really
Speaker 8:  telling to me. So there, their new thing with visual
Speaker 8:  intelligence is it can see what's on your screen and you just summon it
Speaker 8:  by taking a screenshot. You, you already know how to take a screenshot with
Speaker 8:  your phone, like it's a thing you do and then they kind of
Speaker 8:  go from there and that's where you can add something to your calendar or
Speaker 8:  whatever. That just feels like that's where these things
Speaker 8:  should kind of live and belong. And I think that's how
Speaker 8:  ai, you know, as a tool on our phones makes sense to me.
Speaker 8:  I do think it's gonna beat, you know, whatever
Speaker 8:  pendant screenless thing is coming next, but
Speaker 8:  who knows?
Speaker 7:  Well a lot of the features they announce today are features that got approximately
Speaker 7:  zero people to switch to an Android phone over the past five years. Sure.
Speaker 7:  Like just straightforwardly. These are features that exist on Android phones
Speaker 7:  circle, the search exists on Android phone. Like we've covered that.
Speaker 7:  Android can now look at what's on your screen and do a Google search based
Speaker 7:  on it. Like so often that my joke is that Dieter wrote about
Speaker 7:  it in hieroglyphics.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Was Google now like 2012? Yeah. Yeah. It was like this, this
Speaker 6:  idea is is has been around we we've been doing this.
Speaker 7:  So yeah, I mean I, a lot just a lot of these features are
Speaker 7:  old Google ideas, but new ways to kick off searches and,
Speaker 7:  and like see what's on your screen and, and take action on it and which are
Speaker 7:  cool and which are useful. But you know,
Speaker 7:  when they announce Apple Intelligence that I think what
Speaker 7:  the reason people were focused on, the Siri part of it is 'cause that's what
Speaker 7:  looks like the platform shift, however you wanna define that, where
Speaker 7:  instead of like touching a screen or using a mouse, you just talk to the
Speaker 7:  computer and it does stuff and they're still nowhere in that. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  They're a little bit closer to you type to the computer and it does stuff.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Okay. So I wanna get to all the sort of individual platform stuff,
Speaker 6:  but I feel like there were a couple of kind of bigger, broader
Speaker 6:  ideas Apple had here that we should start with. And the first one is obviously
Speaker 6:  Liquid Glass, which every time I say it is a phrase
Speaker 6:  I hate a little more. I'm realizing this now as I say it out loud. I just
Speaker 6:  don't enjoy saying that phrase. I
Speaker 8:  Don't like it. Alison,
Speaker 6:  Can you, you were, you were sitting there taking pictures of this thing.
Speaker 6:  Can you explain what Liquid Glass is and looks like having
Speaker 6:  seen it in person?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Well imagine everything on your phone screen
Speaker 8:  is like kind of transparent. I think the idea is like,
Speaker 8:  you know, you pull down a notification shade or the control center
Speaker 8:  and instead of like a blank slate that sort of
Speaker 8:  launches you in into somewhere else on your phone, it's
Speaker 8:  Transparent Glass now and you can still see what was behind
Speaker 8:  there. So we saw all kinds of little like menu
Speaker 8:  bar things popping up and, and you can still see the apps and the home
Speaker 8:  screen behind them.
Speaker 8:  A mixed feelings about how that all looks.
Speaker 8:  You know, it's, it's all in like early beta right now,
Speaker 8:  but it's clearly something Apple is like pushing
Speaker 8:  into full force and, and it's coming to the iPhone
Speaker 8:  whether anybody wants it or not.
Speaker 6:  Whether you like it or not, it's going Neil, I you
Speaker 6:  they the, like, if I remember the timing correctly, the iOS seven
Speaker 6:  launch was like a seminal Verge moment
Speaker 6:  in the early days.
Speaker 6:  Did, did Liquid Glass feel like that all over again? Where
Speaker 6:  you like, we're, we're so back, we're doing this again. Everything's better.
Speaker 6:  No,
Speaker 7:  I think, I think the answer is no. Iowa seven, remember they went from skew
Speaker 7:  amorphism and texture to nothing
Speaker 7:  to like what if your, what if your phone was
Speaker 7:  indecipherable?
Speaker 7:  Like if you look at our coverage of iOS seven when we came out it, it's harsh,
Speaker 7:  but time has judged it to be fair. 'cause I walked it all back
Speaker 7:  over the course of the next year and then, you know, to where we are now,
Speaker 7:  there's a lot more texture and dimension to iOS.
Speaker 7:  Like they've just added it back. They've let people figure out what they're
Speaker 7:  looking at on their screens And I get what they're trying to do with Liquid
Speaker 7:  Glass, which is reset it once again, not for no reason.
Speaker 7:  Right. A lot of their arguments, a lot of their arguments for even the iPad
Speaker 7:  stuff is we have so much more processing power now. So
Speaker 7:  I get where they're coming from. We have a lot more processing power. We
Speaker 7:  can rethink this interface. We don't have to like throw everything out. We're
Speaker 7:  not going from felt textures and, and literally like wooden,
Speaker 7:  like that wooden texture you get in like 1970s rec rooms, which was part
Speaker 7:  of iOS for a minute. The
Speaker 6:  Notes app was a literal torn off legal pad. Like that's, that's what we were
Speaker 6:  doing before iOS seven.
Speaker 7:  And there were, you know, there were some arguments there for why that was
Speaker 7:  good at that time, but iOS seven was supposed to be a clean break. Like digital
Speaker 7:  interfaces are here now. This is the primary way we, we should not be stuck
Speaker 7:  in the past Leg. Liquid Glass has nothing to do with not being stuck in the
Speaker 7:  past in many ways. It's very much a reflection of the past in like
Speaker 7:  Windows Vista. Yeah. Like this thing has been tried before
Speaker 7:  in this way. I, I suspect there's
Speaker 7:  a ton of refinement to come between now and September and Apple
Speaker 7:  sort of purposefully, fully
Speaker 7:  announces the most extreme version of the idea. And what they announce
Speaker 7:  say was the most extreme version of the idea. Like everything is so transparent,
Speaker 7:  it's almost unreadable. Yeah. And all the effects are totally overdone and
Speaker 7:  Control Center looks at bananas. Like there's no way they're launching this
Speaker 7:  version of, of Liquid Glass. The thing I don't
Speaker 7:  understand is like, what is the point of it?
Speaker 6:  Right? What is this for
Speaker 7:  Other than looks different. They did not make a case for why it looks different.
Speaker 6:  No. And there are, I so it was funny, I went back and was reading a bunch
Speaker 6:  of our old Vista coverage and the, the thesis
Speaker 6:  then was the same as the thesis now for Apple, which is basically like
Speaker 6:  you do this kind of translucency stuff in part to sort of anchor people
Speaker 6:  where they are in a space, right? Like when you can see the things
Speaker 6:  behind and you get these sort of live updating previews and like, it, it
Speaker 6:  just puts you in a place that is a little more understandable. You can kind
Speaker 6:  of figure out where you are. And like a lot of this, they said this,
Speaker 6:  this is all coming from the Vision Pro, right? Which is a, a
Speaker 6:  device with a very specific need, which is to
Speaker 7:  Yeah. But why?
Speaker 6:  Well, yeah, I, I mean I wrote this in a piece today, like I think it is truly
Speaker 6:  wild to be like, we made a vision pro, no one bought it. It's way too expensive.
Speaker 6:  Let's reorient our entire design system around it, which is
Speaker 6:  insanity. But like if you are Apple and you're
Speaker 6:  betting that the next decade is smart glasses or whatever, then sure
Speaker 6:  it does not make sense to me to do this on an iPhone. But again, on a vision
Speaker 6:  pro, the idea of like, okay, I need to, I need
Speaker 6:  to both show you digital information in the real world but not
Speaker 6:  obscure the real world for the digital information. So I have to do this
Speaker 6:  kind of glassy translucent thing that feels a little more physical, right?
Speaker 6:  Like we've talked about this bunch, everybody's doing this in some direction
Speaker 6:  or another. Spaceshipy glass is what Apple has chosen.
Speaker 6:  Fine. The way all of this stuff is implemented is just
Speaker 6:  bonkers. Like you, you mentioned the, the control center and stuff and there
Speaker 6:  have been all these screenshots going around of the dev beta, which everyone
Speaker 6:  immediately installed and started playing with. It's just,
Speaker 6:  imagine if you just took the icons from the control center and
Speaker 6:  just shoved them onto your home screen. Like that's all it is. There's nothing,
Speaker 6:  there's no design. There used to be like the blur behind it. It would blur
Speaker 6:  your home screen, none of that. It's just like, here's some icons. It looks
Speaker 6:  awful. It's so bad. And I'm sure you're right And I'm
Speaker 6:  sure they will frost the glass and everything will be fine. But even some
Speaker 6:  of these ideas where they're like you, you pull, you know, as you're scrolling
Speaker 6:  the, the URL bar down at the bottom will sort of it, the scroll will
Speaker 6:  go underneath it so it'll actually like reflect the light underneath it.
Speaker 6:  All it does in all of the videos that Apple showed is make that
Speaker 6:  bar completely unreadable.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. So the argument for skew amorphism is that by making things
Speaker 7:  reflect real world objects and textures, you would you
Speaker 7:  assign those things, those same qualities. So you open the notes app, it
Speaker 7:  looks like a legal pad, you assigned it the same qualities. Sure. As a legal
Speaker 7:  pad in your mind. You open the games app and it's on a felt background and
Speaker 7:  you think I should smoke a cigar. Like whatever, whatever those things mean
Speaker 7:  to you. The weird thing about this approach
Speaker 7:  is that it breaks all those conventions and it literally
Speaker 7:  posits a world in which everything is made of class to the point
Speaker 7:  where in the video they were showing the designers in the studio.
Speaker 7:  And if you believe Apple's video, apple's
Speaker 7:  designers in their studios printed out like giant Lucite blocks and put
Speaker 7:  the icons in them to see how they would reflect in the real world.
Speaker 6:  That is, I didn't even track that as weird watching that video. Oh my gosh.
Speaker 6:  And
Speaker 7:  It's like, well this is very backwards. Like you reverse skew
Speaker 7:  amorphism to the world. Yeah. Like you're, you're manufacturing
Speaker 7:  Lucite blocks of icons. Like, don't do that because in the real world,
Speaker 7:  not everything is translucent and you get depth and texture by
Speaker 7:  putting things over each other all the time. And you're like, this is on
Speaker 7:  top of that. And it will, will remain the same color no matter
Speaker 7:  what happens. And on the new iPhone, it's like everything is changing in
Speaker 7:  color all the time because everything is over everything else. Right? But
Speaker 7:  still transparent or translucent. And there's just something wrong about
Speaker 7:  that. Like your brain doesn't accept that. The example I'll give you, which
Speaker 7:  is a like ancient history, but it, I think very like funny,
Speaker 7:  inappropriate ancient history. When Steve Jobs first announce Mac OS
Speaker 7:  10, the interface back then was called Aqua. And his
Speaker 7:  joke was that it looked so good, it was lickable and all the buttons were
Speaker 7:  like pulsing blue and like kind of watery.
Speaker 7:  And all of these people on the internet made themes for the old
Speaker 7:  version of Mac os to look like os 10. So you could like buy these
Speaker 7:  like theme packs for your like nineties Mac. And I ran them and
Speaker 7:  every single one of them had a blue menu bar
Speaker 7:  Because they hadn't realized that what, when he was showing it, the
Speaker 7:  menu bar is transparent and he just had a blue background.
Speaker 6:  Interesting. Oh
Speaker 7:  God. So for my God, a year we were all running these themes with this blue
Speaker 7:  menu bar. And then we actually got OS 10, like the first probably beta is
Speaker 7:  S 10. We installed the things and we went, oh shit, the menu bar translucent.
Speaker 7:  And then Apple realize this was a bad idea and now the menu bar is translucent
Speaker 7:  again. And you just go back and forth between these like themes and design.
Speaker 7:  And one of the reasons you make things not translucent is to give them
Speaker 7:  weight in the design, right? Is to say this is always gonna stay the same
Speaker 7:  and this is an anchor for your eyes. And you can just see with
Speaker 7:  Liquid Glass, like that's just out the window and they're gonna have to put
Speaker 7:  it back. They're gonna have to give you some places to anchor your eyes just
Speaker 7:  to get around the phone.
Speaker 6:  Well that's the thing, right? 'cause there, there, I think like you were
Speaker 6:  talking about with iOS seven, the idea was like digital
Speaker 6:  interfaces are now interfaces. I, I wonder
Speaker 6:  if part of the theory here is like you already know how to do everything.
Speaker 6:  Your mu your muscle memory is so good that we don't even have to
Speaker 6:  remind you where the URL bar goes because your, your thumb is there. So actually
Speaker 6:  we're gonna hide all of the interfaces best we can in order
Speaker 6:  for you to just see the beauty of the webpage that you're looking
Speaker 6:  at. And
Speaker 6:  boy is that a bad theory if that is in fact the theory. But that is a
Speaker 6:  theory that would lead you to make something like Liquid Glass.
Speaker 8:  I think just being at Apple Park today too
Speaker 8:  kind of reminds you that Apple is just so committed
Speaker 8:  to a look sometimes where it's like, is
Speaker 8:  a giant
Speaker 8:  circle made of glass? Is that the most practical
Speaker 8:  way to organize an office building? No.
Speaker 8:  You can, you can see into all parts of it from the outside. That's
Speaker 8:  kind of weird. But they're just like, that's their look and they love it.
Speaker 6:  You didn't enjoy your 15 minute golf cart ride from the front door to the,
Speaker 6:  the place you were going.
Speaker 7:  The golf cart today had party speakers
Speaker 6:  Under
Speaker 7:  The seats and the woofers had LEDs and rims and we all like, the first thing
Speaker 7:  Alex he said was, look party speakers incredible. Here, I'll, I'll actually,
Speaker 7:  Alison And I will extend your metaphor 'cause it is a hundred percent on
Speaker 7:  the nose. They built Apple Park and then a little bit later they had to put
Speaker 7:  stickers on all the windows. 'cause people kept walking into them. And this
Speaker 7:  is like a main thing of Apple Park. Now you like see all these little dots
Speaker 7:  that they're gonna have to do this with liquid, Liquid Glass. They're gonna
Speaker 7:  have to put stickers on the windows. Yeah. So you know where they are in
Speaker 7:  space
Speaker 8:  Control center's just gonna have some stickers behind it. So so we don't
Speaker 8:  run
Speaker 6:  Into it. Yeah. People
Speaker 7:  Are just be bonking in control center for about a year and they're like,
Speaker 7:  Johnny put the stickers on the thing and it, it's gonna be fine. But like
Speaker 7:  that's where we are. And I do think they announce them is
Speaker 7:  in a state that's a little bit more extreme than they understand where they're
Speaker 7:  gonna have to go. I, I think Apple wants to be in that position
Speaker 7:  where they want people to react to like an extreme version
Speaker 7:  of it. So then when they walk it back, it one, they get the
Speaker 7:  big reaction in the beginning, but then it seems like they're taking the
Speaker 7:  feedback into account.
Speaker 6:  It's like, what do they say the the the thing you say to your kids where
Speaker 6:  it's like, oh no, your mom's dead. And they're like, what? And you're like,
Speaker 6:  just kidding, but we are getting divorced. And it's like you soften the blow
Speaker 6:  that way.
Speaker 7:  David, you're talking about I hadn't heard that. I've met your parents.
Speaker 7:  They're very happy.
Speaker 6:  They're lovely people. Yeah, I have, they're they're, they're doing great.
Speaker 6:  That's just, that's a story I've heard, you know, secondhand.
Speaker 6:  But no, I, I think it's an interesting theory And I have wondered about
Speaker 6:  it a lot whether this was deliberately too much because I,
Speaker 6:  I do think with a lot of this stuff, you just can't look
Speaker 6:  at control center and be like, yes, that's correct. And so there's some of
Speaker 6:  it that is maybe just like, well this is as far as we got, we have to ship
Speaker 6:  the developer beta because ww DC is when it is. But there's also
Speaker 6:  something like I, I keep going through the thing trying to find sort of what
Speaker 6:  is, what is the thing here. And the only one I've landed on is I think the,
Speaker 6:  the way that they've rearchitected the menus where like when you tap
Speaker 6:  something to open a menu rather than like opening up a new page, it just
Speaker 6:  sort of opens in place, it like radiates out and then you tap it again and
Speaker 6:  it goes back in. That I think is very cool. And it is like in service of
Speaker 6:  like anchoring you in place and sort of keeping you where you are without
Speaker 6:  suddenly dropping you into another menu that looks different only to have
Speaker 6:  to go back. That makes a lot of sense to me. That is the only thing about
Speaker 6:  Liquid Glass so far that feels like thoughtful and good to me.
Speaker 7:  Oh, I have a totally different opinion than you. No, you don't like 'em.
Speaker 7:  I saw this in your piece when I was like on my way back to the hotel to record
Speaker 7:  this And I was like, I'm gonna disagree with David about this.
Speaker 6:  Okay.
Speaker 7:  That's just dynamic user interface. Sure. This is another dream that
Speaker 7:  this industry has been chasing for years. That everything will happen in
Speaker 7:  context, right? Like all the buttons will be there when you need them
Speaker 7:  and they'll go away when you, when you don't want them or don't need them.
Speaker 7:  And the reality is fundamentally that always
Speaker 7:  confuses everyone. So you you have this like idealistic user
Speaker 7:  interface designer who's like, I hate, I hate that I've cluttered up the
Speaker 7:  screen with all this ui. Microsoft Word has too many menus and buttons
Speaker 7:  in the toolbar. We're gonna get rid of all of them and then we will intelligently
Speaker 7:  discover what you need exactly when you need it and then you'll push the
Speaker 7:  button, it'll be right there and you'll think I'm a genius.
Speaker 7:  Whoever the user me, Steve, user interface designer is a genius.
Speaker 7:  And then the reality is, you, you'd try to do this and
Speaker 7:  you've, you always guess wrong. And then there's no anchors.
Speaker 7:  So people don't know where to find the thing unless the
Speaker 7:  object that usually triggers the context is on the screen, which gets people
Speaker 7:  all turned around not having used like a glass. I don't know that this will
Speaker 7:  be the problem, but I was watching the demo And I was like, oh, we're doing
Speaker 7:  the thing. Every, every user interface company
Speaker 7:  walks down this path where they're like, it'll just happen in content. You'll
Speaker 7:  push the button and all the right menus will be there and then the button
Speaker 7:  will go away when you don't need it. And you know, on a
Speaker 7:  desktop computer, this problem is a long solved, like just have a menu bar
Speaker 7:  and we will just get over the toolbar and we won't try this anymore. And
Speaker 7:  I think on mobile, because you have the constrained screen size, the temptation
Speaker 7:  is too great. Like, can we make everything disappear?
Speaker 7:  If you really look at what Apple is saying about Liquid Glass, if what Google
Speaker 7:  is saying about expressive material explosion or whatever it's called
Speaker 7:  material expressive material three,
Speaker 6:  Listen, I was gonna leave you with material explosion, but it is, it is material
Speaker 6:  three expressive. Yes. There you
Speaker 7:  Go. See I knew all the, I had most of the phenoms. Right. At the very
Speaker 7:  least
Speaker 8:  The ingredients were there. That's right.
Speaker 7:  If you look at all of it, they're, what they're trying to do is get rid of
Speaker 7:  the interface. 'cause the screen is so small, right. Compared to everything
Speaker 7:  else. So I get rid of these elements, we'll bring them back when you need
Speaker 7:  them. And I understand the temptation And I, again, not having used it,
Speaker 7:  it, the thing that always confuses everyone in the end is that the tools
Speaker 7:  go away unless a certain object is on screen and
Speaker 7:  that thing is not never guaranteed be on the screen.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, no, I agree. I mean, And I think, again, it goes back to this question
Speaker 6:  of like, does Apple just think we all know how to do everything? Because
Speaker 6:  like, I even think about the, the camera app in a bunch of these and, and
Speaker 6:  we were gonna get to this later, but we're gonna talk about this for a minute
Speaker 6:  now. The super sparse new iPhone
Speaker 6:  camera app that is just like a photo button and a video button and then they're
Speaker 6:  like, oh, do you want all the other stuff that's somewhere else? I'm like,
Speaker 6:  where I, I would like those things. I don't know. Alison, how did, what
Speaker 6:  did you think of that thing?
Speaker 8:  I welcome it. I think that the camera app is
Speaker 8:  confusing as hell lately. So maybe it was time to kind of
Speaker 8:  reset and maybe it is a thing of like, we'll take it one step too far and
Speaker 8:  then kind of like relent a little bit. But
Speaker 6:  Is it less confusing now or is it just fewer buttons?
Speaker 8:  I, you know, I think it, it will be
Speaker 8:  one of those things you have to try out, like the thing I'm definitely on
Speaker 8:  board with is the kind of like toggle between still photo
Speaker 8:  capture and video capture. So you're not like
Speaker 8:  scrolling around trying to switch to a video mode. I think that makes a ton
Speaker 8:  of sense that the thing that I irritates me
Speaker 8:  is that sometimes the setting I'm looking for
Speaker 8:  is in the settings menu under camera and it's the, you know, the
Speaker 8:  like HDR and 4K or whatever option. And sometimes the setting
Speaker 8:  I'm looking for is in the camera app in one of those
Speaker 8:  weird, like, tap up here on this little arrow kind of deals.
Speaker 8:  So I don't know if they address that in this
Speaker 8:  redesign camera app, but I think it is due for
Speaker 8:  a shakeup. It just turns into a like never ending kind
Speaker 8:  of like sideways scrolling list of modes
Speaker 8:  if you just let it, you know, go af year after year.
Speaker 7:  Apple's in a really unique place with the camera app, like industry-wide.
Speaker 7:  Because one of the ways the Android side of the house
Speaker 7:  tries to lower the switching costs from iPhone to Android is by just
Speaker 7:  ruthlessly copying the camera. Yeah. Because if you pick up a new phone and
Speaker 7:  you can't use the camera, you're done. And they know it. Sam Byford actually
Speaker 7:  wrote a great piece for us ages ago about the,
Speaker 7:  the co the ruthless copying of the camera app on Chi, on Chinese Android
Speaker 7:  phones in particular. Hmm. And the, the reason is we, we've
Speaker 7:  seen this, I think with celebrities taking selfie, I can't remember who it
Speaker 7:  was, but there's like some video of a celebrity trying to take a selfie with
Speaker 7:  a fan. She can't figure out the Android camera. Oh
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I remember this. Oh yeah,
Speaker 8:  Who
Speaker 7:  Is that? And they, all the Android manufacturers know what's going on. They
Speaker 7:  know that if you pick up a new phone and the camera app is too different
Speaker 7:  and you can't just figure it out, like you're done, you're, you're not even
Speaker 7:  like thinking about buying that phone for one more second. So they've all
Speaker 7:  ruthlessly copied the camera app. Apple doesn't have this problem, they can
Speaker 7:  ruin the camera app and you not gonna leave the iPhone. Right. Like they've
Speaker 7:  gotta ruin 10 more things on top of it for you to consider switching it.
Speaker 7:  So I think this is them taking advantage of their sort of market position
Speaker 7:  and saying, oh, okay, we can, we can clean up this app in some ways that
Speaker 7:  make sense. And really, I think most people think about it as video and
Speaker 7:  photo and then they have added the formats back to the top, which I
Speaker 7:  think is tremendously useful. Yeah. But again, you've got more,
Speaker 7:  you know, when they announce it, they're like, and to go to these other modes,
Speaker 7:  it's just like one tap away and it's like, oh, so one more tap. Are you suggesting
Speaker 7:  it's one more tap? Right. We'll see, I I hope they kind of offer a
Speaker 7:  simple mode and a pro mode, but that's a dream. Who
Speaker 6:  Knows if that, yeah. I mean I, I wonder with all of this stuff, like
Speaker 6:  how much the design sort of
Speaker 6:  accrues back to like, attach rates. Like should I just assume that the fact
Speaker 6:  that there's photo and video and nothing else means that almost nobody touches
Speaker 6:  anything other than photo and video. And I think intuitively that's probably
Speaker 6:  true. And So there is something too, like let's just put the two buttons
Speaker 6:  everybody touches in front of them and people who wanna find other buttons
Speaker 6:  will find ways to find other buttons.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Like you, maybe that's can, you can make your picture a
Speaker 8:  portrait mode photo after the fact. So you don't need to go looking for that.
Speaker 8:  They'll just, you know, you can decide about that, what your photo is
Speaker 8:  after you take it. It's, it's the dream.
Speaker 6:  I like default to shooting in portrait because I forget that all the time.
Speaker 6:  And that, that's a, that's a useful tip that I should remember. What did
Speaker 6:  you guys hear from folks about Liquid Glass? I would say the, the Internet's
Speaker 6:  reaction was
Speaker 6:  kind of all over the place. Some people who were like, this is the most beautiful
Speaker 6:  thing Apple has ever done, look at this water droplet and other people who
Speaker 6:  were like liquid ass was a, was a phrase a lot of people were using that
Speaker 6:  I very much enjoyed. What was it like in the room? Like was this a
Speaker 6:  standup and cheer Liquid Glass moment? Like what, what did it feel like
Speaker 8:  To me it kind of felt like, well this is what we're doing. You know,
Speaker 8:  there's a little bit, I don't think I got a sense of like, you know,
Speaker 8:  wild appreciation for it or like dislike
Speaker 8:  of it. It just, it feels like a reality
Speaker 8:  of like, Apple's gonna show you how you're gonna redesign your
Speaker 8:  app and you're gonna find a way to do it.
Speaker 8:  That was just my read on the, on the room today.
Speaker 7:  There was just a lot more general sarcasm
Speaker 7:  Mm. From the developers I talked to at Dub dub this time.
Speaker 7:  There, there's, you know what Apple talk about
Speaker 6:  That is not the normal vibe at dub dub. Dub dubs a very like earnest place.
Speaker 7:  Although I did. Yeah. I, I was texting back and forth briefly with Walt Mossberg
Speaker 7:  mostly he was like, what was that song at the end, which we should talk about.
Speaker 7:  But I was like, there's some, you know, they're not a hundred percent app
Speaker 7:  here. And he was like, in my long experience covering Apple, the developers
Speaker 7:  are never a hundred percent app. So take it for what it's for fair. That's
Speaker 7:  my shout out to it. But like Apple didn't talk about
Speaker 7:  app store rates. They didn't talk about coming off of 30 or
Speaker 7:  15%. They didn't talk about web links. There's a
Speaker 7:  whole universe of stuff that developers are unhappy about that they did not
Speaker 7:  hear about. Apple talked about running models locally on the phone.
Speaker 7:  Developers are happy about that because that's faster, right? There's lower
Speaker 7:  latency. If you're doing the AI stuff on the phone, it's free,
Speaker 7:  which is cool. They like that. But now everything has
Speaker 7:  to look different. They're like, I don't know, we're kind of building everything
Speaker 7:  and react on the web and like shipping 'em in wrappers and like get over
Speaker 7:  it. And like, there's just some real questions over whether this stuff
Speaker 7:  comes for free or whether you have to redesign your entire situation
Speaker 7:  from the ground up for a set of iOS customers in a design language
Speaker 7:  that they might may not like very much while 80% of the world has
Speaker 7:  Android phones.
Speaker 6:  Right.
Speaker 7:  And that's a, that's a bigger set of question marks than Oh on iOS. Like
Speaker 7:  we can just run some of our, the stuff on the local AI models for free, which
Speaker 7:  is just a different set of incentives.
Speaker 6:  Right? Yeah. It seems like the upside if you're a developer
Speaker 6:  is in, in a Liquid Glass world, everything runs everywhere. Right.
Speaker 6:  Which is very clearly what Apple's trying to do here. Right? Like they, they
Speaker 6:  talked about this over and over and over that like this is, this is a broad
Speaker 6:  system-wide redesign to bring all this stuff together and all this stuff
Speaker 6:  and like fine, all that makes sense. So you can, you can ship an iPhone app
Speaker 6:  and it'll work ont VOS and look more or less Right.
Speaker 6:  Is something great.
Speaker 7:  How long is Thet v os section of this conversation in your notes? David?
Speaker 7:  Is it more than two seconds?
Speaker 6:  Would you like to hear all of the notes that I wrote? Fort v os We can do
Speaker 6:  this part right now. You're ready? Yeah. More notifications, new
Speaker 6:  screensavers, connect to a speaker. That's, that's all I read, that's all
Speaker 6:  I got for you.
Speaker 6:  But, but the, the flip side then is I think, I think as far as I can tell,
Speaker 6:  and from the little bit I've talked to folks today, this actually is gonna
Speaker 6:  ask a lot of people because it's not just like
Speaker 6:  new, you know, animation styles or, or how you move from place to place.
Speaker 6:  It's like you have to move where the buttons are in your app and that's,
Speaker 6:  that's like a real meaningful thing and the the, they're gonna look
Speaker 6:  different and the way that people navigate them is gonna be different. And
Speaker 6:  you're gonna look at the way that something scrolls under your button and
Speaker 6:  you're not gonna like it and you're gonna have to change where the menus
Speaker 6:  go. And I think this is like to users, it's gonna
Speaker 6:  feel really sort of like a coat of paint. But for developers to do it
Speaker 6:  properly, I think is gonna actually take kind of a lot of sort of
Speaker 6:  architectural work. Unless Apple has done a really good job of
Speaker 6:  building this stuff into its development kits in a way that you kind of get
Speaker 6:  it for free. And I have not heard a ton of optimism that that is the case.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And especially 'cause you know, they're gonna change it over the next
Speaker 7:  six months. Like if you're designing your app and you're like, well everything
Speaker 7:  is clear now, So I need to make this make sense. And then Apple makes everything
Speaker 7:  slightly more frosted over the next six months. Like Right. I think we're
Speaker 7:  in all in for a long period of wait and see here.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Did you guys see the, the home screen mockups with the clear
Speaker 6:  icons? Not a fan. Hmm. Not a fan. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I don't want that
Speaker 7:  The, to actually more directly answer your question. I think the vibe
Speaker 7:  online was much meaner than the vibe there. Okay. In the way that everything
Speaker 7:  online is always meaner. Sure. And you show up in person, everyone, they're
Speaker 7:  like, well it turns out I'm a bit of a coward. Like,
Speaker 7:  like that's the nature of every online bully that is forced to
Speaker 7:  contend with the real world. Like that's what we do. Oh, it turns out I'm
Speaker 7:  gonna wis right out. I mean, you're an Apple's house. Like, everyone's like
Speaker 7:  sort of happy they're playing new age music all over the place.
Speaker 7:  It's very odd.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And the people who are there are the people wanna be there. But then you,
Speaker 7:  I went online, I was like, oh, people are tearing this to shreds.
Speaker 7:  And So I think we're just, we're just in for a period of cooling off
Speaker 7:  And I do think they're, they just have to change it. If they don't change
Speaker 7:  it, I will come, we can rerun this podcast And I will eat my words. There's
Speaker 7:  no way they're not gonna change it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, no, I I think that's right. And one of the things I've enjoyed is there's
Speaker 6:  an accessibility feature in the developer beta that's, I think it's just
Speaker 6:  called high contrast mode. And it just undoes all of it and looks a thousand
Speaker 6:  times better. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  It's like,
Speaker 6:  It just frosts the glass and it's like, guys just, just frost the glass.
Speaker 6:  It's like, it's fine. What if there was a little bit of color but it didn't
Speaker 6:  put the words behind the words so that I couldn't read any of the words anymore.
Speaker 6:  Like wouldn't that be great? What we
Speaker 8:  Need is a slider. How much, how much frost in the glass.
Speaker 6:  I like that idea. Or like a, like a clicker you can use to un rost and un
Speaker 6:  rost the glass at
Speaker 7:  Will. Yeah. Oh, that'd be great. Like a, like a privacy screen. Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 7:  Like those windows they have. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  This is what I'm saying. This is a good idea. So, okay. Before we, before
Speaker 6:  we get into the specific platform stuff, Nila, you made a face at me earlier
Speaker 6:  when I said they didn't even talk all that much about Apple intelligence.
Speaker 6:  How, what's, what's your sort of overall read on like how much today
Speaker 7:  Was an AI day? Like did it feel like an AI day to you maybe in
Speaker 7:  the way that it should have the first time? Okay. Right. So everything
Speaker 7:  they announce had some little component of machine learning smarts built
Speaker 7:  into it. Right? So so much of what they announce across the board and their
Speaker 7:  operating systems are like the phone app is a lot
Speaker 7:  smarter now. It it, you know, like, and these are, again, these are
Speaker 7:  android features, but like it'll wait on hold for you and then when the person
Speaker 7:  on the other end picks up, it'll say like, I'm coming. And then like, ring
Speaker 7:  you. You just need some AI ish features to pull that
Speaker 7:  off, right. To detect the whole music and wait and like do the thing.
Speaker 7:  There's just so much of that throughout the operating system now you're
Speaker 7:  like, oh this is, this is, these are table stakes AI features for a phone
Speaker 7:  operating system at this point, what they didn't announce was
Speaker 7:  Apple Intelligence, the part where you just talk to Siri and it like does
Speaker 7:  stuff for you. Right. Which I'm just gonna keep hammering this point home.
Speaker 7:  That's what people want AI to be. They're talking to chat
Speaker 7:  JPT all day long and thinking it's alive. Yeah. So you're like, we
Speaker 7:  did AI too. And it's like, what is it? And it's like, well you can
Speaker 7:  screenshot a webpage and then buy a lamp and it's like, well I'm like,
Speaker 7:  that's not what we were thinking about. Right, right. Jen Moji is
Speaker 7:  not digital. God what was the one today with the two?
Speaker 7:  They're like, we combined a, a sloth with a light bulb sloth with a
Speaker 7:  light bulbs to indicate that I was slow to get the joke. Yeah. And it's like
Speaker 7:  guys, like first of all, this is a great PhD thesis in modern communication.
Speaker 7:  Like this is a trillion dollar company. It's one, it it,
Speaker 7:  depending on the stock price, it is the richest company in the history of
Speaker 7:  the world, like on any given day. And you're like, we did a sloth and
Speaker 7:  a light bulb to indicate that I was allowed for him to get a joke. What is
Speaker 7:  going on? Like stop it. Like, no, don't do this.
Speaker 7:  What people want is to talk to the computer in a natural language
Speaker 7:  interface and have it talk back to them and do stuff for them. That that's
Speaker 7:  the only thing that can ever deliver on the promise of something called Apple
Speaker 7:  intelligence. Like it just is. And so all this other stuff, it is
Speaker 7:  ai. So there you look down the list of features, right? There are AI features
Speaker 7:  through and through, there are machine learning features through and through.
Speaker 7:  So I, the, the reason I made the face is one, every time you speak I make
Speaker 7:  a face's And I often have to hold myself back from revealing it, but I'm
Speaker 7:  quite tired today. So just kinda that's the tracks. But
Speaker 7:  they screwed up last year by, by just sort of like mashing
Speaker 7:  up like text generators and writing tools with like,
Speaker 7:  you know, super Siri and this year they just talked,
Speaker 7:  they didn't talk about that at all and they gave you a sloth with a light
Speaker 7:  bulb. And I like, AI is here and it's like we have to get ourselves straight.
Speaker 7:  There's exactly one big thing that AI's gonna do and no
Speaker 7:  company has shipped it yet at scale in a way that works. And we're all just
Speaker 7:  gonna keep working on it and that's fine or whatever. You can have whatever
Speaker 7:  feelings you want about it In the meantime, all of this other stuff is actually
Speaker 7:  quite useful and it's, it's kinda like unfair to punish it
Speaker 7:  with this isn't digital cause right? Like it is
Speaker 7:  genuinely useful that it, the phone can detect more scams
Speaker 7:  in messages on and in the phone app and like shunt those people off into
Speaker 7:  like a waiting, like you can't be too mad at that stuff, especially when
Speaker 7:  it's happening locally on the phone. So I think you see more and more of
Speaker 7:  that happening on the phone. They're finding more and more places to use
Speaker 7:  the tools. They're just the only real way you can deliver on something
Speaker 7:  called Apple Intelligence is by letting you talk to Siri and having it talk
Speaker 7:  back to you.
Speaker 6:  Right? Yeah. I mean I think I, I was thinking about this a lot with all the
Speaker 6:  translation stuff which kept showing up across a bunch of these platforms.
Speaker 6:  So they're doing like real time on device
Speaker 6:  cross app translation stuff. Whether it's like, you know,
Speaker 6:  translation of lyrics in Apple Music I think was a neat one or
Speaker 6:  translation on calls. It's like that's pure AI
Speaker 6:  for that stuff to work is pure ai. That is the stuff. And it's like,
Speaker 6:  I, I think I like the phrase we shouldn't punish it for not being God.
Speaker 6:  It's like, it's true that stuff is like, but it is just, it's
Speaker 6:  just software. Like before, before chat GPT
Speaker 6:  we would've just called this software, right? And it's like machine learning's
Speaker 6:  been around for a long time. We've been doing this for a long time. This
Speaker 6:  stuff is, is cool and interesting and useful and it is better because
Speaker 6:  these large language models exist. That stuff has been like
Speaker 6:  a, a leap in a lot of that technology, but it's not
Speaker 6:  God. And So I think you're right that like Apple should have talked about
Speaker 6:  a lot of this stuff this way last year And I think
Speaker 6:  the, the vibe probably would've been really different. But instead you promised
Speaker 6:  God how do you, like you can't walk back from promising God to people.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. You're gonna talk to Siri and it's gonna remember who you had a meeting
Speaker 7:  with while you're like cowering in the anti chamber of the coffee shop. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  That's the ad that they had to pull. Right. And remember that's a lot.
Speaker 7:  There's a lot of steps between here and there to pull that off. And that
Speaker 7:  has nothing to do with whether you can incrementally, incrementally improve
Speaker 7:  the experience you're using the phone today. But that's what everybody
Speaker 7:  wants. Like, and when I say that's what everybody wants, what I mean is chat
Speaker 7:  is one of the most popular consumer apps ever. Like maybe the most popular
Speaker 7:  consumer app ever. People just wanna talk to their phone in that way. And
Speaker 7:  Apple's argument is, well they great, they're doing it on the iPhone today,
Speaker 7:  they're downloading the chat GPT app and when you subscribe to it, we take
Speaker 7:  30% of that and we're good. Like, what more do you want from us? Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And the pressure is everybody understands, well maybe I can get you to buy
Speaker 7:  a different device if that actually occurs. Google very much is like, maybe
Speaker 7:  you'll just say stuff to Google and we'll go and do everything for you. And
Speaker 7:  that's the app platform of the future. Apple has to make the turn
Speaker 7:  and they haven't expressed how they're gonna make the turn.
Speaker 8:  Right? Yeah. If they had kind of set up the Siri
Speaker 8:  remembers who you talk to at a party stuff as like
Speaker 8:  future, you know, this is kind of the north star where
Speaker 8:  we're headed. I think that would've been one thing, but they literally presented
Speaker 8:  it like it's here, it can, it's gonna do this, you know,
Speaker 8:  any minute now. And that's why it just feels weird to kind
Speaker 8:  of go back into like, oh these are machine learning
Speaker 8:  updates. Yeah. You know, it was like, okay, you had us going all the way
Speaker 8:  to like, Siri fixes your social life to like
Speaker 8:  we're back at square one now. Like if it had all kind of built
Speaker 8:  in in a more linear fashion, I think it it would've made sense. But
Speaker 8:  it's it's a little like whip flashy right now. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Well so that's, I mean I, we will probably come to this when I guess to the
Speaker 7:  Mac, but if you look at what they were showing off in Spotlight, it's right
Speaker 7:  there,
Speaker 7:  right? You can just search across your Mac, you can, you
Speaker 7:  can type in shortcuts to get it to send emails for you. Like all this stuff
Speaker 7:  you can do where the puzzle pieces are very
Speaker 7:  clearly in place
Speaker 7:  but they just haven't been put together in, in the new Spotlight. You can
Speaker 7:  sort of put them together yourself. I don dunno if any of that's gonna work
Speaker 7:  either.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Let, let's, let's start talking about the platforms. I that's, that's,
Speaker 6:  we should get into all of that. But first let's take a break. We're
Speaker 6:  All right, we're back. V song is here. Hy-Vee welcome. Hi you,
Speaker 6:  you made it out of Apple Park. We're very happy you're here
Speaker 13:  In one piece.
Speaker 6:  It's not a small task sometimes. Wait,
Speaker 7:  Can I tell a story about being at Apple events with with V when you're live
Speaker 7:  logging?
Speaker 13:  Oh my god. Okay, sure.
Speaker 7:  Normally everyone's like, you know, busy, they're focused, they're looking
Speaker 7:  down. V is like a, like a mystery science
Speaker 7:  theater, 3000 but of size and moans
Speaker 7:  just like ah, ah.
Speaker 7:  And it like, especially in like the fitness segments
Speaker 7:  where they're like a personalized health coach will like walk you through
Speaker 7:  all of the data we've been scanning from your body and give and these just
Speaker 7:  like the whole time. It's very
Speaker 7:  entertaining. It's,
Speaker 13:  Well I'm at least it's entertaining. I am not aware that I'm making those
Speaker 13:  noises half the time.
Speaker 7:  So no, that much is also very clear to everyone.
Speaker 7:  Full involuntary, full body reactions to what see
Speaker 6:  Is like the real time audience reaction meter like from one to 10 at all
Speaker 6:  times. It is
Speaker 7:  Very good. Hi again. Again, if you have the means, I highly recommend it.
Speaker 13:  You know, I think someone reached out to me on Blue Sky And I was like,
Speaker 13:  it's been an honor watching you live blog. And I was like, oh my God. What?
Speaker 6:  It's terrifying. My experience of what it looks like to watch someone
Speaker 6:  live blog is they just sit there until they sunburn typing on their
Speaker 6:  computer in Apple Park and that's
Speaker 13:  The live experience. Oh no, I had three bottles of sunscreen And I
Speaker 13:  was making several pale white men who did not bring sunscreen, put
Speaker 13:  sunscreen on their face today.
Speaker 7:  I can confirm this Lord's work. Both, both Allison and V said it was their
Speaker 7:  mission to get people to our sunscreen today. Yeah. And we did it.
Speaker 6:  I'm very proud of both of you. Yeah. Alright, let's talk about platforms.
Speaker 6:  So we, we've talked about the big picture stuff. V you missed us having
Speaker 6:  a lot of feelings about Liquid Glass.
Speaker 6:  I suspect there will be ample time to have more feelings about Liquid Glass,
Speaker 6:  which again, I hate more every single time I say it out loud.
Speaker 6:  Let's talk about the Mac first. I have this in rough order of how interested
Speaker 6:  I am in it personally, but Neli for you, I switched
Speaker 6:  one and two because you, you are just dying to talk about Spotlight.
Speaker 6:  So the, the big news Mac OS 26, it's called
Speaker 6:  Tahoe. It has the new design, it has all the Liquid Glass stuff, but the
Speaker 6:  big new feature And I would say potentially the like most
Speaker 6:  universally exciting thing at all of WWDC
Speaker 6:  was new Spotlight. Do, do you wanna explain what New Spotlight is and
Speaker 6:  why you're excited about it?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, although I think it's a tie. I think it's New Spotlight and the iPad
Speaker 7:  stuff. Okay. Those are the things that I heard about.
Speaker 6:  That was gonna be my number one. We were gonna do that first, but for you
Speaker 6:  we're doing Spotlight.
Speaker 7:  I think we can move through the new Spotlight pretty quickly. So Spotlight
Speaker 7:  is when you hold down command space on a Mac, it initially just started as
Speaker 7:  like a search of all your files and then they started adding more features
Speaker 7:  to it. And I could start like search the web and now they're just adding
Speaker 7:  the capabilities to take actions across your computer to it
Speaker 7:  in weird ways. Like you can launch shortcuts from it,
Speaker 7:  which implies that you have a library of shortcuts, which implies that David
Speaker 7:  has to talk about shortcuts, which implies that David is gonna receive hate
Speaker 7:  mail from the many dozens of shortcuts fans that exist in this world.
Speaker 7:  Just
Speaker 6:  Know that I hear you and that you're wrong and that's okay.
Speaker 7:  And then you know, it it, they've added stuff they should have had from the
Speaker 7:  beginning. Like all of the menu items and whatever app you're using
Speaker 7:  are now available on Spotlight. So you can just like start typing a menu
Speaker 7:  command and issue a menu command. And then there's, you know, the, because
Speaker 7:  shortcuts are more powerful and have access to some amount of ai,
Speaker 7:  you can start to take more complicated commands that feel more
Speaker 7:  natural language and you're just inching towards, what I keep describing
Speaker 7:  is like a magic command line on your computer where you can just open
Speaker 7:  it and type it and tell it what to do and then it off it goes off and does
Speaker 7:  something. And that is so close to just saying what you want to Siri
Speaker 7:  to the point where like the, the technology mechanisms behind the
Speaker 7:  new Spotlight are the same is what they talked about with Super Siri last
Speaker 7:  year. It's the app intense framework where Spotlight is just talking
Speaker 7:  to apps through this new framework that eventually Siri will use to
Speaker 7:  talk to apps. And so they're, they're inching towards a place
Speaker 7:  where you have like a command line that is not just a, like a
Speaker 7:  tape, properly formatted commands command line, but
Speaker 7:  just you open it up and you start typing and stuff starts happening and that's
Speaker 7:  awesome. Whether any of this will work or any of developers
Speaker 7:  will support app intents or importantly whether anyone is
Speaker 7:  using applications on our Mac that aren't just web apps and a web browser.
Speaker 7:  All of this remains seen. David, I'm very curious for your take
Speaker 7:  on this 'cause apps like raycast have existed forever. Like there's a
Speaker 7:  universe of apps that take over command space to do stuff in the
Speaker 7:  productivity world. And I can't tell if all of them just got sherlocked or
Speaker 7:  none of them feel competitive at all or what the, what the overlap
Speaker 7:  really is,
Speaker 6:  They will tell you things like, we're so
Speaker 6:  glad the space is expanding and we think this really validates our thesis.
Speaker 6:  The
Speaker 7:  Last thing you see before you die. That's
Speaker 6:  Right. We're so glad that others are, are, you know, really believing in
Speaker 6:  this thing that we've been, they are all going to be petrified because this
Speaker 6:  is, this is the thing that is now
Speaker 6:  good enough that people might not switch to Raycast or Alfred. Right? So
Speaker 6:  like based on what we've seen these other apps, specifically
Speaker 6:  Raycast and Alfred, which are like the two biggest ones in this space and
Speaker 6:  have been around for a long time and are like enormously powerful, right?
Speaker 6:  They have these huge extension libraries that let you essentially like plug
Speaker 6:  them into all kinds of other apps and all kinds of other uses and you can
Speaker 6:  essentially do anything on your computer through one of these apps
Speaker 6:  if you program it correctly enough. And now Raycast in particular is also
Speaker 6:  like deep into AI stuff. So you can interact with AI models
Speaker 6:  just right through Raycast that way. But it's a lot of
Speaker 6:  that is predicated on the fact that Spotlight is really, really bad. And
Speaker 6:  is it like Spotlight, Spotlight is pretty bad. It's a useful like
Speaker 6:  me search engine for the stuff on your computer that's like as good as it
Speaker 6:  has been for a very long time. And now it's gonna be much better than that
Speaker 6:  if this stuff works to the point where a, it might teach people
Speaker 6:  that this is a thing you can do. I don't know if y'all have this experience,
Speaker 6:  but like on my phone I use Spotlight all the time to like find an open apps.
Speaker 6:  But most of the other people in my life when they take my phone don't just
Speaker 6:  like instinctively pull down and search for Spotify. They go like hunting
Speaker 6:  for the Spotify logo. And I'm just like, this is just not a, this is just
Speaker 6:  not an ingrained use case. Like Spotlight is not a mainstream tool
Speaker 6:  on any of these platforms. And I think, I think this might be the turn
Speaker 6:  that helps it start to get there. And I just think that's super
Speaker 6:  interesting. Like forget what people actually use it for. The idea that this
Speaker 6:  is now like a text box becomes the way I interact with my computer.
Speaker 6:  It it, it's the first time that's been true in 40 years And I think that's
Speaker 6:  really fascinating. Like v are you, are you a Spotlight person?
Speaker 13:  I am And I was a really big Alfred person for a long time
Speaker 13:  and then I just stopped one day. I don't really know why I did, but
Speaker 13:  I just did. So yeah, to your point, I use Spotlight
Speaker 13:  nonstop on my phone and it's because I have too many freaking apps.
Speaker 13:  So like I, we were talking about how bad my eyesight is, I
Speaker 13:  don't have time to look at my giant iPhone screen to, to find a tiny little
Speaker 13:  app on the whatever page. So I, yeah, I'm a big Spotlight user,
Speaker 13:  So I mean it does suck. Alfred
Speaker 13:  is better. I'm sure I haven't used Raycast, but I'm sure that's also
Speaker 13:  better. So yeah, I'm kind of excited to see how
Speaker 13:  it works. I'm just super skeptical that it will work the way
Speaker 13:  I want. 'cause I just feel like anytime they say it's gonna make
Speaker 13:  your life better, I'm like, yeah, I can't wait. This isn't what I wanted
Speaker 13:  close, but eh, so I'm, I'm reserving judgment, but this
Speaker 7:  Is the peril of the magic command line, right? Right. To make
Speaker 7:  it work in a way that makes it useful.
Speaker 7:  You have to be able to type anything you want into it. This is why like my
Speaker 7:  like windows and mice and graphical user interfaces took over from old
Speaker 7:  school command lines. 'cause you like show a blinking cursor to people that
Speaker 7:  could only accept certain commands like that just made computers
Speaker 7:  inaccessible. You're like, here's some pictures you can move 'em around.
Speaker 7:  Like, okay, everybody can use this. You wanna bring it back? It has to
Speaker 7:  be able to take whatever you put into it, which is where LLMs and all this
Speaker 7:  AI stuff should shine. And like that's the
Speaker 7:  gap. And that's why I keep saying like, they talked about that stuff and
Speaker 7:  they showed you how it would work and then they didn't connect it to Siri.
Speaker 7:  'cause it, they can't make that promise again because that's also how
Speaker 7:  Siri should work where you just say whatever you want, like figures it out.
Speaker 6:  I think it's partly that I also think I, I'm realizing more the more we talk
Speaker 6:  that like the, the Siri reputational hole is
Speaker 6:  so deep for all of this stuff for Apple that if, if it, if it
Speaker 6:  were to have connected that to Siri and it was like, oh, you know, Spotlight
Speaker 6:  is gonna let you through Siri, everybody would've immediately been like,
Speaker 6:  oh, this will never work. There's no chances This is a look Tomatoes thrown
Speaker 6:  at the screen. Yeah, exactly. Yeah. But So I, So I think, I think like I'm,
Speaker 6:  I'm starting to realize maybe Apple is going out of its way to not connect
Speaker 6:  this stuff back to Siri in order to maybe convince you that
Speaker 6:  it can actually still work because the, the brand whole
Speaker 6:  that Siri has just like burned through Apple is pretty nuts.
Speaker 6:  And Siri just went off two times while I was saying that. So I'm sorry to
Speaker 6:  everyone watching and listening, this is what we do here. But no, I
Speaker 6:  I think, I think you're right that Spotlight could like
Speaker 6:  it could feel that way now and there's nothing sort of technically
Speaker 6:  impossible about a lot of the stuff Apple is trying to do here. Like the
Speaker 6:  app intent thing is very smart. If developers get on board, the the
Speaker 6:  commands it was doing are mostly pretty easy. Like what was the example he
Speaker 6:  gave? He typed sm to send a message like that's solved
Speaker 6:  technology. This stuff works.
Speaker 7:  It's important to, to kind of pull this apart. There's the
Speaker 7:  SM to send a message was they had made like a short, like
Speaker 7:  a quick key shortcut, which you can do right now. It's like a text expander,
Speaker 7:  but they had mapped it to a shortcut and then the shortcut could do stuff.
Speaker 7:  So this is like their layers of automation in the Mac that they're
Speaker 7:  like, look at what you can do as a Mac power user.
Speaker 6:  So that was hitting Spotlight and shortcuts. I was thinking that was just
Speaker 6:  a like a system level thing. Okay. That makes me like a,
Speaker 7:  Well so the system level thing, this is where, where I think it got particularly
Speaker 7:  confusing the demo on their website right now, if you go to
Speaker 7:  apple.com/os/macs, you can scroll down, you can like look at this thing.
Speaker 7:  They open Spotlight, it says biggest Spotlight ever and here's the, the graphic
Speaker 7:  that's animating on the screen and he the IT type send
Speaker 7:  and that brings up a list of commands. And so one of them is
Speaker 7:  send in messages and you like click that and then you type
Speaker 7:  let's meet at the studio and you click two and then it has a list of
Speaker 7:  like your contacts. So you see like it's
Speaker 7:  prompting you to issue a command that looks an awful lot like
Speaker 7:  a shortcut.
Speaker 7:  This is a lot of like puzzle pieces, right? And so
Speaker 7:  what you, what they're getting at is, okay, all
Speaker 7:  the apps in your system will tell Spotlight all of the things they can do
Speaker 7:  and you'll start typing some stuff you want done and we'll like auto complete
Speaker 7:  the actions you want taken the data you want taken in like the,
Speaker 7:  the recipients of your message, which is another data in another field. And
Speaker 7:  then we'll like send that command into messages, which will then send this
Speaker 7:  thing off. And that is just like a hop away from making a
Speaker 7:  shortcut, which is itself a hop away from having a quick key assigned to
Speaker 7:  it. Like, and so you're, oh we're just stacking all of these capabilities
Speaker 7:  and we're making the interface Spotlight and eventually you're gonna be able
Speaker 7:  to just say out loud, send this to whoever at what time and
Speaker 7:  like we'll just, we'll just parse it all and do it correctly.
Speaker 7:  And there's like a little turn in there that's the natural language turn.
Speaker 7:  But in the meantime it's type as you start typing it, like
Speaker 7:  pre-populates all the commands and prompts you for what you wanna put, like
Speaker 7:  what variables you wanna pass through. This is all very smart, it's very
Speaker 7:  clever if they announce this stuff five years ago, it'd be like, this is
Speaker 7:  the future of computers here in 2025. Johnny
Speaker 7:  Ive and Sam Altman are like, what we're doing is we're gonna put Jesus in
Speaker 7:  a necklace. And it's like you're just in a whole different Jesus
Speaker 6:  In a
Speaker 7:  Right. Like you're just in a whole different context and like I think
Speaker 7:  it's very clever. I the idea that all the commands that are available from
Speaker 7:  all the applications of their computer are sort of just available in a command
Speaker 7:  line that is universally accessible is wild shit.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  But all those application developers have to like do it and then people
Speaker 7:  have to use it. And the thing that's staring 'em in the face is
Speaker 7:  literally chat GPT being like, what would say anything? And I'll lie to you
Speaker 7:  until you're happy. Yeah. Like that's, that's just a radically different
Speaker 7:  context to be. So
Speaker 6:  I will say, by the way, what you just described is, is pure Raycast, like
Speaker 6:  you just described Raycast. And, and the thing that Raycast did that was
Speaker 6:  so smart is like you can, you can build extensions that plug into other apps
Speaker 6:  and when you do that, it, it sort of declares a bunch of specific
Speaker 6:  actions you can do and things that you can look for and you can map those
Speaker 6:  things to keyboard shortcuts. And it is, it is both very
Speaker 6:  complicated and also kind of very simple at its core, right? Like what
Speaker 6:  you, none of what you just described requires groundbreaking
Speaker 6:  advances in artificial intelligence. That's just computer stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Right. It's just, it's just here. And there's, there's another thing Spotlight
Speaker 6:  can do where when you're in an app, you can invoke Spotlight to search the
Speaker 6:  menu inside of that app, which like every Photoshop user
Speaker 6:  is going to be thrilled about, right? Because suddenly instead of navigating
Speaker 6:  through six trees of menus, I can just search for
Speaker 6:  the menu item. I want to click and press enter and click it. Right?
Speaker 7:  But the problem with that is every Photoshop user also now largely a
Speaker 7:  Figma user and Figma is an app is expressed inside of a web
Speaker 7:  browser, right? That has no idea that any of this shit is happening, right?
Speaker 7:  Right. And the every electron app, which is like
Speaker 7:  a, you know, cheap and dirty way of getting web apps to look native on a,
Speaker 7:  on a Mac or pc And I know the electron, there's some very good electron apps
Speaker 7:  out there. There's some very bad electron app apps. So they're not gonna
Speaker 7:  know about this stuff. They're not gonna do this stuff. And so you really
Speaker 7:  just Apple's betting on developers, particularly on the Mac
Speaker 7:  participating in an ecosystem that right now they have no incentive to participate
Speaker 7:  in.
Speaker 6:  Right? This whole thing makes way more sense to me on an iPhone honestly,
Speaker 6:  as both as like a, a way I want to use it and as
Speaker 6:  a place you can actually do it because they don't, that same problem does
Speaker 6:  not exist in the same way on the iPhone. Yes,
Speaker 7:  Apple has militant control over it, right. Platform look,
Speaker 6:  You feel about it however you want, but the, the facts on the ground are,
Speaker 6:  it's all native apps. And and like to v's point, I have
Speaker 6:  a million apps, I don't know where any of them are. I would actually like
Speaker 6:  to not have to organize them And I would like to not have to go to them and
Speaker 6:  open them and look for them. I would like to just pull down and say,
Speaker 6:  play the song and it'll play the damn song. That's, that's how it should
Speaker 6:  work on my phone. I firmly believe that
Speaker 7:  It kind of works that way on your phone today. Are you,
Speaker 7:  you play you can just say play a song.
Speaker 6:  Play the song.
Speaker 13:  I gotta test this now too.
Speaker 6:  It it wants me to play it. It just started playing play
Speaker 6:  that song by train on Spotify. Oh no, it's a touche.
Speaker 6:  Oh I'm
Speaker 8:  Sorry about
Speaker 6:  That wind this round.
Speaker 7:  Just the the, the computers work today.
Speaker 6:  That one might have been a bad
Speaker 7:  Example
Speaker 6:  But if you wanna play any song other than play that song, you're,
Speaker 7:  This is why we need to build digital. God can I have
Speaker 7:  $1 trillion please?
Speaker 8:  I'm sort of reminded of like the Google search bar and how
Speaker 8:  that kind of changed over the years where it was, you know, you would just
Speaker 8:  type things to it and search Google. But then we all learned eventually like,
Speaker 8:  oh it'll do a math equation for you or you can just convert currency
Speaker 8:  and it sort of like the scope of what the search bar
Speaker 8:  became changed. And I, I don't know, I can see that
Speaker 8:  happening with Spotlight. Like I had to train myself to use it.
Speaker 8:  I just had the muscle memory of like looking for my apps and then once you
Speaker 8:  use it it was like, no, this is, this is better and other
Speaker 8:  things pop up too. And if it's gonna start prompting me to like do the thing
Speaker 8:  I was, I was trying to take three steps to do and it'll
Speaker 8:  do it in one tap. Like yeah I'll, I'll come back to that.
Speaker 13:  So what I actually use Spotlight for most on my Mac is
Speaker 13:  doing equations. So the debt
Speaker 8:  Tracks. Sure, there you go.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I'll
Speaker 13:  Buy that. I don, I don't wanna open a calculator app, I don't wanna type
Speaker 13:  it into another thing. No, I'm just gonna write my little equation while
Speaker 13:  calculating various debts in
Speaker 13:  Spotlight. That's my little calculator friend.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that works. And that's like, yeah. And again, there's so much stuff
Speaker 6:  you can plug into this if you can get people A, to put
Speaker 6:  their apps into it and B, to use it. And I think like the reason I'm so
Speaker 6:  interested in this is this feels like the biggest bet on Spotlight as an
Speaker 6:  interface in kind of that I can ever remember from Apple Spotlight has just
Speaker 6:  like been there for a long time and it's just like what if, what
Speaker 6:  if there was a plan for this and this feels like a plan, which I think is
Speaker 6:  very cool. Other Mac stuff before we move on, stop me if any of this is
Speaker 6:  interesting to any of you. Shortcuts automations, which means you can run
Speaker 6:  a, you consider shortcut to run at a time or when an event happens on your
Speaker 6:  computer. All my shortcuts nerds get excited. Sorry to
Speaker 6:  everyone else because you'll never learn how to build shortcuts. The journal
Speaker 6:  app coming into the Mac, people excited about that.
Speaker 7:  Wait, can I say one thing about shortcuts please? There are new shortcuts
Speaker 7:  that are like LM based. Yeah. So
Speaker 7:  really interesting ideas. Like if an image matching this
Speaker 7:  description shows up in this folder, take this action requires the
Speaker 7:  computer to be able to like look at an image and like decide whether it has
Speaker 7:  a tree in it or whatever you've specified. Fascinating. Then you can be
Speaker 7:  like, take my notes from the notes app and look at the text
Speaker 7:  and then transcribe it if it matches whatever. And then summarize that. Like
Speaker 7:  just interesting shortcuts that require you to have access to an LM in
Speaker 7:  specific ways are now just like there whether or not they will be
Speaker 7:  useful or function on time. Right. Which is
Speaker 7:  a major criticism of shortcuts that some people have and some people do not
Speaker 7:  apparently remains to be seen. But that kind of stuff is like
Speaker 7:  pretty interesting like image-based workflows that require the computer to
Speaker 7:  understand the contents of the image. I'd say a whole universe of, of new
Speaker 7:  things that people be able to build. Totally.
Speaker 13:  And I think my problem with like the shortcut stuff is that
Speaker 13:  it's still not smart enough for me because you still
Speaker 13:  have to be the person putting all of the components
Speaker 13:  together. You have to be the one defining what things are gonna be used
Speaker 13:  and then of course you can prompt the shortcut, but then you have to be,
Speaker 13:  you just have to use too much of your brain to make the smart shortcut work,
Speaker 13:  which is the current problem that I think a lot of people who don't have
Speaker 13:  functional developer brains and are like good at coding or these
Speaker 13:  like different logic trees have with shortcuts. 'cause you just don't know
Speaker 13:  what you can do with it. You don't know how to think in that way. Which
Speaker 13:  has been my problem with shortcuts this entire time. I wanna use shortcuts.
Speaker 13:  I love it. Like when you go into the little gallery and you're like, ooh,
Speaker 13:  I could, I could do this. This is a little fun. There's no like, you know,
Speaker 13:  I asked Apple and I'm, I was just like, hey, so can the Apple
Speaker 13:  intelligence just see the things that I do and what I'm doing
Speaker 13:  on like a bit regular basis and make that suggestion for me? Is
Speaker 13:  that what we're having here? And they're like, no, you still gotta use your
Speaker 13:  little brain and then have the AI help you. It's it's supplemental.
Speaker 13:  And I was like, but that's, that's, that's not what I want. I I wanna turn
Speaker 13:  my brain off and have the shortcut happen.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, you want the thing that's like every time you download a picture of
Speaker 6:  this, you put it over there. Do you want me to just start doing that for
Speaker 6:  you? Like that's, that's just sitting right there. Yes.
Speaker 7:  That's just super clippy. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I mean that's where we're, that's where we've been going buddy. That's what
Speaker 6:  I want. That's what we're doing. You know,
Speaker 13:  It's what we want. And, and and you still have to make the super clippy,
Speaker 13:  you can't just like offload the making of the super clippy. So I, I think
Speaker 13:  that's the most disappointing thing about it so far. It's a step in the
Speaker 13:  right direction. It's just not where I want it to be yet.
Speaker 7:  Well you know, it's, I agree that like either you have automation brain
Speaker 7:  or you don't, right? Like when I get home, turn on all the lights
Speaker 7:  is you can just say it out loud and then actually programming any smart home
Speaker 7:  platform to make that happen requires you to like understand if
Speaker 7:  then statements in a way that some people are like, I'm just never gonna
Speaker 7:  do this. And then some people are like, that's my whole personality, right?
Speaker 7:  And so that's one or the other from what I can tell. And
Speaker 7:  the dream is that, you know, even when you talk to the Alexa people or
Speaker 7:  whoever that the smart home platforms will start to do that for you.
Speaker 7:  It's still not the case. And even if you look at sort of where the cutting
Speaker 7:  edge of AI agent stuff is and kinda these new look platforms
Speaker 7:  like N eight N which I'm a little bit obsessed with, it's not,
Speaker 7:  you don't have logic gate automation brain. It's that the
Speaker 7:  stuff you can put like the legal blocks of the if then statements
Speaker 7:  are vastly more powerful than they were before. And you have all these kids
Speaker 7:  making tiktoks using NAN to like create agents doing all kinds of wild stuff.
Speaker 7:  'cause the tools even given are more powerful. Not the tool to author
Speaker 7:  the automation. And I want like that dynamic I think will always exist.
Speaker 7:  And here I think you're just seeing it play out in shortcuts where the, they
Speaker 7:  haven't figured out the technology problem of making the people who don't
Speaker 7:  have automation brain like find this to be a rewarding experience
Speaker 7:  and maybe they never will. But they're giving more and more powerful tools
Speaker 7:  to people who are like, I love this. And somehow that has to come
Speaker 7:  together. 'cause it does feel like the future of all computing is
Speaker 7:  just telling computers what to do and assuming that they will do it and that
Speaker 7:  requires the backend to work in this way. But in the meantime they're just
Speaker 7:  like, here's some more powerful Legos. Like go build whatever weird Lego
Speaker 7:  structure you want out of if then statements,
Speaker 6:  Right? And then two thirds of the world looks at those and goes, what is,
Speaker 6:  why do I have all these legos in front of me? I'm gonna leave.
Speaker 7:  And then one third of those people sends David angry emails about shortcuts
Speaker 6:  And I welcome them. I will, I will as I like to do,
Speaker 6:  show you the opening screen of a new shortcut and you can tell me what to
Speaker 6:  do about it. The first word is scripting and we're done. All right,
Speaker 6:  let's talk with the iPad, which I think was the other kind of big hit
Speaker 6:  moment and is also the thing I have been playing with for the last couple
Speaker 6:  of hours And I have a lot of feelings about it already. iPad S 26,
Speaker 6:  the same thing, Liquid Glass, lots of new apps, but like
Speaker 6:  v they kind of just made this thing a Mac. Did they just kind of make this
Speaker 6:  thing a Mac? They
Speaker 13:  Did, they made it a Mac. I, you know, like we've been talking for years
Speaker 13:  about just let me use Mac os on the iPad and they were like,
Speaker 13:  no, but kind of. So, you know, I I was
Speaker 13:  watching that through the live log And I was like, da David Pierce is like
Speaker 13:  screeching at this moment somewhere in, in the us Is it a
Speaker 13:  happy screech or is it a angry screech? I, I don't know, but it it's a screech
Speaker 13:  that the screech is happening.
Speaker 6:  I've just been burned so many times. Speed. Do you know what I mean? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Every time Apple is like, we've invented a new way to move windows around
Speaker 6:  And I keep being like, what if you, we, we already invented the only one
Speaker 6:  that needs to exist and it's just put them wherever you want. So I don't,
Speaker 6:  whatever you invented, I like it less,
Speaker 6:  but they did it better this time
Speaker 7:  By the way. I have an answer from some, you know, on the ground conversations
Speaker 7:  about why, why they tried everything else first. You are not gonna
Speaker 7:  like it, but this is the answer I was told because
Speaker 6:  They hate me personally. Yes.
Speaker 7:  They're like, we're we've run out of ways to torture David Pierce.
Speaker 7:  No, the iPad is a touch device and they were never ever,
Speaker 7:  ever gonna trade away against the zero lag responsiveness of the touchscreen
Speaker 7:  on the iPad. And so they were like, it would be too hard to allow
Speaker 7:  full Mac like multitasking and multi windowing and apps all running
Speaker 7:  at once because we can trade away against the latency of
Speaker 7:  the Mac interface. Like you can, this happens, you can click on stuff
Speaker 7:  on a Mac of like, nothing happens. You're like, huh, that's weird. If you
Speaker 7:  touch a screen and nothing happens, you're like, this thing's dead, right?
Speaker 7:  Like you can see the mouse pointer always moves on a Mac when
Speaker 7:  the mouse pointer stops moving, you're like, my Mac is dead. The mouse pointer
Speaker 7:  moves and you click on stuff and nothing happens. You're like, oh, this thing's
Speaker 7:  being slow. You touch an iPad screen, nothing happens. Or it gets dead and
Speaker 7:  there's no other indication that it's still alive. So their, their argument
Speaker 7:  was, we, we needed this much horsepower on the latest blah blah, blah generation
Speaker 7:  of blah blah blah, blah blah. So that we could finally allow you to do full
Speaker 7:  window multitasking in this way. I didn't say you were gonna like it And
Speaker 7:  I can already see David's face, but I'm telling you this is a thing that
Speaker 7:  a a few people there told me,
Speaker 6:  I buy the premise, I don't buy that the technology did not exist
Speaker 6:  before today. Do you know what I mean?
Speaker 7:  Just like telling you what I heard.
Speaker 6:  But so the the new multitasking system is is like, it's it's
Speaker 6:  almost freeform multitasking. It is not
Speaker 6:  exactly. There are a couple of rules you have to follow and it also, a lot
Speaker 6:  of it as ever depends on the, the actual design of the
Speaker 6:  apps themselves. I installed the beta and I've been playing around with it.
Speaker 6:  And if you want to just pull 12 apps in and have them
Speaker 6:  all sitting on top of each other, you can and it's awesome and no one
Speaker 6:  should do it because it breaks immediately and it doesn't really,
Speaker 7:  Doesn't make sense. Well there you go.
Speaker 13:  I was gonna ask, I was gonna ask like what is the maximum window
Speaker 13:  count that you can have on, on an iPad?
Speaker 6:  I believe I've had eight at once on the screen so far, which is
Speaker 6:  already like three or four more than makes any plausible sense to have.
Speaker 6:  But you, but I did it and it was there and it was working. And that is
Speaker 6:  something, it's a little confusing now because there are,
Speaker 6:  so the, the, the framework is basically you have, you have your
Speaker 6:  home screen with the app icons and then the, the sort of mental model is
Speaker 6:  there is now just like a screen over here that you put apps on.
Speaker 6:  You can either open an app full screen or you can you, you tap the little
Speaker 6:  bar in the corner and drag it to whatever size you want it to be and then
Speaker 6:  it sits there. You can drag another one on top of it. You can change the
Speaker 6:  size depending on how they've laid the app out. Some of them will only do
Speaker 6:  like iPad size, smaller iPad size and iPhone size. Some will
Speaker 6:  only do one. Some you can like freeform move around as you want to, but they
Speaker 6:  all just kind of live on this one screen together, right? All the apps.
Speaker 6:  And then if you, if you tap on the new little menu, it gives
Speaker 6:  you the, the red, yellow green buttons, you hit the green one, it full
Speaker 6:  screens it. If you hit the yellow one, it minimizes it
Speaker 6:  and if you hit the red one, it closes it. And if you were to say, David,
Speaker 6:  what's the difference between minimizing an app on an iPad and closing an
Speaker 6:  app on an iPad? I absolutely could not tell you no idea.
Speaker 6:  In both cases it just like animated retreats back into the icon
Speaker 6:  and then when you tap it, it opens again And I don't, I don't know what the
Speaker 6:  difference is. I will say
Speaker 7:  Apple has never, from the beginning of the
Speaker 7:  three, the stoplight metaphor for the windows, they've never
Speaker 7:  really known what the other two buttons are for. No. Like they've always
Speaker 7:  known what red is for. Yes. And the other ones are like, well we have
Speaker 7:  the stoplight
Speaker 7:  stuff, they're for stuff.
Speaker 8:  It's like when I, you know how you have there, there's clean
Speaker 8:  clothes in your house, there's a dirty clothes and then there's the like,
Speaker 8:  ah, you know I'm, I might not be done with this. That's like the yellow light
Speaker 8:  one that's just a little pile on the dresser of
Speaker 8:  like, maybe I'll use that a
Speaker 6:  Little bit. It's the one you smell and you're like, I can get away with it.
Speaker 6:  And it is kind
Speaker 8:  Of, you're like, yeah, this is still okay.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, the green button in particular for a long time on the Mac was just
Speaker 7:  like a
Speaker 7:  whatever we think this time. Like
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Didn't it just sort of, my memory of it is it just randomly changed
Speaker 6:  the size of the app to whatever it felt like.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, that's what it's, it's just like green means go, you know what I mean?
Speaker 7:  Like whatever you think go means in this context, it's, that's what might
Speaker 7:  happen. Yeah. And I think on the iPad you have the same between red and yellow.
Speaker 7:  It's fine, it's fine. Sure.
Speaker 6:  It's whatever. But there are a bunch of things about it that I think are
Speaker 6:  pretty clever. Like it has a little, they demoed this, the sort of little
Speaker 6:  flick gesture that you can do to, to anchor it to one side of the screen
Speaker 6:  or the other that works well. But like a lot of apple things you have
Speaker 6:  to like really learn how to do it. It's like a, you have to do kind of a
Speaker 6:  half flick to like the middle of the side. If you flick it too hard,
Speaker 6:  it just like bounces off and comes back. Wait,
Speaker 7:  Do you, are you flicking with your finger or using the mouse?
Speaker 6:  So you can do it with the mouse but I I I've just mostly been doing it with
Speaker 6:  my thumbs. So you've
Speaker 7:  Been like steam decking apps all over you.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, absolutely. But now to your point about the,
Speaker 6:  the mouse there is now like an honest to God pointer,
Speaker 6:  which makes such a bigger difference than I realized. Like there's been,
Speaker 6:  you could, you could move a cursor around but it was a little, little circular
Speaker 6:  thing. Yeah. Now it feels like you have a mouse on the computer and you can
Speaker 6:  click small things now. And it really like
Speaker 6:  those two things. Plus there's now a preview app which is just for PDFs,
Speaker 6:  which speaking of like a whole industry that just immediately got sherlocked
Speaker 6:  like sorry to everybody who built the $10 app for editing PDFs
Speaker 6:  because you're out
Speaker 7:  Of this, you're fine, you deserve to die and you know it. That's
Speaker 6:  Fair. I don't feel that
Speaker 7:  Bad. Your weird subscription N-F-T-P-D-F viewer, like
Speaker 7:  you should have been dead a long time ago. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  All the free trials I have signed up for to get Acrobat for one day to be
Speaker 6:  able to edit A-P-D-F-I no longer feel bad. You're
Speaker 7:  Not seen in the first Batman movie, the 89 Batman where the joker says, I'm
Speaker 7:  glad you're dead and starts cackling. I want you to picture my face, do an
Speaker 7:  AI of my face doing that A PDF
Speaker 6:  App. Love that for you. So yeah, put those things together. And then there's
Speaker 6:  a bunch of changes to the files app where now there's a list
Speaker 6:  view. They made a big deal out of a list view once a year. There
Speaker 6:  is a thing at WW DC where they're like, we've invented a computer feature
Speaker 6:  from the
Speaker 8:  Seventies. Can, can I say they did a whole screen that was just
Speaker 8:  files in the doc like, like just in bold, like
Speaker 8:  beautiful print. And I was like, oh well that's going in the live
Speaker 8:  blog 'cause it's so silly.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And then they're like, oh do, we're gonna explain to you how it works
Speaker 6:  and how it works is exactly like it does on the Mac. You tap on it
Speaker 6:  and it opens up and shows you the files and then you can click the files
Speaker 6:  and drag them somewhere. Like Neela, what was the, what was the thing last
Speaker 6:  year where they were, they were showing some kind of multitasking thing and
Speaker 6:  Craig Figi was like, he dragged something from one screen to another
Speaker 6:  on it was like the external display thing and he like it was, it was, it
Speaker 6:  was just his mind was blown that you could have something on one display
Speaker 6:  and then you could have it on the other display and then it was just like,
Speaker 6:  we're just doing this again.
Speaker 7:  There isn't most of the iPad features where they just made the iPad
Speaker 7:  a Mac were I think targeted specifically at me and my complaints about
Speaker 7:  the iPad over the years. They're like, let's talk about files. And it's like,
Speaker 7:  yeah dude, I told you do this a decade ago,
Speaker 7:  but they ended it all by, you know, like a very self-deprecating way,
Speaker 7:  right? They're like, can you imagine a pointer in a menu bar and Windows?
Speaker 7:  Who would've thought of these ideas? Like that's true. They know. Yeah, they
Speaker 7:  know what they're doing. But you know, the opportunity with the iPad
Speaker 7:  is you get to have these ideas from a fresh start because every year you
Speaker 7:  can change them app apparently. You know, and like the thing
Speaker 7:  that's holding the iPad back is not the multi window model. It's
Speaker 7:  that iPad apps are bad. Yes. And until they open up the app store in some
Speaker 7:  way to solve that problem, well the iPad apps
Speaker 7:  are still gonna be bad and you can have as many, you know, sort of like cut
Speaker 7:  down versions of real apps as you want in your iPad in as many windows as
Speaker 7:  you want. But that's your problem. And they didn't nothing to address that.
Speaker 6:  No that, I mean that has forever been the thing Apple
Speaker 6:  just can't figure out how to do for some reason is convince
Speaker 6:  anyone other than like a very specific set of creative tools like
Speaker 6:  you, you can get honest to God, like professional class creative tools
Speaker 6:  on the iPad. They're very good and you, you can, if you are a
Speaker 6:  creative person, you want to do your job. Ironically it is easier
Speaker 6:  to do your like fancy 3D modeling job on your, on
Speaker 6:  the iPad than it is to send emails all day on the iPad. Like
Speaker 6:  it's crazy. This is where we are. But I think, I think you're right,
Speaker 6:  but I also think to the extent that what maybe has been
Speaker 6:  gating people from doing that is the sense of like, I can
Speaker 6:  do a lot of stuff at once and move quickly between things and sort of feel
Speaker 6:  powerful on an iPad. The way I feel powerful on a Mac.
Speaker 6:  This theoretically at least we'll see how it all actually works. But like
Speaker 6:  this kind of solves all of my problems in a way that I have not experienced
Speaker 6:  before with an iPad.
Speaker 7:  I look forward to the years worth of, I try to use it an iPad to replace
Speaker 7:  my Mac coverage to come.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I suspect everyone's gonna end up right back on their max, but yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I I, I inevitably I am going to write that story in the next three
Speaker 6:  months. So I, I shouldn't, I shouldn't really give anybody any crap. Like
Speaker 6:  I had a second kid and decided to go all in on an iPad is like a thing that's
Speaker 7:  Coming. It's
Speaker 6:  A thing that's coming for me. It happens.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Let's see. Other stuff in the iPad there
Speaker 6:  again. Also got a phone app. Is it weird that there's just now a
Speaker 6:  phone app everywhere? I've been having a lot of like Galaxy brand feelings
Speaker 6:  about this, but I I maybe it doesn't matter. It just make phone calls, who
Speaker 6:  cares? Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I think Apple realize that messaging is like a core use case of every kind
Speaker 7:  of computer now. And it's weird to only tie
Speaker 7:  their ecosystem to the like Cell
Speaker 7:  Voice network that exists on the phone. 'cause they also
Speaker 7:  have messages and FaceTime and all this other stuff and they control your
Speaker 7:  phone and they can just pass like real phone audio to it. Like no one else
Speaker 7:  limits themself in this way.
Speaker 13:  But can you imagine the phone app going off on all of your Apple devices
Speaker 13:  at the same time? Because it's there.
Speaker 7:  That happens today.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it already does. Do you not, does 10 things not ring when you get a
Speaker 13:  Phone call? I know, but like even more.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. By the way, they, what the thing they didn't solve anywhere is like
Speaker 7:  notifications or prioritizing which devices get notifications like
Speaker 7:  the main problem in their ecosystem as expressed. Ve to your point,
Speaker 7:  like the phone app goes off everywhere without any sense of what what you
Speaker 7:  are or like where you are or what you're doing. It would
Speaker 7:  be nice if they were like, also we've made it so that notifications consistently
Speaker 7:  show up where you, they need to be no mention of that.
Speaker 6:  The other thing was local video and audio capture. They made like
Speaker 6:  a real outreach to podcasters in this one. They're like, if you're, if
Speaker 6:  if you wanna record all your stuff locally while you're on video calls now
Speaker 6:  you can,
Speaker 7:  I think this is like, this is a main complaint of creators who use iPads
Speaker 7:  a lot From what I, from what I gather. That's true because app, like we're
Speaker 7:  recording this in this app called Riverside and like that just is not a choice
Speaker 7:  on an iPad, right? You have you running a local recording while you're doing
Speaker 7:  that. It's interesting that they didn't express some API to let two apps
Speaker 7:  pull audio and video and record them themselves, which is what every Mac
Speaker 7:  in the world can do. But they're like, we'll do it for you.
Speaker 7:  And then they made a big demo, they made a big deal out of like, and then
Speaker 7:  you can share your local files and it's like, yeah, that's what you would
Speaker 7:  if you recorded my local files. You lemme share them like that. That makes
Speaker 7:  no sense.
Speaker 7:  But you know, they, what they did is they came after platforms like Riverside
Speaker 7:  with that. That is the thing that a Riverside would do. There's a bunch of
Speaker 7:  other ones there, but that's what they, that's what a lot of creators have
Speaker 7:  asked for on the iPad. This is a great mobile podcasting setup, but for
Speaker 7:  the fact that I can't actually record locally. Well they've the problem,
Speaker 6:  Right? And I yeah, there's a, there's a real, like do any creators
Speaker 6:  actually use iPads Road? We could go down right now, but let's let's avoid
Speaker 6:  that. Alison, you, you are a creator who uses an iPad for everything,
Speaker 6:  right? This is like, I oh God, you, you did not seem as excited as I was
Speaker 6:  about multitasking. So like, let's just, how do you feel about the
Speaker 8:  IPad? You know what, before we, before I, so many, many years ago
Speaker 8:  I was between jobs And I had to like give away my work
Speaker 8:  computer and didn't have a computer for a while and
Speaker 8:  went to Best Buy. I was like, iPad
Speaker 8:  and a keyboard. This is computer, right? And it was like
Speaker 8:  all the pieces are here. I like bought it all and, and went back home And
Speaker 8:  I was like, oh no, this is not a computer. This
Speaker 8:  doesn't let you do the thing you need to do. It just like, is so funny. Like
Speaker 8:  how many ways Apple will give you this and give you that?
Speaker 8:  And they're like, well you can record locally 'cause you're a creator
Speaker 8:  who's traveling with an iPad so you can do this computer thing on
Speaker 8:  your iPad or we'll give you the red, green and yellow buttons
Speaker 8:  and it, but you know, won't go up to the
Speaker 8:  line of this is a full computer. It's just, yeah.
Speaker 8:  It it is a very interesting kind of dance, I think to see them
Speaker 8:  do.
Speaker 6:  Somebody once described the difference to me, and this is years ago, but
Speaker 6:  I think it's still true, is when you buy a Mac you buy a computer
Speaker 6:  and when you buy an iPad you buy a list of things you're allowed to do.
Speaker 6:  And I, I think about that all the time. Yeah. And I think it's it's so true
Speaker 6:  that it's like, and the list is getting longer, right? And and to Apple's
Speaker 6:  credit, the list is is more sort of power user friendly than ever. But
Speaker 6:  it is still a list of things you can do. And it is not, it is
Speaker 6:  not a computer in in that same way. Let's talk about iOS,
Speaker 6:  which is shockingly third on the list for me. And I went through this list
Speaker 6:  and was like, iOS is kind of not that
Speaker 6:  exci like to me, me, the messages app is the most interesting thing happening
Speaker 6:  in iOS 26. Well you don't think
Speaker 7:  The dynamic dynamic clock on the lock screen is worth five minutes of keynote
Speaker 7:  time. Long
Speaker 8:  Clock get ready for long clock. Long clock.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I mean it's, but the clock gets dynamically less long when you get notifications
Speaker 8:  Dynamically less long. Is is a that's a, that's a short,
Speaker 7:  That's a bad date. That's what that
Speaker 7:  Oh no, well now we're gonna make that
Speaker 8:  Shirt.
Speaker 6:  I love that. Dynamically less long. 20 20, 26
Speaker 6:  vote vote The Verge.
Speaker 6:  Well first of all, shout out to Joanna Stern who was on this podcast on
Speaker 6:  Friday demanding typing indicators in group chats and she got them.
Speaker 6:  That's chaotic. Yeah. Okay. That's so chaotic. You, you said this in the
Speaker 6:  live blog And I assumed everyone would be happy about this feature. Why are
Speaker 6:  you not happy about this feature?
Speaker 14:  Do do you,
Speaker 13:  Do you not have group chat drama happening all the time? Have you seen this
Speaker 13:  TikTok series of this woman who just, she is acting out nine
Speaker 13:  people in a group chat and just like the social dynamics
Speaker 13:  that happen in this group chat typing indicators. What what's gonna
Speaker 13:  happen is you're gonna have the group chat and the side chats going on and
Speaker 13:  everyone's gonna be ganging up on let's call her Betty. And Betty is just
Speaker 13:  gonna put a little question in and then she's gonna see 5,000 different
Speaker 13:  people doing the typing indicator, stopping typing, stopping typing,
Speaker 13:  stopping. Betty's gonna have an anxiety attack breakdown. And then, you
Speaker 13:  know, the, the group chat's going to implode and someone is going to just,
Speaker 13:  friendships will end over typing indicators as will
Speaker 13:  family relationships. 'cause you're just gonna see someone typing for a
Speaker 13:  really long time and two family members are gonna go, oh my God, was she
Speaker 13:  she's typing forever. Was she gonna say something? And then they're gonna
Speaker 13:  put it in the wrong group chat. Friendships and families will end. I I am
Speaker 13:  telling you right now, typing indicators are
Speaker 7:  Dangerous. I've never been happier to be an old dad.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. My group chats are not that dramatic.
Speaker 13:  Oh, I, you know what, I love this for you. I think that's blessed.
Speaker 13:  My group chats are cursed.
Speaker 6:  Okay.
Speaker 7:  We're gonna find out if we can turn 'em off or somehow make them bigger and
Speaker 7:  louder. 'cause I think like this, you want to go in one of two directions.
Speaker 6:  I think four dots for vs group chat. I think
Speaker 8:  That is the indicator. Think the angrier your message, the bigger the indicator
Speaker 8:  gets. It could be really chaotic. I like that. I think just like, where are
Speaker 8:  we safe from typing indicators like they've crept into
Speaker 8:  so many messaging apps. It's like everybody's gotta know when I'm typing
Speaker 8:  a message in Slack And I change my mind. Like I have to consider that
Speaker 8:  now. Now it's gonna be in the group chat and you have to think about that
Speaker 8:  dynamic. Yeah, I I can I I think I side with me on this.
Speaker 8:  That's,
Speaker 13:  That's, that's exactly it. You know when you're in Slack and then someone
Speaker 13:  says something and then you just see several people are typing.
Speaker 13:  T you bring that into the group chat on your phone. Now it's gonna be something.
Speaker 13:  Someone's gonna say something controversial and then several people typing
Speaker 13:  indicators are happening and then it's, it's just, I, but
Speaker 6:  That's, that's Eli's dream. Just drop a bomb in the group chat and cause
Speaker 6:  us several people are typing and he's just like, I did it. Everything. Wait,
Speaker 6:  real, real quick poll of the group here. Are y'all read receipts people?
Speaker 6:  No. Do you read receipts on or off? No. Thank
Speaker 13:  You. No, no. I I I had one instance where I didn't realize they
Speaker 13:  were on And I left someone on red and they crashed out so
Speaker 13:  hard. And lemme tell you, this was not someone I was seeing, this was not
Speaker 13:  a friend. This was my like father's friend And I just didn't have an
Speaker 13:  answer for her And I'll be like, I'll answer this later. She crashed out
Speaker 13:  and sent me so many screenshots going like, I see that you read my message,
Speaker 13:  you didn't say anything. And I was like, after that, whoa, I have never
Speaker 13:  had red receipts on because I was just like, there are some people.
Speaker 7:  Did he tell your dad
Speaker 13:  This knowledge? No, my dad was dead. So this was after his funeral.
Speaker 13:  I see. Which made it even more insane. So it was just like, some people,
Speaker 13:  they don't need to know what you're doing. Yeah. I think they don't need
Speaker 13:  to know.
Speaker 7:  That's how you would turn off read receipts forever, I think is the, just
Speaker 7:  walking through that situation mentally. Yeah. That's you would, that would,
Speaker 7:  you would turn that off. Yeah. Yeah. I just don't people to know. I I I
Speaker 7:  prefer to operate with an Air Fisher street.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I, it, i I think it accomplishes nothing. I cannot think
Speaker 6:  of one good thing that would happen in my life because of
Speaker 6:  read receipts And I, it's, but I, most people
Speaker 6:  anecdotally based on like what I see texting with people, most people have
Speaker 6:  'em on And I can't tell if that's just like, you don't see your own read
Speaker 6:  receipts so people probably don't know or think about it or lots of people
Speaker 6:  that are like choosing to do it. Alison, you're the only one who hasn't answered
Speaker 6:  yet suspiciously quiet about reader sleep.
Speaker 8:  I have them on And I think I don dunno, I feel like I've kind
Speaker 8:  of tuned them out. I sort of appreciate the Android,
Speaker 8:  like little check mark. It's like, it, it feels
Speaker 8:  friendlier I think to have the little check mark of like,
Speaker 8:  yes, you sent this message, message and yes, they, they
Speaker 8:  received it and looked at it. I'm like, okay, let's leave it at that. We
Speaker 8:  don't need to get involved in like who read what, you know,
Speaker 6:  He and Allison are a real like inside of us all. There are two wolves kind
Speaker 6:  of situation right now.
Speaker 7:  What I'm no, what I'm telling you is that tech billionaires have taught a
Speaker 7:  generation of Americans to be surveilled and to surveil one another and you
Speaker 7:  can fight back.
Speaker 13:  I agree. I like, you don't need to know if I read the message because
Speaker 13:  you can just send another one. You don't need to know when I read something,
Speaker 13:  you don't need to know how bad my A DHD is. So things should just be pri
Speaker 13:  private also, sometimes I just wanna clear the little red notification
Speaker 13:  badge and I've just like, that's just what I wanna do. Oh, I'm not
Speaker 13:  sliding you people just read too much into read receipts.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I, I agree. Alright, we need to take one more break and then we're
Speaker 6:  gonna come back and we're gonna do what I'm calling the, the, all the rest
Speaker 6:  of the stuff. It's gonna be great. Stick around, we'll be right back.
Speaker 6:  Alright, we're back. Let's talk watch OS and V.
Speaker 6:  This we're just, the floor is yours here. Would you like to talk about
Speaker 6:  Workout Buddy for no more than 72
Speaker 6:  minutes?
Speaker 7:  Just it just again we're, I just want Alice And I experienced
Speaker 7:  sitting next to V in real time while this was being announce
Speaker 7:  it was like literally like a, another show was taking place. It was very
Speaker 7:  good.
Speaker 6:  It was a roller coaster. So watch S 26, same new design,
Speaker 6:  Liquid Glass, lots of stuff going on. Gets a bunch of stuff from from other
Speaker 6:  ones. And then there is Workout Buddy V How do you feel?
Speaker 13:  That's how I feel about it. Like, yeah, I don't know if you've ever seen
Speaker 13:  Bob's Burgers and Tina and Bob's burgers, how she just like
Speaker 13:  sits there sometimes and just makes a low grade home like that. That was
Speaker 13:  me. That was what was happening while Workout Buddy
Speaker 13:  was so like, okay, you hear the size now so
Speaker 13:  it makes sense that Workout Buddy is happening just because if you
Speaker 13:  look at any major fitness app, the AI is there, it it, it is there
Speaker 13:  and it is there to tell you how you're doing based on your data.
Speaker 13:  Because the thing about fitness tracking is that it
Speaker 13:  generates a lot of data, but no one knows what to do with that data without
Speaker 13:  the context. And so everyone is just for years now struggling how
Speaker 13:  to give context to your fitness data and help you interpret it. So
Speaker 13:  this is like the latest take about shoving AI into fitness
Speaker 13:  tech. Garmin just introduced a subscription and
Speaker 13:  shoved AI summaries in there. Anyone who has been using
Speaker 13:  Strava has been like roasting Strava's implementation
Speaker 13:  of AI summaries in that platform. So,
Speaker 13:  you know, whoop has an AI coach, aura has an AI
Speaker 13:  advisor, there's just AI buddies everywhere. In the fitness
Speaker 13:  tech world, it is very annoying because
Speaker 13:  most of it is just captain obvious insights. So it's just like
Speaker 13:  you did a run. Okay, cool. Great. Love that
Speaker 13:  For
Speaker 7:  Me, I, that specifically was the demo with a Workout Buddy. Yeah. And we
Speaker 7:  spent Apple spent minutes of its developer's keynote making us watch a video
Speaker 7:  of a woman running while a voice was like, you're doing great.
Speaker 7:  Yes. That was the whole, that was the expression of the product
Speaker 7:  that we all watched. Yeah.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. So that's Workout Buddy kind of. But
Speaker 13:  so what I was told is basically that at the beginning of your
Speaker 13:  workout, it's going to give you some motivational pep talk at the end of
Speaker 13:  the workout, it's going to give you a summary of what happened,
Speaker 13:  which you're gonna have in your workout app. Anyway, I don't understand
Speaker 13:  why we need to have these audio cues, but if anything significant
Speaker 13:  happens in the workout itself, like if you reach a
Speaker 13:  milestone or something, you get the little Workout Buddy going like,
Speaker 13:  Hey great, you did a PR or something like that. It's
Speaker 13:  meant to be motivational and positive, which
Speaker 13:  was a question I asked because I was like, like, you know,
Speaker 13:  different people respond to different types of training and workout
Speaker 13:  motivations. I, for example, bristle at every
Speaker 13:  single workout instructor who has had the drill sergeant
Speaker 13:  thing going like, come on, pick it up, you can do it faster. I will go
Speaker 13:  slower because I'm like, f you, you don't get to tell me how this run is
Speaker 13:  gonna go. This is my run buddy.
Speaker 6:  I'm imagining what works for you is is just someone just very quietly being
Speaker 6:  like, you're the worst. Just give up. Who even cares? Why, why
Speaker 6:  are you even trying just go home, you know? And you're like, shut up, I'm
Speaker 6:  gonna run 70 miles.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. You know, honestly, is
Speaker 7:  There a Workout Buddy that just like gently negs you the whole time?
Speaker 13:  Oh no, there is not,
Speaker 7:  Not Does workout, does Workout Buddy have personalities or is it always just
Speaker 7:  like chipper or Apple fitness instructor?
Speaker 13:  It's kind, I think it's the, the concept is based around
Speaker 13:  different types of Apple fitness instructor personalities. So
Speaker 13:  that different like 50 shades of gentle motivation
Speaker 13:  is what I think the concept is there because, you know, anytime when we
Speaker 13:  talk about Apple's approach to fitness, it is meant to be inclusive. It
Speaker 13:  is meant to be. They don't really go into the drill Sergeant,
Speaker 13:  come on, run faster buddy. Like kind of motivation,
Speaker 13:  which personally I appreciate because that's rude.
Speaker 13:  I'm just sort of like when I am running And I'm in the zone
Speaker 13:  when I'm listening to my stray kids talking about God's menu and do do
Speaker 13:  do doing, I don't wanna hear, Hey, you did a pr
Speaker 13:  Yeah, that, that's, that's a later insight. I don't need that while I'm
Speaker 13:  running. But you know, I'll give it a try. I'll see. Maybe, maybe I will
Speaker 13:  change my mind. I have changed my mind before, but
Speaker 7:  Well what's the connection to like, hey, you did a PR
Speaker 7:  or like, here's your time to a mile run a little bit faster. Like that's,
Speaker 7:  that's just a combination of like doing some math and then having a text
Speaker 7:  to speech model. But I haven't What's the connection to like, we're collecting
Speaker 7:  a bunch of data about you, right? Like that's what
Speaker 7:  I hear what you're saying, like fitness tracking generates a bunch of data
Speaker 7:  that no one knows what to do with. Isn't that where you would have an AI
Speaker 7:  being like, here are some patterns, do some stuff
Speaker 13:  Like ostensibly
Speaker 7:  Don't only run downhill neli, like, you know, like stuff,
Speaker 13:  But it depends on your goals, right? Because maybe if your
Speaker 13:  goal is to run a half marathon and the half marathon is really
Speaker 13:  hilly. Yeah, maybe you want an AI saying like, Hey, So I
Speaker 13:  see that you are avoiding hill intervals. Maybe don't do that
Speaker 13:  if you wanna have a good time on your run. Yeah, that ostensibly that could
Speaker 13:  be something that you want. But if the goal is to just
Speaker 13:  be active, do you really need that? Do you really need to chase
Speaker 13:  prs? Because I can tell you from a lot of peop you are gonna get injured
Speaker 13:  if you do any sport for any period of time. And if you're only chasing
Speaker 13:  prs, if you're only chasing these goalposts, you will burn out and you will
Speaker 13:  feel terrible about yourself because you will fall off at a certain
Speaker 13:  point in time. It's a very delicate balance about what actually
Speaker 13:  motivates people. And like it's sort of also just like taking
Speaker 13:  your historical data into context, being like, congratulations, you ran
Speaker 13:  three times and this route and this is this second best thing
Speaker 13:  that you've done on this segment of this wrap. Do you really meet? Is
Speaker 13:  that really Yeah. Something that you wanna hear during your run slash walk
Speaker 13:  slash cycling segment. There's some psychos out there who do love this kind
Speaker 13:  of granular data. I
Speaker 6:  Will also say, I think a, a thing that we are quickly learning about AI
Speaker 6:  interactions in general is that that kind of stuff is more meaningful to
Speaker 6:  more people than I expected. And I, I say that with as little judgment as
Speaker 6:  possible that like having, having a fake voice in your ear telling you that
Speaker 6:  you're doing a good job actually means a lot to a lot of people. And
Speaker 6:  I, I am still trying to figure out what to make of that as like a person,
Speaker 6:  but I think it's true And I think there's something to it. And, and I
Speaker 6:  also really like the idea of something that would be like just gently rude
Speaker 6:  to me the whole time. Like what would really work for me is if my Workout
Speaker 6:  Buddy was just like sort of sarcastically be like, oh, great job
Speaker 6:  David.
Speaker 7:  You're
Speaker 6:  What a good workout you just did. You ran so fast
Speaker 7:  After David. I tried to use my iPad as a real computer feature.
Speaker 7:  We're gonna, we're gonna run. I fell in love with my Workout Buddy.
Speaker 13:  Oh no. Oh
Speaker 7:  No. Workout Buddy tries to convince David Pierce to leave wife and family.
Speaker 6:  It's okay. My wife is already successfully mean to me all the time. So it's,
Speaker 6:  it's
Speaker 7:  No, I know your suggest that a robot tell you to
Speaker 7:  run faster in that exact personality. I became worried for
Speaker 7:  you.
Speaker 6:  Listen, I am who I am,
Speaker 13:  Eli. This is what it's, I mean, we'll see, I I asked if you could, I asked
Speaker 13:  if you could like calibrate the Workout Buddy. I didn't
Speaker 13:  really get a clear answer there, but I think if you could calibrate your
Speaker 13:  Workout Buddy to be your ideal
Speaker 13:  companion while you do a workout. Sure. That might help a bunch
Speaker 13:  of people.
Speaker 13:  'cause I, I don't know, exercise is, is it only for running of those things?
Speaker 13:  Is it for
Speaker 7:  All the workouts?
Speaker 13:  No, no, it's for walks. It's walking. You can have it, I believe
Speaker 13:  you can do it with cycling. So it's, it's multiple different workout
Speaker 7:  Types. So all dumb feet exercises?
Speaker 13:  Yes. All dumb feet cardio exercises. Which, because it
Speaker 13:  makes sense. These are generally solitary activities, right. You can
Speaker 13:  turn it on and off. It's, it's not like mandatory. Can
Speaker 7:  You be like, Workout Buddy? I want to get jacked. And then
Speaker 7:  So just, just cardio, just foot based cardiac,
Speaker 13:  I think it's just like what I, what I will say is that no very few
Speaker 13:  apps actually do strength training. Well 'cause it's,
Speaker 13:  it's just one of those things that is repetitive and boring if
Speaker 13:  you're doing it well. And also very different
Speaker 13:  depending on everyone's needs and equipment issues. So, no,
Speaker 13:  I, I think maybe exactly one app does it well and that's ladder.
Speaker 13:  But yeah, I don't think strength training is,
Speaker 13:  I don't even know what a strength training Workout Buddy would be like.
Speaker 13:  Because what you would want from an AI buddy is prompt cues
Speaker 13:  or like form check prompt cues. So who, how does it
Speaker 6:  Doing ears just be like, yo bro, you need a spot? You can
Speaker 6:  before we, before we move on, anything else in, in watch West 26 do you think
Speaker 6:  is interesting?
Speaker 13:  I, you know, the, the one thing that stood out to me with the Smart stack,
Speaker 13:  because it is just like a really funny, paradoxical,
Speaker 13:  paradoxical thing because they're saying that the smart stack is gonna get
Speaker 13:  even smarter with Apple intelligence so that when you look at the stack,
Speaker 13:  it'll surface the things that are most useful to you at any given one point
Speaker 13:  in time. And that's such a hard thing to judge because
Speaker 13:  if it's doing its job really well, you will never notice it.
Speaker 13:  So that's just like a, I was sitting there going like, how am I gonna test
Speaker 13:  if this is actually useful to me? I have no idea how I would even notice
Speaker 13:  it, but maybe that's just how I know it'll be doing its job. So
Speaker 13:  Smart Stack. Let's see, what
Speaker 6:  Was the like flippy thing? They
Speaker 13:  Were like, and now you flip It's new gesture. Okay. Yeah. It's a new
Speaker 13:  gesture wrist flick. We gotta, we gotta workshop a
Speaker 13:  new name for this gesture. I like flippy flip is flippy flip,
Speaker 13:  pinchy pinch, flippy flip. Yeah. So, okay, so in the live blog I was like
Speaker 13:  twisty twist, but I think I like flippy flip better.
Speaker 6:  Pinchy pinch and flippy flip. Pinchy pinch and flippy flip. That's good.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. There we go. Think So. I love it. All right, well problem solved. All
Speaker 6:  right now TVOS we already did. I will remind you
Speaker 6:  more notifications, new screensavers, connect to a speaker. The end.
Speaker 6:  That's, that's it. That's all I got for you. Fully out
Speaker 7:  Of ideas. No one has any more ideas for TV UIs
Speaker 6:  Literally they, like, they do the Bento boxes at the end of everyone that
Speaker 6:  just has a bunch of the features and like half of them were just shows on
Speaker 6:  Apple TV Plus like, what are we doing?
Speaker 6:  visionOS is the, the last platform we should talk about.
Speaker 6:  The big thing here I think is widgets. Oh, I was
Speaker 7:  Gonna say connect to a speaker,
Speaker 6:  Connect to speaker, question mark.
Speaker 6:  VII would like you to just briefly convince me as probably the person among
Speaker 6:  the four of us who have spent the most time in a vision Pro.
Speaker 13:  Yes. What
Speaker 6:  An honor the widgets is cool and good.
Speaker 6:  I will allow you 11 seconds.
Speaker 13:  Okay.
Speaker 13:  I guess. Okay, So I guess the one thing is that every single time you have
Speaker 13:  a, you know what, I, I I can't do it. All right, cool. Widgets, I guess
Speaker 13:  the widget wall clock. Yay clock. Yeah. The
Speaker 6:  Widgets are a little
Speaker 7:  Like augmented reality ish. Like they're not augmented
Speaker 7:  reality. You know, that's the new term. I just made up
Speaker 6:  Augmented reality ish. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  I like that. Like they, they look like they're on the wall, but they're not
Speaker 7:  actually augmented reality. They're just like, you know what I mean? They're
Speaker 7:  just like pictures. They don't, yeah.
Speaker 6:  Do you
Speaker 7:  Remember that they're not interacting with reality, that they just, they're
Speaker 7:  just stuck up there, you know? Do
Speaker 6:  You remember that Facebook event a bunch of years ago where Marcus Zuckerberg
Speaker 6:  was like, the future is, you're not gonna have a TV on your wall.
Speaker 6:  You're gonna have an AR tv that you look at through your glasses that you're
Speaker 6:  gonna like buy for a dollar in the app store and you'll put that on the wall.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. This, I, I saw this And I was like, oh my God was Mark Zuckerberg,
Speaker 6:  right? Like, is the future of wall clocks widgets in my Vision Pro,
Speaker 6:  this is what we're doing here.
Speaker 7:  There's one big vision os feature that we should talk about for just like
Speaker 7:  half a second. And it is actually the feature they needed to launch with,
Speaker 7:  which is guest access and like shared support.
Speaker 7:  So now you can like, let someone else set up a, the Vision OS device for
Speaker 7:  themselves. They, all of those settings, it's saved to their phone. And then
Speaker 7:  if they go to any other Vision OS device running what is now called Vision
Speaker 7:  OS 26,
Speaker 13:  We just skipped 24, 24 different vision oss
Speaker 13:  straight to Vision 26.
Speaker 7:  They can say, I, I've got one. And like, send
Speaker 7:  the data from their phone to the, the headset and it will just be ready for
Speaker 7:  them. And they should have had this from the beginning. And what's amazing
Speaker 7:  about this is that they, they announce this
Speaker 7:  feature in the context of enterprise use because it's
Speaker 7:  enterprises who want this feature. Businesses who are like, we have lots
Speaker 7:  of shared headsets that go out in the field. People need to switch between
Speaker 7:  them all the time. They're not, we're not buying one for everybody, but they,
Speaker 7:  it's also for consumers. I made sure that it's also for consumers, but you
Speaker 7:  can see where the action is on the Vision Pro. It's, it's in the enterprise.
Speaker 6:  It's like fancy architecture firms. I assume that that's what I think of
Speaker 6:  when I think of the Vision Pro.
Speaker 13:  This is so funny because I literally just got a text message from our dearly
Speaker 13:  departed Wes Davis, who is a Vision pro owner with
Speaker 13:  his own money. And he said, the widgets are good.
Speaker 7:  So
Speaker 13:  Whoa. So there you go. But also think of
Speaker 6:  All the money he's saving on wall clocks. You know what I mean?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. The wall clocks are how you pay for the Vision Pro. If you buy, you
Speaker 7:  can buy now buy up to 350 fewer wall clocks.
Speaker 13:  I mean, to be fair, the one of the issues that I've had with the, the Vision
Speaker 13:  Pro is like, let's say I have all my big screens in the room that I
Speaker 13:  want, and in the perfect allocation it, I have to kind of
Speaker 13:  re-put them up every single time I put the headset on, which is annoying.
Speaker 13:  And the fact that I can remember where things are supposed to go. Now, I,
Speaker 13:  I do think for the vision, pro power users is a, is a good thing. But what
Speaker 13:  I am actually most excited about are the persona updates because
Speaker 13:  I really just want to see how cursed or how
Speaker 13:  much more or less cursed the new personas are. That got a huge
Speaker 13:  round of applause from the audience during the, the keynote.
Speaker 13:  But I really just, as soon as I get home And I get that headset, I'm gonna
Speaker 13:  call Wes and I'm just gonna be like, is your mustache finally capable
Speaker 13:  of moving?
Speaker 8:  Is it free? Because
Speaker 13:  It's, it's, is it, is it finally capable of moving? Can, can your
Speaker 13:  mouth now move? Yeah. Without your mustache being a
Speaker 13:  static weird thing. I, I'm excited.
Speaker 7:  The folks on the ground, there're very excited about the persona updates.
Speaker 7:  I did not get to see them, but people are very excited about them.
Speaker 8:  I think even if they're like better, they're worse in a way. Like,
Speaker 8:  I don't know, what they showed us was like, like
Speaker 8:  rendered better. It looked more like a person, but it was also
Speaker 8:  creepier.
Speaker 7:  Oh, they're deep in the uncanny valley. Also, the demo was two people
Speaker 7:  sitting next to each other on a couch wearing headsets watching a show together
Speaker 7:  and interacting with their personas, which is just full
Speaker 7:  dystopia. Like, yeah, that sucks,
Speaker 8:  Man, that's so weird.
Speaker 7:  I'm out on that. That's some real, that's $7 worth of equipment
Speaker 8:  So that we don't have to talk to, we have widget wall clocks and then a persona
Speaker 8:  of your partner that you can look at instead of looking at their own
Speaker 8:  face. So, okay, got it. Every
Speaker 7:  Part of the, the Vision Pro from the very beginning has required Apple to
Speaker 7:  take itself deadly seriously in a way that is incompatible
Speaker 7:  the reality of people wearing headsets with external battery
Speaker 7:  packs connected with the water to them. Like, and
Speaker 7:  it, one of my first briefings with them when they were like talking about
Speaker 7:  it, I was like, have you guys ever like talked to each other, both wearing
Speaker 7:  headsets with the eyes on, was it funny? And they're like, we don't
Speaker 7:  laugh at each other's work. And I was like, I don know, people laugh at night
Speaker 7:  work all the time. Like, whatcha talking? Like it's a workplace. Like
Speaker 7:  have you seen The Office? Like I didn't talk. The culture of laughing
Speaker 7:  at each other at work is like well established, but like the Vision Pro
Speaker 7:  rejects that as, as a product because it's so inherently silly.
Speaker 7:  Apple has to take it deadly seriously and be like, yes, two people will sit
Speaker 7:  together on a couch wearing their vision pros watching a show together and
Speaker 7:  con conducting business in their personas. And you're like, good luck.
Speaker 7:  Like sure. Yeah.
Speaker 13:  Oh my god. Wes just tried to FaceTime me from his
Speaker 13:  vision pro. Oh God. He's, he's, oh no, he, he's so excited. Anyway,
Speaker 6:  You're gonna have to report back. Yeah, this is gonna be great. All right.
Speaker 6:  Bunch more things then we're gonna get outta here. We talked a little bit
Speaker 6:  about the AirPods camera control thing. I missed this part of
Speaker 6:  the keynote. Did we get a sense of how you take the picture with your
Speaker 6:  AirPods? No, nothing. No, I
Speaker 7:  Missed it. No, this is more creator stuff where it's like you can start the
Speaker 7:  capture by clicking your AirPod and then again immediately begin talking
Speaker 7:  to camera. So I think we, when we were talking about it last, we were thinking
Speaker 7:  about it because we're old dads about like taking the group photo at the
Speaker 7:  Grand Canyon. And what they were talking about is a bunch of Zoomers who
Speaker 7:  are like, Hey guys,
Speaker 6:  How to start the TikTok video. Right? Yeah. Okay. It
Speaker 6:  also, they introduced studio quality recording for the AirPods, which I
Speaker 6:  will just say as someone who makes a podcast on which we use AirPods, you're
Speaker 6:  lying. And I don't believe you
Speaker 7:  By the way, the, the claim there wasn't even what you would expect the claim
Speaker 7:  to be
Speaker 7:  you. 'cause if they had just been like, here's what we're gonna do. We're
Speaker 7:  gonna take your AirPods audio, we're gonna ai the shit out of 'em and make
Speaker 7:  'em sound good, you'd be like, all right, that's gonna be weird. Yeah, there
Speaker 7:  might be some artifacts or like whatever, we will like check it out. But
Speaker 7:  they were just like, no, we've just made AirPods Suji quality. It's like,
Speaker 7:  how,
Speaker 7:  why did you do that the first time? Did you turn up the base slider? Like,
Speaker 7:  what did you do?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, they just magically sound better though.
Speaker 7:  They, they got one of those like 1980s, like 24 band parametric
Speaker 7:  EQs and just like turned up at the whole right side. Like how
Speaker 7:  not unclear.
Speaker 6:  Don't believe you. All right, next one. There's the new games
Speaker 6:  app, which they, they kind of skimmed past in a way. I was a little surprised
Speaker 6:  by. We expected there to be a lot of noise about like Apple's, you know,
Speaker 6:  annual huge play into gaming. And this kind of was that, but
Speaker 6:  I don't know, I didn't get the sense that this was a huge
Speaker 6:  new initiative from Apple to try and make gaming work so much as it is just
Speaker 6:  like a place to find all the games you have on saw.
Speaker 7:  Well, so there's a, John Gerber posted his read on this, which
Speaker 7:  lightly tracks with mine, which is they are making the
Speaker 7:  games app like a separate app store and app
Speaker 7:  experience so that eventually when the regulators come for app
Speaker 7:  store fees, they can be like game, we're gonna treat games differently and
Speaker 7:  all the other apps differently. 'cause we make all our money Candy
Speaker 6:  Crush Whale. 'cause they compete with Xbox and PlayStation and Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And those all the same fees. And they made this tiny distinction in the keynote.
Speaker 7:  It was, it went by in a flash, but they made a distinction between app store
Speaker 7:  games and Apple Arcade games.
Speaker 6:  Oh, interesting.
Speaker 7:  So even games from the App store versus Apple Arcade games and it's like,
Speaker 7:  oh, you think, you think about these differently. Which kinda makes sense.
Speaker 7:  'cause Apple Arcade games are another subscription and all this other stuff,
Speaker 7:  but they're just the, the first hints that they're, they're
Speaker 7:  peeling things apart.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Interesting. Okay.
Speaker 6:  The tabs came back to the Photos app
Speaker 7:  Announce, by the way, joy Streets of the internet, Craig, it was like many
Speaker 7:  of you enjoyed tabs in the old
Speaker 13:  I'm just the, the Satan Elmo G where he's just like, the
Speaker 13:  fires behind him and the arms are up. That's, I just, I really hated how
Speaker 13:  they changed the Photos app. So thank God. Yes.
Speaker 13:  Many people enjoy tabs. I am one of them and I'm happy,
Speaker 13:  happy. I won't, we'll see. I I I think I'll be happy with it. So,
Speaker 13:  yay. We enjoyed knowing how to look for the thing we're looking for.
Speaker 6:  Man, I don't, this, this whole backlash has made me absolutely convinced
Speaker 6:  that I'm using photos wrong because I opened the
Speaker 6:  app, it showed me all my photos and that was fine. And now,
Speaker 6:  now I open the app and it shows me all my photos and it's still fine. So
Speaker 6:  like, I'm, I'm doing it wrong and we'll, we'll figure this out together,
Speaker 6:  I think. But I, I'm, I'm lost. All right. We're almost
Speaker 6:  done here. Apple Maps will now learn the
Speaker 6:  routes you take on your commute and such. And we will try to
Speaker 6:  automatically help you with them when, like, if you're gonna hit traffic
Speaker 6:  you don't know about, even if you don't plug in the directions, it will try
Speaker 6:  to alert you to take a different route. I think that's very cool. I also
Speaker 6:  don't use Apple Maps for anything ever. So here we are.
Speaker 7:  The one place Apple Maps is absolutely superior to Google Maps
Speaker 7:  is the state of New Jersey. And if they could just get Apple Intelligence
Speaker 7:  to force me to use Apple Maps when I travel to New Jersey,
Speaker 7:  I'd be, that's all it's for. I
Speaker 13:  I live in New Jersey,
Speaker 7:  I'm sorry, against
Speaker 13:  My will, but I don't think that Apple Maps is good in
Speaker 13:  New Jersey.
Speaker 7:  It's, no, it's good. I have, I have one specific way, I have lot of thoughts.
Speaker 7:  I'm just, I'm just putting this out there. It's good. In one specific way
Speaker 7:  Google could catch up tomorrow. Driving New Jersey is
Speaker 7:  a series of like nonstop events. Yes. Right. You're
Speaker 7:  merge on this highway, immediately change five lanes to merge onto another
Speaker 7:  highway, then another highway, then another highway, then 15th Highway. We've
Speaker 7:  named this place the Garden State for some unbelievable reason. But
Speaker 7:  this is the experience of being here. And Google Maps just does not
Speaker 7:  acknowledge that every action will be followed by a series of
Speaker 7:  45 other actions
Speaker 6:  Two seconds later. Yeah. Google is always like, turn in a hundred feet
Speaker 6:  and then you turn and then it's like, oh, 75 feet ago you were supposed to
Speaker 6:  turn again. That's
Speaker 7:  A cool thing. And so Apple Maps, at least Apple Maps is like this. Some things
Speaker 7:  are gonna happen to you and you're gonna get through them together as a family.
Speaker 7:  And it's like, this still sucks. Mm. I still hate it.
Speaker 7:  Sorry. So like, every time I've ever driven New Jersey, my wife and I have
Speaker 7:  gotten into a fight and Apple Maps has reduced the fights like by
Speaker 7:  10%.
Speaker 13:  This is, this is fa this is fascinating data because
Speaker 13:  obviously my spouse And I drive in New Jersey all the time and
Speaker 13:  they switch between Apple Maps and Google Maps
Speaker 13:  and
Speaker 13:  it's, it's a lot. The only thing I think actually
Speaker 13:  Apple Maps has over Google Maps is that if you have an
Speaker 13:  Apple watch, it'll like, if you have to cues for when you're supposed to
Speaker 13:  take the next action. So yes, in that sense it is superior,
Speaker 13:  especially in Jersey where there is a right lane exit every
Speaker 13:  five seconds. And you have to know the difference between this
Speaker 13:  right lane exit versus the one right before driving in jersey's just a
Speaker 13:  shit show, Joe. You
Speaker 7:  See what I'm saying? And so if Apple could use its trillions of dollars
Speaker 7:  and its data centers and its intelligence to somehow improve this,
Speaker 7:  I think, I think they would take massive share in one state in the union
Speaker 7:  from Google. That's all I'm saying.
Speaker 8:  I have a very v specific question when it's doing that haptic thing
Speaker 8:  on your wrist and it's like tapping you, is there different
Speaker 8:  taps for the direction you're supposed to turn? It like freaks me out a little
Speaker 8:  bit. I'm like, ah, is is this supposed to be telling me like turn left or
Speaker 8:  turn right? Like
Speaker 13:  I don't use Apple Maps when I drive the, the, the
Speaker 13:  spouse does because they swear it will reduce the number of
Speaker 13:  times that they miss the exit. Which,
Speaker 13:  you know, this is getting too much into my marriage. But I think if they
Speaker 13:  just turned on the audio cues, they would miss 20%
Speaker 13:  fewer returns.
Speaker 8:  Oh well you're right
Speaker 13:  Buddy.
Speaker 7:  But
Speaker 13:  For driving they insist.
Speaker 6:  You are also in my driving buddy.
Speaker 13:  This buddy actually.
Speaker 7:  And every time you get the turn right it's like you did great.
Speaker 6:  You so good.
Speaker 8:  Yes.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. You know what? Didn't
Speaker 6:  A personal
Speaker 13:  Record didn't work. Workout Buddy. We need a driving buddy. Driving buddy.
Speaker 13:  Just for your jersey specifically for marriages in Jersey. Just anybody
Speaker 13:  in a marriage in Jersey trying to get somewhere on time.
Speaker 13:  You need driving buddy?
Speaker 7:  I can feel David like knowing that this podcast needs to wrap up. 'cause
Speaker 7:  V And I are just complaining about New Jersey now, but that's it's
Speaker 6:  Day. It was, the show ended like a half hour ago. Yeah. No, it's,
Speaker 6:  I this is, this is, I'm learning a lot about why I need to just
Speaker 6:  switch to ways is the thing that I'm taking away from all of this. Waze just
Speaker 6:  has me drive through neighborhoods and everything goes fine.
Speaker 6:  The, there was some new stuff for like digital IDs in Apple Wallet,
Speaker 6:  which I bring up only so that Neli can remind people.
Speaker 7:  Never, never hand your phone to a cop. Don't do it.
Speaker 6:  There you go. That's a good one. I also have another one
Speaker 6:  for our good friend Neli Patel. We got some CarPlay updates. Are you so
Speaker 6:  excited about CarPlay the car? Neli Patel, America's number one lover of
Speaker 6:  CarPlay. Do you have any thoughts?
Speaker 7:  I I've asked Apple to, you know, send me home with an Aston Martin
Speaker 6:  For journalism.
Speaker 7:  So far they haven't said no. I would not say
Speaker 7:  that they've said yes, but we're in a liminal place
Speaker 7:  where, you know, hope is alive.
Speaker 6:  Schrodinger's Aston Martin
Speaker 7:  CarPlay Ultra is its own beast. And I, I don't know what's gonna happen there.
Speaker 7:  It's by the way, Jeep Stellantis, the company owns Jeep broke its
Speaker 7:  software relationship with Amazon a couple weeks ago. And of all of the companies
Speaker 7:  that should like, screw it, like just glue an iPhone to your dashboard,
Speaker 7:  call it a day. Like they should just do it. Most of the other car companies
Speaker 7:  are still like in a real wait and see the, but the CarPlay updates,
Speaker 7:  they're, they're fine, they're good. You get tap back emojis. Like mostly
Speaker 7:  what you should send is a response to a text message while you're driving
Speaker 7:  is a thumbs up.
Speaker 6:  Yes.
Speaker 7:  If they made that easier, that's great, right? To just emoji respond to text
Speaker 7:  so you're not like talking and you know, screwing on a serial, all that stuff.
Speaker 7:  But it's, it's, it's never been more clear that CarPlay is just a
Speaker 7:  second monitor for your phone than looking at the set of updates. 'cause
Speaker 7:  they're just like, it, we changed how the phone looks. So CarPlay looks different
Speaker 7:  now. Like we've made some widgets move around, added some features. They're
Speaker 7:  like, oh, this is just a second monitor for your iPhone running on your car
Speaker 7:  display. And like that's what it is and it's what it should be. And I think
Speaker 7:  people are generally happy with that. But this the
Speaker 7:  fact that CarPlay Ultra is over there and it's like we've, we've added
Speaker 7:  the climate controls to it has never seemed less important.
Speaker 7:  Like it just doesn't matter. Like what you want is a second monitor for your
Speaker 7:  phone running in your car display. And I, it it is more of that than it has
Speaker 7:  ever been before. I'm hoping to go home with an Aston Martin and Apple if
Speaker 7:  you want to convince me otherwise I'm, you know, black is great. I will accept
Speaker 7:  silver.
Speaker 6:  We've been looking for a reason to do The Vergecast Road trip and I'm just
Speaker 6:  saying that the Aston Martin with CarPlay Ultra is, is the solution to all
Speaker 6:  our problems. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  The whole, we have an ethics policy. I can't actually accept the Aston Martin.
Speaker 7:  You understand what it's, it's a joke. We
Speaker 6:  Can't have it forever. But you can long-term loans exist. That's what
Speaker 13:  You're saying. There are review units of cars, so
Speaker 7:  That's true. I know that people, I know that the review, there's like a
Speaker 7:  review warehouse in in the Northeast. I'm friendly with them. But
Speaker 6:  If you think about it, like you have to drive it long enough that you're
Speaker 6:  no longer amazed by the novelty of an Aston. And that's like at least a year
Speaker 6:  before you can even really properly review CarPlay Ultra. Yeah. As, as
Speaker 6:  software divorced from the existence of the Aston. So it's it's gonna be
Speaker 6:  fine. We're gonna make this work for you. All right. We need to get outta
Speaker 6:  here, but I I do just want to just check in one last time y'all were there,
Speaker 6:  y'all, y'all have been through all this. We've talked through a lot of the
Speaker 6:  news. There was a lot of stuff.
Speaker 6:  My sort of overall takeaway is that like if it, if it wasn't in the shadow
Speaker 6:  of last year and it wasn't in the shadow of sort of everything else
Speaker 6:  that's been going on with Apple that like from a pure,
Speaker 6:  here's the new stuff coming to your devices world,
Speaker 6:  this was like a fine wwdc.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Not, not the greatest we've ever seen. Not bad. And, and what
Speaker 6:  makes all of it weird is all of the other stuff happening around Apple,
Speaker 6:  which is really unusual for Apple, which is a company that has like lived
Speaker 6:  in its own bubble for as long as we've all been doing this. Was that your
Speaker 6:  read too? Like good not great. Your phone's probably gonna be fine
Speaker 6:  once they walk back. All the Liquid Glass ness.
Speaker 13:  Yeah. Is that like a, like a off year where you are
Speaker 13:  just going, you're following up Vision Pro, you're following up Apple Intelligence
Speaker 13:  and now it's this stuff that's just kind of how it
Speaker 13:  felt like
Speaker 6:  The big three. Yeah. Vision Pro bad
Speaker 6:  Siri, windows Vista is the, the true legacy of that. I don Moist Vista.
Speaker 6:  Moist Vista. No
Speaker 7:  Gross.
Speaker 7:  Moist Vista is not a great, I
Speaker 6:  Feel I don we will not be making that t-shirt. I can tell you that. Really
Speaker 7:  Unhappy that I'm actually, the more I think about it,
Speaker 7:  I think, I don't think you can ignore the other stuff. The rest of this industry
Speaker 7:  is chasing an uncertain technology that might not
Speaker 7:  be the future. It just might not be, but which
Speaker 7:  has a lot of capabilities towards like an entire new
Speaker 7:  model of applications. That's just a thing that's happening out there.
Speaker 7:  Like Sundar Hai coming under coder. I mean like the web is a series of databases
Speaker 7:  and like my agents can just go ping the databases and Kevin Scott from
Speaker 7:  Microsoft coming on and being like MCP is the future And I can re-architect
Speaker 7:  the Open web based on these new protocols and the kids on TikTok using
Speaker 7:  NAN to make new automations out of all these tools. Like there's something
Speaker 7:  actually happening there. Like some big thing is actually
Speaker 7:  happening there and all of the app action And we like app
Speaker 7:  development right now is happening with those kinds of tools
Speaker 7:  on the web in like really weird ways. It might come to
Speaker 7:  nothing. And I think Apple's point of view is like we
Speaker 7:  don't do, comes to nothing
Speaker 7:  like they're like, we make great products. When they're finished, we ship
Speaker 7:  them except for the fact that like
Speaker 7:  for, you know, over a decade now, all of the hottest apps have launched on
Speaker 7:  the phone and that at a developer's conference, what you
Speaker 7:  want is lots of new reasons to make cool apps on the phone.
Speaker 7:  And Yeah, I I don know there's just a gap there that is like worth
Speaker 7:  thinking about longer than it was just fi like yeah, they just did, they
Speaker 7:  revved all the stuff. Here's all the stuff they worked on for the last year
Speaker 7:  here. It's, but last year they're like, Siri will be
Speaker 7:  your best friend. Right? And they, they haven't shipped it yet. And
Speaker 7:  meanwhile like, you know, coming off of io you know, like here's Google
Speaker 7:  being like, here's all these new ways to think about using your computer
Speaker 7:  all like, and it's a bunch of Google stuff. Something will just come to nothing.
Speaker 7:  Project Mariner were they run Chrome in the cloud and click around the web
Speaker 7:  for you. Like, ooh, I don, I don't know man, but like,
Speaker 7:  there's just all these shots at what are new ways of using
Speaker 7:  computers that are taking place, including Johnny. Ive going to go work on
Speaker 7:  new devices at OpenAI. Like all that stuff is happening. People see a
Speaker 7:  way around the next turn. I don't know, like, I don't know if LMS are the
Speaker 7:  way through it, I really don't. But Apple just being like, yeah, we're, we're
Speaker 7:  we're taking a beat. It's just kind of off. Like there's something there
Speaker 7:  that, I don't know how anybody makes the next great device,
Speaker 7:  but everyone else is taking shots at it and Apple's like, no, no, the phone
Speaker 7:  will win.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's weird. Like this, this part of the reason I ask this question
Speaker 6:  is that Apple is sort of, it felt like a return to like
Speaker 6:  pre pandemic Apple WWCs
Speaker 6:  and Apple is the only company left on this particular
Speaker 6:  island. Yeah. Like it, it is so unlike every other conversation we're
Speaker 6:  having about technology. Allison, what was your read?
Speaker 8:  I, it just kind of like, I understand why Apple
Speaker 8:  had to jump in AI last year and like
Speaker 8:  make the big Apple intelligence announcement, but it, it does feel
Speaker 8:  backwards now that I think about it of like, if this had been
Speaker 8:  our kind of first step into like, you know, it's not just machine
Speaker 8:  learning, it's intelligence and it's gonna do these things for you and you're
Speaker 8:  gonna take a screenshot and it's gonna put it on your calendar and be like,
Speaker 8:  great, I'm on board. You know, and then work up to the
Speaker 8:  series, your best friend stuff. It, it, it couldn't be that
Speaker 8:  way, you know? And Google has shipped a ton of stuff that
Speaker 8:  is in the Gemini is your best friend track.
Speaker 8:  So I, it's just a weird kind of a, a
Speaker 8:  no win position for Apple, I guess. But
Speaker 8:  some, some interesting stuff I'm like excited to play with. I think.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I like we, the idea that Gemini is going to win the
Speaker 6:  race to be your best friend is a deeply terrifying state of affairs.
Speaker 6:  But it, like you, you might not be wrong. Alright. You guys have
Speaker 6:  been sitting here with me long enough. You need to go do other things in
Speaker 6:  Cupertino. I think you're gonna see the F1 movie. This is, this is the thing
Speaker 6:  that's gonna happen. It's the rumor. This is not today. This is, this is
Speaker 6:  what they say. Yeah. Alright. Thank you all for being here. Safe travels
Speaker 6:  home. We will have lots more to talk about. Hit us up on the hotline. Tell
Speaker 6:  us all the stuff that we missed, all the weird, tiny, bizarre features on
Speaker 6:  all of these platforms. Tell David how much you love shortcuts. Tell me all
Speaker 6:  of your favorite shortcuts. Send me links so that I can click them and
Speaker 6:  add them to my own shortcuts and use them every single day. Until
Speaker 6:  then, that's it. That's Vergecast. Rock and roll
Speaker 5:  Support for this show comes from Pure Leaf iced tea. When you find yourself
Speaker 5:  in the afternoon slump, you need the right thing to make you bounce back.
Speaker 5:  You need Pure Leaf iced tea. It's real brewed tea, made in a
Speaker 5:  variety of bold flavors. With just the right amount of naturally
Speaker 5:  occurring caffeine. You're left feeling refreshed and revitalized
Speaker 5:  so you can be ready to take on what's next. The next time you need to hit
Speaker 5:  the reset button, grab a Pure Leaf iced tea time for a tea break.
Speaker 5:  Time for a Pure Leaf
Speaker 5:  support for this show comes from Pure Leaf iced tea. When you find
Speaker 5:  yourself in the afternoon slump, you need the right thing to make you bounce
Speaker 5:  back. You need Pure Leaf iced tea. It's real brewed tea,
Speaker 5:  made in a variety of bold flavors. With just the right amount of
Speaker 5:  naturally occurring caffeine, you're left feeling refreshed and
Speaker 5:  revitalized so you can be ready to take on what's next. The next time you
Speaker 5:  need to hit the reset button, grab a Pure Leaf iced tea time for a
Speaker 5:  tea break. Time for a Pure Leaf.