# Transcript
ID: f653fc51-7c0d-4858-ac5d-257c878db7c6
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/3912272050225838374/-3348976023566969088/s93290-US-4065s-1754390250.mp3
Description: This week on The Vergecast, guest host Mia Sato talks to YouTube fitness pioneer Cassey Ho (better known as Blogilates) about the well-oiled machine that is the dupe economy. Ho shares her experience creating her own line of athletic wear that sooner or later gets ripped off by countless copycats — and how she tries to fight back.
Then, Mia brings an audio diary from a visit to Fabscrap, a textile recycling facility in Brooklyn, that is working to save fabric and other materials from the landfill. Fashion is a wasteful industry, not unlike tech — luckily, there are people like Fabscrap staff and volunteers who are working towards solutions.
Finally, Victoria Song swings by to help answer a hotline question about how to make the high-tech Clueless closet a reality. If you have a question for us, call 866-VERGE11 or email vergecast@theverge.com.
Further reading
How dupes turned online shopping upside down
Lululemon sues Costco over viral alleged “dupes”
The US finally acknowledges textile waste in new report
Your stuff is actually worse now
Ghana becomes dumping ground for the world’s unwanted used clothes
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (25 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of knocking off other
Speaker 2:  people's work and selling it for $2. I'm your host, Mia Sato.
Speaker 2:  And today we're talking about knockoffs and waste. Two big
Speaker 2:  problems in the fashion industry. Whenever a design goes viral, the
Speaker 2:  copycats are close behind. Today I'm going to talk with an
Speaker 2:  OG fitness YouTuber, Cassie Ho, better known as tis
Speaker 2:  about how she fights the ES of her products. Another result
Speaker 2:  of the ultra fast fashion cycle is a lot of textile waste.
Speaker 2:  I visited a textile recycling plant in Brooklyn, New York
Speaker 2:  to find out how they save textiles from the landfill. And finally,
Speaker 2:  if you're into fashion like me, you probably wish you had the clueless
Speaker 2:  closet. We'll have Vong to take a listener question about how to make
Speaker 2:  that a reality. All that is coming up. But first I have to go
Speaker 2:  maximize shareholder value in an ad break. We'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  Welcome back. The internet is built on repetition and
Speaker 2:  copying, and now that same dynamic has
Speaker 2:  permeated our real lives as well. A photo will go viral
Speaker 2:  and thousands of lookalike products will follow, often sold
Speaker 2:  from faceless, nameless companies. Cassie Ho built a fitness
Speaker 2:  empire on YouTube. She now has her own line of athletic wear
Speaker 2:  that's prime material for dupes. Cassie, you've
Speaker 2:  been online a long time, so tell us who you are and what you do.
Speaker 6:  All right. My name is Cassie Ho, but I may be better
Speaker 6:  known as Blogilates. I started my YouTube channel in
Speaker 6:  2009 teaching free fitness workouts and it's been a
Speaker 6:  long time. I can't believe it's 2025 now, but I am still
Speaker 6:  online. But my content has changed a little bit. You know, it
Speaker 6:  transformed from free fitness, horizontal long form videos
Speaker 6:  to now vertical short form where I'm teaching people about
Speaker 6:  the why behind my designs. I run
Speaker 6:  a very rapidly growing active wear and
Speaker 6:  apparel company called Pop Flex and we just
Speaker 6:  started our second brand, launched our second brand blog, a lotti at Target
Speaker 6:  earlier this year. So my life is all about
Speaker 6:  innovation design and it's just been really, really fun
Speaker 6:  to build this company.
Speaker 2:  And I just wanna like clarify for anyone who doesn't know that Cassie is
Speaker 2:  like an OG blueprint fitness
Speaker 2:  blogger, like I remember watching Cassie's videos when I was
Speaker 2:  a teenager. So it was kind of surreal to talk with you about something that
Speaker 2:  is kind of, you know, related but different. So you've been building Pop
Speaker 2:  Flex Active, you have this blog lots deal with Target, and obviously
Speaker 2:  you share a lot of like behind the scenes stuff and development with your
Speaker 2:  fans online, on, on social. Do you remember the
Speaker 2:  first time that you saw something, whether that was online or in store and
Speaker 2:  you were like, wait a minute, I, I designed this.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean I designed this very
Speaker 6:  specific score called the Pirouette score in 2021. And I remember as I
Speaker 6:  was designing it, I told my husband who's also my business partner, I
Speaker 6:  said, she's gonna take this one. I just knew it. I had a feeling. We
Speaker 6:  released the design, it goes viral and three months later,
Speaker 6:  guess who takes it? It's she. And so that was a whole
Speaker 6:  situation. I made a big post about it. The us she and president reached out
Speaker 6:  to me and wanted to speak because his daughter was a fan of tis and
Speaker 6:  came into his room yelling, being like, oh my God, what did you do Cassie?
Speaker 6:  And I'm very grateful for her because we ended up talking and
Speaker 6:  even though he and she and promised that this wasn't going to
Speaker 6:  happen again, surely enough in another three months
Speaker 6:  another dupe of the pirouette squirt shows up. And since
Speaker 6:  then there's been multiples over a dozen
Speaker 6:  different designs from Pop Flex stolen by Sheen. But also since
Speaker 6:  then I've been granted the U-S-P-T-O design patent for
Speaker 6:  that specific squirt, which has helped protect it in some ways.
Speaker 6:  But at the same time it's been extremely frustrating because the lack
Speaker 6:  of enforcement from the government to help innovators and
Speaker 6:  inventors, designers protect their creative work
Speaker 6:  makes it almost impossible sometimes to go up against these
Speaker 6:  Goliaths when I'm this small David. But you know, I
Speaker 6:  keep speaking up because it is unfair to be taken
Speaker 6:  advantage of and at least I have a platform from which to speak, whereas
Speaker 6:  a lot of independent designers may not. So when I do this, I speak
Speaker 6:  for all of us.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, And I want like to just sort of describe the skirt a
Speaker 2:  little bit. I have a skirt in the other room that I bought for the story
Speaker 2:  that I was working on, but it's like a unique type of active wear. It's like
Speaker 2:  kind of lilac, well the one I have is lilac, but it comes in a bunch of colors.
Speaker 2:  It has several tears of mesh skirting shorts
Speaker 2:  underneath. But what else makes a design special where you were like, I know
Speaker 2:  that this is so special that someone will knock it off.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so the thing with Pop Flex with me and all of my designs is
Speaker 6:  I had this element of just like romance
Speaker 6:  to every design because that's who I am. And so I love when
Speaker 6:  there's this intersection of fashion and functionality and innovation
Speaker 6:  altogether in one. So you get this beautiful twirl little
Speaker 6:  mesh score with tears and then you also get the
Speaker 6:  functionality of a drawstring, the cinch in your waist a little bit. Of course
Speaker 6:  no front seam for no camel toe pockets on the side so that you don't have
Speaker 6:  to carry a purse if you don't want to. Which I, I don't really. And so
Speaker 6:  this score was so unique. I had never seen anything like it on the
Speaker 6:  market before, which is also why the U-S-P-T-O granted me the patent for
Speaker 6:  it, which is extremely hard to get, but like so exciting that I was able
Speaker 6:  to get it. And then wildly enough,
Speaker 6:  a couple years after the shehan incident,
Speaker 6:  Taylor Swift ends up wearing it in 2024
Speaker 6:  and then the court goes crazy viral. So viral
Speaker 6:  that you know, our, our sales go up insanely, but at the same time the
Speaker 6:  dupes get out of control because now everyone has
Speaker 6:  seen it. And since then it's been so wild.
Speaker 6:  There's been over 2065 different
Speaker 6:  infringements on my designs since the Sheen one.
Speaker 6:  It's insane. And it is game of Whack-a-Mole.
Speaker 2:  And is that just a drop in the bucket? Do you feel like you're getting a
Speaker 2:  lot of these dupes that are floating around?
Speaker 6:  I mean I think we're getting some of them. I don't think I'm getting all
Speaker 6:  of them. It's nearly impossible. You know, I have
Speaker 6:  almost two full-time people constantly
Speaker 6:  typing in these forms to take down these infringing listings.
Speaker 6:  And it's so frustrating because it takes so much time to take down a
Speaker 6:  listing that's if the platform even like decides to believe in you that day.
Speaker 6:  I feel like sometimes the rules are just changing all the time depending
Speaker 6:  on who's reading these forms. That's with, with the platform, they have
Speaker 6:  a place for you at least to type in the form, right? But then when it comes
Speaker 6:  to these larger multi-billion dollar
Speaker 6:  companies, which is something that just recently happened within the past
Speaker 6:  few months, and I'm talking about the Nordstrom's, the Kohls,
Speaker 6:  the JC Penney's, the Macy's, the Victoria's Secrets, the TJ Max's and Marshalls,
Speaker 6:  now they all have dupes of either this court or other
Speaker 6:  patented products. And with them it becomes a game of
Speaker 6:  money, right? Who can pay their lawyers more to
Speaker 6:  shut the other person down to overwhelm the entire out the other person.
Speaker 6:  And so when I talk about being a David versus a Goliath, this is
Speaker 6:  exactly what it is except I'm one David against
Speaker 6:  several Goliaths now. And it's just so frustrating that these are
Speaker 6:  American corporations, we're all supposed to be abiding by the same
Speaker 6:  law, but there's no governmental enforcement to
Speaker 6:  help me enforce the law. So it's just been
Speaker 6:  so frustrating and that's why I keep speaking up about it because there is
Speaker 6:  also the court of public opinion and social media,
Speaker 6:  but when it comes to money, they obviously have the billions that I do not.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I wanted to ask like where are these dupes popping up? Are there certain
Speaker 2:  sites that like every single day you know there's going to be another
Speaker 2:  lookalike product from as yours? Or are there some sites where like it's
Speaker 2:  shown up once and then you kind of knocked it out and then they didn't try
Speaker 2:  it again, but like where are you seeing the dupes?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, the biggest culprits are TikTok shop, Amazon
Speaker 6:  Temu, Ali Express, Alibaba, and
Speaker 6:  she, and of course, but I feel like everything is coming from
Speaker 6:  probably these third party sellers buying from Ali Express or Alibaba
Speaker 6:  because some of these, they look exactly the same, but they're under different
Speaker 6:  vendor names. So trying to attack the ALI sources is
Speaker 6:  the best, but it is a constant game of whack-a-mole. It's insane.
Speaker 6:  And I also see do influencer as a whole
Speaker 6:  category, especially with the affiliate links that they have. Like
Speaker 6:  it's multiplying like a virus. It's really bad right now.
Speaker 6:  We will actually gift influencers, the real pople
Speaker 6:  obviously. But there was an incident where we noticed that this
Speaker 6:  particular influencer was then promoting the dupe
Speaker 6:  and linking to it with an affiliate link. And so, you know, the internal
Speaker 6:  team was like talking about it like how do we deal with this? This is so
Speaker 6:  weird. And so we crafted a response that was very much like,
Speaker 6:  hey, I don't know if you've like seen Cassie's stories and stuff. It was
Speaker 6:  very much like an educational response and like we, we hoped that
Speaker 6:  you can continue to wear the real one. And so that particular influencer
Speaker 6:  was very sorry. She didn't realize what was going on. And so she was fine.
Speaker 6:  We've had other influencers where they'll promote a dupe, we'll reach out
Speaker 6:  and offer to send them a free one of the real one and some have
Speaker 6:  been gracious and accept it and some will just straight up ignore us
Speaker 6:  because they know that they can sell the do, but maybe they can't sell the
Speaker 6:  original version. So it's a tough place out there. But all I can say is that
Speaker 6:  I can lead with love and education, but what people
Speaker 6:  decide to do is what they decide to do. And I don't have control over that.
Speaker 2:  That's absolutely wild. Like I have to say. That is
Speaker 2:  really, really wild. It feels like, you know, because the
Speaker 2:  dupes are constantly popping up on platform after platform, like
Speaker 2:  there's always that affiliate money theoretically, right? Like
Speaker 2:  dangling in front of them. Even if one Amazon listing gets removed, you can
Speaker 2:  just link to a new one. So it, it really feels like, I think you used the
Speaker 2:  term Whack-a-Mole.
Speaker 6:  Whack-a-Mole. It is absolutely whack-a-mole. And like we also have affiliate
Speaker 6:  links to pop flags, but I understand that there is that
Speaker 6:  dupe customer.
Speaker 2:  How many dupes does your team go after in like a month? Let's say
Speaker 6:  Just this year it's been an average of 600 a month. Wow. So
Speaker 6:  it's gone insane in 2025.
Speaker 2:  And when these are showing up on these platforms, are they using your
Speaker 2:  photos? Are they taking their own product photos? Like what do the listings
Speaker 2:  actually look like?
Speaker 6:  It's a mixture of everything. So in the beginning it was a lot of
Speaker 6:  just taking photos from our website and then because
Speaker 6:  we were able to take down listings based on copyright infringement, they
Speaker 6:  then used AI to change the model's faces even though it was
Speaker 6:  still obviously the same photo. So that made it
Speaker 6:  really hard for straight up like copyright infringement. So we had to prove
Speaker 6:  in different ways that no, this is actually our photo, but manipulated. Then
Speaker 6:  it turned into them stealing my content and posting it, for
Speaker 6:  example, as a TikTok commercial, which would then link over to a drop
Speaker 6:  shipping website, which also had the photos stolen from our website. So what
Speaker 6:  ends up happening is that a fan or a
Speaker 6:  potential customer will think it's me because clearly it's my content
Speaker 6:  linking to a place with our photos, they buy it, they get something that's
Speaker 6:  really bad quality because obviously, and then they end
Speaker 6:  up coming back to my page and blaming me for bad quality, slow
Speaker 6:  shipping and all this stuff that is not my product. So when it comes to duping,
Speaker 6:  oftentimes people are like, oh well but you should be grateful for the free
Speaker 6:  marketing or whatever. And it's like, no, actually they have duped the customer
Speaker 6:  so hard that not only do they blame me for bad product, in
Speaker 6:  some cases fans have dmd me and said like, oh is ha
Speaker 6:  your sub-brand because they've copied the marketing not
Speaker 6:  just of me, right? But the marketing of them hiring
Speaker 6:  a model with my body type shooting in a bedroom that looks like mine
Speaker 6:  to the point where people think it is my company because they're,
Speaker 6:  they like, I have such a way of doing my marketing. So the
Speaker 6:  duping has gone so insane and so deep that
Speaker 6:  it's not beneficial at all for anyone who's trying to say that it's absolutely
Speaker 6:  harmful and tarnishing the brand. The other thing is once you start
Speaker 6:  seeing all these dupes everywhere that aren't mine,
Speaker 6:  it kind of saturates the market. People become tired or
Speaker 6:  sick of seeing this thing. But the thing is it wasn't the original thing,
Speaker 6:  it's everywhere because it's also the fake thing. So it also devalues the
Speaker 6:  novelty and the specialness of the original design and that's extremely
Speaker 6:  frustrating.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, there are so many weird levels of like lookalikes
Speaker 2:  happening in that example you gave, there's like obviously the lookalike
Speaker 2:  product, there's the lookalike model, there's the lookalike house, there's
Speaker 2:  a look of like photo shoot, like I'm, it's like breaking my brain just thinking
Speaker 2:  about like how deep this goes.
Speaker 6:  It goes really deep and people don't know. And even when I try to explain
Speaker 6:  to them that they can't really understand and you don't really understand
Speaker 6:  until you've gone through it yourself. But yeah, it goes too deep and, and
Speaker 6:  the consumer, I mean I don't even blame them for not knowing
Speaker 6:  if someone's duping you this hard, how are you supposed to even get out of
Speaker 6:  that?
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I know if you've posted about one really wild example where like your
Speaker 2:  face was sort of like face swapped in some way and it was your
Speaker 2:  video, but your, the face was different. Can you talk about that a little
Speaker 2:  bit?
Speaker 6:  This one just brought chills throughout my body when
Speaker 6:  I found this video I was like, wait,
Speaker 6:  that's literally my house, my body.
Speaker 6:  But now the face is a face of a Caucasian woman. And I was like,
Speaker 6:  what? And for everyone listening who's not watching this? I am Vietnamese
Speaker 6:  and Chinese. So that was very unsettling to see. And
Speaker 6:  again, because if the platform is using an AI
Speaker 6:  tool, right, to check if this is copyright infringement, they're gonna be
Speaker 6:  like, no, the face is different. But it's obviously the, it's taken from
Speaker 6:  a source, which is mine. And in so many ways,
Speaker 6:  just duping in general has been so dangerous for, you know, small
Speaker 6:  business owners, creatives, but women as well. And I've seen
Speaker 6:  a lot of influencers have their faces taken mouths
Speaker 6:  manipulated to sell something that they never even spoke about. And it gets
Speaker 6:  even dirtier and deeper than that when it comes to certain
Speaker 6:  websites that, you know, certain people are visiting for
Speaker 6:  certain types of videos. I think you know what I'm talking about and it's
Speaker 6:  a, it's a lot of ai, I don't know, violence I suppose,
Speaker 6:  against women too. And that, that's just a whole nother topic.
Speaker 2:  I'm curious if you've ever purchased a dupe of one of your products and what
Speaker 2:  was that dupe like?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so I have purchased the sheen dupe
Speaker 6:  'cause I just wanted to see what it looked like. It was horrendous quality.
Speaker 6:  The mesh was kind of rough. I believe that one had a front seam still.
Speaker 6:  I don't even know if it had pockets, I'm not sure. But I just needed to have
Speaker 6:  one in my hand so I knew. But more recently I
Speaker 6:  got a dupe from TJ Maxx and Marshall's because
Speaker 6:  a fan had gone shopping and alerted me that there were
Speaker 6:  racks full of pure, we score dupes. And when I compared it side by
Speaker 6:  side, I knew for sure that they had
Speaker 6:  my score, my original score in hand because there were details on that score
Speaker 6:  that you can't see from the online photos. You can only see it if you, you
Speaker 6:  have it in hand. For example, we have this specific bar tack tack in the
Speaker 6:  back of her waistband to ensure that the, the drawstring doesn't fall out
Speaker 6:  in the wash. You can't see that on the photo that was there. Even
Speaker 6:  the shape of the end cap at the end of the drawstring was exactly
Speaker 6:  the same.
Speaker 2:  I wanna switch gears a little bit and talk about like, you know, a lot of
Speaker 2:  the discourse around dupes ends up actually kind of
Speaker 2:  maybe spiraling in other directions into sometimes a discussion of class
Speaker 2:  or what people can afford and you know, there are a lot of shoppers who say,
Speaker 2:  well we deserve a cheaper alternative because it's not our fault. We can't
Speaker 2:  afford the original or we don't want to pay for the original. What do you
Speaker 2:  make of that kind of like discussion?
Speaker 6:  Look, I understand because I grew up shopping at
Speaker 6:  the Ross's and buying everything on clearance. We never
Speaker 6:  bought anything full price. Okay. However,
Speaker 6:  in this day and age, you know, you also have so many
Speaker 6:  different ways to get clothing. There's
Speaker 6:  thrifting, of course there's clearance racks, there's also sample sales.
Speaker 6:  Like we just had our sample sale where you can get the original score,
Speaker 6:  the original pople, anything at a literal
Speaker 6:  fraction of the price. And we had people lining up around the block to
Speaker 6:  go purchase this. And so there are different ways
Speaker 6:  to do this without supporting
Speaker 6:  thievery because that's what it is. And like I, I understand like not being
Speaker 6:  able to afford something and that's why I came out with the blog Pilates
Speaker 6:  line at Target, which is a more affordable price point for
Speaker 6:  something still designed by me, still designed by Cassie Ho. And
Speaker 6:  so I feel like with those like alternatives, why do we have to
Speaker 6:  go and buy the dupe? Why do we need to do that? Because you're only
Speaker 6:  hurting someone. And I just feel like that's a, like I can
Speaker 6:  understand where that argument comes from, but there's also alternatives
Speaker 6:  and I've tried to offer solutions so that you don't have to.
Speaker 2:  Mm. And I'm curious like how you feel as someone
Speaker 2:  whose creative work went into this product. Like when you see
Speaker 2:  a dupe, I guess you feel like your creative work is being
Speaker 2:  devalued.
Speaker 6:  When I see a dupe, I feel like it's my stolen property. I feel like someone
Speaker 6:  went into my house and stole something from my closet. Like that
Speaker 6:  is literally what it feels like. Except multiply that and see it
Speaker 6:  also morphed into something uglier. Like that's really, really weird. And
Speaker 6:  because I spend anywhere between one and a half to
Speaker 6:  three years on one design, these are my
Speaker 6:  babies. It's not just like a thing that I'm throwing out
Speaker 6:  there. There's love and passion and soul in every single
Speaker 6:  one of these And look like if somebody can't spend
Speaker 6:  the time to design their own creation, then maybe
Speaker 6:  do we talk about a royalty situation? Like it's like I'm not trying to
Speaker 6:  keep this away from anyone, it's, but it's just like, but don't steal it
Speaker 6:  from me either. This has to be done in a
Speaker 6:  business partnership type way. You can't just steal, that's not
Speaker 6:  fair.
Speaker 2:  Fashion obviously is a pretty wasteful industry
Speaker 2:  and humans are buying more clothes than maybe ever before
Speaker 2:  in the history of humanity. How do you as like a designer
Speaker 2:  and a business owner make sure that what you sell will last a really
Speaker 2:  long time? That people will love it. How do you convince shoppers that,
Speaker 2:  you know, spending a little bit more to buy the original is worth it for
Speaker 2:  them?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so look, the quality of an item
Speaker 6:  is going to be how long does this last? Right? That's the sustainability
Speaker 6:  of an item. Now I will say at the beginning of this conversation right here
Speaker 6:  about sustainability, that the best way to be sustainable is to
Speaker 6:  not buy anything. Okay. To be like our dads who are still wearing shirts
Speaker 6:  from the eighties. Like that's the most sustainable. Now I am in the apparel
Speaker 6:  industry and I'm, I am creating product, but I am
Speaker 6:  choosing the best fabrics that don't break down. The
Speaker 6:  fibers don't break down in the wash after like the first one. Like it's gonna
Speaker 6:  last you like several years or more. And what we do is we
Speaker 6:  do wear testing on all different sizes. We're checking everything. It
Speaker 6:  goes through a third party testing to ensure that this
Speaker 6:  product is really good. And here's the thing, I'm not charging
Speaker 6:  Lululemon or aloe prices, I'm also not charging sheen prices.
Speaker 6:  I'm somewhere right in the middle, but I'm giving you that same quality And
Speaker 6:  I, I'm just gonna say it like as a Lulu. So I think it's a great deal
Speaker 6:  if you're willing, I guess for certain price point people, if you're willing
Speaker 6:  to save up a little bit and buy this like one good legging instead of like
Speaker 6:  seven bad leggings, it's gonna feel so good and a lot more
Speaker 6:  sustainable when you can do that.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. You mentioned that you know, sometimes you spend years designing and
Speaker 2:  developing products. I wonder if you can talk about like how that compares
Speaker 2:  to the speed with which dupes kind of just are churned out.
Speaker 2:  Like those happen what? Like overnight?
Speaker 6:  Oh my god, it's insane. Okay. So like I said, I spend between one
Speaker 6:  and a half to three years designing and developing one style.
Speaker 6:  Okay. The she and Dupe came out three
Speaker 6:  months later. That's when I found it. I don't even know
Speaker 6:  when it actually came up, but I would not be surprised.
Speaker 6:  And I've like read it in different places that sometimes dupes can come out
Speaker 6:  in as little as like three to seven days, like based on whoever
Speaker 6:  this manufacturer is because they might just have stock mesh on hand,
Speaker 6:  they may have stock whatever on hand and they just, I don't even know
Speaker 6:  how the supply chain works for fast fashion. I, I, I can't even comprehend
Speaker 6:  it because for me it's like every time we develop something
Speaker 6:  we're actually like weaving the actual fabric. We we're ding the fabric that
Speaker 6:  we cut in. So, and then like there's like so much stuff that goes into it.
Speaker 6:  I do not know how these fast fashion companies do it. They have to have on
Speaker 6:  hand stock or something so that they can just like go. And it's funny
Speaker 6:  'cause sometimes I'll like watch these tiktoks from girls who are buying
Speaker 6:  from these fast fashion websites and they're getting things that don't look
Speaker 6:  like the picture. Which no doubt if you're buying a dress for $5, it's not
Speaker 6:  gonna look like this dress that you know, I saw somewhere else for 250. And
Speaker 6:  you can so tell that whoever, I don't even wanna call it a
Speaker 6:  pattern maker, but let's just say the sower was forced to copy this thing
Speaker 6:  from a photo. You can so tell that they had no idea what they were doing
Speaker 6:  because there was no time for like pattern making and developing.
Speaker 6:  It's just sew it, get it out. I honestly, I mean I think
Speaker 6:  you'd have to talk to someone in fast fashion to truly know because I don't
Speaker 6:  even know how that works.
Speaker 2:  Cassie, you and your team encounter dupe listings constantly.
Speaker 2:  So have you found any like tips for how
Speaker 2:  consumers can spot whether something is a dupe?
Speaker 6:  Yes. These are the things that I look out for as a consumer myself when I'm
Speaker 6:  shopping online. Okay. So one, if you see a listing
Speaker 6:  where the angle stays the same the whole time and as you're clicking different
Speaker 6:  colors, only the color is photoshopped and changing super red flag.
Speaker 6:  If you see a listing where all the model's heads are cut off
Speaker 6:  super red flag, if you see that
Speaker 6:  all the photos in the listing kind of look like they're from different photo
Speaker 6:  shoots, that is also a red flag. There's just
Speaker 6:  so much you can tell from the listing
Speaker 6:  specifically the photo shoot that definitely gives me like this is a dupe
Speaker 6:  vibes and of course the price, like if the price just seems
Speaker 6:  too low to be true, likely it is.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Sometimes I also will take an image that I see from
Speaker 2:  like Amazon and just throw it in Google reverse image search
Speaker 2:  to see what site it's actually from. And that's actually a really good way
Speaker 2:  to figure out like, oh this is definitely a copy of something.
Speaker 6:  Oh 100% I, I will also do that spec, like specifically if
Speaker 6:  I just can't find it And I know like this is definitely from
Speaker 6:  somewhere else. Oh, something else to check too is go
Speaker 6:  to like the returns like FAQs page and
Speaker 6:  if it's starting to get a little dicey, like you can't find an address or
Speaker 6:  it's from overseas or they don't allow returns or exchanges like
Speaker 6:  super duper red flag. 'cause you wanna be able to try something on
Speaker 6:  and return it if it doesn't fit.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I actually wanted to ask if you like do a lot of online shopping. Like
Speaker 2:  I am also kind of paranoid about buying stuff, especially from like new brands
Speaker 2:  that I've never tried. So do you shop online a lot?
Speaker 6:  Yes, I shop online a lot and because
Speaker 6:  women's sizing is all over the place and sometimes brands don't even pay
Speaker 6:  attention to their own size chart. What I do sometimes is I have to buy
Speaker 6:  two of everything 'cause I'm never sure I'm happy to pay the return
Speaker 6:  fee. I'll pay it. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Have you ever gotten got by any listings where you were like, oh, I think
Speaker 2:  I like this, I think I want this, and then it came and you were like, I was
Speaker 2:  definitely catfished.
Speaker 6:  Oh, gotten got le. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  TikTok shock. Some of my friends have been like, oh,
Speaker 6:  oh my God, I love TikTok shop and coupons and stuff. I'm like, ugh, I don't
Speaker 6:  know, I feel weird about this, but I kept getting an ad or like
Speaker 6:  influencers or creators talking about this, like one jumpsuit with a scrunch,
Speaker 6:  But that just make the butt look so good. And I was like, ugh, okay, fine.
Speaker 6:  It was like really late at night And I like decided to just buy it,
Speaker 6:  whatever. And you know, it came back and
Speaker 6:  when they sent me, I bought two things. One, they
Speaker 6:  sent the wrong thing, which was bad. And then secondly, the other thing,
Speaker 6:  the scrunch bot wasn't doing anything. And so, you know, I just, I
Speaker 6:  don't trust TikTok shop for clothing. I'm very
Speaker 6:  scared and so I'll stick to like my, my main brands that I
Speaker 6:  buy from, that I, that I know my size in. It's just too scary out there.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I'm so curious if the jumpsuit with a scrunched butt, was it In
Speaker 2:  fact maybe a dupe of something else? Like a, a poorly executed dupe?
Speaker 6:  You know what, I'm not sure because that scrunch butt jumpsuit, I
Speaker 6:  see it all over Amazon. I see it on TikTok shop, I also see it with the head
Speaker 6:  cut off in certain places and then I see it on like AI models, but
Speaker 6:  I actually don't know where did that come from? Yeah,
Speaker 6:  there should be a website. I feel like someone needs to make a website called
Speaker 6:  like dupes exposed.com or something and then you could
Speaker 6:  like put a picture of the thing that you're looking at and they can show
Speaker 6:  you where the original came from. Like that would be a really, really good
Speaker 6:  idea for somebody out there.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I mean I think it's really hard to just like get to the bottom of things,
Speaker 2:  right? And like track down where it started because these things
Speaker 2:  pop up in so many different corners of the internet and it's, I'm sure
Speaker 2:  like you can attest to this, it's impossible to track them all down. It's
Speaker 2:  impossible to get to every customer and be like, no, no, no, this is actually
Speaker 2:  a lookalike of this other thing, right? Like there's just like, there's endless
Speaker 2:  shelf space on the internet and someone's gotta fill it.
Speaker 6:  No, that's very true and that's why I am so vocal about
Speaker 6:  telling my story and calling out these thieves that are
Speaker 6:  doing this because what ends up happening is that if you are able to educate
Speaker 6:  a larger audience, then they'll also wanna help fight for you. And it's been
Speaker 6:  really cool to see us all rally together because by telling
Speaker 6:  my story, I've connected with other independent designers who are going through
Speaker 6:  the same thing. So new friendships have been brought forth there
Speaker 6:  and then, you know, I'll meet fans on the street and they'll just be like,
Speaker 6:  keep fighting, like never give up. And so it's been really, really cool because
Speaker 6:  nobody wants a big corporate Goliath to take advantage of them.
Speaker 6:  And so I feel like we're all just helping each other and also seeing the
Speaker 6:  comments online too, underneath someone selling a dupe. Some of my
Speaker 6:  fans will call it out and like I love that and I'm just so
Speaker 6:  grateful for it because me as a singular human, I, there's no way I
Speaker 6:  could do this alone.
Speaker 2:  You have been online through many different iterations of
Speaker 2:  the internet. You've seen platforms come and go, you've seen formats come
Speaker 2:  and go, you've seen businesses come and go. You've seen creators come and
Speaker 2:  go. I'm sure And I keep having this experience
Speaker 2:  recently and it's really why I wanted to write about dupes where I just feel
Speaker 2:  like I'm seeing the same thing online over and over and over again.
Speaker 2:  Like it does not stop. I scroll my feed, I get like four of the same videos,
Speaker 2:  I go on Amazon or I go on other shopping platforms and
Speaker 2:  like item after item. It's just the same thing. Do you
Speaker 2:  feel, well one, I guess does that feel familiar to you? Is this your
Speaker 2:  experience right now of parts of the internet?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean TikTok when it first started for a lot
Speaker 6:  of us in the pandemic was such a pure
Speaker 6:  and innocent, fun, quirky plays, right? Like as
Speaker 6:  any website or social media platform, when it begins, it's very much
Speaker 6:  like that, right? And now it's turned into
Speaker 6:  what feels like a vertical video, QBC, like
Speaker 6:  everyone is selling at you. It's a lot of affiliates. And when
Speaker 6:  affiliates can make their little chunk of change from their
Speaker 6:  link and it becomes a very viable business for them, then that
Speaker 6:  ends up becoming the feed because it also helps TikTok end up making money.
Speaker 6:  And at the end of the day, like we talked about with the big corporations,
Speaker 6:  like continuing to sell my product even though they're infringing my patent,
Speaker 6:  like it's about the money. So my experience is the same
Speaker 6:  as yours. And it is frustrating to have product
Speaker 6:  being pushed in my face all the time when sometimes I'm, I'm just trying
Speaker 6:  to, I don't know, see a recipe, a look at the
Speaker 6:  different fish in the ocean or just like a new trend.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I'm seeing a lot of the same thing. But
Speaker 6:  yeah, it's, it's a lot of creators also
Speaker 6:  kind of mimicking other creators because they've seen what works.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's starting to get really tiring online.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. And you know, obviously you've had your designs, your
Speaker 2:  physical goods copied. Have you had content copied
Speaker 2:  in the past?
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. When I first came out with my format
Speaker 6:  for a design video, which really tells you the why behind a design, I'll
Speaker 6:  put like, you know, I'll tug on the front seam or the lack of a front seam
Speaker 6:  and show that there's no camel to, I'll put a very specifically, I put a
Speaker 6:  water bottle in my pocket. I remember just a few months
Speaker 6:  after me doing that, I started to see that type of
Speaker 6:  video almost frame by frame with the same phrasing that I would
Speaker 6:  use like anti camel to like who says that
Speaker 6:  used in videos across the internet. And it made me really upset, but
Speaker 6:  of course like I don't own a video format, whatever, right? Everyone
Speaker 6:  says like, oh, imitation is the best form of lottery. Okay fine, whatever.
Speaker 6:  And it happened until it actually stopped happening because what ended up
Speaker 6:  happening that was a lot of happening in one sentence is that
Speaker 6:  I continue to innovate so I can continue to do that type of video, not just
Speaker 6:  for a legging or a biker short, but I have
Speaker 6:  rompers cargo pants, I have dresses, you know, things that
Speaker 6:  these other brands, they can only copy me on the legging because
Speaker 6:  they've only innovated so far. And so for me that actually
Speaker 6:  stopped happening, which is really great. I'm very happy. And I remember
Speaker 6:  during that time I was so upset and so sad about just being
Speaker 6:  copied everywhere, just like design wise, content-wise, marketing wise, like
Speaker 6:  everything right? But my friend told me, Cassie, you have to
Speaker 6:  keep innovating, keep thinking about the future because
Speaker 6:  even though they're gonna copy you, like don't think they're gonna stop,
Speaker 6:  they're gonna keep copy you, but at least you'll always be a few steps ahead.
Speaker 6:  So never stop focusing on the innovation. And because
Speaker 6:  I've done that, I guess the copycat video is like kind of like, at
Speaker 6:  least to me now is a smaller part of my frustrations
Speaker 6:  than it was before.
Speaker 2:  And do you spend that time instead just like designing new products or
Speaker 2:  interacting with fans? Like what is your, what is like I guess the antidote
Speaker 2:  as someone who sees their work all over
Speaker 2:  done by someone else?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean I have to pour my energy into creation, into innovation,
Speaker 6:  into design, but in this very moment, even though I don't
Speaker 6:  want to be, I am also pouring a lot of my energy
Speaker 6:  into fighting the Goliaths and getting the story out there.
Speaker 6:  I hope one day that I won't have to do that, but
Speaker 6:  maybe this is a part of my journey as a designer and an
Speaker 6:  innovator. But I think the best use of my time, And I know this
Speaker 6:  is to keep designing, but there's just a fire
Speaker 6:  inside of me And I just like can't, I won't, I won't be silenced if
Speaker 6:  someone is doing the wrong thing, not just to me, but
Speaker 6:  to a lot of other independent designers without a voice. And so
Speaker 6:  right now my energy is split between that and innovation.
Speaker 2:  That's Cassie Ho from Blog ATI's and Pop Flex.
Speaker 2:  After the break I have an audio diary from my trip to a Brooklyn fabric
Speaker 2:  recycling facility. This is The Vergecast, we'll see you on the other side.
Speaker 2:  landfills just like our old tech. I love fashion and
Speaker 2:  clothes, but I wanted to know what's being done about the tremendous amount
Speaker 2:  of waste in the industry and what technological challenges
Speaker 2:  still exist for the people doing this work. Luckily, a small
Speaker 2:  fashion nonprofit has saved millions of pounds of textiles from
Speaker 2:  landfills and it's doing it in Brooklyn, New York. I went over there with
Speaker 2:  my producer Owen Grove. We made an audio diary for The Vergecast and you
Speaker 2:  can also check out video from our visit on social.
Speaker 2:  When I visit the fab Scrap warehouse in an industrial part of Brooklyn,
Speaker 2:  the first thing I notice is an enormous pile of black trash bags
Speaker 2:  stacked up to the ceiling and taking up an entire area of the
Speaker 2:  warehouse's main room. The Fab scrap staff call this Mount
Speaker 2:  Everest. All of these bags are filled with pre-consumer
Speaker 2:  textiles, stuff like leftover fabric that never got made into clothing
Speaker 2:  or scraps of sample fabric that brands were testing out.
Speaker 12:  So all of these bags, again, are from our
Speaker 12:  brand partners.
Speaker 2:  That's Camille Tegel, co-founder and interim executive director at Fab
Speaker 2:  Scrap who's showing me around today. Fab Scrap works with brands of
Speaker 2:  all sizes. Everyone from household names like J Crew and
Speaker 2:  Macy's, as well as more niche brands like Streetwear Company, Noah,
Speaker 12:  They get Renumbered so that we are able
Speaker 12:  to collect data and assign it to that number and then it's an
Speaker 12:  easy way for us to provide data back to our brand partners.
Speaker 12:  So that's the biggest thing about what we do is
Speaker 12:  encouraging and educating brands to actually track their
Speaker 12:  impact and to easily analyze the numbers.
Speaker 12:  And so the types of data points we give them are total pounds that they've
Speaker 12:  saved from landfill by recycling with Fab Scrap, what percentage of their
Speaker 12:  total pounds were reused, what percentage was
Speaker 12:  recycled down cycles. And then you know, some simple
Speaker 12:  conversion metrics like the equation of
Speaker 12:  CO2, you know, saved the like
Speaker 12:  equivalent to trees, planted
Speaker 2:  Hundreds of fashion brands, big and small, send leftover textiles
Speaker 2:  to Fab. Scrap Tegel says the nonprofit receives six to
Speaker 2:  7,000 pounds of material every week.
Speaker 12:  We actually just hit 2 million pounds. Wow. Of fabric
Speaker 12:  saved. Oh my gosh. Which is such a crazy amount. Yeah, I think a really
Speaker 12:  good visual is if you were to fill every single seat
Speaker 12:  at Madison Square Garden with a hundred pounds of fabric, that would be
Speaker 12:  2 million pounds. Oh my god. Of fabric. That's crazy. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Fab Scraps work is limited to materials that are coming directly from their
Speaker 2:  brand partners. The millions of pounds they've saved from landfills
Speaker 2:  represents just a tiny portion of overall textile waste. They
Speaker 2:  don't take used clothing donations from individuals, for example,
Speaker 2:  and Fab Scraps operation is focused on New York based
Speaker 2:  designers and brands. Just think of all the other textile
Speaker 2:  waste happening across the world. Still 7,000 pounds
Speaker 2:  of material a week is a huge undertaking. And how does
Speaker 2:  Fab Scrap do it? An army of volunteers on
Speaker 2:  the day we visit the place is buzzing with people who've come to help
Speaker 2:  fab scrap sort through thousands of pounds of textiles at
Speaker 2:  workstations organized in rows. Volunteers dig through black trash
Speaker 2:  bags to divide fabric into different categories.
Speaker 2:  Pieces of fabric larger than the workstation table will be
Speaker 2:  resold to the public at Fab Scraps thrift store. The more complicated process
Speaker 2:  comes with smaller scraps of fabric.
Speaker 12:  Most typically, if something is not
Speaker 12:  sequin leather, plastic
Speaker 12:  has no like really hard components to it. If it's
Speaker 12:  really just fabric, even if it's a mixed like mixed composition,
Speaker 12:  even if it's a hundred percent of a certain fiber,
Speaker 12:  we can downcycle or shred this.
Speaker 2:  All of these smaller pieces of fabric get mixed together and shredded into
Speaker 2:  tiny pieces and made into something called shoddy. Shoddy takes
Speaker 2:  on a bluish color with straight pieces of different fabric mixed in a
Speaker 2:  streak of yellow or smudges of black and brown. Think of it like
Speaker 2:  a fabric trail mix that can be molded for different uses.
Speaker 2:  Shoddy often becomes different types of insulation,
Speaker 12:  So you could have them be pretty like
Speaker 12:  dense,
Speaker 2:  Oh
Speaker 12:  My gosh, and
Speaker 2:  Heavy
Speaker 12:  Like this. A lot of times they're used for the automotive
Speaker 12:  industry, so like car doors require so much insulation, like really, really
Speaker 12:  dense, hard compact and installation. Or you could have it be really
Speaker 12:  thin and lightweight like a lot of times they're now being used for
Speaker 12:  packaging. You could have it for flooring for
Speaker 12:  walls and homes.
Speaker 2:  Another bin for sorting is reserved for denim. Denim fabric
Speaker 2:  also gets shredded into pulp, but it gets its own process because it's great
Speaker 2:  for fiber to fiber recycling, using textile waste to create
Speaker 2:  new fabric. Tegel says that there's been a lot of technological
Speaker 2:  advancement for 100% cotton and 100%
Speaker 2:  polyester recycling. Most of our clothing is made from these
Speaker 2:  two compositions, so recycling 100% cotton
Speaker 2:  and 100% polyester fabric is a way to get the biggest impact
Speaker 2:  in the industry. Denim is the least varied fabric when it comes to
Speaker 2:  composition and it's an easily recognizable fabric for
Speaker 2:  volunteers. From one of the black trash bags, Camille pulls out a
Speaker 2:  piece of cardboard with little pieces of fabric stapled onto it.
Speaker 2:  Each piece is just a few inches big. These are called headers.
Speaker 12:  Headers are swatches or essentially sales
Speaker 12:  tools that mills will use to market their fabric
Speaker 12:  out to designers and it's how designers are shopping for their fabric. So
Speaker 12:  a lot of times it, there is a lot of information that's really helpful for
Speaker 12:  placing an order. So it'll say the fiber content, it might give a range
Speaker 12:  of colors that that fabric's available. It'll say like maybe the
Speaker 12:  minimums required to purchase that order. So it's really a
Speaker 12:  tool for purchasing, for sourcing, but after
Speaker 12:  they've placed the order for that fabric, these swatches
Speaker 12:  become a little useless to designers.
Speaker 2:  In order to downcycle or recycle the fabric on headers,
Speaker 2:  you have to separate out all the stuff that's not fabric,
Speaker 2:  the cardboard, the staples, the tape. The problem is that
Speaker 2:  every header looks a little different. Some fabric has stickers
Speaker 2:  on it, some doesn't, and headers are all different sizes,
Speaker 12:  So that does make the sorting a bit tedious. And one of the reasons
Speaker 12:  why this can't be easily mechanized is because all the
Speaker 12:  formats of headers are completely different. Like
Speaker 2:  There is, it's one of the reasons that all of this human labor is involved
Speaker 2:  in the sorting process. There's no standardization of headers,
Speaker 2:  it's just a tiny piece of the fashion industry, but shows how
Speaker 2:  wasteful or inefficient it can be.
Speaker 2:  All of those small cuts of fabric that were sorted by volunteers
Speaker 2:  eventually get compressed into a giant cube
Speaker 2:  using fab scraps baler machine. The baler kind of resembles an
Speaker 2:  elevator. There's an open area inside that is loaded up with
Speaker 2:  fabric by a fab scrap staffer. Close the front of the baler,
Speaker 2:  hit the button and the machine compresses the fabric down.
Speaker 2:  The Baylor creates giant blocks of mixed fabric weighing
Speaker 2:  between 350 and 380 pounds
Speaker 2:  and they kind of look like a closet threw up all over. I'm just like
Speaker 15:  Fascinated to see what's in each of these like it's like kind of fun like
Speaker 15:  this looks like maybe like a sweater.
Speaker 2:  You can examine the bales and find hints of what kind of fabrics were being
Speaker 2:  don cycled. In one cube I found part of a knit sweater
Speaker 2:  with a slashed Ralph Lauren tag. Elsewhere there were
Speaker 2:  chunks of a puffer coat and soft fleece like fabrics.
Speaker 2:  These 350 pound bales will get sent to South Carolina
Speaker 2:  where they'll be shredded by a fab scrap partner. That's how you get
Speaker 2:  shoddy, that fluffy fabric trail mix that's used to make
Speaker 2:  insulation.
Speaker 2:  One of the most exciting things about Fab Scrap, at least for me, is a thrift
Speaker 2:  store. This is where the pieces of fabric too big to shred
Speaker 2:  end up tucked in a corner of the warehouse is a room
Speaker 2:  filled with reams of fabric, big cones of yarn
Speaker 2:  of every color, buckets full of zippers and so much more.
Speaker 2:  And all of it is for sale to the public.
Speaker 16:  The amount of things are so random, like these are bag straps. Okay, this
Speaker 16:  is interesting. Unfair and Klein
Speaker 16:  clearly came from that brand. There's a bunch of them in here actually.
Speaker 16:  These look like maybe Elastic or like undergarments,
Speaker 16:  more elastic metal like
Speaker 16:  I don't know what, these are actually some buttons in here.
Speaker 16:  Oh, these are like zipper pulls,
Speaker 16:  belts maybe, or buckles like
Speaker 2:  Some of the thrift store offerings. VERGE on the absurd. There's a bucket
Speaker 2:  filled with mutant swimsuit pieces, some of which are only half constructed.
Speaker 2:  Another bin has jeans in various states of completion.
Speaker 2:  They might be missing chunks that were cut out by designers perhaps in the
Speaker 2:  development process. In another area we find fringed
Speaker 2:  leather jacket sleeves detached from the rest of the garment. It's a
Speaker 2:  crafty person's paradise. If you sew at all or if you've been to a
Speaker 2:  fabric store, this is exactly what a, a normal store looks like. This is
Speaker 2:  how they sell fabric. And it is
Speaker 2:  kind of wild to imagine that all of this otherwise would just be thrown out
Speaker 2:  because there's, I mean like look how beautiful this is.
Speaker 2:  The team at Fab Scrap is fewer than 15 people standing in
Speaker 2:  the thrift store and talking to Camille, I'm moved by
Speaker 2:  how much Fab Scrap has been able to do without Fab Scrap. Where would
Speaker 2:  all of this stuff be?
Speaker 12:  Oh my gosh.
Speaker 12:  I mean that's kind of the, the hard thing to understand when you walk
Speaker 12:  into this room specifically is that when you look around the room and see
Speaker 12:  how many things are so easy to work with, realizing that before Fab
Speaker 12:  Scrap existed, all of it went to landfill. I think that's where
Speaker 12:  that realization of, oh my gosh, like this, like
Speaker 12:  Fabs Scrap was able to help divert this material. But
Speaker 2:  Fab Scrap doesn't exist in a vacuum. The textiles that come to Fab Scrap
Speaker 2:  are upstream from the things we buy in stores during the height
Speaker 2:  of the pandemic. For example, Camille says they saw less evening wear
Speaker 2:  textiles and lots of athleisure and knits.
Speaker 2:  Fast fashion has no doubt contributed to waste in the industry.
Speaker 2:  But Camille points out that those problems exist at smaller brands
Speaker 2:  and other companies that people might not consider quote unquote fast fashion.
Speaker 2:  It's not just companies like Sheen or Zara that might throw away
Speaker 2:  bags and bags of materials through its recycling program,
Speaker 2:  brand education efforts and community thrift store Fab Scrap
Speaker 2:  to me embodies what change in the fashion industry might
Speaker 2:  look like. Camille and the Fab Scrap team challenge us all
Speaker 2:  to reset our relationship with the clothing we buy and wear.
Speaker 12:  And I think that's what's kind of amazing is that it's all built around
Speaker 12:  this passion for textiles and understanding that fabric is
Speaker 12:  such a valuable resource and it's only because of fast
Speaker 12:  fashion and all of these really absurd like
Speaker 12:  societal things that like our perspective has changed on fabric and it's
Speaker 12:  become less recognizable as something to protect. And
Speaker 12:  instead there's been this twisted perspective of it being really
Speaker 12:  easy to discard
Speaker 2:  From consumers to big fashion companies. Everyone has a role to
Speaker 2:  play. When I buy something, I want it to be made out of
Speaker 2:  materials that are kinder to the environment. I want the craftspeople making
Speaker 2:  my clothing. I be paid fairly and treated with dignity.
Speaker 2:  I want my clothes to last And I want the ability to repair them. And I
Speaker 2:  believe the fashion companies have a responsibility to strive for excellence
Speaker 2:  in all these areas, even if it means producing less.
Speaker 2:  Fab Scrap is small but unbelievably scrappy, no pun intended. And
Speaker 2:  I really and truly did not mean to make that joke.
Speaker 2:  Camille hopes the organization will continue to grow and expand.
Speaker 12:  The next 10 years hopefully looks like a bit more robust in
Speaker 12:  terms of like having more team members, being able to reach other
Speaker 12:  cities, maybe calling more people to the cause and
Speaker 12:  having them either, you know, do that work through
Speaker 12:  Fab Scrap or as a volunteer or as a shopper. I think just really building
Speaker 12:  this community and really establishing ourselves more
Speaker 12:  in other cities would be amazing.
Speaker 2:  We're going to one more break and when I come back, I'll be here with V Song
Speaker 2:  to talk about the clueless closet. It's The Vergecast
Speaker 2:  Hello, we are back and let's get to the hotline as always.
Speaker 2:  The number is 8 6 6 VERGE one one and the email is
Speaker 2:  vergecast at The Verge dot com. We love hearing your questions and we try
Speaker 2:  to answer at least one on the show every week. And today I
Speaker 2:  have Victoria Song to help me answer a very fun question from James.
Speaker 2:  James says, in the last episode, the clueless closet was
Speaker 2:  mentioned and Mia talked about their spreadsheet system. That's me.
Speaker 2:  I've been looking for a solution to the same issue since I can never make
Speaker 2:  up my mind, I'd love a deeper dive in the system used or an app,
Speaker 2:  maybe the AI ones if they're good. Sincerely, James. James,
Speaker 2:  thank you for this question to catch people up if they didn't hear
Speaker 2:  the last one. We were talking about all the fake movie and TV tech Yes. That
Speaker 2:  we would love to steal. And I mentioned the clueless closet,
Speaker 2:  which is sort of like a computer system that inventories
Speaker 2:  all of the characters clothing pieces. And then she will like match it and
Speaker 2:  the computer will say if it's a good match, if it's a good outfit or not.
Speaker 2:  And I mentioned that I have something that's like kind of halfway there where
Speaker 2:  I basically have this giant Excel spreadsheet that I have
Speaker 2:  logged every single article of clothing. I love that. I love that I own,
Speaker 2:  I love how meticulous that is it. So if you knew
Speaker 2:  my closet and my living situation, you would understand why it's essential
Speaker 2:  for context. I think there are probably about like 300
Speaker 2:  lines rows on the spreadsheet each containing an item. Oh
Speaker 2:  my god. And I will say like it, it doesn't include shoes, bags, belts,
Speaker 2:  hats, a lot of outerwear. But in my spreadsheet I have like
Speaker 2:  what the item is, descriptions, what season it's good for, whether it's short
Speaker 2:  sleeve, long sleeves, sleeveless tube top, whatever. If it's a
Speaker 2:  dress, if it's like long, short, somewhere in the middle, oh my god.
Speaker 2:  Colors like predominant colors. Whether it's vintage, whether I, it was a
Speaker 2:  hand me down from my mom or a family member. And I
Speaker 2:  also mark where in my apartment I've stored it because I have like crucial
Speaker 2:  that's crucial marking where it is. Yeah. I have boxes under my bed
Speaker 2:  in my closet, in my bureau, in the like front hallway
Speaker 2:  closet. So like I need to know where things are. If I need to pull something
Speaker 2:  that's like out of season or whatever. This is amazing. Yeah, this is dedication.
Speaker 2:  It's no clueless closet, but it gets the job done and I'd be
Speaker 2:  happy to include like screenshots or image of like what the spreadsheet
Speaker 2:  looks like. But yeah, it's partially just like
Speaker 2:  practical, you know, like I, I live in New York, I live in a small apartment
Speaker 2:  and if you know anything about New York apartments, you know that they never
Speaker 2:  come with enough closet space. No. VI know. You
Speaker 20:  Know, like I know that they never come with enough. You know, I, I moved
Speaker 20:  to Jersey for a house. That place still doesn't have enough closet space.
Speaker 20:  Yeah. For all the, the, And I, like, I finally have a dream walk-in closet
Speaker 20:  that I have to share, but it's still not enough space And I still
Speaker 20:  don't know where all the clothes are. I still have to have a different dresser.
Speaker 20:  So I, I get the impulse behind this, but oh my God,
Speaker 20:  it seems like a lot of manual work as well.
Speaker 2:  It's, it's so manual and so like what I do basically is
Speaker 2:  twice a year I rotate my wardrobe. So I put away
Speaker 2:  winter things and take out summer things. So right now all my winter stuff
Speaker 2:  is in the spreadsheet logged where I've stored it, but it's like
Speaker 2:  inaccessible to me unless I go digging for it. And I was just sick of having
Speaker 2:  to try to find where I put things. And so that's like a big reason
Speaker 2:  for the spreadsheet. But you know, it doesn't do a lot of the things that
Speaker 2:  the Clueless closet does like Right. Combine outfits or give me
Speaker 2:  feedback, which honestly like, I don't want feedback, but
Speaker 2:  there are a lot of apps and things that people have built that kind of mimic
Speaker 2:  the clueless closet. So there's one version of this that is very
Speaker 2:  DIY kind of crafty that is like basically a
Speaker 2:  flip book where someone has copy, you know, printed
Speaker 2:  every article of clothing they have and put it in a little three ring binder.
Speaker 2:  So this seems like a lot of work. I don't know how you
Speaker 20:  Feel. It's, it's, it's a lot of work. Like I love journaling. I have all
Speaker 20:  the tools necessary to make that And I feel like I need to lie down
Speaker 20:  because that, that is a lot of dedication, a lot of work. And I kind of
Speaker 20:  do a capsule closet because I, if you don't know what a capsule
Speaker 20:  closet is, it's you kind of have a bunch of basics that you've figured out
Speaker 20:  how to mix and match so you maximize the stuff and reduce closet
Speaker 20:  space. I said try because you can try And I
Speaker 20:  don't know anyone who's successfully done forever. I don't know anyone who's
Speaker 20:  successfully done a capsule closet. Yeah. But yeah, I think, I think I sent
Speaker 20:  also another TikTok to you over the weekend. I went, oh my god is this?
Speaker 20:  Yeah, let's
Speaker 2:  Look ATS Closets.
Speaker 21:  Look at Power Digital Wardrobe. You upload photos of your clothes, the background
Speaker 21:  gets removed. Be real. When was the last time you wore the t-shirt that's
Speaker 21:  crumpled up in the bottom of your dresser right now? I know for me the shirts
Speaker 21:  that are down here have not been worn in a very long time. And some of those
Speaker 21:  are shirts I used to wear every single day. I just forgot that I own them.
Speaker 21:  I was tired of this. So I created the solution for it. And this is the solution.
Speaker 21:  It's an app I made called Fitted and it's an AI powered digital wardrobe.
Speaker 21:  You upload photos of your clothes, the background gets removed and then
Speaker 21:  they get tagged using AI immediately right here in the pieces tab. I can
Speaker 21:  see every item of clothing that I own, whether I wear it or not. And I can
Speaker 21:  go to the fits tab And I can start creating outfits with all of those clothes.
Speaker 21:  So this is integrating everything in my entire closet and making outfits
Speaker 21:  with them. Especially these pants, they the only pants that fit me. This
Speaker 21:  right here is the key to wearing the clothes that you don't normally wear
Speaker 21:  or wearing the clothes you forgot you own. Of course you find an outfit
Speaker 21:  you like, you can save it. It shows up in your safe fits with all the rest
Speaker 21:  of them. Absolute game changer. It does take some time to actually upload
Speaker 21:  your clothes to the app, but I promise you once you have them up there,
Speaker 21:  it is the best feeling in the world. Go download Fitted
Speaker 2:  Now. Wow. Interesting. I mean it's built an app. Yeah. I will say that
Speaker 2:  this type of app has existed for a while. Yeah. Where you basically like
Speaker 2:  digitally log all of your clothing. I find
Speaker 2:  the, like taking a photo of it cropping the background, like all of that
Speaker 2:  work to be very tedious. It's extremely, and they usually lose me there.
Speaker 20:  That I think the, the problem that we're coming up against is the
Speaker 20:  actual logging of the, the items that you have.
Speaker 20:  'cause there's no way AI is getting around that either. You have to manually
Speaker 20:  take a picture of all of this sort of stuff. And
Speaker 20:  like, I don't know if they still do this, but like look books I think might
Speaker 20:  be kind of
Speaker 2:  Polyvore. Do you remember
Speaker 20:  Polyvore? Oh my god, that's a name I haven't heard in
Speaker 2:  85 years. I know, I know.
Speaker 20:  But yeah, so I think maybe one way around it for those of us who
Speaker 20:  are not particularly adept is to do a lookbook,
Speaker 20:  which is you just create a little, I, I started in
Speaker 20:  my, my camera roll of going like, this outfit is fire. Let me Yeah.
Speaker 20:  Take a picture of it and add it to an album called Lookbook. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  I also have an outfits album. Yeah. So
Speaker 20:  Of
Speaker 2:  Just photos and there's like
Speaker 20:  Three in there, right. Because I'm so lazy.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. I mean it's pretty, in terms of like logging things, the easiest
Speaker 2:  thing is like you snap a photo of your outfit before you leave. And actually
Speaker 2:  I did do something that I can share a screenshot of or just
Speaker 2:  a quick clip of what I did. But if you have an iPhone, which I guess I shouldn't
Speaker 2:  assume, but if you have an iPhone, you can take a photo of your outfit,
Speaker 2:  open a notes document in the notes app and then like
Speaker 2:  long press on your body in the photo and copy it
Speaker 2:  and then just plop it into the notes app and it's like a little sticker of
Speaker 2:  yourself. Oh my God, that's so smart. And its the background. It, it does
Speaker 2:  everything. And so I have a notes app full of just like little
Speaker 2:  miniature stickers of my outfits of myself.
Speaker 2:  And it kind of needs to be cleaned up a little bit. But I have
Speaker 2:  just like a general feed of all of them. You can also click into them
Speaker 2:  to see it bigger and then like swipe through it like a photo album. But
Speaker 2:  crucially, what I use this for is outfits that I have worn to
Speaker 2:  work things because that is like, I don't know about you, but
Speaker 2:  women's professional wear is so, it's a curse.
Speaker 20:  It's a absolute, it's just so one, it's either not fun
Speaker 20:  or it's not comfortable. Yeah. Or it's just like people
Speaker 20:  notice if you wear the same thing. Too many times I've, I've had some VERGE
Speaker 20:  commenters and other commenters when I was at Gizmoto. They're like, does
Speaker 20:  she have another shirt? And I was like, oh my God,
Speaker 2:  That's so rude. First of all, that's so rude. But also,
Speaker 20:  But also point taken. Yeah. Well
Speaker 2:  It's really hard, it hard to like calibrate your personal style to
Speaker 2:  the setting and like the tyranny of
Speaker 2:  women's workwear is something that I just will never, ever, ever
Speaker 2:  surrender to.
Speaker 20:  And Taylor,
Speaker 2:  I'm, I'm not wearing that. I'm sorry I'm not wearing the like little
Speaker 2:  blazer and pencil skirt vibe. I need to feel comfortable
Speaker 2:  also, like this video, this podcast, I need to find something that
Speaker 2:  like looks kind of normal on screen that also I'm not having to go buy
Speaker 2:  like a new wardrobe. Nice. Yeah. So yeah, I have a section in my notes
Speaker 2:  app that says work outfits and when I don't know what I'm doing when it's
Speaker 2:  a night before and I'm freaking out because I have nothing to wear to this
Speaker 2:  conference or whatever, I will just like pick a little mia
Speaker 2:  sticker outfit to just recreate.
Speaker 20:  That's genius. That's genius. Highly
Speaker 2:  Recommend.
Speaker 20:  I I am going to do that because like to your point, anytime there's
Speaker 20:  like, you're gonna be on camera, you need to take a photo And I was like,
Speaker 20:  oh God, what do I have? What do I wear that is solid. That is not white.
Speaker 20:  That is not, there's just like so many considerations that you have to think
Speaker 20:  of because
Speaker 2:  Not green. Right.
Speaker 20:  That how you'll come up on camera. Yeah. Yeah. Green you might just be a
Speaker 20:  floating head. Yeah, exactly. So yeah, if you see us wear repeat
Speaker 20:  outfits,
Speaker 2:  Don't say anything. Don't
Speaker 20:  Say anything. But that's the reason. It's because that's, it's we,
Speaker 20:  we don't have an infinite budget. Yeah. We don't have, we don't actually
Speaker 20:  have shares closet, which
Speaker 2:  Is I wish, which
Speaker 20:  Gigantic
Speaker 2:  I wish,
Speaker 20:  Do we look like we're wearing the same outfits? It's because we pre-taped
Speaker 20:  some of these things. So what are we gonna do? Bring half of our closet
Speaker 20:  in and switch out and all of that. No, that's just,
Speaker 20:  although I have done that on certain occasions. Yeah. For certain videos.
Speaker 20:  So that's just dedication. Yeah. But
Speaker 2:  If The Verge wants to create a closet for me in the Vox Media office, I will
Speaker 2:  not say No Jim, Jim Benoff,
Speaker 20:  NELI, NELI, NELI, NELI. Can we, can we have a sheriff's closet?
Speaker 2:  Can we take what? Share over your office while you're on leave and make it
Speaker 2:  into a closet.
Speaker 20:  Yeah. What if we have a sheriff's closet that we can all share
Speaker 2:  A I like it. I like it too. The the last point I'll make too is like the
Speaker 2:  AI ification of this type of feature
Speaker 2:  or tool. For me it probably wouldn't work
Speaker 2:  because so much of clothing is like tactile
Speaker 2:  and sensory and even though things like a shirt and
Speaker 2:  then pants separately, like when you slide them next to each other on top
Speaker 2:  of each other, it looks normal. There are so many like nuances to how
Speaker 2:  clothing falls on the body that Yeah. Doesn't mean it will work. That's why
Speaker 2:  you need to like try on outfits to
Speaker 20:  See that's, that's the thing I have about that one guy in the TikTok, the
Speaker 20:  fitted app. It's like you're taking pictures of the clothes but not on you.
Speaker 20:  Yeah. There's just certain ways that it's like, oh theoretically this crop
Speaker 20:  top and this pair of jeans would look good. But actually that's not
Speaker 20:  a high enough rise jeans for me. So when I put it on, I don't like the way
Speaker 20:  it looks. That sort of stuff. So you know, AI is not always
Speaker 20:  gonna be able to distill what you like and what your personal style
Speaker 20:  is, so eh, yeah. I don't know.
Speaker 2:  I think kind of diminishing returns on something
Speaker 2:  Efford, Travis Ick, and Andrew Marino. The Vergecast is The
Speaker 2:  Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Jake will be
Speaker 2:  back on Friday to discuss all the news from the week. And thank you as always
Speaker 2:  for listening. See ya.