# Transcript
ID: e366069b-ab81-4862-9c6e-eea0ba778c85
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-7324605319412949367/7574987121860263850/s93290-US-6936s-1759489183.mp3
Description: This week, everything is a HomePod. And has ads. The Verge’s Jen Pattison-Tuohy joins the show to talk about all of Amazon’s new hardware, the current state of Alexa Plus, and whether the new Kindle Scribe is the one we’ve been waiting for. Then, The Verge’s Emma Roth tells Jen and David about her experience with Telly, the TV that ships to your house for free in exchange for showing you ads all the time. Telly may not be for everyone. Finally, in the lightning round, the gang talks about a handy new Spotify feature, Emma’s first Waymo ride, and the glory that is Chunk.
Speaker 5:  Jen Tui is here. Hi Jen.
Speaker 7:  Hi, David. Yes. It's, it's all about round fabric wrapped
Speaker 7:  balls.
Speaker 5:  This is just what we do now. We have one video app, we have one idea about
Speaker 5:  phones. We have one idea about ai, and we have one idea about speakers Indeed.
Speaker 5:  And then this is what we do. So you are in our New York studio right now
Speaker 5:  because you've been in New York doing like a, just a
Speaker 5:  truly wild, like 48 hours of smart home and speaker
Speaker 5:  news. Yes. How are you holding up?
Speaker 8:  I'm, I'm, I'm doing good. Yeah, I'm still on the high. I'm still on the smart
Speaker 8:  speak high. That's
Speaker 5:  Good. I'm glad for you. So we, there's, there's like a ton of news This week.
Speaker 5:  Yes. So we have so exciting big Amazon event, which we're gonna spend a lot
Speaker 5:  of time talking about. We have a bunch of Google stuff that all also happened
Speaker 5:  This week. Weird timing from Google. On that front, we're gonna
Speaker 5:  talk about tele the TV that I care more about than most
Speaker 5:  reasonable things in my life. We have some Microsoft News. We're gonna
Speaker 5:  talk about soa, we're gonna talk about all kinds of different stuff. There's
Speaker 5:  just a lot to get to. We're gonna get to all of it. But let's start with
Speaker 5:  Amazon, because I think this was like the, the sort of gadget news
Speaker 5:  of the week. You were there. You went to this event, this is kind
Speaker 5:  of an Amazon event we've ve been waiting for, for a while.
Speaker 5:  So Panos Pane who ran devices and windows at Microsoft
Speaker 5:  for a long time, left to go to Amazon and
Speaker 5:  basically like started making giant promises about the future of AI hardware.
Speaker 5:  I think you, you And I have both talked to him in the intervening time
Speaker 5:  and you, you get a pretty clear sense that the idea was
Speaker 5:  we are going to come out with a big swing about
Speaker 5:  new ideas about what Alexa in particular
Speaker 5:  is going to be. So you, you went to this event on Tuesday, I should say.
Speaker 5:  We're recording this on Wednesday morning, because again, scheduling is insane.
Speaker 5:  We will be back to our normal time very soon and I'm very excited about it.
Speaker 5:  But tell me about the event. What was the, what were the vibes like in, in
Speaker 5:  the room at this launch event? Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So it was actually the same venue as the event
Speaker 8:  they had in February when they announced the sort of revamped Alexa
Speaker 8:  Plus. So it had very sort of similar vibes, looked very similar.
Speaker 8:  Panos had his same sort of very strong
Speaker 8:  personality. He really fills the room
Speaker 8:  and he, he did, he came on stage. There was nothing there. There was no set
Speaker 8:  decoration or anything. It's very, very clean. They had some little
Speaker 8:  plints on the side that were empty. So that we were like, okay, so at some
Speaker 8:  point, hopefully something is gonna appear. And sort of
Speaker 8:  magically during the event when they talked about each new piece of hardware,
Speaker 8:  little devices popped up on the, on the plinth. So it was very
Speaker 8:  nicely done. The vibes were actually a little low key
Speaker 8:  in a weird way to start with. But once,
Speaker 8:  once, you know, once we got going, it was more
Speaker 8:  exciting because I think we've all been waiting for some really
Speaker 8:  interesting hardware. Especially because, so Panos started at
Speaker 8:  Amazon almost two years ago now. So this, we were
Speaker 8:  expecting a lot of this to have really have his stamp on it and
Speaker 8:  talking to people at the event. It sounds like he'd brought in a
Speaker 8:  number of people from Microsoft to help design
Speaker 8:  these new devices. The, the new head of design
Speaker 8:  and that the VP of Alexa and devices are both
Speaker 8:  Microsoft alum who have moved to Amazon. So, you know, I was,
Speaker 8:  and Tom Warren asked me to ask him if when he was gonna put a floating hinge
Speaker 8:  on an echo. So I was expecting, I was expecting a lot
Speaker 8:  and ultimately, I don't know, I'm not sure that what we got
Speaker 8:  was necessarily like a whole new vision,
Speaker 8:  but it was definitely a big jump up from
Speaker 8:  where Amazon's hardware has been to date. And
Speaker 8:  talking with Panos afterwards, he said the key, and he didn't say
Speaker 8:  difference because that would be mean to his predecessor, but I filled in
Speaker 8:  the blank. The key difference is rather than starting from a price
Speaker 8:  point, they started from, he said,
Speaker 8:  where what the customer needs. So a product
Speaker 8:  that's gonna fulfill what you need it to do,
Speaker 8:  not just what Amazon was looking
Speaker 8:  to provide, if that makes sense. Right. So the Echo Show devices in the
Speaker 8:  past have, have been very interesting products. They filled
Speaker 8:  an interesting space, often difficult to
Speaker 8:  figure out exactly what they were meant to do, but, but they were interesting.
Speaker 8:  But they were always very underpowered and like touching a touch screen is
Speaker 8:  something we're used to doing all the time and it should respond very quickly.
Speaker 8:  And that is sort of, for me, the key takeaway from this is that touchscreen
Speaker 8:  now on the Echo shows so much better. Interesting. I mean, ing, it's like
Speaker 8:  a tablet, not like a smart display. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Well, so, okay, so let, let's actually start with those. So the, the four
Speaker 5:  new devices, just to, for anybody who didn't follow the event,
Speaker 5:  starting from the cheapest. I think I can, I think I can do this off the
Speaker 5:  top of my head. There's the Echo do Max, which is a hundred dollars. Yes.
Speaker 5:  And is now the sort of basic smart speaker. It is. If you close your
Speaker 5:  eyes and imagine a home pod mini, you're 95% of the way there.
Speaker 8:  Especially if you put it up right the other way. Just
Speaker 5:  Tilt it a little. Yeah. Yes. And I think that's not to degra. I actually
Speaker 5:  think the Echo do Max is the single most interesting of these devices. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And we can come back to that. Yeah. But then there's the Echo Show eight,
Speaker 5:  which is 180 bucks. And then the Echo show, is it 10
Speaker 5:  or 11? The other one Echo
Speaker 8:  Show 11. 11. So it's the upgrade to what was the 10? Okay, so,
Speaker 8:  okay, so the 11 is the size of the screen. Right. So the eight is the eight
Speaker 8:  inch or eight and a bit, and yeah, so it's the Echo Show 11. Okay. And then,
Speaker 5:  And then there's the Echo Studio. Yes. Which is
Speaker 5:  220 bucks the same price as the Echo Show 11.
Speaker 5:  Yes. And it's basically, it is designed to be the like great
Speaker 5:  sounding speaker. I think those really high-end smart
Speaker 5:  speakers exist only for executives that work at that company and no one
Speaker 5:  buys them. That's just a theory that I've had for a long time.
Speaker 5:  But I do think, I, I think you And I agree on something which is that the
Speaker 5:  best version of a smart speaker in
Speaker 5:  2025 probably has a screen. And so I think for that reason,
Speaker 5:  these shows are the most interesting ones. So let's just start with those.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, tell me about the, like, if you're starting from, not just, we have
Speaker 5:  to make this thing as inexpensive and accessible to as many people as possible,
Speaker 5:  but we wanna make it good. Yeah. What does that actually look like in the
Speaker 5:  new shows?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, so the screen is the key. And when these devices
Speaker 8:  launched, the Echo show was the first smart display, and then we had the
Speaker 8:  Nest hub. They were low cost, low
Speaker 8:  component price. You know, they were trying to sort of
Speaker 8:  be an easy to add to your home device. I remember Google
Speaker 8:  Home was giving away Nest hubs like willy-nilly. And
Speaker 5:  I think at a certain time that made a lot of sense, right? It did what what
Speaker 5:  you needed was to give people a reason to try this stuff. Yes. And I think
Speaker 5:  to like for the first generation of smart speaker and smart device to just
Speaker 5:  basically be like, throw it in with any box that
Speaker 5:  is leaving your warehouse. Yes. Which is like what both Google and Amazon
Speaker 5:  did for a long time. Made a lot of sense. But I do think we're,
Speaker 5:  we have to be past that now. Yes. So I think, I think it is good that we
Speaker 5:  seem to be pushing past
Speaker 8:  That because, and what they did, just when they first came out, smart displays
Speaker 8:  were just like a visual cue for what you were talking to your assistant about.
Speaker 8:  Now they're turning into more devices
Speaker 8:  that you interface with to control things in your home for the smart home.
Speaker 8:  But also, you know, you can watch TV on some of them. You can,
Speaker 8:  you know, scroll through photos, you can interact with the voice assistant
Speaker 8:  and like look up things and click and go to different
Speaker 8:  aspects of the assistant, like if you wanna book tickets, those types of
Speaker 8:  things. These are all things that Alexa Plus can do. So they really needed
Speaker 8:  the hardware to be able to work, to have more power and you to be
Speaker 8:  able to do more because it was so frustrating. You would ask it something
Speaker 8:  and there would be something on the screen and you would sort of go to tap
Speaker 8:  it or do something and it, it's like, yeah, you can't do that here.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. You have to go to your phone. What are you thinking? So
Speaker 8:  now this feels, I mean, it's not a laptop, it's not a tablet, but it feels
Speaker 8:  much closer to that kind of an experience when you are interacting
Speaker 8:  with it. Again, I literally spent five minutes tapping around. So
Speaker 8:  this is all with a big caveat once I've actually got to test it. But from
Speaker 8:  what I've seen so far, this is a big upgrade. It was faster. There's
Speaker 8:  a new AZ three pro processor
Speaker 8:  that they're using and also a huge upgrade here
Speaker 8:  that none of the previous smart displays bar
Speaker 8:  one have got, have managed to do is the thing can actually
Speaker 8:  hear you. Hmm. Because
Speaker 8:  if you look at Smart displays design, they are a giant screen
Speaker 8:  blocking a speaker, all of them. And when you try and talk to it,
Speaker 8:  it can't hear you. I have to mute every other echo
Speaker 8:  display speaker in my home when I try and talk to a smart display
Speaker 8:  echo because they won't hear, they just won't hear you. Interesting. The
Speaker 8:  others will hear you first. So what they've done here is they've lifted the
Speaker 8:  screen up, it's now floating, which also makes the design
Speaker 8:  look a little more modern than the older ones on top of this speaker.
Speaker 8:  So In theory, your voice should be able to go to the speaker
Speaker 8:  underneath and over the top and ran the sides a little bit better. And there's
Speaker 8:  this big oblong squashed home pod, mini style
Speaker 8:  speaker on the back. And the sound quality, I didn't get to hear
Speaker 8:  this one, but I was told is in between the max and the studio.
Speaker 8:  Okay. So this is slightly better sound quality than the, the max, but not
Speaker 8:  as good as the studio. So yeah, this new design with the kind of floating
Speaker 8:  display, bigger speaker at the back, but that's more,
Speaker 8:  that has a bit more shape isn't just a big bulbous bottom.
Speaker 8:  Like most of them are. I mean, the Nest hub had
Speaker 8:  that a little bit. It, it's raised slightly, so there's a little bit of speaker
Speaker 8:  below it, but there's a lot more room here. So again, haven't tested
Speaker 8:  this, but it looks like the design should be much better for voice
Speaker 8:  control. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And there's some interesting ideas in all of that that I think you see across
Speaker 5:  the whole line here. One is the, the processor, right? Like they, they made
Speaker 5:  a lot of noise about this AZ three chip. Yeah. And the, the things
Speaker 5:  it will enable and the speed at which it'll work and the ways that it will
Speaker 5:  be able to like, make this whole process more seamless, which is a huge deal.
Speaker 5:  Right. I think like you hear about the reason people churn out of these devices
Speaker 5:  and one of the ones is that it sucks and one of the ones is that
Speaker 5:  it's annoying, right? Like it, the the thing where it doesn't hear you Yes.
Speaker 5:  Is is both like a physical microphone placement problem and a
Speaker 5:  processing problem. Yes. And so, like the work that they're doing to solve
Speaker 5:  both of those things to just sort of solve one small annoyance
Speaker 5:  at a time, I actually think is really exciting. And it's the same with the
Speaker 5:  touchscreen. It's like, you, you, I sort of expected this thing to
Speaker 5:  have some like wild new like articulating robot arm And I like
Speaker 5:  the stuff we've been hearing about like what Apple might be doing this. Like
Speaker 5:  yeah, what if it spun 360 degrees to follow you around the room? And so it
Speaker 5:  was actually just like, it was a little bit surprising to see it just be
Speaker 5:  like a speaker. Yeah. But then you go through the list and it's like, oh,
Speaker 5:  this is actually just trying to poke at everything you actually do with this
Speaker 5:  device all day and make it work a little bit better. Better. And I feel like
Speaker 5:  that is, that is the precise correct approach for this because it is like,
Speaker 5:  the smart home system, at least in my life, has been
Speaker 5:  totally like death by a thousand cuts, right? Yeah. And, and the way to solve
Speaker 5:  it is not with some brand new idea about everything, it's just fix the damn
Speaker 5:  problems.
Speaker 8:  Make it work. Yes. Definitely.
Speaker 5:  And, And I think like that's the, there's a lot of that in all of these,
Speaker 5:  including things like mic placement. Like I think we're right to be excited
Speaker 5:  about mic placement because like when it can hear me I will use it more.
Speaker 5:  Exactly.
Speaker 8:  It matters. And there's, there's also some other nice touches here. Like
Speaker 8:  Amazon has never been really great about the details with their hardware
Speaker 8:  and like these have fabric wrapped.
Speaker 5:  That's a kind way of saying it. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  These have fabric wrapped cables that like lay fat and they match
Speaker 8:  the color of the speaker. So no more white cable with a black
Speaker 8:  speaker. That is nice too. You know, those just sort of small little things.
Speaker 8:  Like there's a purple one, the Purple Nest Max Hub show.
Speaker 8:  I'm gonna be doing this all day. Sorry, too many. Yeah, too many. The purple
Speaker 8:  show, the Purple Max is very purple and has
Speaker 8:  a purple cable and that's just fun. It's like, it's a small thing
Speaker 8:  but it really, you know, that it just elevates the feel of the device. And
Speaker 8:  that's what these, these just feel more premium,
Speaker 8:  better quality. They have the same kind of, th
Speaker 8:  I've learned a lot about 3D knit fabric in the last couple of days, but apparently
Speaker 8:  I'm so sorry. This is what is the best thing for speakers. And
Speaker 8:  it's not something that any Echos had before and they've brought it to this,
Speaker 8:  this is also what gives it the home pod mini feel. And the, and the,
Speaker 8:  the Google home speaker also has the same, so they all do
Speaker 8:  really feel and look quite similar. But yeah, just, just more
Speaker 8:  premium. The only thing I would say that people are gonna potentially
Speaker 8:  really not like about the new design is there is no physical camera
Speaker 8:  shutter anymore.
Speaker 5:  Oh, interesting.
Speaker 8:  And that was because they said that was because, so
Speaker 8:  it has much thinner bezels, which again good. Yeah. But
Speaker 8:  that sacrifice, the camera shutter they say, but you
Speaker 8:  still, when you press the mute button, it does turn off the camera. You just
Speaker 8:  do not have that physical feeling that it's shuttered.
Speaker 8:  And I know that some people do prefer that.
Speaker 5:  That's such an interesting trade off. 'cause on the one hand that's like,
Speaker 5:  if the goal is just to sell more devices, I think that's pretty clearly the
Speaker 5:  right trade off. Yeah. Like make it look nicer and sacrifice a, a thing that
Speaker 5:  is like, makes you feel good, but doesn't necessarily have a huge
Speaker 5:  impact on actual functionality of the device. Probably the right trade off.
Speaker 5:  But I, I am one of those people who has really, really
Speaker 5:  appreciated the thing where I can switch a button and know that it is
Speaker 5:  like, just know it is, it is mechanically disconnected. And I think that
Speaker 5:  is like important and valuable. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  It does give you that peace of mind for sure. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And there's just something about these now And I think like one of the other
Speaker 5:  changes that they've made with lot of these devices is they're making the,
Speaker 5:  the light rings easier to see from everywhere, which
Speaker 8:  I think is a big upgrade. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Oh, I totally agree. Love that. And like, you don't have to sort of like
Speaker 5:  lean over the speaker to see if
Speaker 8:  It's Yeah, yeah. You can actually reach the buttons rather than just like
Speaker 8:  be slapping at it Yeah. To figure out what's gonna happen. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And so I think that that kind of, sort of the, the thing is
Speaker 5:  more transparent about what it's doing all the time. Yeah. I think is a good
Speaker 5:  tack. But I, I will miss the shutter button. I'm a little bummed about
Speaker 8:  That. Well, and the, the, the light ring thing is a, a big upgrade
Speaker 8:  for me because I have one of these, one of the Alexa speakers in my
Speaker 8:  kitchen And I can see my kitchen from my bedroom and if someone leaves the
Speaker 8:  door open and the Alexa is muted, there's this big
Speaker 8:  red glow in my kitchen And I, it's so
Speaker 8:  annoying. So I've unplugged it because of that. Whereas now when you mute
Speaker 8:  it instead of this huge red glow, it just glows red on the
Speaker 8:  little mute button. So they just little quality of life upgrades
Speaker 8:  that make the whole thing feel better. But I do have to address the elephant
Speaker 8:  in the room because you brought it up with the displays.
Speaker 8:  The big problem with Amazon displays to date
Speaker 8:  have been the, the ads people. Yes. And understandably
Speaker 8:  dislike how many ads you do get. The rigid, the current shows
Speaker 8:  I get these full screen ads on. Oh it's awful. Not these, not the new ones
Speaker 8:  with Alexa plus I've not yet had any,
Speaker 8:  but I realize this is in early access. So yeah, that's probably gonna
Speaker 5:  Change. And I think there's a, there are a lot of echo show owners who
Speaker 5:  were bait and switched by this the first time who are
Speaker 5:  I think in a real like, fool me once, shame on you kind of, kind of situation
Speaker 5:  here.
Speaker 8:  Yes. I mean that and talking to the Amazon execs, ads are not going anywhere.
Speaker 8:  They are talking about how they want to, you know, it's more about discovery
Speaker 8:  and there's a lot of promoting Amazon products and Amazon services,
Speaker 8:  but they're still ads. I mean you get these in the home app now for, you
Speaker 8:  know, in Apple, on Apple hardware, there'll be ads for Apple Music. You know,
Speaker 8:  it's everywhere. Sure. I'm sure we're gonna start seeing more ads with Alexa.
Speaker 8:  Plus they're not there yet. But I'm, I'm not, I wouldn't be surprised
Speaker 8:  that they do come, they do change the experience
Speaker 8:  on the display devices. I have not seen, I
Speaker 8:  haven't heard the by the way, on Alexa Plus yet, if anyone's not familiar
Speaker 8:  with that, this is where on the speakers. 'cause obviously no screen,
Speaker 8:  no ads, they will suggest things to you by saying, oh by the way,
Speaker 8:  would you like to buy more toilet paper?
Speaker 8:  So that's not arrived yet, but who knows? It's probably coming. I think I
Speaker 8:  just wanna say, 'cause I know there's a lot of conversation about this in
Speaker 8:  our comment section. Oh yeah.
Speaker 8:  So people, people, people, people. You have to pick your poison.
Speaker 8:  This is in the smart home with these devices. There are
Speaker 8:  trade-offs. It's, it sucks. I wish the perfect
Speaker 8:  experience existed. You've got a few options. You go
Speaker 8:  with Amazon, which has a lot of hardware, supports
Speaker 8:  its hardware, comes out with new hardware, but is probably gonna put ads
Speaker 8:  in your face. Not too expensive though. Quite innovative.
Speaker 8:  You've got Google, not a lot of hardware.
Speaker 8:  Are they gonna support their hardware? Well yes, but are they going to give
Speaker 8:  you new features and new hardware? Mm hmm.
Speaker 8:  Probably. And also Google if you're worried about ads. Yeah. If you're worried
Speaker 8:  about privacy, Google, so Apple,
Speaker 8:  they may come out with a smart speaker, everyone's waiting, you're gonna
Speaker 8:  spend a lot of money
Speaker 5:  Also, which it doesn't exist yet.
Speaker 8:  Doesn't exist yet. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Which is part of the problem. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Bigger part of the problem. Yeah. You're gonna, and then the, the, the fourth
Speaker 8:  option, obviously roll your own go home assistant use private voice
Speaker 8:  assistants, great local, really hard
Speaker 8:  to manage buggy as hell. So, you know, you've got to pick
Speaker 8:  at the moment, sadly, I would love for something to come along that that
Speaker 8:  ticks all the boxes. But right now, you know, there's, there
Speaker 8:  just isn't the perfect solution. So yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's a tricky one. 'cause I think to me the, the by the way thing on
Speaker 5:  a speaker is like a horrible dystopian nightmare that I am just utterly unwilling
Speaker 5:  to put up with. Like truly that is, that to me is like an instant non-starter
Speaker 5:  for me. I think the onscreen ads bother me less
Speaker 5:  than they bother some people. And I think truthfully, a a lot of what I've
Speaker 5:  seen in our comments and elsewhere is the sense of, well you didn't have
Speaker 5:  this and then I put it in my house and then you put it there. Yeah. And so
Speaker 5:  to me it's like, just say you're gonna do ads Amazon, like stop playing
Speaker 5:  this game with people where you're like, ha who knows?
Speaker 5:  Probably fine. And then once you have a giant install base, you start rolling
Speaker 5:  ads on people who can't do anything about it. And this by the way, is Amazon's
Speaker 5:  whole mo with everything. They get you signed up for things with the promise
Speaker 5:  of nothing and all good things. And then the minute you get attached,
Speaker 5:  Amazon starts finding ways to make more money off of you.
Speaker 8:  I know.
Speaker 5:  Like, that's just what it
Speaker 8:  Is. Yeah. I wish they would do a, a version of the Kindle for a, for
Speaker 8:  Alexa. Like you pay extra for your Echo show a hundred percent.
Speaker 8:  And you don't get ads just like you can pay extra for a Kindle with no ads.
Speaker 8:  But
Speaker 5:  The Kindle's a funny example because I always tell people to just get the
Speaker 5:  Kindle with ads because it's not Yeah. The, the light's not on. It's not
Speaker 5:  super annoying. The ads never appear when you're looking at the thing. It's
Speaker 5:  just there when they're off. So to me that's like, save the 15 bucks
Speaker 5:  or whatever it is and just, just, you'll never even really notice the ads
Speaker 5:  in any meaningful way. I think the echo show stuff is a little
Speaker 5:  messier because it is like a bright screen blaring ads at
Speaker 5:  you all the time. But that, that I'm,
Speaker 5:  it's, it's the beat and switch that bothers me. It's not actually the existence
Speaker 5:  of the ads that drives me the most crazy. It's the fact that people put this
Speaker 5:  in their house with no ads and then they did ads. Yeah. That's the thing
Speaker 5:  that feels gross. But I think like you describe all the trade-offs, I would
Speaker 5:  handily pick Amazon's version of this. Even if include, even if it includes
Speaker 5:  ads
Speaker 8:  Right now, it is definitely the strongest, it has the most legs,
Speaker 8:  most innovation, you know, and Amazon's not, I don't think
Speaker 8:  Amazon's backing away from it. We know that they struggled financially in
Speaker 8:  this division for a long time, but they've obviously still investing a lot.
Speaker 8:  Google will we'll get to, we'll see what, what's gonna happen
Speaker 8:  there.
Speaker 5:  Google's once in a decade remembered it has, here it is. Smart home stuff.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And then Apple obviously is the dark horse. Everyone is waiting to see what
Speaker 8:  they're gonna do in this space. So
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So real quick before we get off the, the echo stuff, are you as excited
Speaker 5:  about the dot max as I am? I think the idea of like a hundred dollars, pretty
Speaker 5:  good, relatively good looking. They fixed a bunch of the
Speaker 5:  usability stuff like this to me looks like it has a chance
Speaker 5:  to be the like default smart speaker that I tell people to get in their house.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I think, I think it's a, it's a really nice piece of equipment.
Speaker 8:  It's well designed. It had really good sound. I did get to do a sound demo
Speaker 8:  and you know, they were, they're boasting that it's like way better than
Speaker 8:  the home board mini definitely more improved. It's
Speaker 8:  basically this, it's what it is is it's the echo. If everyone remembers the
Speaker 8:  echo speaker, like the flagship echo speaker, that's essentially what this
Speaker 8:  is. It's that same price point too. Okay. Yeah. So even though that
Speaker 5:  I thought the tennis ball can sounded pretty good. It was fine.
Speaker 8:  It was all right. Yeah. Like a
Speaker 5:  Serviceable decent speaker. But then there
Speaker 8:  Was if, then there was the echo fourth gen, which was the big ball,
Speaker 5:  Right? Yeah.
Speaker 8:  That is what, this is really just smaller. So you've still got
Speaker 8:  the dot the DOT's not going away. The original, the the current dot, which
Speaker 8:  is the fifth gen, then there's the dot max, which is basically
Speaker 8:  what the echo this, it's almost the upgrade of the echo fourth
Speaker 5:  Gen.dot max is such a stupid name.
Speaker 8:  I don't like the name. It's,
Speaker 5:  It's the big small one. Yeah. It's nothing.
Speaker 8:  I dunno why they didn't just call the Echo Echo.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. What are we
Speaker 8:  Doing? Yeah, I'm may naming in this space
Speaker 8:  has has never been smooth. Agreed. And then the studio,
Speaker 8:  the big, which is the big boy. So I think, I think yeah the dot max
Speaker 8:  fills I've the echo fourth gen was always my number one re
Speaker 8:  pick for a smart speaker if you were gonna get one. And I feel like this
Speaker 8:  just fills that spot. The nice thing, although this is technically a dot,
Speaker 8:  is it's the first.to have all the smart home radios. So it's a
Speaker 8:  thread border router, it's a matter controller and it has ZigBee. So
Speaker 8:  they're really going all in on the smart home side for all of the smart
Speaker 8:  speakers. So yeah, dot dot max if you are interested in
Speaker 8:  adding a new smart speaker to your home that uses Alexa, I
Speaker 8:  would definitely say based on what we've seen so far, that's the winner.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think that is like a, a kitchen speaker is gonna be a pretty big
Speaker 5:  win for a lot of people.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And you can do two and get stereo sound and Yeah, it's got, and then
Speaker 8:  you can also put five together and do a home theater. But we could
Speaker 8:  talk about that later. We,
Speaker 5:  We, we should talk about that later. So the, the, the sort of
Speaker 5:  underpinning of all of this is Alexa plus, which is still, if I'm
Speaker 5:  understanding correctly, in early access, this is Amazon's like
Speaker 5:  LLM powered futuristic Alexa that you And I were at the launch of
Speaker 5:  65 years ago now under an entirely different regime.
Speaker 5:  The world was like just insane. But anyway,
Speaker 5:  it's still technically an early access, but it's shipping by default on
Speaker 5:  these new devices. So it both is and is not
Speaker 5:  fully launched.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, it's confusing. Yeah. So what's going, so it's
Speaker 8:  shipping by default on these new devices in the US and Canada. Okay. These
Speaker 8:  new devices are shipping to lots of countries, but if you're not in the US
Speaker 8:  and Canada, you don't get Alexa Plus when it, when it comes outta the box,
Speaker 8:  you'll just get the option when you're setting it up. I've been told to just
Speaker 8:  say yes I want Alexa plus. I see. So if you don't do that,
Speaker 8:  you'll have regular, regular old Alexa. You can click yes,
Speaker 8:  you get Alexa plus you don't have to sign up, but it is Alexa
Speaker 8:  plus in early access and that moniker is basically, it's still in
Speaker 8:  better and there are bugs and it may not work exactly as
Speaker 8:  intended and some features don't work at all. So Yes.
Speaker 8:  And then in terms of for everyone else that has devices, if
Speaker 8:  they want Alexa plus you do still have to
Speaker 8:  sign up to for early access and wait for an invitation. But I
Speaker 8:  am told that the waiting period is gonna go away
Speaker 8:  really soon. But it'll still be an early access in terms
Speaker 8:  of Alexa Plus is now here and for everyone that's
Speaker 8:  on the horizon still. I see. I think they feel like there's still a lot
Speaker 8:  that they need to work on because many of the features they announced in
Speaker 8:  February still aren't live. They demoed some of them
Speaker 8:  again This week, but again said coming
Speaker 8:  soon. Yeah. So yeah, a lot is still sort of hinged
Speaker 8:  on rolling out what they've promised. Interestingly,
Speaker 8:  they have announced that they are bringing, they announced This week
Speaker 8:  that, that it is coming to third party speakers. So that's as question I've
Speaker 8:  been asked a lot because you know, Alexa is on like Sonos and Bose
Speaker 8:  and other speakers and that is something that is is coming but again
Speaker 8:  coming soon. So there's just, yeah, it's, it's gonna gonna take a while
Speaker 8:  until we see this everywhere.
Speaker 5:  You've been using Alexa plus for a long time. Is it, is it at or
Speaker 5:  even nearing the point where it's like worth leaping for new hardware to
Speaker 5:  get it?
Speaker 8:  Yes, depending on your use case. It, it is, we should mention
Speaker 8:  $20 a month once it's out of early access. Although
Speaker 8:  right now it's free and then if you get Prime you'll
Speaker 8:  also get it for free, which is kind of weird 'cause that's what, $15 a month.
Speaker 8:  So we'll see how that pans out.
Speaker 5:  Amazon would very much like you to get Prime. Yes. It's like, but also if
Speaker 5:  you, if you don't have a prime account, but you have an Alexa speaker, I
Speaker 5:  have a bunch of questions Yes. About like your your Life choices subscription
Speaker 5:  decisions. Yeah. So I think, I think you, we can fairly safely assume that
Speaker 5:  most people who have these things are going to have a prime account and thus
Speaker 5:  you're gonna get free will eventually get Alexa plus for free. And so I think
Speaker 5:  this is kind of the thing right, is to me these are
Speaker 5:  slightly better versions of the existing things, which is like
Speaker 5:  great, right? As as a way to, if you, if you just assume most people's
Speaker 5:  smart speaker experience is basic smart home stuff, music and timers. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Which is what it's like that that is, that is statistically speaking how
Speaker 5:  most people do smart speakers.
Speaker 5:  These things are going to be slightly better hardware but not like huge new
Speaker 5:  ideas. The huge new idea is Alexa Plus
Speaker 8:  Is Alexa plus and it is better, much better than the old Alexa. Like
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Even now.
Speaker 8:  Oh yes, yes. Okay. This makes me happy. So you, yeah, you can talk to it
Speaker 8:  naturally. Natural language is just a game changer
Speaker 8:  for smart speakers. The problem is, And I think the reason why a lot of people
Speaker 8:  complain about that I've seen complaining about Alexa Plus is we've trained
Speaker 8:  ourselves how to talk to these devices. Oh, totally. And the
Speaker 8:  new versions don't really understand that language.
Speaker 5:  They Oh, interesting.
Speaker 8:  You need to talk to them. Like you would just talk to a person. They're not
Speaker 8:  designed to be deterministic, they're not designed to follow a pattern.
Speaker 8:  So when you say, you know, a turn on the light in
Speaker 8:  the living room to 50%, it'll be like, I mean
Speaker 8:  it might do it, but it's, it's less if you say,
Speaker 8:  hey, a make it brighter in here, oh, a bit more.
Speaker 8:  Okay, bring it down a little, it'll do all of that. That's so much easier
Speaker 8:  than the, the previous way. It's just, we're so used to saying the first
Speaker 8:  way. And so some of those issues I think when people have
Speaker 8:  just been using these devices for a long time and they, they've trained themselves
Speaker 8:  how to do it. So you do have to rethink the way you communicate with them.
Speaker 8:  But once you do that, it is a big change. And I've actually
Speaker 8:  found that, you know, my family uses it more now because they never trained
Speaker 8:  themselves. They just relied on me to do it. But because you can literally
Speaker 8:  just say what you want it to do and it mostly will do it, it makes a huge
Speaker 8:  difference. It's also easier. It's knows a lot more.
Speaker 8:  The old Alexa used to always, you know, say, I am not
Speaker 8:  sure about that or sorry, I can't help with that if you asked more
Speaker 8:  intricate questions or more specifics. But like the other day, my
Speaker 8:  husband was very jealous. I was coming to New York and he was like, oh, I
Speaker 8:  heard about this great play, it stars the girl from Dexter
Speaker 8:  that we really liked. You should go see it. And I was like, what play is
Speaker 8:  it? And he's like, I can't remember. And I said, well let's, why don't we
Speaker 8:  ask Alexa? And so he said, Hey what? And he tried to explain,
Speaker 8:  he said, well exactly what he said to me. And it came back and came up with
Speaker 8:  the name of the play. I think it's like the Great Americans or something
Speaker 8:  I've forgotten, but came up with the name of the play, said where it's playing
Speaker 8:  when it's playing. You know, the old Alexa would never have been able to
Speaker 8:  do that. Right. So that kind of stuff is great. I, a lot
Speaker 8:  of the, the more agentic capabilities, which I tested a while back, I
Speaker 8:  haven't tested again recently. Those were a little hit or miss.
Speaker 8:  I also don't find much use for them. I could just as easily get my phone
Speaker 8:  out. Yeah. The recipe stuff is so good.
Speaker 8:  Like using a smart display in the kitchen is like for me the number one use
Speaker 8:  case. And you can now like snap a picture of a recipe, send it
Speaker 8:  to Alexa and it will break it out
Speaker 8:  into a format for you with the ingredients, the steps. It will talk you through
Speaker 8:  it. You can say, hey what, what was the temperature I needed to set it for
Speaker 8:  for the oven? And just go back and forth while you're walking around your
Speaker 8:  kitchen. That experience so much better. That's
Speaker 5:  The stuff, right? Like that to me is where you go the all the agentic stuff
Speaker 5:  is like fine and interesting And I think like a long way off from actually
Speaker 5:  being relevant to anybody. But like if I can just do all of the things that
Speaker 5:  it seems natural that my Alexa device should do. Yeah. That's
Speaker 5:  the stuff. And I think especially with the smart home stuff, like you And
Speaker 5:  I haveve been talking about this forever. Like I just, no one will ever convince
Speaker 5:  me that having to remember the names of my lamps is a thing that
Speaker 5:  I need to do. Something
Speaker 8:  You need to do. And
Speaker 5:  So like how, what I have and and remembering to say brightness 60% is
Speaker 5:  like insane. No, yeah, I will not do that. But this this change
Speaker 5:  you're describing where it's like just, it just like a little brighter but
Speaker 5:  not too bright and it actually knows what to do. Yeah. That that matters.
Speaker 5:  That's, that's a real switch in what it means to actually use this stuff
Speaker 5:  inside your house.
Speaker 8:  And you can set up a routine for something like that by just saying, oh you
Speaker 8:  know, Alexa, I can you please actually I, I feel like
Speaker 8:  it's gonna be really cold tomorrow. Can you make sure to set the temperature,
Speaker 8:  change the temperature in the afternoon after the kids get home? Like you
Speaker 8:  can go back and forth about things you want to happen in your home that you
Speaker 8:  would maybe just think in your head about and then think, oh I should sit
Speaker 8:  down and program it into my app. But instead of doing that, you just spew
Speaker 8:  it all out and she sets up a T it sets up, sorry, I've been hanging out
Speaker 8:  with Amazon people too long. It sets up a routine for you. You can go
Speaker 8:  and change it in the app or you can talk to it and change it. Say actually
Speaker 8:  no I don't want it to happen at four. Can you make it happen at five and
Speaker 8:  it adapts and changes. So that kind of stuff really is game changer,
Speaker 8:  game changing for the smart home. But the thing about the smart home
Speaker 8:  Alexa that I should just mention before we wrap up is it's not always
Speaker 8:  re reliable, which is a bit of a problem, especially in
Speaker 8:  the smoke minor detail in the Yeah. In the smart home. And this is down to
Speaker 8:  the technology and this is something that I'm assuming is gonna be a problem
Speaker 8:  for all of these systems and I've been doing a bit of digging
Speaker 8:  into this and basically what it is, as we know
Speaker 8:  LLMs are not deterministic, right? They are
Speaker 8:  designed to be creative, like designed to be you ask chat
Speaker 8:  TP TA question and then ask the same question again and you get a different
Speaker 8:  response in the smart home, if you ask your smart assistant
Speaker 8:  to turn on the lights, you want it to do that every time.
Speaker 8:  And sometimes, depending on how you phrase it, it may misinterpret what
Speaker 8:  you're asking. May not realize you're talking about the smart home might
Speaker 8:  think you're talking about traffic lights. I dunno. It could come up
Speaker 8:  with some other perspective and then forget or not
Speaker 8:  send the command to the APIs or the smart home
Speaker 8:  devices that it's trying to communicate with. And where that breakdown happens.
Speaker 8:  That's where things, And I think a lot of people who have been using the
Speaker 8:  smart home with Alexa for a long time and now use
Speaker 8:  Alexa plus. So like it's ruined my smart home. These things aren't working
Speaker 8:  anymore And I have had to rebuild a few routines
Speaker 8:  because they don't work anymore because the new Alexa doesn't understand
Speaker 8:  them. So yeah, there's, there's a friction there that, that talking to the,
Speaker 8:  to panelist penne This week about it, he said, you know, that is the problem
Speaker 8:  that we are working on now. That is one of the reasons why Alexa plus
Speaker 8:  is in early access because we need more and more people to be experiencing
Speaker 8:  these sort of breakdowns in handoff between the
Speaker 8:  LLMs and the more deterministic models so that we can figure out how to fix
Speaker 8:  that. But he was very sort of saying, well, we're the only ones that
Speaker 8:  are doing this at all right now, so, which
Speaker 8:  is fair enough. We'll see what Google's experience is like now that that's
Speaker 8:  launching. But yeah, that, that is the problem. And this is probably why
Speaker 8:  Apple is still not in the game because you know Siri
Speaker 8:  for all she, he it isn't great does still
Speaker 8:  turn the lights on every time you ask it to. Yeah. So this, that kind of
Speaker 8:  stuff is still being worked out and whether it's going, whether they're gonna
Speaker 8:  be able to find a, a good solution or not, we're just gonna have to wait
Speaker 8:  and see.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That trade between, it does a lot of things kind of
Speaker 5:  well and it does a tiny number of things really reliably
Speaker 5:  is the big challenge with all of this stuff right now. Because the, the ceiling
Speaker 5:  for all of this LLM based stuff is so much higher. There's new things it
Speaker 5:  can do. It works new ways. The floor is so much lower because it will make
Speaker 5:  dumb mistakes all the time that like you can just program Siri
Speaker 5:  with an if then statement that will work most of the time, right? Yes. And
Speaker 5:  it's like you can't do anything else. Siri sucks at everything. That is not
Speaker 5:  a very basic if then statement. Yeah. But it does the if then statements
Speaker 8:  And it doesn't. Right. It does.
Speaker 5:  And that's
Speaker 8:  Something but it doesn't think of talking about something else.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Except for now, like anyway, I'm very mad at Apple reminders right
Speaker 5:  now because sir is so bad. But that's a whole different story.
Speaker 5:  I want to switch gears to talk about Google here a little bit, but the, the
Speaker 5:  last Amazon device we should talk about. There's lots more stuff. There's
Speaker 5:  ring stuff, there's Blink stuff, there's a million new cameras. I don't go
Speaker 5:  read all of Jen's stories about them. There's thousands of them. I do wanna
Speaker 5:  talk about the new Kindle scribe just for a minute because I think Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Oh so pretty.
Speaker 5:  So, okay, so I got, I got a virtual briefing of this. Todd Hazelton on our
Speaker 5:  team went and actually saw the thing before it launched. You saw the thing
Speaker 5:  at the event. I think this might be very exciting. Mm.
Speaker 5:  It's expensive, particularly the new Kindle scribe Color Soft,
Speaker 5:  which is 630 bucks. But you can get a Kindle scribe
Speaker 5:  for 430 bucks. It doesn't have a front light. The real one they want you
Speaker 5:  to buy is I think 4 99. But the the basic
Speaker 5:  new thing is it's thinner, it's lighter, it, it works
Speaker 5:  better in all of the ways. You would hope the second generation would work
Speaker 5:  better, lower latency, faster it in, it integrates with
Speaker 5:  OneDrive and Google Drive. So it'll do some like productivity stuff a lot
Speaker 5:  better. This like, seems like a, a paper
Speaker 5:  notebook competitor in a, in a real useful, interesting way. You've
Speaker 5:  actually like held and touched and seen the thing. Is it, is it,
Speaker 5:  does it look great? Is it great?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I, I mean I've not, I've, I have a Kindle from
Speaker 8:  maybe a decade ago, so I've not been like really
Speaker 8:  the front of technology when it comes to changing my Kindle. And I think
Speaker 8:  a lot of people don't because you know, it is such a great device. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  And you read your book like how much more do you need to do this?
Speaker 5:  You just described the best and worst thing about the Kindle line Yes. Is
Speaker 5:  they can't figure out how to make any money because every bought a really
Speaker 5:  good Kindle 10 years ago and has no need to.
Speaker 8:  But this feels like as a sort of step forward for the device in terms
Speaker 8:  of actually becoming a paper replacement,
Speaker 8:  a notepad replacement. And I think when I was, I mean I was live blogging
Speaker 8:  the event And I, I said actually I've always been a pen and paper girl.
Speaker 8:  I use a physical notepad, but I really like the idea of this.
Speaker 8:  I could really like the fact that it just, and Pan os pane was showing up
Speaker 8:  on screen on stage and he was saying it's like milliseconds of latency,
Speaker 8:  you know, you really won't notice. It's really easy to write. 'cause that's
Speaker 8:  been one of my other problems is I tried to use an iPad with a pen and it
Speaker 8:  just wasn't intuitive. He was kind of cradling this thing. I mean he
Speaker 8:  was, I think this was the thing he was most excited about. Panos
Speaker 5:  Is like famously a long-term believer in handwriting on
Speaker 5:  device, like all the way back to like killed Microsoft devices. Like that
Speaker 5:  that man loves a digital writing experience.
Speaker 8:  Oh yeah. He seemed like this sort of seemed really, really exciting
Speaker 8:  for him. I think he was more excited about these than the shows honestly.
Speaker 8:  But, but yeah, it was, I mean I, my daughter
Speaker 8:  is an artist And I've been desperately trying to find a good
Speaker 8:  sort of tablet for her that's not an iPad because iPads are
Speaker 8:  kind of heavy. I mean they really are for writing. You were used to doing
Speaker 8:  it on a, a a, a nice notepad with a pencil and they're
Speaker 8:  distracting. And what's nice about this, I think, you know, if you can create,
Speaker 8:  if you can create this experience that's just your notes and just your books
Speaker 8:  and just your sketches, But that you can get material in and out
Speaker 8:  of, I mean I, I remember, I'm sure it's better now, but sort of trying
Speaker 8:  to send articles to my Kindle through Instapaper way back when.
Speaker 8:  Oh yes. But this seems like
Speaker 5:  A, it's not better by the way. Oh, okay. Not better. That's
Speaker 8:  Sad to hear. So I, I mean as a, a reading
Speaker 8:  and drawing and somewhat content creation device that isn't a
Speaker 8:  bright screen that isn't distracting. I know there are other EAN
Speaker 8:  tablets out there that are kind of trying to do this as well, but obviously
Speaker 8:  Kindle has that lock-in with your books and Yeah,
Speaker 8:  I, I'm very, I was very impressed with this and very tempted not,
Speaker 8:  maybe not for, well maybe for me, but definitely for my daughter. It's
Speaker 8:  easier to spend $600 on her than on me. So
Speaker 5:  This is one of those things that I think the price to me is the only thing
Speaker 5:  that kills me. Yeah. It's a lot like, it's, it's a lot of money for this
Speaker 5:  specific thing And I think it, it is inching closer
Speaker 5:  to being what I want it to be. Like. I think color's a big deal And I think
Speaker 5:  there are a lot of people who will see this as the big color
Speaker 5:  Kindle and we'll want it for that reason alone. Right. Like as a, if, if
Speaker 5:  you're reading comic books, when the first color soft came out, the main
Speaker 5:  feedback I saw was from people being like this, this looks great, I want
Speaker 5:  a bigger one. Yeah. Well the first feedback was why is the screen yellow?
Speaker 5:  But then they fixed that and, and then the feedback was why isn't this
Speaker 5:  bigger? And I think this is gonna be exciting to a lot of those people.
Speaker 5:  It's just $630. And so I think the, the next phase of this is like,
Speaker 5:  okay, let's take this stuff and bring it down towards regular Kindle prices
Speaker 5:  and we'll be really onto something.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Well and this goes along with the, the shows and the dots and because,
Speaker 8:  you know, everything has got more expensive, but it also has got
Speaker 8:  better. So there's that trade off again. Like we want the more premium
Speaker 8:  experience. Yeah. Right now it's too, it's maybe
Speaker 8:  more or too expensive in some cases, but as we've seen the trend
Speaker 8:  normally will be in two or three years, hopefully some of this technology
Speaker 8:  will get cheaper and, and we'll get the, you know, the first gen of these
Speaker 8:  devices are always gonna be a little, I mean the original color, like
Speaker 8:  Kindle Oasis wasn't that like one of the first big redesigns that was quite
Speaker 8:  expensive and that's now much more affordable.
Speaker 5:  So yeah, it's, it's, Amazon does have a pretty good track record of sort
Speaker 5:  of pulling this stuff down the lineup over time. Yeah. And I will probably
Speaker 5:  been waiting for that one. Real quick, before we take a break,
Speaker 5:  we're gonna talk a lot about Google's smart home strategy for
Speaker 5:  next Tuesday's show. But there was some news This week, Google
Speaker 5:  as it does every once in a while, completely changed its mind about everything,
Speaker 5:  about how its smart home strategy works.
Speaker 5:  Just give me sort of the, the top line news. All I know is I saw a picture
Speaker 5:  of a red speaker that I immediately was like, that is the best looking smart
Speaker 5:  speaker I have ever seen in my entire life. It's very pretty. But inside
Speaker 5:  that speaker, Google seems to have like, kind of changed its whole smart
Speaker 5:  home strategy. What is happening here?
Speaker 8:  Yes. So the, the sort of top line is Google is
Speaker 8:  relaunching, its Google Home under, well it's still called Google
Speaker 8:  Home, but Gemini for home is sort of the overarching
Speaker 8:  theory. Now it's, it's similar to what Alexa Plus is doing for
Speaker 8:  Amazon, but it's Gemini for home is infusing
Speaker 8:  Gemini AI throughout the smart home lineup
Speaker 8:  and to partner products as well. So products developed by other
Speaker 8:  manufacturers for Google Home. So what this is, is that
Speaker 8:  the Google assistant on the smart speakers and smart displays
Speaker 8:  is gonna be replaced by Gemini. That's already sort of happened. Or you can,
Speaker 8:  you can get access to Gemini features, but this is now
Speaker 8:  a complete wholesale shift that's actually gonna be
Speaker 8:  available in an early access program.
Speaker 8:  Another one of those for anyone starting on
Speaker 8:  October 1st, which was Wednesday, which is actually today. But if you're
Speaker 8:  listening to this on Friday time
Speaker 5:  Travel time
Speaker 8:  Travel. So you can sign up for this in your Google
Speaker 8:  Home app. You don't have to be in the public preview program or anything.
Speaker 8:  And you can use Gemini instead of Google Assistant on all of
Speaker 8:  Google Home hardware going all the way back to the original
Speaker 8:  Flower Pot looking one. Oh yeah, in 2016.
Speaker 5:  I still had that thing around here somewhere. You do? Oh you I loved that
Speaker 5:  it, I thought it was great looking.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. See if, see see what it, how it runs on there. It's
Speaker 5:  Still, I think that original Google Home speaker
Speaker 5:  I think was the least speaker looking smart speaker
Speaker 5:  anyone has made And I loved it for that. It just looked like a little like
Speaker 5:  tchotchke on your table. Yeah. In a, in a way that it like, I wish more of
Speaker 5:  these smart speakers
Speaker 8:  And Google's being very good. Google's definitely led the way on the design
Speaker 8:  front for these smart devices. The Nest Mini was,
Speaker 8:  was nice as well. It was small and easy to sort of tuck away and they made
Speaker 8:  it so you could like mount it on the wall, which was always, which was kind
Speaker 8:  of neat. And these new, the new one, so go the Google Home
Speaker 8:  speaker, they're getting rid of the Nest name that's now just
Speaker 8:  for cameras.
Speaker 5:  I hate this. I don't like, we, we don't need to dwell
Speaker 5:  on this for too long, but I, I think Nest is a, a terrific brand
Speaker 5:  and B, a brand that a lot of people know and have known for like the Nest
Speaker 5:  thermostat is so like iconic a thing in the like
Speaker 5:  Annals of Smart home history. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  That
Speaker 5:  It just seems weird, especially to turn it into this branding mush where
Speaker 5:  Nest still exists, but now Google Home exists and Gemini at home exists.
Speaker 5:  Just, it was
Speaker 8:  Nest Pick a name, just call it
Speaker 5:  Nest, what are we doing?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I know. Well so yeah, it's Nest is still on the cameras and obviously
Speaker 8:  on the thermostat, but as I wrote about a couple weeks ago, nest
Speaker 8:  Google is very much got gotten out of the Nest hardware game. Yes.
Speaker 8:  So the speaker, the speakers were originally Google.
Speaker 8:  So Google Home Speaker was the first speaker, then they made them Nest
Speaker 8:  and now they're going back to Google. So
Speaker 5:  They're gonna be Fitbit in six months. Like this is just what Google does.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Drives
Speaker 8:  You crazy. The camera's a nest, the thermostat's nest. But the app,
Speaker 8:  there was also a Nest app. You can still use the Nest app, but now everything's
Speaker 8:  gone. Now everything is in the Google Home app. You can use, you can even
Speaker 8:  set passcodes for your Nest X
Speaker 8:  lock, which I know is something that many of our readers are very keen to
Speaker 8:  be able to do. So this one's for you, you can now do that in the Google Home
Speaker 8:  app. But the other in the Nest as a
Speaker 8:  whole is now very much just sort of a subset because they got rid of the
Speaker 8:  Nest Protect, they got rid of the Nest, secure. Any other, the
Speaker 8:  Nestl, Yale Lock, all that Nest branding has gone, those products have gone
Speaker 8:  because Google is basically saying we're only making the flagship products
Speaker 8:  that make sense for our Gemini Smart Home
Speaker 8:  speakers. Cameras, they haven't mentioned the thermostat, but they did
Speaker 8:  just update that quite recently. Yeah. And then they're moving towards
Speaker 8:  partners. They just announced This week Walmart,
Speaker 8:  the On Brandand has new cameras that work with Google
Speaker 8:  Home. There's, there was a post This week from the
Speaker 8:  developer blog saying, you know, we're opening up all this Gemini
Speaker 8:  intelligence to anyone that wants to partner with Google Home
Speaker 8:  to developed products for the platform. So the outta the
Speaker 8:  hardware game, except for where it works for Gemini and where it works for
Speaker 8:  Gemini. And this is what's the big news This week is that the
Speaker 8:  cameras, the new cameras that they've announced, which is a new outdoor camera,
Speaker 8:  a new indoor camera and a new video doorbell, all wired,
Speaker 8:  all now have 2K sensors. Because the
Speaker 8:  more data and the more fidelity they can pull in, the better they can
Speaker 8:  feed into Gemini for home. And they, Anish
Speaker 8:  Cran, who is the head of Google Home was sort of saying, these are the, these
Speaker 8:  are the eyes for Gemini, this is like the multimodal AI that we need.
Speaker 8:  Google Home has facial recognition feature.
Speaker 8:  So you know, now your home, if you have these cameras, can
Speaker 8:  recognize like who's who's at home and maybe adjust different
Speaker 8:  routines or re you know, make your home fit
Speaker 8:  how you want it based on who's in the home because it can use
Speaker 8:  the information and the data from these cameras also tell you who's
Speaker 8:  at the front door, who's in the backyard, like having this
Speaker 8:  extra data to pull into the Gemini
Speaker 8:  ecosystem to be able to then inform other things in your smart home. This
Speaker 8:  is also what Amazon's doing with Ring and Alexa plus it's all
Speaker 8:  bringing the AI is bringing together all the sources and the data sources
Speaker 8:  of your home sensors, cameras, temperature,
Speaker 8:  anything that that could play into what you want your home to do for you
Speaker 8:  so that your home can potentially become more proactive.
Speaker 8:  So you won't necessarily have to program it. Google is
Speaker 8:  not at that stage yet. They seem a little behind,
Speaker 8:  but they're, what you can see the, the path that they're going on. What's
Speaker 8:  interesting about the new cameras, and actually this is also coming to all
Speaker 8:  the current cameras and even the discontinued ones going all the
Speaker 8:  way back to 2015. So that's nice. I mean, I know yeah, good on
Speaker 8:  Google. We rag on Google for discontinuing products all the time, But that,
Speaker 8:  that they are still supporting this in the cameras that people may still
Speaker 8:  have is a good thing. Yeah. So now you do have to pay a subscription
Speaker 8:  for this, but with Gemini for home, you can type into their new app.
Speaker 8:  So they have a new home app. You can sort of say, when was the last time
Speaker 8:  you saw my cat? And it can pull, pull up any videos of cats
Speaker 8:  or was there a skunk in my driveway? Or what time did my
Speaker 8:  daughter get home? Or you know, you could type that into the new home app
Speaker 8:  and it will pull up footage for you. You can also use the home app to
Speaker 8:  create automations. So you can just type in and say, you know,
Speaker 8:  I want you to make me feel more secure. And it might come up with a suggestion,
Speaker 8:  well, we'll lock your doors every day at 6:00 PM we'll turn the lights on
Speaker 8:  when you know when and when it gets dark, it'll come up with automations
Speaker 8:  for you. So all of this sort of intelligence is using the data
Speaker 8:  from your home and sort of being able to manage things for
Speaker 8:  you. And it as, like I said, it's still kind of early days. So what
Speaker 8:  I'd really like to see is like an automation based on
Speaker 8:  the triggers that that cameras can now do. So like, okay,
Speaker 8:  I saw your cat outside and it was after dark, so I'm gonna send
Speaker 8:  you an alert or I'm gonna flash a light or you know, you know, to be
Speaker 8:  proactive rather than me having to set up. But that's where you can see
Speaker 8:  all of this going. And actually that's what Amazon demoed where
Speaker 8:  it, it demoed an example with using Alexa plus
Speaker 8:  Alexa actually said, oh, I noticed no one has fed the dog
Speaker 8:  today. Would you like me to set a reminder to feed the dog
Speaker 8:  every day at a certain time? And they were able to set up an
Speaker 8:  automation. So whenever the dog, whenever Alexa notices
Speaker 8:  the dog hasn't been fed, it would send an an alert to,
Speaker 8:  to the person who was supposed to feed the dog, obviously, you
Speaker 8:  know, you could also get a smart pet feeder. But the idea here is
Speaker 8:  your home being proactive and both companies, Amazon and Google sort of moving
Speaker 8:  towards that and this new hardware and this new Gemini for home platform
Speaker 8:  is sort of laying the foundations for all of this. I know that was a lot.
Speaker 5:  No, And I think it's, it's telling that a, these companies have, are, are
Speaker 5:  all sort of converging on this same idea of like, what we need is lots and
Speaker 5:  lots and lots of input in order to do this kind of stuff. I also think, by
Speaker 5:  the way, it's very funny that a huge part of the marketing for all of these
Speaker 5:  platforms is you have a pet and you are a terrible pet owner. And
Speaker 5:  Yes. And like Ring is like, we have a, we have a way to use Ring cameras
Speaker 5:  to search for your lost dog because I know you're a terrible person who can't
Speaker 5:  stop losing your dog. It's just all very funny. It's
Speaker 8:  Because no one can complain about pets, like, you know? Right,
Speaker 5:  Right. It's soft subject and everybody is subject. It's, it's like, it's
Speaker 5:  like kids, right? Like I will spend an unlimited amount of money if you can
Speaker 5:  convince me that it will be good for my kids. Do you know what I like? It's,
Speaker 5:  this is how they get you.
Speaker 8:  The other thing I didn't mention, mention that about the new Google Home
Speaker 8:  hardware. So the Google Home speaker has Gemini in it now. Not Google
Speaker 8:  Assistant, but it also has Gemini Live.
Speaker 8:  And this is, so this is, most of the
Speaker 8:  listeners I'm sure are familiar with Gemini live like on your smartphone.
Speaker 8:  Or you can like converse back and forth and it's, you don't have to keep
Speaker 8:  saying the wake word, right?
Speaker 5:  It's Gemini's version of like voice mode that you see in Chat GT or Claude.
Speaker 8:  Exactly. And so you can now do this with the, it'll be on the
Speaker 8:  new Google Home speaker, which is not launching until next spring,
Speaker 8:  but it's also on the Nest hub Max and the Nest audio
Speaker 8:  and the Nest Hub second gen. So you'll be able to use this
Speaker 8:  starting today if you're in, or This week, if you're in early access and
Speaker 8:  you actually wake work, you do a different wake word. You say, Hey gee, let's
Speaker 8:  chat. And you get this little ding ding and you get this new
Speaker 8:  Gemini assistant Gemini live. And you can do that back and forth conversation.
Speaker 8:  But annoyingly Gemini live has no way of taking any
Speaker 8:  actions. So like, it can't do anything in your smart home. It can't like
Speaker 8:  send you recipes to your phone or to the Nest hub. Right now it's
Speaker 8:  just a, a more chatty chat bot. And that's actually
Speaker 8:  something I should mention about all of these. They do talk way too much.
Speaker 5:  They always kind of have, and no one, no one has quite,
Speaker 8:  That is a bit a problem figured this
Speaker 5:  Out yet. And they're also proud of themselves that they can talk in sentences
Speaker 5:  now and they're just like, yeah, give us 11 paragraphs of information. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's like, don't
Speaker 8:  Just shut up and then all this kind of like, I hope that helped. Don't forget
Speaker 8:  to have a nice day. Oh my gosh. Like, no, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 5:  This is the stupidest thing. But ev whenever I'm in my car, in car play,
Speaker 5:  Spotify has a thing. You tap the thing to search with audio while you're
Speaker 5:  in the Spotify app on CarPlay and it pops up and the lights go around
Speaker 5:  signaling that it's listening. But then you have to wait a full beat before
Speaker 5:  Siri then goes, what would you like to play? And then you have to wait again
Speaker 5:  and it dings again and then it's listening and it's like this, what are we,
Speaker 5:  yeah, it's impossible Yeah. To do. It just drives me insane. We're gonna
Speaker 5:  talk more about Google on Tuesday's show because I think
Speaker 5:  the, the strategy there is really interesting And I continue to think
Speaker 5:  Google is the company that has the most pieces already in the right
Speaker 5:  place to do all of the things that it's trying to do. Definitely. I just
Speaker 5:  have no faith in that company's ability to A, execute on them or B, stay
Speaker 5:  interested in them long enough to do them. So we are going to
Speaker 5:  get deep into that on next week's show. So we'll come back to that. Great.
Speaker 5:  For now, we're gonna switch gears and talk about
Speaker 5:  the strangest and most interesting television I have seen in a very long
Speaker 5:  time. But first we're gonna take a
Speaker 8:  Break of ads. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Seriously. We're Yeah, the the everything is ads.
Speaker 5:  It's 2025. We're gonna take a break, we'll be right back. We're gonna talk
Speaker 5:  tally, be right back.
Speaker 5:  have been using this device called Tele, which is basically a free
Speaker 5:  television that they ship to your house and put in your house and an
Speaker 5:  exchange for it being a free television. There's a big bar of
Speaker 5:  ads that runs below your television at all times. Is
Speaker 5:  that a, is that a fair description of what you've been going through?
Speaker 11:  Yes, that's, that's very accurate.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So this has been a fascination both of mine and of the whole
Speaker 5:  VERGE and Vergecast audience for a long time. And actually, let me just play
Speaker 5:  a voicemail. We got on The Vergecast hotline from a listener a couple of
Speaker 5:  weeks ago and then we're gonna get into it.
Speaker 12:  Hey Vergecast, this is Eric Ju calling from Los Angeles. I
Speaker 12:  just listened to your last pod and it really got me wondering what's going
Speaker 12:  on with telly. That company that gave
Speaker 12:  everyone free TVs for unlimited advertisements on their TV
Speaker 12:  or the second screen of their tv, I haven't heard from them in a while.
Speaker 12:  I was wondering if we could check in with people and see what's going on
Speaker 12:  with them. Is it going good? Isn't it a good model? I'm
Speaker 12:  really curious. Thanks.
Speaker 5:  We had the, the CEO of Telly on the show a while ago, and ever
Speaker 5:  since I actually, The Verge has been covering telly for a long time and you
Speaker 5:  got a telly but you, you didn't get one as like a reviewer,
Speaker 5:  you got a telly,
Speaker 11:  Right? Yeah, I just kind of put my name in the hat. I mean, I didn't like
Speaker 11:  contact them or anything and tell them, oh, I'm gonna review this. They
Speaker 11:  just kind of picked me out I guess and sent one to me
Speaker 11:  and yeah.
Speaker 5:  So tell me, I, I'm like, I just wanna start this experience at the very beginning.
Speaker 5:  'cause I think literally everything about Tell is weird and fascinating.
Speaker 5:  Tell like what happens when telly arrives at your house?
Speaker 11:  Yeah, well I think it actually begins before it even gets to your house
Speaker 11:  because when you reserve a tele you have to
Speaker 11:  agree to so many different things.
Speaker 11:  Like it is, I mean, I do kind of give them credit for being very
Speaker 11:  upfront about what they are doing here and that's to
Speaker 11:  collect your data to use for its ads. And
Speaker 11:  like a lot of the questions you'll have to answer is like, how many people
Speaker 11:  are living in your house? Like, are you a parent? Like, do you
Speaker 11:  like to go to the movie theater? Like stuff like that. Oh, interesting.
Speaker 11:  And I filled all of this like giant questionnaire out
Speaker 11:  and
Speaker 11:  I, as I know in my report, the first time the tell arrived it
Speaker 11:  was broken
Speaker 11:  and
Speaker 5:  Like broken, like broken how
Speaker 11:  The whole screen was cracked. And of course Oh great. I didn't realize that
Speaker 11:  until I got out of the box and set it up and turned it on and
Speaker 11:  it was just broken. So I
Speaker 11:  have to at least it was free. Exactly.
Speaker 11:  It would've been more disappointing I think if it was like a Samsung or
Speaker 11:  something. But,
Speaker 5:  So I think, I mean part of what I think is so interesting is like this,
Speaker 5:  that's such a perfect company who has never shipped a
Speaker 5:  television trying to figure out how to ship a television thing because I
Speaker 5:  think like we, I I just looked this up And I, I interviewed Ilia pose
Speaker 5:  in the CEO of Telly almost exactly two years ago on the show. Oh
Speaker 5:  wow. And this was after they had started taking reservations and the thing
Speaker 5:  existed and Telly's whole thing was like, we're
Speaker 5:  just gonna say the quiet part loud, right? Like the, the, the Vizios of the
Speaker 5:  world out there are selling UTVs essentially at
Speaker 5:  cost and they're making all of their money with advertising. And Roku
Speaker 5:  is selling stuff really cheap and making all of its money on advertising
Speaker 5:  and like, this is the business of television now is sneaky advertising.
Speaker 5:  And he's just like, well what if I just took that all the way to
Speaker 5:  its logical conclusion And I will ship you a television for free and it's
Speaker 5:  gonna be a big beautiful television that is gonna have another screen
Speaker 5:  underneath it that just always shows you ads. And the ads are gonna be how
Speaker 5:  we make money by putting a billboard inside of your house. That's how we're
Speaker 5:  gonna make money. And then you can just sort of see them in the intervening
Speaker 5:  two and a half years be like, oh my God, we have to build and ship a television.
Speaker 11:  And,
Speaker 5:  And I just think that to me is like the, the perfect microcosm of this whole
Speaker 5:  thing. And we've heard from so many people who are furious about the, the
Speaker 5:  amount of time it has taken for their own tellie to show up. And
Speaker 5:  it's just like the, the things that they're doing where they're like, well,
Speaker 5:  it's really easy to make a tv, we'll just ship it to you for free and everything
Speaker 5:  will be fine. Like, nope, it's not nearly as simple as you make it
Speaker 5:  sound. But you did eventually get a working television
Speaker 5:  to your house.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I have to say they were like pretty responsive with that. Like they,
Speaker 11:  they sent a new TV like pretty quickly After that and it came
Speaker 11:  through FedEx and once a, like we finally got it
Speaker 11:  set up.
Speaker 11:  It's, it's just funny 'cause it, like, it shows you like a whole introduction
Speaker 11:  like how telly's the future of TV and like all this
Speaker 11:  stuff. And then you just see the secondary display light up
Speaker 11:  and it's just, it's pretty wild to see. Is it very
Speaker 11:  distracting? It is. Like, can you watch a show and like, does
Speaker 11:  it go away when you watch a show? No. Oh. I mean it's on
Speaker 11:  all the time. You cannot turn it off and you can't cover it up because
Speaker 11:  tele has it in their terms of service. You cannot cover the second screen.
Speaker 5:  So wait, okay. Like, just describe what this thing looks like in your living
Speaker 5:  room. Like, you, you, you get the whole thing set up and I'm just imagining
Speaker 5:  like a, a TV on top and like a,
Speaker 5:  I don't know, an iPad on the bottom. Like what, what, what does this actually
Speaker 5:  look like when you put the thing in in place?
Speaker 11:  Yeah, so the TV itself, it's a 55 inch screen and
Speaker 11:  beneath it, it's a 10 inch display that runs the entire
Speaker 11:  length of the screen. Okay. So it's just like an elongated, kinda like a
Speaker 11:  bar,
Speaker 5:  But it's 10 inches tall. That's a pretty tall Yeah.
Speaker 11:  Screen. You
Speaker 8:  Have to wall mount it then?
Speaker 11:  No, I just, I put it on a stand. I'm not sure. You probably could
Speaker 11:  well mount it, but this thing is heavy. Like it is very heavy. It is
Speaker 11:  very tall and it's very like awkward to
Speaker 11:  put on your stand. And does it
Speaker 8:  Kind of do the bottom bit? Like is it connect fully connected or is it
Speaker 8:  kinda like on a hinge?
Speaker 11:  It's fully connected and there's a,
Speaker 8:  It's just like part of the entire screen. So what's the total size
Speaker 11:  That's, I actually am not sure about how tall it is,
Speaker 11:  but I know there's a soundbar like connecting the top
Speaker 11:  screen to the bottom and there's like a little webcam in there too.
Speaker 11:  So
Speaker 8:  It's like watching you,
Speaker 11:  The it has a privacy shutter. Okay. And it only opens,
Speaker 11:  I
Speaker 8:  Mean this is like Amazon's dream, right? Let's
Speaker 5:  All be honest with each other. It's watching you. And, and again, this is
Speaker 5:  like the, the thing I love about this so much is it is, it is so
Speaker 5:  upfront straightforward about what it is doing. It's like, yeah, we're watching
Speaker 5:  you.
Speaker 8:  People will do it like yeah, for free.
Speaker 5:  We'll throw you in jail if you cover up the advertising
Speaker 5:  screen. But yeah, I'm just looking at this picture that you took of it, Emma.
Speaker 5:  And the only way I can think to describe it is like, it it, imagine
Speaker 5:  if you took like a, like a just a row of laptop
Speaker 5:  screens and, and sort of put them on your table and then mount it your TV
Speaker 5:  above it is like the size wise, the only way that this is starting to
Speaker 5:  make sense to me 'cause it's this, it's a big bottom thing and then it has
Speaker 5:  a soundbar in the middle and then the 55 inch screen and then the little
Speaker 5:  camera, it just looks like it's gonna tip over at all times. Like this,
Speaker 5:  this whole thing is like top heavy in a way that I'm finding really kind
Speaker 5:  of unnerving to look at.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. It's, I think it's a little bit more stable than it looks, but it
Speaker 11:  is just very unwieldy.
Speaker 8:  Okay. The design was not thought through. It sounds like
Speaker 8:  it's not interior design ready. It's not a frame. Yeah,
Speaker 11:  No, I mean it's just, it's very tall. Like that's what I have to say. I've
Speaker 11:  never seen a tall TV like this before.
Speaker 5:  So the viewing experience, I would think best case scenario is
Speaker 5:  it would kind of feel like watching every show through
Speaker 5:  the like cable news Chiron where like you're, you're watching what you're
Speaker 5:  watching, but there's like something sort of happening on the bottom. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And we're all like a little bit used to that. It's a little annoying, but
Speaker 5:  you're, we're a little bit used to it
Speaker 5:  over time. You used the thing for months. Did you eventually train yourself
Speaker 5:  to stop looking at the bottom screen? Can you, can you successfully ignore
Speaker 5:  it? Like that would be the goal, right? It's like you kind of stop noticing
Speaker 5:  it's there and you just watch the TV and everybody wins. Did you ever get
Speaker 5:  to that point?
Speaker 11:  Not really. Oh no, it's just, it's like very distracting because
Speaker 11:  there's moving elements in the bottom screen, so your eyes are
Speaker 11:  just always drawn to, like, there's a news ticker,
Speaker 11:  there's some of the ads that it shows are video ads and
Speaker 11:  they don't have sound, but they have subtitles that you can barely
Speaker 11:  read. But, And I, they have like
Speaker 11:  rotating news stories, like you can customize like what the
Speaker 11:  widgets, the bottom bar shows, but you can't, you can't like fully
Speaker 11:  get rid of that screen or like, I tried lowering the
Speaker 11:  brightness even and it just, it didn't even do anything. I feel like.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So it looks like basically the, the left two thirds
Speaker 5:  is like widgets And I think you had it set up that it's like baseball scores
Speaker 5:  and weather and other news information.
Speaker 8:  So you can customize it a little bit there.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, you can, you can like kind of choose what you want in there or
Speaker 11:  like, and stuff like that. But,
Speaker 5:  And that I think was telly's big like operating system plan, if I'm remembering
Speaker 5:  this correctly. They had ideas about like, we're gonna have a whole app story.
Speaker 5:  You're gonna be able to do all kinds of stuff down there. It's gonna be super
Speaker 5:  cool and exciting and like you can, you can sort of, if you squint at it,
Speaker 5:  see why that might be something.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. But how much would you pay for a TV like this? Like how much are you
Speaker 8:  really saving to give up your experience watching tv?
Speaker 8:  I mean, yeah,
Speaker 11:  That's like the main question because it's,
Speaker 11:  I mean the TV itself, it's a, the display is nice And I mean it's
Speaker 11:  decent and the soundbar's nice. It's just,
Speaker 11:  is it worth your privacy and your sanity basically?
Speaker 11:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  I mean, in TVs you could buy a TV for a nice TV for
Speaker 8:  not very much money these days.
Speaker 5:  I just, I just did one single Google search, so take this for
Speaker 5:  whatever it's worth. But I, I can, I can very quickly find a a
Speaker 5:  55 inch reason, like very well reviewed
Speaker 5:  TCL TV for 280 bucks. Yeah. I
Speaker 8:  Just, we just bought for our porch a 65 inch
Speaker 8:  TCL Google tv, I think it was
Speaker 8:  350 and we got it from wow. Costco. So it's like that,
Speaker 8:  I mean, how much better is something like this? How big is this?
Speaker 11:  How big is the It's a 55 inch. Okay.
Speaker 8:  So yeah.
Speaker 11:  Display.
Speaker 8:  So this, but, but,
Speaker 5:  But if I were to tell you that you can either have a TV for
Speaker 5:  $300 or you can have a TV for $0 and they're gonna make
Speaker 5:  the same amount of money on you either way. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  People love free. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But wait, Emma, can I say the single most devious thing that I think Tely
Speaker 5:  is doing here? And the thing that I kept laughing at reading your story is
Speaker 5:  that not only is it against the terms of service to cover up the advertising
Speaker 5:  stuff, they've actually moved so much of the interface down to the
Speaker 5:  bottom screen that you have to look at it all the time just to use
Speaker 5:  the television. Yeah. Which to me seems it's somewhere between
Speaker 5:  like really deeply gross and totally genius. Yeah. And I think
Speaker 5:  they're like, they know that you can't cover the TV and they have
Speaker 5:  made damn sure that you can't cover that bottom screen.
Speaker 8:  All of that effort. I mean yeah, everything they effort they've put into
Speaker 8:  making sure you see those ads. It is, it's like, it's like
Speaker 8:  evil genius levels here.
Speaker 11:  It truly is like you can't, you have to go to that screen to like
Speaker 11:  switch in between like your inputs and
Speaker 11:  to navigate between other apps as well and you really can't cover
Speaker 11:  it up. And I, they definitely did think about that.
Speaker 5:  It's really smart. So as other than watching TV like you, you know, you
Speaker 5:  mentioned you tried it as a, as a way to make Zoom calls. 'cause I think
Speaker 5:  again, like the thing I found fascinating about Telly's whole
Speaker 5:  idea other than the, like we're just doing the quiet
Speaker 5:  part loud piece of it is like, Jan, I think you And I have talked about before
Speaker 5:  and agree on, is that there is huge potential for the TV as like the
Speaker 5:  central computer in your house. Yes. And there's lots of interesting smart
Speaker 5:  home stuff you can do. I think I spent a long time during the
Speaker 5:  pandemic, like doing Zoom calls from a Facebook portal camera that I put
Speaker 5:  on top of my tv and it was awesome. Yeah. And so there's like, I think tele
Speaker 5:  has a bunch of those ideas. Did you get to test any of that
Speaker 5:  stuff? Is does any of that stuff even exist? Like what, what was good and
Speaker 5:  what was bad outside of just the TV watching experience?
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I tried doing Zoom and
Speaker 11:  I mean it, it worked for a little bit,
Speaker 11:  but for some reason,
Speaker 11:  oh, the microphone on the telly was not picking
Speaker 11:  up my voice. Like at first it was, it was worked for
Speaker 11:  like two seconds and then it just like cut off And I tried it again and
Speaker 11:  it like, like another day and it just like totally didn't work. And
Speaker 11:  I'm not sure what happened there, but
Speaker 11:  I have to say like the navigating YouTube
Speaker 8:  Hardware is hard. Kelly, did you find this out?
Speaker 11:  But I mean, if you could get it working, it was kind of, it would be kind
Speaker 11:  of cool and you could have like little watch parties. Like, like you could
Speaker 11:  have your friends like on the bottom display. Like you could see them
Speaker 11:  while you like watch a show together. I mean, they don't Oh, that's
Speaker 8:  Fun.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. Like they don't have to have a tele either. Like they could just go
Speaker 11:  on Zoom. Like if I could actually get like the mic working, like that would
Speaker 11:  be kind of cool.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Th this is, this is the thing Tele keeps saying things that you're
Speaker 5:  like, oh, that seems like a good idea. And then they're like, but the device
Speaker 5:  is free. And you're like, oh, I bet it's gonna be bad. Yeah. You also tried
Speaker 5:  an app that I believe is called Gofi.
Speaker 11:  Oh yeah, yeah. The fitness app. Tell me about
Speaker 8:  Go.
Speaker 11:  So basically it's almost like the Xbox Connect, like
Speaker 11:  it walks you through various like workouts and it uses like the
Speaker 11:  camera to I guess look at what you're doing and like
Speaker 11:  judge if you're doing it right. But I mean, I didn't, I thought
Speaker 11:  it was kind of cool 'cause I used to like used to connect so much
Speaker 11:  when I was like a long time ago when that was a thing and
Speaker 11:  I, yeah, it was just, it's just interesting. Like I thought that was kind
Speaker 11:  of a cool idea that they had.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, there's a lot of this happening in TVs, like the Samsung TVs and also
Speaker 8:  the new fire TVs. They have millimeter wave sensors to kind of see
Speaker 8:  like your check your form and stuff, but, or you can stick a little
Speaker 8:  camera there as well. They don't have them built in for obvious reasons.
Speaker 8:  But yeah, I mean the tv, the giant screen in your living room is kinda like
Speaker 8:  the obvious place for so much of what we're seeing with like the smart home
Speaker 8:  and like home wellness, fitness, there's so much you can do there. I mean
Speaker 8:  Apple TV fitness, obvious, I mean I use the fitness program with
Speaker 8:  my Apple TV all the time, you know, watch the guys
Speaker 8:  rowing in the studio and row along with them. All that kind of
Speaker 8:  interactive stuff is great. And it seems like if tele could start to
Speaker 8:  add a bit more value like that,
Speaker 8:  those types of features, you could kind of see perhaps
Speaker 8:  the point of this. But I'm still, I'm still far behind, even though I don't
Speaker 8:  mind Amazon's ads on my Echo show device. It's
Speaker 5:  Emma
Speaker 8:  Is too much. This is,
Speaker 5:  This is the big thing I've been thinking about this whole time is a question
Speaker 5:  I asked Ilia two years ago is you have all these big ideas about what a
Speaker 5:  TV could be. You have all these interesting features you wanna add, you have
Speaker 5:  all this stuff you could do. What if instead of selling me a free tv, you
Speaker 5:  sold me a really expensive TV
Speaker 8:  That did everything
Speaker 5:  Right and you, you made this stuff really good and it, it all worked and
Speaker 5:  you actually tried to sort of proactively make the case that this thing should
Speaker 5:  be the center of your home in this like meaningful technological way. And
Speaker 5:  his answer to me was essentially I could do that and it would be great and
Speaker 5:  absolutely nobody would buy it because oh, the, the price race of televisions
Speaker 5:  has gone all the way down to the bottom such that if I tried to sell you
Speaker 5:  the best TV you've ever seen in your entire life and it did everything perfectly,
Speaker 5:  no one would buy it anyway. But I'm curious, you've now used the thing and
Speaker 5:  lived with it for a while. Like, is is there a version of this
Speaker 5:  idea that is compelling to you?
Speaker 11:  I think it would be kind of, it is an interesting concept
Speaker 11:  And I think like in the future,
Speaker 11:  I know like even streaming services are free now. I just, I
Speaker 11:  think, I think like they're relying on being free so much
Speaker 11:  that it's almost like taking away from the tv. Like you were,
Speaker 11:  like you were just saying, I mean I, I do wonder
Speaker 11:  how it would be if they did sell it like for a price tag.
Speaker 11:  I mean it's just, I don't know. Like, I just don't
Speaker 11:  know if like, I don't know about the ads. Like I think if they got rid of
Speaker 11:  the ads and maybe made it like a really innovative tv,
Speaker 11:  like kept the secondary display, but maybe
Speaker 11:  like did have cool apps on there, like allowed you to do watch parties and
Speaker 11:  stuff like that. Maybe that would be viable.
Speaker 11:  I think
Speaker 8:  We just all have to come to terms with that this is probably the future and
Speaker 8:  that we are all gonna have mini billboards all over our homes. It's gonna
Speaker 8:  be our fridges, it's gonna be on our smartest place. Yep. It's gonna be hanging
Speaker 8:  under our TVs. It is like, the home has
Speaker 8:  been the sacred space for advertising, right? It's not been in our
Speaker 8:  homes. It's everywhere else you go. It's in your email, it's on your phone,
Speaker 8:  it's wherever you walk around the world. There are ads, but they've not
Speaker 8:  been in our homes. But it does seem inevitable.
Speaker 8:  It's like they're coming and obviously in this instance telly, you are
Speaker 8:  inviting them in, in Amazon's instances with the shows they added them
Speaker 8:  after the fact. And same thing's happening with the Samsung fridge. I know
Speaker 8:  you guys talked about that on the show a while back. I haven't seen them
Speaker 8:  on mine yet. I'm keeping an eye out. But yeah, that it's like, that
Speaker 8:  encroaching on the sacred space is just happening more and more and
Speaker 8:  more and it needs to stop and we yeah. We need one safe space.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And I think like there's already so much advertising on your tv, right? Like
Speaker 5:  I'm on record is saying I have absolutely no problem with the pause ads
Speaker 5:  that everybody has on streaming services now. I actually think that is like
Speaker 5:  a terrifically good idea And I hope they all make so much money on it that
Speaker 5:  they never have to do anything else. Like if I'm pausing my show, I'm not
Speaker 5:  watching, I don't care what's on the screen. Right. It's, it's the same way
Speaker 5:  I feel about the, the Kindle ads. Like we were just talking about, like,
Speaker 5:  I'm not doing anything here. Sure. Show me an ad. But I think like
Speaker 5:  Emma, it seems like the, the real bummer of your experience so much was that
Speaker 5:  not only are the ads there, they are perpetually fighting the thing that
Speaker 5:  you're actually trying to do on your tv. That so it's not Yeah, it's not,
Speaker 5:  it's not even interruptive. It's, it's actively making the
Speaker 5:  experience worse.
Speaker 11:  Mm. Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 5:  And that's hard to get over.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I think so. Are you
Speaker 8:  Sending it back?
Speaker 11:  I am going to soon. I think,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, because this is not, this is actually a really an unusually good question
Speaker 5:  to ask in this context because like mostly we're like product
Speaker 5:  reviewers who use these things and then send them back to companies anyway.
Speaker 5:  'cause yes, for ethical reasons, we don't, we don't keep any of the stuff
Speaker 5:  that we review a I don't know if that applies here 'cause the TV's
Speaker 5:  free in the first place, but B you just got one. So if you just wanted this
Speaker 5:  to be your tv, it could be your tv. Yeah. Is this gonna be your
Speaker 5:  tv?
Speaker 11:  No,
Speaker 11:  like I, I have a, my lg I'm very,
Speaker 11:  I'm very happy with
Speaker 5:  What was the, what was the breaking point for you that you were like, I just,
Speaker 5:  this is not an experience I can do anymore?
Speaker 11:  It was almost like, not even the ads, it was just the interface
Speaker 11:  itself because it kind of takes a long time to boot up.
Speaker 11:  God, it
Speaker 8:  Just gets worse.
Speaker 11:  Your subject to like an AI news
Speaker 11:  segment when you turn on the TV and Wait
Speaker 5:  What? Hold on,
Speaker 11:  Hold on.
Speaker 8:  How
Speaker 5:  So
Speaker 8:  There's an ad before you get to actually see the tv? Yes. Oh
Speaker 5:  My. Okay. This is not a thing I even thought I needed to ask. Okay. I need,
Speaker 5:  I have a new question for you, Emma. You walk into the room, you sit down,
Speaker 5:  you pick up the remote, what happens?
Speaker 11:  Okay, so it, like, it'll display
Speaker 11:  telly on the TV while it like boots up. Okay. And then once that
Speaker 11:  happens, the telly today segment comes on and
Speaker 11:  that uses an AI likeness of an actress
Speaker 11:  who then details all these news stories. Like, I
Speaker 11:  did not know she was ai at first. I was like, 'cause then when I started
Speaker 11:  using the TV I was like, why is she wearing the same outfit every day
Speaker 11:  and with the same hair? I was like, this is not women
Speaker 8:  Would really pick up on that. She's
Speaker 5:  So busy. How is she doing this every
Speaker 11:  Day? I, I was just like, this isn't right. Like,
Speaker 5:  Okay, how, how long is this news broadcast?
Speaker 11:  It's not like I like listen to the whole thing on like
Speaker 11:  the whole thing through. 'cause then it just like loops. I'm not sure how
Speaker 11:  long it is, but it was not that long. Like it'll end.
Speaker 11:  And the worst part is though, is that when you turn off the TV and turn
Speaker 11:  it back on, it just like resets. So you can't like pick off,
Speaker 11:  pick up where you left off on the new segment. It just like starts at the
Speaker 11:  beginning again. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  No, I'm immediately out like yeah, literally just that I'm like
Speaker 5:  back in the box. You didn't
Speaker 8:  Out, you didn't give a score.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. Okay,
Speaker 8:  Come on. What's the score? What's
Speaker 11:  The review score?
Speaker 8:  I mean,
Speaker 11:  If I had to pick a number, I mean like maybe like a
Speaker 11:  a four. I'm not, I'm not a reviewer or something. I'm like,
Speaker 8:  I know. I don't know. Based on this, I I'm thinking a solid two.
Speaker 11:  Okay. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  So,
Speaker 5:  But it's free.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, exactly. I mean, but AI
Speaker 8:  And ads.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. And then in between the new segment you also get more ads. Oh my god.
Speaker 11:  On your main display. Okay.
Speaker 5:  So wait, I'm now so hung up on the startup experience here. I'm really sorry.
Speaker 5:  So so you turn it on the, the the news thing
Speaker 5:  starts playing the, the AI woman tells you what I
Speaker 5:  guess whatever news stories tell he thinks are interesting that day. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Like what is it? Was it
Speaker 11:  What's it's it's mainly like celebrity like news or like
Speaker 11:  viral videos. Like
Speaker 5:  I'm just imagining like the a team at telly trying to like program the daily
Speaker 5:  every day to like make for, but anyway, okay, so you go through that. Can
Speaker 5:  you, can you just immediately like home button out of that and
Speaker 5:  then go to your apps?
Speaker 11:  Yeah, you can like, you can just click your, your
Speaker 11:  input 'cause Okay. It operates like you can't even, it doesn't even have
Speaker 11:  built in streaming apps. Like you, it comes with a a Google
Speaker 11:  dongle.
Speaker 5:  Oh, right.
Speaker 8:  Like a Chromecast.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I think so. Google
Speaker 8:  TV thing.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. It's like the little Google TV dongle. And
Speaker 5:  I forgot that it was that they haven't even, yeah. And I think the plan was
Speaker 5:  not to be like that forever, but to like offload
Speaker 5:  Again, this is an advertising company, right? That's, it's important to keep
Speaker 5:  remembering that this is an advertising company. Okay. But so, but you're
Speaker 5:  gonna get like a jump scare essentially every time you turn on your tv because
Speaker 5:  there's just gonna be an AI woman yelling news at you every time you turn
Speaker 5:  on, which is kind of alarming when first turn on the tv.
Speaker 11:  It's a little, it's a little unsettling. 'cause she's always like, hello,
Speaker 11:  hello friends. Like we're gonna, and then like she goes
Speaker 11:  into the thing and it's, I don't know. And there's, there's another
Speaker 11:  AI person that shows up. I noticed too in there edge.
Speaker 11:  It's just, I it's just a bizarre experience.
Speaker 8:  It's a dystopian nightmare. Yes.
Speaker 11:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That is, that is tough.
Speaker 8:  But you brought into your home for free though, so there's the bonus. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  You didn't spend any money on this.
Speaker 5:  I do think this is a fascinating test And I know we, we should, we should
Speaker 5:  switch gears and, and get to the lightning round. But I I do know there are
Speaker 5:  a lot of VERGE readers and Vergecast listeners who signed up to get one of
Speaker 5:  these things and have them in your house. And I think this is maybe the most
Speaker 5:  straightforward test we've ever had of what people are willing to put
Speaker 5:  up with for free stuff. Yeah. And I I mean that like,
Speaker 5:  like everybody's price tolerance is different. There is a whole spectrum
Speaker 5:  of stuff we are willing to put up with for free, right? Like my Gmail got
Speaker 5:  more and more ads all the time And I keep using Gmail. Like the, everybody
Speaker 5:  has been testing this theory for years and years and years and years. And
Speaker 5:  I think this is the most extreme version of it we've ever encountered. Like
Speaker 5:  what if all of this was blaring in your face at all times, but you
Speaker 5:  got to save $300 on your tv. And I think I, I want to hear from everyone
Speaker 5:  who has one of these in your house. Call the hotline, it's six gigs, version
Speaker 5:  one, one, send us an email Vergecast to The Verge dot com. I
Speaker 5:  genuinely no judgment on any direction, but I want to know if you kept your
Speaker 5:  tell, And I want to know whether it has proven to be worth it for you or
Speaker 5:  not. Because I think there's a lot of this stuff that Emma sounds like just
Speaker 5:  sort of first gen problems that it's like, I suspect the next webcam
Speaker 5:  would be better. I suspect some of the apps would get better if this thing
Speaker 5:  becomes popular. People will start to like there if there is
Speaker 5:  a, there, there with this. I actually think V two might be really
Speaker 5:  fascinating. I also think it's possible that enough people are gonna have
Speaker 5:  the experience you did of just like, this becomes untenable. Because the
Speaker 5:  longer I sit here and watch it, the more I hate it that the whole
Speaker 5:  thesis behind this device is just not going to work
Speaker 8:  Well and this has to be in your main viewing
Speaker 8:  area, right? I think I read that in your piece. Yeah. You can't like put
Speaker 8:  this in the guest room or something as your extra tv. This has Yeah,
Speaker 11:  You're not supposed to.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I was gonna say, how do they know that?
Speaker 11:  Yeah. Well that's another thing. Like you're supposed to keep it connected.
Speaker 11:  The internet plugged at all times, but at one point.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Has anyone from telly like shown up at your house to make sure I'm
Speaker 5:  imagining just like a, like a random inspection kind of situation.
Speaker 11:  I was actually kind of scared because like, I left it unplugged for like
Speaker 11:  three weeks. I was like on vacation and nothing happened. So
Speaker 11:  I was a little bit nervous about that
Speaker 5:  Though. You come home, you're like, I've been robbed, but only for one specifically.
Speaker 5:  All right, I wanna hear from everybody. Emma, are you, will you stick around
Speaker 5:  and do some lightning round with us? Yeah. All right. Good. All right. We
Speaker 5:  are gonna come back and do a lightning round. Emma's going to ship her tele
Speaker 5:  back and we'll be right back.
Speaker 11:  I mean, they're not like realistic human faces. They're like kind of cartoony
Speaker 11:  and it's just bizarre to see
Speaker 11:  like, you, you click on 'em and they're like, hello Emma, how may
Speaker 11:  I help you today? And they're like, whole mouth moves and
Speaker 11:  it's just kind of creepy to be honest. And I think I'd rather have
Speaker 11:  the little copilot bean thing that they used to have or
Speaker 11:  that they were trying before. Like I'd rather have that talk
Speaker 11:  at me. I think
Speaker 5:  Jen's out on The Bean. No,
Speaker 8:  The idea of giving AI a face is definitely something we're seeing ev all
Speaker 8:  the tech companies try and sort of tackle with now. I mean the, the rumor
Speaker 8:  wasn't the rumor here that the new Apple smart display
Speaker 8:  is gonna have like a clippy, like, not like bean, but what's the, the
Speaker 8:  finder like face. So like, because I think one of the keys
Speaker 8:  here is some expression does help with the communication,
Speaker 8:  but does it need to be human or can it just be, you know, some
Speaker 8:  kind of of like smile, like on the Echoes devices you're talking
Speaker 8:  about there, it's like little smile now pops up to sort of show some
Speaker 8:  interaction. So you kind of need some feedback, but does it need to be,
Speaker 8:  and yeah, you're right, these are not, these are kind of creepy looking
Speaker 8:  characters. Can you stylize them at all? Do
Speaker 8:  you know? Or does it you just choose one of them? Yeah. Like can you customize
Speaker 8:  your copilot creature? I
Speaker 11:  Think you can, you have to just choose one of them.
Speaker 8:  Okay.
Speaker 11:  I can see them in the future, like making, letting you customize them. But
Speaker 11:  for now it's just kind of like, here you go. Like just pick. And
Speaker 8:  Where does it come? Like I have not used a Windows computer in a very long
Speaker 8:  time. So does it like just middle of the screen or is it in the corner or
Speaker 8:  where, where do they appear? I
Speaker 11:  Just put it like on a, it's on like the browser.
Speaker 11:  Like I just tried it on the browser and it just is like in the middle of
Speaker 11:  your browser, like a big face that's just like talking to you
Speaker 11:  and you and you talk back aloud to it and it's just like, it's
Speaker 11:  just kind of bizarre. Like I can see that what they're trying to get at.
Speaker 11:  But like I, I'm not sure if AI really needs a human face.
Speaker 5:  It is, it is one of those things that I I think you're totally right, Emma,
Speaker 5:  that you can like absolutely a hundred percent imagine the series of
Speaker 5:  decisions that led to the launch of, I think it's called portraits.
Speaker 5:  And every single one of those decisions was the wrong one.
Speaker 5:  And it's just like, it's you because it's like, I think that most people's
Speaker 5:  experiences, you, you load up something like the chat GBT voice mode and
Speaker 5:  it has this sort of pulsing thing that's that that gives you this idea that
Speaker 5:  it's listening and you want something that seems active, right? So
Speaker 5:  it doesn't just feel like you're shouting at a static screen, which feels
Speaker 5:  bad. And so figuring out what those animations
Speaker 5:  should be and how they should work and what kind of character it should be,
Speaker 5:  I actually think is a really interesting exploration. And I know all these
Speaker 5:  companies are doing that on terms of like what is the, the tone of voice
Speaker 5:  that these things should have and what is the character of them and how should
Speaker 5:  they talk and should they use words like suss, like all these different things
Speaker 5:  I think are, are super interesting and valuable. And I think if you land
Speaker 5:  on like polar express level animated people, you have gone
Speaker 5:  wrong.
Speaker 8:  It's just,
Speaker 5:  I I agree that we should a, in principle, we should not be
Speaker 5:  training people to think of these things as humans. I understand why the
Speaker 5:  companies want you to do that. And I think it is bad and they should stop.
Speaker 5:  I also think like the idea that
Speaker 5:  maybe it should seem like some cool weird alien bean creature
Speaker 5:  is like maybe closer and right. And there's all kinds of
Speaker 5:  interesting examples in science fiction of these like weird objects. Like
Speaker 5:  I was just watching E Leo, the Pixar movie that just came out that nobody
Speaker 5:  saw delightful movie by the way. Highly recommend it. And there's this really
Speaker 5:  cute little like blobby alien that just like follows him around through most
Speaker 5:  of the movie. And I was like, that's what I want my aa to be like, forget
Speaker 5:  the rest of this. Just gimme a little jellyfish looking alien that talks
Speaker 5:  to me in every language known to man. And I, and I'm in
Speaker 8:  The floating around part would be great too. Oh yeah.
Speaker 5:  Sort of just like kick it up here next to you. It just hangs out. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  It's it's
Speaker 5:  The dream. Yeah. But copilot portraits is, is not it.
Speaker 5:  That's that's all I know for sure. While we're on the subject of
Speaker 5:  slightly creepy ai, my first lightning round thing is this new
Speaker 5:  SOA app that OpenAI put out This week and this slightly
Speaker 11:  Creepy,
Speaker 5:  It's fair. We're gonna talk more about SOA
Speaker 5:  over time because it's still the, it's in an invite only app that
Speaker 5:  most people have not had access to. But I think the idea is essentially
Speaker 5:  it's TikTok, but everything is AI generated is what it's gonna be. This is
Speaker 5:  like the, the vibes app that meta put out, which is essentially the same
Speaker 5:  thing. It's just like, what if Facebook was all ai, which AI would point
Speaker 5:  out, it's just what Facebook is now. But also
Speaker 5:  the, this question of like, will you as a person want to spend your days
Speaker 5:  scrolling through a bunch of AI generated content is the big question that
Speaker 5:  these companies are trying to answer right now. But the, the thing that
Speaker 5:  happened This week, two things that I think are really interesting, one is
Speaker 5:  SOA two, the, the model that powers all of it appears to be
Speaker 5:  so good, it's going to be terrifying, like in, in some really big and
Speaker 5:  important ways. And I think we've been burned by how good the demo videos
Speaker 5:  are before. So I, I am withholding a lot of judgment
Speaker 5:  until we actually see what this stuff looks like in real life.
Speaker 5:  But like the, the videos that we've seen are nuts.
Speaker 5:  Like truly I think, I don't know how you guys feel, but I'm like, I'm a relatively
Speaker 5:  sophisticated viewer of both real and
Speaker 5:  artificial stuff And I had a really hard time distinguishing what was in
Speaker 5:  was not AI from these things. And like people talking
Speaker 5:  and recognizable people in these videos. Which goes to the
Speaker 5:  other thing I think is really interesting, which is this idea that is inside
Speaker 5:  of the SOS app called cameos, which is basically the,
Speaker 5:  the idea is that you as a person upload a video that you take
Speaker 5:  on your phone or whatever. You upload a video to the app with your face
Speaker 5:  in it. And what that then does is give everyone else on the
Speaker 5:  app permission to use your face in generated
Speaker 5:  videos. And, and there's a really interesting like permission structure in
Speaker 5:  that, which is like, it can't do anything until I add myself
Speaker 5:  to the corpus of data. But once I do, I become fair
Speaker 5:  game in the model with which to, you know, do any kind of deep fake you want.
Speaker 5:  I just think that's a really interesting way to think about this kind of
Speaker 5:  permission that is messy and problematic in a whole bunch of ways, but is
Speaker 5:  apparently what they're headed for. But it does feel like I, I have been
Speaker 5:  reluctant to fe to say and feel like we are heading towards some, like
Speaker 5:  truth is unknowable and everything is a disaster, but like looking at these
Speaker 5:  Sora videos, it was unnerving. I don't know, did either of you
Speaker 5:  experience that looking at this stuff?
Speaker 11:  Yeah, I did. See, I don't know, I think, I don't know if it was Sam
Speaker 11:  Altman or somebody else, they posted like a video of like an AI
Speaker 11:  generated gymnastics routine or like a clip from that. And
Speaker 11:  like AI has notoriously like had trouble generating this 'cause
Speaker 11:  it shows like gymnast with like three arms or something. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  They'll do like one normal flip and then they like do like a weird fly off
Speaker 5:  of the map. Yeah.
Speaker 11:  But it seems like, so like I didn't, it looked like a real
Speaker 11:  clip, like this one looked legit and it was kind of
Speaker 11:  unsettling and just
Speaker 11:  not great.
Speaker 8:  I think one of the, I mean it's terrifying that all of this is getting
Speaker 8:  so real, but one of the, the kind of the flip side that makes it even
Speaker 8:  more terrifying to me is that when the fake
Speaker 8:  stuff gets so real, it means that no one believes the real stuff either.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. It's like the fake news dichotomy that we've ended up in.
Speaker 8:  It's like, you know, you've got to trust your sources, which is always something
Speaker 8:  you've, you've, you know, reliable sources. But with this, it's like
Speaker 8:  if you don't believe, if you can't believe anything anymore
Speaker 8:  and that just puts you in like an existential crisis. Like my daughter's
Speaker 8:  14 and she spends a fair amount of on time on TikTok and she
Speaker 8:  can tell right away when something's ai. It's like, it's now like a new skill
Speaker 8:  that our youth are learning. Totally. Which is a good skill. But it's, I
Speaker 8:  I'm, but this is what I've said to her. It's like, is there gonna be a point
Speaker 8:  where you can't tell the difference and when you get to that point,
Speaker 8:  nothing is real.
Speaker 5:  You know, that was this the SOA two videos and again these, these
Speaker 5:  are just demo videos. Like God only knows how accurate this is to what most
Speaker 5:  people's actual experience will be. That would, these are the first time
Speaker 5:  that I have looked at them And I like, I've had to watch them
Speaker 5:  several times before you could clock anything that looked like ai, anything.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And like maybe the youths will be better at this than, than
Speaker 5:  we are like, and hopefully they will be. But, but it, I I
Speaker 5:  would've said we were a long way away from it being
Speaker 5:  really impossible for anyone to tell and now suddenly
Speaker 5:  it feels like it's closer than I realized. Yeah. Which is pretty scary.
Speaker 11:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Alright. That's my deep existential crisis for the week.
Speaker 5:  Jen, what's your, what's your first lightning round?
Speaker 8:  It's Fat Bear week.
Speaker 5:  I dunno why I'm surprised this is what you think.
Speaker 8:  It's so exciting. I've missed the entire week thanks to Google and
Speaker 8:  Amazon, but I did get to see or hear
Speaker 8:  thanks to Justine's wonderful reporting, most important story she's reported
Speaker 8:  on ever sorry
Speaker 8:  that there was a champion crowned. And now for those of you
Speaker 8:  who sadly are not familiar with that, their week,
Speaker 8:  it's one of my favorite weeks on the internet. It is when a
Speaker 8:  group in Alaska live streams
Speaker 8:  all of the brown bears coming to
Speaker 8:  the cat, my national park where they converge
Speaker 8:  on, I forget the name of the river, but one, one of the big rivers where
Speaker 8:  all the salmon are, are jumping, jumping up and the bears
Speaker 8:  just stand there and let the salmon jump in their mouths. It's amazing. And
Speaker 8:  they're doing this to get fat for the winter, Sam,
Speaker 5:  Honestly. Yeah,
Speaker 8:  That's right. I feel that. So this group, it's a conservancy
Speaker 8:  nonprofit, it's called explore.org. They, they have
Speaker 8:  webcams set up and they track the bears when they arrive. 'cause
Speaker 8:  they arrive relatively, you know, normal healthy bear looking.
Speaker 8:  And then over the time they get fatter and fatter and fatter because they're
Speaker 8:  just eating salmon. Eating salmon. And you get to vote on the champion
Speaker 8:  fat bear. And this winner this year was Chunk,
Speaker 8:  which is a great name. Yes. Bear 32. And it's
Speaker 8:  just the most delightful thing on the internet. Like I spent most of my summer
Speaker 8:  watching the Eagles and in the Nest in
Speaker 8:  California that was live streamed. There were these three and then
Speaker 8:  two baby eagles that were hatched and you got to watch them get raised
Speaker 8:  and then fly the nest and oh it was so amazing.
Speaker 8:  And then this watching brown bears coming to the
Speaker 8:  rivers and eat feeding and fighting and like, there's a lot of, you know,
Speaker 8:  it's like real housewives type stuff going on. And
Speaker 8:  I literally, most years I will just, I have two monitors and one monitor
Speaker 8:  will be live feeds at brown bears in Alaska eating salmon.
Speaker 8:  And it's just so soothing and great and fun and I'm so, I was so
Speaker 8:  excited. I was excited. But chunk weighing in at
Speaker 8:  1200 pounds. Wow. An impressive,
Speaker 8:  that's a chunk he got, one of the reasons he won, I think he got the sympathy
Speaker 8:  vote because he had sadly had a broken jaw. Oh. So,
Speaker 8:  and you know, any kind of injury like that could be technically
Speaker 8:  could definitely be fatal for an animal if it's not able to feed. And then
Speaker 8:  the winter comes. 'cause what they, what bears do, obviously they go and
Speaker 8:  hibernate for the winter and they need all the extra blubber from the
Speaker 8:  salmon to keep them through the winter. And if they don't eat enough they
Speaker 8:  could die. So it's, you know, it's real survival of the fishes out there,
Speaker 8:  but also great YouTube viewing.
Speaker 5:  Very good. We all root for chunk. My favorite thing about this story was
Speaker 5:  there was, there was a comment on Justine's story,
Speaker 5:  which is very good and we'll put in the show notes. There was basically like,
Speaker 5:  I don't know why this is on The Verge dot com, but I like it. And somebody
Speaker 5:  else just responded to that comment and it was like webcams or tech. Yes.
Speaker 8:  Hell yeah. I mean that, yeah, that was why I, I was like, I asked Richard,
Speaker 8:  the new editor, I was like, can I post about the Eagle Nest? And he's like,
Speaker 8:  but it's, but it's in a webcam. I could use a webcam. And
Speaker 8:  Baby Eagles
Speaker 5:  Neli in the past has approved stories because there's a phone there and that's
Speaker 5:  good enough. Sometimes it's, sometimes it's good enough. It's, this is what
Speaker 5:  tech, we do whatever we want. This
Speaker 8:  Is the good stuff tech brings to us.
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent. I love it. I cannot recommend chunk enough to everyone.
Speaker 5:  Emma, what's your next one?
Speaker 8:  Yeah,
Speaker 11:  So my next one was that Waymo now supports YouTube
Speaker 11:  music. And
Speaker 11:  I chose this because I got to go into Waymo for the first time
Speaker 11:  recently. And Ooh, you're
Speaker 5:  Just living in the future over here
Speaker 8:  Is great. Were that ads in the, in the car? Like, oh,
Speaker 11:  I now, I don't even remember that because I was too, I was too busy like
Speaker 11:  staring at like this, the
Speaker 8:  Steering wheel. Well I hate about New York cabs, the ads, I can never turn
Speaker 8:  them off that, you
Speaker 11:  Know. Oh yeah.
Speaker 8:  They don't have ads in Waymo's though.
Speaker 11:  I don't remember.
Speaker 8:  I'm sure they're coming if they don't yet. Exactly.
Speaker 5:  How was your Waymo experience? Was it everything you dreamed of?
Speaker 11:  It was actually like really cool And I
Speaker 11:  was just like, they integrated like Spotify earlier, now it's
Speaker 11:  YouTube music. But I just wanted to like say that the music that you
Speaker 11:  hear when you first like get into the Waymo, it's very like soothing
Speaker 11:  and it's like, I can't imagine like,
Speaker 11:  like rocking out in there because I feel like you need the
Speaker 11:  relaxing music. So is
Speaker 8:  It like elevator music
Speaker 11:  Kind of, it's like lo-fi music. Like you just need that so you don't like
Speaker 11:  freak out that nobody's driving the car and like
Speaker 11:  I feel like it's very, it's very relaxing. 'cause sometimes at one point,
Speaker 11:  like the way Waymo was making a right turn And I was just like, holy crap.
Speaker 11:  Like I don't know what's gonna happen to me after this.
Speaker 8:  But
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I feel like every, everybody I know who takes a Waymo describes their
Speaker 5:  first experience as like, oh my God, I'm gonna die. I'm gonna die, I'm gonna
Speaker 5:  die. And then by about the third one you kind of just get used to it.
Speaker 11:  Yeah, yeah. It's true. But yeah, I mean I just think
Speaker 11:  I could totally like see like how people do jam out in the Waymo. 'cause
Speaker 11:  nobody's in the car and you can just like kind of party in there and go
Speaker 11:  crazy. But
Speaker 11:  I just, I do like the relaxing music that they play by default.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I tend to agree that like,
Speaker 5:  it should probably not try to distract me with my favorite
Speaker 5:  songs, but I also feel like, listen, Waymo and YouTube owned
Speaker 5:  by the same company. Yes. And, and these people need to have a meeting with
Speaker 5:  each other that so that it knows when I get in the car and it plays the
Speaker 5:  music that I like, the second I step into the va, this is the most obvious
Speaker 5:  thing in the world and Google will never do it And I will just be angry about
Speaker 5:  it forever.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. I was, that's all I've used at one of the comments on the quick post
Speaker 11:  for this, because somebody was like, of course, it's like the most Google
Speaker 11:  thing ever to integrate their own service. Like after doing
Speaker 11:  Spotify and iHeartRadio. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Every, yeah. Like, oh God, every, every once a year. Everyone
Speaker 5:  who works for Google should be required to all meet each other. Like just
Speaker 11:  Yes.
Speaker 8:  In a Google Home. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Exactly. All right. My next one is, I, I mean this
Speaker 5:  sincerely maybe the single most exciting product announcement for me
Speaker 5:  personally that has happened this year, which is that Spotify
Speaker 5:  will now let you exclude a single song from
Speaker 5:  your algorithm and taste profile on Spotify.
Speaker 5:  So recently I have a, I have a two and a half year old
Speaker 5:  who only wants to watch Toy Story 100% of the
Speaker 5:  time this morning. I'm pretty sure he faked sick for I think the first
Speaker 5:  time ever. So that he, because he wanted to stay home and watch TV. And I
Speaker 5:  saw through him and he's not here. But anyway,
Speaker 5:  his favorite song on Earth is the third song from the
Speaker 5:  Toy Story soundtrack, which is called I Will Go Sailing No More. And
Speaker 5:  it is, it's the one where Buzz finds out he's a toy
Speaker 5:  and then tries to, tries to fly out the window and falls down. And Arthur,
Speaker 5:  my son, likes to stand there with his buzz and act out this whole thing as
Speaker 5:  we play the song 700 times in a row. So all of this is to say, I will
Speaker 5:  go sailing no more is going to be the number one song on my Spotify wrapped
Speaker 5:  this year. It's going to be the song. All of my other
Speaker 5:  recommendations are based on, I get Discover weekly recommendations every
Speaker 5:  week now by bands called like Fart Poop, poop, pee Pee. And like
Speaker 5:  it's just, this is my life now. And so the idea that I'm going to be able
Speaker 5:  to go in and say, exclude this from my profile, this is not representative
Speaker 5:  of my actual taste is so exciting and every other service needs
Speaker 5:  to have this. Like, if I watch a YouTube video that I don't want to
Speaker 5:  influence the rest of my YouTube videos. I want to be able to be like, I
Speaker 5:  didn't like that one. Pretend you never saw that. I saw it. Like I want that
Speaker 5:  on every service. And it makes me so happy that it exists on Spotify.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Oh, completely agree. I need it on Netflix. 'cause every, for some
Speaker 8:  reason, even though my kids have their own profiles, my daughter loves to
Speaker 8:  watch all her sort of anime k-pop type
Speaker 8:  movies and shows on my, and literally everything I have is
Speaker 8:  Asian influenced for all of my watch list now. And it's like, some
Speaker 8:  of it's great, but it's, you know, I also, you know, gimme a good CSI come
Speaker 8:  on. But yeah, I agree. I had the same issue with Spotify. I ended up having
Speaker 8:  to get the separate accounts with the kids and spend the extra money you
Speaker 8:  you get that's in your future. David,
Speaker 5:  I just want the button. I want one button that says, this is not the person
Speaker 5:  I aspire to be. Take this out of my profile. And then I want another button
Speaker 5:  that is like, I would like to be more like the person who watches and listens
Speaker 5:  to this. Please show me more This, more of these. Yes. Yeah. Like when I,
Speaker 5:  when I come across like a, like a gardening video on TikTok, I
Speaker 5:  want a button that is like, hell yeah. More of these. You know what I mean?
Speaker 5:  Yes. Yeah. I, I want to be the person who watches this video. So show me
Speaker 5:  more of this video.
Speaker 8:  No, I agree. The opt out great button should be everywhere. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The, I didn't watch this because I liked it. Please leave me alone
Speaker 5:  with it. Button needs to exist everywhere and I'm thrilled that
Speaker 5:  it exists on Spotify.
Speaker 5:  Jen, you're up last, what's, what's your last thing? Yeah,
Speaker 8:  Just to bring it back full circle I guess to all the Amazon announcements,
Speaker 8:  we didn't dive into this because there was a big surprise, actually this
Speaker 8:  was quite a big surprise for the ring ring. The
Speaker 8:  Amazon owned video doorbell camera company,
Speaker 8:  Jamie Siminoff, who has recently returned, came out on stage at the event
Speaker 8:  and introduced a boatload of new cameras. Nine in total,
Speaker 8:  all 2K and 4K, which they've never done before. So 4K is
Speaker 8:  a huge jump. So you know, they're just leapfrogging the nest there
Speaker 8:  who just went to TK 2K, now they've gone to 4K and there's a new
Speaker 8:  ring battery, sorry, a ring doorbell.
Speaker 8:  There's two versions of that. 2K and 4K. These are wired, they're all
Speaker 8:  wired cameras. Again, the higher resolution more, you need
Speaker 8:  a bit more power. This is all feeding into the Alexa plus AI as well.
Speaker 8:  So you've got two new doorbell cameras, new design.
Speaker 8:  Nice. Quite sleek, little slimmer, still
Speaker 8:  not a good design I'm afraid. But it looks like a doorbell.
Speaker 8:  That's what Jamie OV said to me afterwards when I commented on this. I'm
Speaker 8:  like, this was a chance for a big redesign. He is like, it looks like a doorbell.
Speaker 8:  That's what it needs to do. Fair enough. So you, your doorbell isn't something
Speaker 8:  you use. Which is a good point. That is a good point. But
Speaker 8:  yeah, so these come in. You've also got new floodlight camera, new outdoor
Speaker 8:  camera, new indoor camera that are all 4K. There are 2K
Speaker 8:  options for some of these as well plus POE options,
Speaker 8:  which are more for professional installs. But I know some of our listeners
Speaker 8:  are handy with the sort of the more permanent installs. POE is a great
Speaker 8:  solution if you can do it. So these are all, these are all
Speaker 8:  announced along with something called Retinal Vision,
Speaker 8:  which sounds like the worst. I'm sorry, it's the worst Mark. That's just
Speaker 8:  vision. That's all. That's what vision is. I know, I thought it was like
Speaker 8:  an eye scanner at first. I'm like, yeah, I know. I was like, that would be
Speaker 8:  cool. Like, so you are, it does what
Speaker 8:  it's like, do I need to go to the eye doctor? What's going on? What's going
Speaker 8:  on? Basically it's a fancy way of describing
Speaker 8:  ai enhancing the video feed. So you're supposed,
Speaker 8:  you will supposedly get much better video quality, which
Speaker 8:  again is feeding into the Alexa Plus and the ai. So you can
Speaker 8:  get new, there's text descriptions now on the Ring video
Speaker 8:  doorbells and the cameras. So you'll get a description of what's happened
Speaker 8:  as opposed to suggest, hey there's, you know, right now you might get person
Speaker 8:  detected or motion detected and you will also, because they
Speaker 8:  introduced facial recognition for the first time to ring cameras.
Speaker 8:  So you now could get an alert that says, Hey David's at your front door.
Speaker 8:  If you're gonna come visit sometime, that would be great. So
Speaker 8:  facial recogni and like tele has arrived at your front door, Kelly has arrived
Speaker 8:  at your front door. Yes. They've come to make sure you are watching your
Speaker 8:  tele.
Speaker 8:  So this was a hu all these like big upgrades for Ring that are
Speaker 8:  things that people have been wanting for a while, especially the new increased
Speaker 8:  resolution, the facial recognition feature. You know, some people love it,
Speaker 8:  some people don't. Obviously you don't have to turn this on. It is all
Speaker 8:  cloud process, but whereas some, I think Nest does most of its,
Speaker 8:  apple does most of its local. I think some of Nest is local Google
Speaker 8:  Nests. So that, that was all interesting. But the star of the show
Speaker 8:  was, I would, was the dog. As we
Speaker 8:  mentioned, they do, you know, the tech companies do love
Speaker 8:  to use pets and, and pets and kids to, to keep us interested.
Speaker 8:  But there's a new feature called Search Party. And what this
Speaker 8:  does is when you lose, if you lose your dog
Speaker 8:  or just Dogs Now Cats coming soon, you
Speaker 8:  can send out an alert in your, in the Ring Neighbors
Speaker 8:  app, which is a separate app. It's kinda like next door.
Speaker 5:  Like next door, but only for crime and yeah.
Speaker 8:  Yes. Yeah. Any ring cameras in your
Speaker 8:  neighborhood will get so that they can,
Speaker 8:  the, the image can be recognized, the image of your dog can be
Speaker 8:  recognized by any local cameras. And then if the
Speaker 8:  ai, this is all AI based, sees your dog on someone
Speaker 8:  else's camera, that ring owner will then get an alert saying,
Speaker 8:  we've spotted this lost dog on your camera.
Speaker 8:  Would you like to, you know, get in touch with the owner, take
Speaker 8:  the dog home, you know, they can then decide what they're gonna do. So the
Speaker 8:  idea is this AI, neighborhood AI is working
Speaker 8:  to help find your lost dog. So it, it's, it's a neat
Speaker 8:  idea. I was very excited when they first showed the dog on the
Speaker 8:  screen thinking we are finally getting the Vet Pet Tracker
Speaker 8:  from 2019. But no, this is far more
Speaker 8:  technically advanced Yeah. Than just a little neat
Speaker 8:  pet tracker, which was very cool 'cause it was one of the first
Speaker 8:  devices they announced for Sidewalk
Speaker 5:  What happened to Sidewalk. Like every, every time.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like you say, you know, all the rings will talk to each other and I'm
Speaker 5:  like, oh, didn't Amazon make a, a big splash about
Speaker 5:  how it was gonna connect all of its devices and build a whole new internet
Speaker 5:  out of all of your connect? Is this that
Speaker 8:  No, this has got nothing to do with Sidewalk. Oh Chuck Jen, don't do that
Speaker 5:  To me. That's not nice.
Speaker 8:  I know, I, I think Sidewalk is a really interesting idea And I, that's
Speaker 8:  why I was excited about this pet tracker from six years ago. I was
Speaker 8:  excited six years ago making that clear because I've used a lot
Speaker 8:  of pet trackers and they use GPS or Cellular, which where I live, both of
Speaker 8:  which are very unreliable and also expensive.
Speaker 8:  Whereas the idea of the site of Sidewalk is it's a free low
Speaker 8:  power local network that uses already
Speaker 8:  existing infrastructure. All those many, many millions of echo devices out
Speaker 8:  there. But no one has really, nothing has really come of
Speaker 8:  developing products for Sidewalk. There are a few that came out but you
Speaker 8:  don't really hear much about them. Ring never did its Pet Tracker. I asked
Speaker 8:  Jamie about the pet tracker and he said, you know, I always, it was something
Speaker 8:  they wanted to do, but he said this is easier
Speaker 8:  in many ways because it's very hard to get a hundred percent penetration
Speaker 8:  on pets pet trackers. Whereas, you know, we have a lot of
Speaker 8:  of Ring doorbells already out there and this only works on outdoor cameras
Speaker 8:  obviously. So, but I don't know, I
Speaker 8:  mean you also have to have ring cameras, so whereas
Speaker 8:  that's probably likely it's got one of the lar larger market
Speaker 8:  penetrations that your neighborhood would have them. But yeah, it's, it's
Speaker 8:  kind of locking it into one ecosystem whereas, yeah, sidewalk Sidewalk
Speaker 8:  does work today. Like it, I have it use using it in my
Speaker 8:  home and it sends, it helps keep devices. No sending
Speaker 8:  notifications when the internet goes down. So when the internet goes down,
Speaker 8:  I still get alerts from my ring cameras because it's using Sidewalk.
Speaker 8:  It, it's a great system, it's a great network. It helps extend
Speaker 8:  connectivity outside of your home without using wifi. Sure. But
Speaker 8:  yeah, nothing, they don't seem to have done much with it recently. I'm hoping
Speaker 8:  to get an update one day. Fine.
Speaker 5:  Whatever. Haos, if you're listening, give me sidewalk, everything will be
Speaker 5:  fine. I'll say the search party thing is like in this context,
Speaker 5:  they're very smart to talk about this with pets because if they're like,
Speaker 5:  we will track your children around
Speaker 8:  The neighborhood, around the neighborhood, all
Speaker 5:  Of a sudden you have, I, we can follow you from house to house sounds really
Speaker 5:  creepy, but in the like, we're just going to use it to find your lost dog
Speaker 5:  way. It's like, oh this is, this is just a good thing. This is like welcome
Speaker 5:  to the double-sided coin of all of ring's. Everything.
Speaker 5:  It's like there's, if you look at it one way, it's nice and helpful
Speaker 5:  and good and if you look at it another way, it is just a horrible like
Speaker 5:  dystopia for snitching on each other about everything.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Especially now that you've added the facial recognition. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Ring. This is what we do. I will say though Ring is at least in my neighborhood
Speaker 5:  everywhere. Yeah. Like we, we've, we spent the summer house hunting and it's
Speaker 5:  like just the, I started just clocking the percentage of places that we would
Speaker 5:  go that would have a ring and it's like, I mean a most
Speaker 5:  places now seem to have some kind of smart doorbell. Like I
Speaker 5:  more of, more often than not, I feel like the places we go have smart doorbells
Speaker 5:  and most of those are rings. Yeah. Like Ring is just the default player
Speaker 5:  in this category, which is nuts.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Which is why I wish they would come up with some nicer designs
Speaker 8:  because you go to these gorgeous houses I'm sure, I mean you live in DC I'm
Speaker 8:  sure there's some lovely old houses there. And then they'll have this bright
Speaker 8:  stainless steel looking thing on with a big blue ring.
Speaker 8:  I know you can get face plates and there's the elite that can kind of be
Speaker 8:  installed properly, but most people don't do that. They just stick the big
Speaker 8:  battery powered one on the front door and it's glaring there at you. Which
Speaker 8:  is part of the point I suppose if you see it, you know you're be being watched.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  It's something. Yeah. Emma, are you a smart home person?
Speaker 11:  I have a smart doorbell. It's not a ring, it's a ufe.
Speaker 11:  But yeah, there's a lot of rings around my neighborhood. I could definitely
Speaker 11:  vouch for that. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  The neighbor's app is just forever like a weird, sketchy, dystopian
Speaker 5:  place that I do not
Speaker 11:  Enjoy doing.
Speaker 5:  Alright, it's time for us to get outta here. We have, we have been talking
Speaker 5:  about ads for too long.
Speaker 5:  We've, we've gone way over. Thank you both for doing this. This was very
Speaker 5:  fun. I know it's been a, a truly nuts week and month
Speaker 5:  frankly for, for both of you. And it appears it's not over
Speaker 5:  like tech timber is a real thing, but I think October
Speaker 5:  is, is coming fast so it's, it's gonna be busy. We'll have to do this
Speaker 5:  more. Thank you both for doing this. This is a lot of fun. We'll be back
Speaker 5:  on Tuesday. Jen, you And I are gonna have some more smart home stuff to talk
Speaker 5:  about.
Speaker 5:  It all just keeps happening And I think actually you And I are gonna be doing
Speaker 5:  a lot of fun smart home stuff this fall. So stay tuned for all of that. I'm
Speaker 5:  moving at some point so I'm just gonna like ask you for help on smart home
Speaker 5:  things that I can try and convince my wife to install in our house to, that's
Speaker 5:  fun. Absolutely no success. That's gonna be fun. It's gonna be great. But
Speaker 5:  until then, a couple things before we go, by the way, one call The Vergecast
Speaker 5:  hotline. Eight six six VERGE one, one email Vergecast at The Verge dot com.
Speaker 5:  I will, I genuinely wanna know all of your feelings about tele. If you've
Speaker 5:  got nut tele, tell us what you think about Amazon stuff, all of your feelings.
Speaker 5:  Also version history. Our new podcast is launching this Sunday,
Speaker 5:  October 5th. If you are subscribed to The Vergecast on
Speaker 5:  any podcast platform or to The Verge on YouTube, you'll get it automatically.
Speaker 5:  But also subscribe to the version History Feed. That's like one huge way
Speaker 5:  that we make this thing work is by building its own feed itself. Go find
Speaker 5:  that. We'll link it in the show notes. Thank you for listening and I'm genuinely
Speaker 5:  curious what you think about that show after you hear it this weekend. So
Speaker 5:  get at me all of your thoughts. I wanna hear them all. Alright, The Vergecast
Speaker 5:  is The Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network. This show
Speaker 5:  is produced by Eric Gomez, Brandon Keefer, and Travis Lord Chuck. We will
Speaker 5:  be back on Tuesday and Friday. We got so much more. The news just never
Speaker 5:  stops. We got weird AI apps to test. We got all kinds of stuff to do. Until
Speaker 5:  then, that's the first cast, rock and roll.