# Transcript
ID: fd3c7a88-d669-41b5-a65e-1749b568fae7
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-5829523163046338163/5562793495546504988/s93290-US-5780s-1748609253.mp3
Description: It's a slowish news week ahead of some very busy news weeks, so of course Nilay and David start the show with a long discussion about party speakers. Eventually, they get into the news, beginning with some of the huge Apple redesigns planned for WWDC in June. For the first time in a long time, the stakes for Apple's software teams feel really high. After that, the hosts talk about Nilay's recent interview with Google CEO Sundar Pichai, and what the AI-ification of everything means for the future of the web. Finally, in the lightning round, it's time for another Brendan Carr is a Dummy, plus some talk about the Nintendo Switch 2, a bit of confusing tariff news, and more.
Speaker 4:  Hello and welcome to broadcast the flagship podcast of the
Speaker 4:  United States Party Speaker industry.
Speaker 6:  Only the US
Speaker 4:  I don't know that there is a US party speaker industry.
Speaker 6:  It's a global marketplace, Eli.
Speaker 4:  It's happening everywhere. I, I don't know where they're manufactured, I
Speaker 4:  don't know who designs them. I've been begging one of these companies to
Speaker 4:  let me into the room with their designers where they plan the next year's
Speaker 4:  party speaker lineup. Imagine that meeting.
Speaker 4:  Someone's like, make it put more lights on it and another person's like,
Speaker 4:  no, we can't afford it. You've gone too far.
Speaker 6:  I like to think of it as like a, there's like a price to lights
Speaker 6:  to size continuum and they're just like sort of sliding the thing
Speaker 6:  along the scale. And if you get too many lights, it's too expensive. But
Speaker 6:  if you get too big, you can have more lights. And so it's, they're just,
Speaker 6:  it's there. It's a lot of triangulation. But this is what product work is.
Speaker 4:  That's what I'm saying. There's a spreadsheet, there's a model. Someone's
Speaker 4:  got a slider. McKinsey's in there, you know.
Speaker 4:  Hi, I'm your friend Neli. That's David Pierce.
Speaker 6:  Hello.
Speaker 4:  It's just the two of us today. We're doing a concentrated dose of Neli and
Speaker 4:  David because you know, eventually we're both gonna have children and leave,
Speaker 6:  Right?
Speaker 4:  So you gotta get it all while you can.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, this is going to be 19 hours of just us yelling at each other
Speaker 6:  about the internet.
Speaker 4:  It's also a slow week, which actually usually means the show goes longer
Speaker 4:  than ever. Yeah, I, I don know why that is, but when we have
Speaker 4:  nothing to talk about, it's like a three hour show. So buckle up. It's gonna
Speaker 4:  be wild. A little housekeeping before we start. We've got a survey going
Speaker 4:  on, we just want feedback from the audience. It's fox
Speaker 4:  media.com/survey. Go take that. Let us know what you think and how we're
Speaker 4:  doing. And then I should remind you that no one can tell us what to do,
Speaker 4:  which is important. We don't do the ad reads, we don't do brand
Speaker 4:  sponsorships. I'm not out here trying to sell flavored water. Although
Speaker 4:  I have been thinking about selling a vodka for a number of years. That might
Speaker 4:  be the one exception to, it's a long story. Some people know.
Speaker 4:  But the reason that we are able to have total editorial independence and
Speaker 4:  we don't talk to our sales team and we don't do the brand sponsorships that
Speaker 4:  everyone else has to do is 'cause we are, we get support from all of you.
Speaker 4:  So right now VERGE subscriptions are on sale. They're 40% off.
Speaker 4:  We're kind of running 'em through developer season. So through the end of
Speaker 4:  wwc, basically you can go to The Verge dot com slash subscribe. They're
Speaker 4:  40% off. It's like $35 for the year cheap. And you get to support our whole
Speaker 4:  newsroom. And most importantly, what you are buying
Speaker 4:  is our editorial independence. No one gets to tell us what
Speaker 4:  to do. It's very powerful. It's a very powerful tool in our arsenal. We've,
Speaker 4:  we've relied on it for a long time and it's because you all
Speaker 4:  have supported us. There's this thing, we always say that
Speaker 4:  like anyone can get traffic, but it's really hard to have an audience. You
Speaker 4:  are the audience. That's you. Thank you. We appreciate you. Now give us your
Speaker 4:  money. I'm still learning how to be a salesperson.
Speaker 6:  Step one, editorial independence. Step two, Neela gets less awkward
Speaker 6:  asking you for money. Step three, everybody gets boats. That's, that's the
Speaker 6:  move here. That's what we're doing.
Speaker 4:  It's not a yachts industry. We're gonna come to what's going on on the web,
Speaker 4:  in the media in, in the second segment.
Speaker 4:  But I wanna start actually 'cause it's a slow week. I wanna start with
Speaker 4:  an actual party speaker update. We've been getting a lot of photos of party
Speaker 4:  speakers from all of you. As you probably know. I
Speaker 4:  believe party speakers are undercovered. They're a
Speaker 4:  massive market. They're many, many, many companies have
Speaker 4:  made giant Bluetooth speaker, like giant speakers
Speaker 4:  that have LED lights around the speakers, around the speaker drivers.
Speaker 4:  Some of them have handles that we've covered them that have literal beer
Speaker 4:  can holders. Sony made one with beer can holders.
Speaker 6:  It's the rare industry I think that knows exactly what It is it like,
Speaker 6:  which I have come to really appreciate.
Speaker 4:  These are a huge success story. Yeah. And they're undercovered 'cause everyone
Speaker 4:  wants to talk about Sam Altman writing a pony or whatever he did today. But
Speaker 4:  like the, the consumer electronics industry is doing
Speaker 4:  something right 'cause they've been making these and iterating on them for
Speaker 4:  decades and they are everywhere. Once you see them you realize like, oh
Speaker 4:  this is as big as the iPhone. Okay. Maybe not as big as the iPhone, but you
Speaker 4:  understand what I'm saying. Like everyone has them. They're all over the
Speaker 4:  place.
Speaker 6:  Physically. Much larger than the iPhone. Physically
Speaker 4:  Much larger. Yeah. But it's a cultural phenomenon. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  They're just part of the fabric. They're just everywhere. And no one talks
Speaker 4:  about them.
Speaker 6:  They're so entrenched that I think the, the great service
Speaker 6:  that you in particular have done for people is you have opened their eyes
Speaker 6:  to the party speakers that are everywhere. They're everywhere. Because like,
Speaker 6:  this has been my experience is that I have started noticing in places
Speaker 6:  that a party speaker has no business being,
Speaker 6:  there's almost always a party speaker. Like wherever you are, you
Speaker 6:  are within a hundred yards of a party speaker. I really have come to believe
Speaker 6:  that, that
Speaker 4:  That's true.
Speaker 6:  And and they're just so, they're so ubiquitous that we just don't even notice
Speaker 6:  them anymore.
Speaker 4:  They're so big you can't see 'em.
Speaker 6:  Exactly.
Speaker 4:  It's crazy. So people have sent us lots of pictures of party speakers. We
Speaker 4:  had pictures of party speakers, literally next to fa eighteens being
Speaker 4:  repaired. The maybe the high point of the entire birch cast to date.
Speaker 4:  But we've got some new ones
Speaker 4:  and I gotta say there's some wild stuff going on in the world.
Speaker 4:  So here's our first one. It's from Alan. It's it's graduation season out
Speaker 4:  there. We're getting a lot of photos of party speakers at
Speaker 4:  proms. Yes.
Speaker 6:  Getting
Speaker 4:  Ready at proms back pro prom. It makes sense.
Speaker 4:  I understand teenagers want light up speakers while they're all dressed up
Speaker 6:  Anywhere. There is like a school official and a stage. There is a party speaker
Speaker 4:  Somewhere. Yep. And tons, tons and tons and tons of commence commencement
Speaker 4:  addresses being delivered through party speakers in the little karaoke mics.
Speaker 4:  Yes, but here's this picture from Alan who sent it in. This is a
Speaker 4:  graduation procession of some kind. And I replied and said, is that on
Speaker 4:  her head? And the answer is it's on her head.
Speaker 4:  And so she's leading a graduation procession and she's
Speaker 4:  carrying the party speaker on her head. No,
Speaker 6:  No, no, no. But if you're watching this on video, Nila just put both hands
Speaker 6:  up. This woman does not have both hands up. Yes. It's
Speaker 4:  One, it's one huge bazooka party speaker.
Speaker 6:  This woman is in like a light dress and a red hat and is carrying a party
Speaker 6:  speaker on her head with one hand. Which is so
Speaker 4:  It's a lot
Speaker 6:  Spectacularly. Physically impressive. There's so much
Speaker 6:  about this. I have questions about like the, the graduation parade is an
Speaker 6:  incredible idea that every school should do. Yeah. There's a
Speaker 6:  surprisingly large like police and ambulance presence for this, which I have
Speaker 6:  questions about. But it's, it's this, it's this woman in a flowy dress just
Speaker 6:  like sauntering down the street. One arm party speaker on the head. Baz
Speaker 4:  Like Baz, unbelievable size party speaker. So this is incredible.
Speaker 4:  This is, this is among the best graduation photos we've gotten.
Speaker 4:  Keep keep 'em coming. 'cause if you notice them at, at graduations and proms,
Speaker 4:  they're, they're everywhere. I would, I would go so far as to say our nation's
Speaker 4:  high schools are powered entirely by party speakers at this point.
Speaker 6:  It seems like it.
Speaker 4:  We've gotten an infinite number of photos of baseball and
Speaker 4:  softball games. It's baseball and softball season for the kids. My daughter's
Speaker 4:  playing softball. There's party speakers there. Yep. Lots and lots of that
Speaker 4:  going on. Very cool market for party speakers. Very curious.
Speaker 4:  Who gets playlist control dying to know how that works and
Speaker 4:  the politics of playlist control for walk-on music at softball games? Do
Speaker 4:  each of the teams have different party speakers? Or if the coaches coordinated?
Speaker 4:  I
Speaker 6:  Don't know. Is it like a Spotify jam situation where
Speaker 4:  Everybody, you see what I, you see what I'm saying? Does
Speaker 6:  Max have a walkup song?
Speaker 4:  Max does not yet have a walkup song and if she did it would be one of the
Speaker 4:  songs from Frozen. So I think or Frozen two rather. That would
Speaker 4:  be just
Speaker 6:  Like metal. Do you want to build a snowman and up comes max to bat. It's
Speaker 6:  a lot.
Speaker 4:  It's or Taylor Swift And so, but it would be Wildest Dreams, which is
Speaker 4:  her favorite Taylor Swift song. And I don't know that that's a great softball
Speaker 4:  walk rock
Speaker 6:  On song. I think the 10 minute all too well is is the one and just stand
Speaker 6:  in the battered box all 10 minutes. Really? Psych up the
Speaker 6:  pitcher.
Speaker 4:  Okay. Lots and lots and lots of party seekers at kids softball.
Speaker 4:  But Luis sent us a, a tip
Speaker 4:  that the Yankees put up an Instagram post.
Speaker 4:  You gotta see this picture you got if you're in your car, just like stop
Speaker 4:  and pull over and we'll put the click on the link in the show notes. The
Speaker 4:  Instagram post or watch the video on YouTube. It's Jason Dominguez. It's
Speaker 4:  Jason with two S's and he is getting on a plane. This is very important.
Speaker 4:  The caption of this carousel is airplane mode 'cause they're obviously traveling
Speaker 4:  to a game and he's carrying a massive
Speaker 4:  white JBL party speaker onto this plane. Like it's the size of a
Speaker 4:  carry-on suitcase. It looks hot as shit by the way. Like I was
Speaker 4:  like I should buy the speaker. It's the JBL party stage three 20. It retails
Speaker 4:  for 5 99. It's sometimes on sale for 5 49. Good lord.
Speaker 4:  It has not one but two handles. There's one handle on the back with Jason
Speaker 4:  in the photo. He is carrying it by the back handle. But he also has the
Speaker 4:  pop-up handle that you can wheel it around
Speaker 4:  I am in a workplace where we're not allowed to wear headphones. A lot of
Speaker 4:  machine shops, right? Airplane technicians, all kinds of places where safety
Speaker 4:  requires that you need open ears that you'll be able to hear. And so we've
Speaker 4:  heard a lot of stories about competing party speakers.
Speaker 4:  So I'm just, are the Yankees in a similar situation on their plane?
Speaker 4:  But I'm telling you, party speakers have infected the sport of baseball.
Speaker 4:  They're everywhere in baseball. Yes. They're part of the fabric now of baseball.
Speaker 4:  So this picture's incredible. Jason, if you wanna come on the show and talk
Speaker 4:  about the JBL stage three 20. I don't know if you're sponsored. I was
Speaker 6:  Gonna say my great hope for this is that JBL sponsors Jason
Speaker 4:  office with a massive JBL party speaker
Speaker 4:  in a what appears to be like a reasonably small waiting room. But it's it's,
Speaker 4:  it's huge. Like it's for, it's like the PA for a small concert.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Look at this thing. If you walked into your dentist's office and you
Speaker 4:  saw this thing, you'd be like, kick out the jams brother, let's go. It's
Speaker 4:  incredible. Love it. This is what I mean. They're everywhere people like
Speaker 4:  there's not even etiquette around them anymore. The dentist was like, screw
Speaker 4:  it, light it up.
Speaker 6:  What's weird about this one to me is like there are smaller Bluetooth
Speaker 6:  speakers out there that are very good. Like I tell a lot of people to buy
Speaker 6:  like the the UE booms. There's a lot of those. And if all you're doing is
Speaker 6:  pumping music into your waiting room, 99 bucks will get you as
Speaker 6:  much speaker as you need to do the job here. No. And they're like, no, I
Speaker 6:  need a speaker the size of a third grader.
Speaker 4:  We're gonna rattle your teeth loose man. Let's, let's get this done.
Speaker 4:  This one is so big it has feet so it can go horizontally and serve as a bench.
Speaker 4:  It's very good. Everywhere you look man, they're everywhere. And I'm telling
Speaker 4:  you, the etiquette is at the window. Right. That
Speaker 4:  normal people would not have thought to put a speaker of the size and a dentist
Speaker 4:  office his waiting room.
Speaker 6:  It's true. This is innovation.
Speaker 4:  All right. And then the last one, my favorite one, our old
Speaker 4:  producer Creighton, he worked on The Vergecast before he worked on decoder
Speaker 4:  part of The Verge story for years and years. Creighton sends in,
Speaker 4:  he, he texted me actually from Rome. He was in what
Speaker 4:  appears to be like a soccer store, a football store. It's
Speaker 4:  Rome. And he is like, there's a party speaker here. The owner told me he
Speaker 4:  wanted one of the CD player 'cause the audio quality is better. So it has
Speaker 4:  a CD player at the top. The owner also told him Sony was the best
Speaker 4:  branded party speaker, which is a hot take. I think Sony was a progenitor
Speaker 4:  of the space, but in many cases JBL is doing better brand
Speaker 4:  integrations. You can see it. And then Ion is fast
Speaker 4:  approaching from the rear. I don't know what ion
Speaker 6:  Is ion the company. We still don't understand. If
Speaker 4:  You work at Ion, lemme know. I don't, I I think you might be like
Speaker 4:  a ghost company anyway. This is an ancient Sony party speaker CD player in
Speaker 4:  the top. It's kicking out the jams in a, in a store in in, in Rome.
Speaker 4:  And I, the only reason I wanna bring it up is 'cause if you zoom in on the
Speaker 4:  picture on the top here and you look for the mega base button,
Speaker 4:  you can see that it has been pushed so many times
Speaker 4:  that the letters are starting to wear off. None of the other buttons
Speaker 4:  have this problem. Right. The w party chain
Speaker 4:  has not been pushed so many times. The word sound field has not been pushed
Speaker 4:  so many times. The letters mega base has been pushed so many times
Speaker 4:  the the letters are wearing off. Which implies to me
Speaker 4:  that whoever owns this party speaker has determined there is a time for megabase.
Speaker 4:  And there is a time when you should not have mega base.
Speaker 6:  Well right. Because you have to turn it both on and off. It is, this is not
Speaker 6:  a permanent state.
Speaker 4:  You're turning it on and off all the time. Yeah. And I would just like to
Speaker 4:  know what times are mega base times and what times are definitively not
Speaker 4:  mega based times.
Speaker 6:  I think it's pretty easy because
Speaker 4:  This button is not one you should push. You should push it once and be like
Speaker 4:  the mega base is on.
Speaker 6:  But if you go mega base all the time, is it mega base anymore? Do you know
Speaker 6:  what I mean? Don't you like you need to live without in order to appreciate
Speaker 6:  what you have. Right.
Speaker 4:  You can't have lab parts on this. Have quiet parts. It's like a core Exactly.
Speaker 4:  Conceit of ver storytelling. Exactly. I'm with you. Exactly. I'm just saying
Speaker 4:  it's rare that you see a mega base button that has been pushed this many
Speaker 4:  times. I'm dying to know, as you know, we're no longer in the mega base era.
Speaker 4:  I think the Megabase era really that was the height of American
Speaker 4:  like soft power around the world. The eighties and nineties, the mega base
Speaker 4:  era we were doing it. We, I mean that's when people look back fondly. That's
Speaker 4:  when America was great that Sony moved on to ultra base. And I think
Speaker 4:  things really, really started falling down a cliff. And now we're in the
Speaker 4:  ULT Power Sound era and fully just off the rails. I couldn't even tell
Speaker 4:  you what's going on. Bring it back. Sony executive order, 1012
Speaker 4:  mega base shell return to American soil
Speaker 6:  Mega base told you the truth about what it was we need, we need more of that
Speaker 6:  ULT
Speaker 4:  Power sound. Get outta here. All right. Yeah. That's the party speaker update.
Speaker 4:  Thank you to everyone who sent them in. Let me know what you think the times
Speaker 4:  for Megabase are and are not. I'm dying to let me know what you think the
Speaker 4:  etiquette of these speakers are. 'cause they're everywhere man. And as always,
Speaker 4:  I thank you all for thinking of me. When you see
Speaker 4:  a giant speaker in the wild, like you have, you have, I have, I don't have
Speaker 4:  like massive ambitions to fame. You know, it, it's not, it's not what
Speaker 4:  motivates me,
Speaker 4:  but when people see a giant stupid speaker, there's a flicker of
Speaker 4:  recognition that these should tell me. That's pretty good.
Speaker 6:  It is good. I'll I'll take it. It's, you've accomplished something. I
Speaker 4:  Don't, I don't need much more than that. It's pretty good. All right. We
Speaker 4:  should get to some actual tech news for the people who are mad that we spend
Speaker 4:  so much time on party speakers every so often. I'm sorry, but that's what
Speaker 4:  the mo that's why you pay us the money.
Speaker 6:  Get a party speaker and play it loudly next to whatever you're listening
Speaker 6:  to The Verge cast on. And you don't have to hear us talk about it. It's
Speaker 4:  Very hit that mega base button, man. Let's live this life. All right.
Speaker 4:  There's some actual techniques in the world. It feels like we're in the
Speaker 4:  runup to the runup to ww DC,
Speaker 4:  A lot of weird vibes around Apple in this wwc, right? Yes. Google just
Speaker 4:  came off io which we'll we'll talk about in a little bit. There's some reactions
Speaker 4:  to Google's confidence and the products it might be building.
Speaker 4:  Obviously OpenAI announced its deal with Johnny
Speaker 4:  Ive and love from, they're in a moment. And then Apple's,
Speaker 4:  you know, they're, they're gonna have wwc, they will project confidence.
Speaker 4:  They're good at it. A lot of question marks around what Apple might be doing.
Speaker 4:  What its fives are. I got a weird open letter from a group of Apple fans
Speaker 4:  today demanding that the company do better at ai. And
Speaker 4:  at the bottom of the open letter it said, this letter was generated by chat
Speaker 4:  GBT. And I was like, well this is, I'm throwing this out the window so don't
Speaker 4:  do this to me,
Speaker 4:  but like that's the level of weirdness. Yeah, right. Like
Speaker 4:  open letters to Apple to reclaim the mantle of innovation.
Speaker 4:  That's some like late nineties, early 2000 stuff. That's not,
Speaker 4:  that's not been how anyone has felt about Apple for years now. And like
Speaker 4:  here we are.
Speaker 6:  I do think you could argue this, apple is sort of
Speaker 6:  at its weakest position
Speaker 6:  perception wise in a very, very, very long time because right, there's
Speaker 6:  all the AI stuff, there's all of the regulatory stuff, which it just continues
Speaker 6:  to lose in increasingly spectacular ways while
Speaker 6:  continuing also to alienate developers. Like everything that I'm hearing
Speaker 6:  about Apple and all these changes from developers, they understand
Speaker 6:  that Apple is being like bullied into making these changes that are obviously
Speaker 6:  good for developers and users. And It is not making anybody feel better about
Speaker 6:  Apple. Then there's also this thing that has gone around where
Speaker 6:  Tim Cook has lost his influence with the Trump administration. And so this
Speaker 6:  idea that he was like the, the all powerful whisperer of
Speaker 6:  the government who could get everything done and save tariffs and everything
Speaker 6:  was gonna be fine. That has waned. Like there's, there's this real sense
Speaker 6:  that the, the sort of overall bloom is off the rose at Apple.
Speaker 6:  And whether that's deserved or not or whether that something matters or not,
Speaker 6:  we'll see. But It is fascinating how much that
Speaker 6:  perception has changed. Like all of the things that Apple could sort of
Speaker 6:  clinging to for a long time seem to be degrading
Speaker 6:  all at once, which I think means the stakes for this WWDC and then the
Speaker 6:  iPhone launched in September are maybe as
Speaker 6:  high or higher than any I can remember before, like right
Speaker 6:  after Steve's jobs died, there was that big transition where it was like,
Speaker 6:  okay, what is Apple now and, and what is, what is going to be
Speaker 6:  kind of, how is this company gonna project itself going forward? That's the
Speaker 6:  last time I can remember coming into something like this being like, oh,
Speaker 6:  it actually really matters what Apple does here and how it talks about itself.
Speaker 4:  I have a slightly different view. I don't, I don't disagree about that moment.
Speaker 4:  Right. Apple needed to change its conception of itself. I think Tim Cook
Speaker 4:  made the company at Financial Juggernaut on the back
Speaker 4:  of it's basically distribution monopoly of
Speaker 4:  applications, right? Like in the smartphone era,
Speaker 4:  the only way you could get an app to someone was through Apple
Speaker 4:  Store or Google Store. Yeah. And people are not gonna like that. I'm saying
Speaker 4:  this, but the iOS store had richer people
Speaker 4:  using it and those people spent more money.
Speaker 6:  And also Google Store works the way it does in large part because of the
Speaker 6:  way that Apple architected its store in the first place.
Speaker 4:  Right. But like the Android app store, the play store,
Speaker 4:  yes, there's some Android apps, like lots and lots of Android apps, but all
Speaker 4:  the new stuff, I mean we got complaints about this career. All the new apps
Speaker 4:  would start on iOS first. Yep. And it was because Apple had the wealthier
Speaker 4:  customer base that spent more money and they were really good at pushing
Speaker 4:  people to the app subscriptions. And so like Apple,
Speaker 4:  I don't think that's diminished right now. Like
Speaker 4:  if people want to use chat GBT, they're primarily doing it through an app
Speaker 4:  on Apple's App store on their platforms. And if you wanna subscribe,
Speaker 4:  the easiest way to do It is to push the button in the app and Apple gets
Speaker 4:  its money. And that might be at risk, but we'll like
Speaker 4:  see what happens. Like Apple has ways to compete there that are within
Speaker 4:  its controls. I think the big risk Apple is all the stuff that's out of its
Speaker 4:  control, can they solve the regulatory problems around the world
Speaker 4:  In Texas, they just passed an age verification law that says the
Speaker 4:  smartphone makers have to verify the age of their users and keep kids out
Speaker 4:  of certain apps like that are educated, which
Speaker 6:  Reportedly Tim Cook personally tried to quash.
Speaker 4:  Yep. And, and they have been like all over this in every state around the
Speaker 4:  country. Like ev the top lobbyists in every state in every
Speaker 4:  like state capital a Apple has bought them all to try to crush these bills
Speaker 4:  and they, they just lost one in Texas.
Speaker 4:  That's, you know, is is that a flicker of diminishing? I, I don't know, but
Speaker 4:  it's out of their control right now. They just have to do it.
Speaker 4:  The big one is whether or not AI is
Speaker 4:  a new user interface that creates a new generation of hardware that
Speaker 4:  ends the smartphone application distribution monopoly. Like
Speaker 4:  that's the thing, that's the thing everyone's like staring at saying that's
Speaker 4:  the weakness. And for years Apple's strength has been like, well we have
Speaker 4:  the iPhone, we'll just like add these features. Yeah, we'll just Sherlock
Speaker 4:  the hell out of OpenAI and then it they'll die. Like
Speaker 4:  that's what they do and they haven't seemed to be able to do it. Right. They
Speaker 4:  announced Apple Intelligence and it went away and it's delayed. I it from
Speaker 4:  every indication we have if they talk about it at
Speaker 4:  WWC will not be the point. Right? Right. We should not expect the big sir
Speaker 4:  at WWC or whatever. So they've, they've got some catching up to you there
Speaker 4:  and then it's can Apple disrupt the iPhone with the next
Speaker 4:  generation advice that has AI as a user interface if that is indeed the
Speaker 4:  user interface of the future. Right. I don't know the answers to these questions.
Speaker 4:  Like, and that's weird. I think, I think Apple has traditionally been like,
Speaker 4:  we'll just wait for Apple to do it and it'll be great. And you know, that's
Speaker 4:  been how it's playing out because Apple has announced every feature that
Speaker 4:  Android has had for years, years after Android announced it and gotten credit
Speaker 4:  for it. And I don't think they can do that this time. No, I
Speaker 6:  And that's, that's, yeah, I think I, I I agree with that and I think there's
Speaker 6:  also, apple has gotten away with so much over
Speaker 6:  the years because it makes the best stuff and appears
Speaker 6:  to be the company that cares the most about making the best stuff.
Speaker 6:  And that's, once you lose that, it's really hard to get it
Speaker 6:  back. And I think again, all of that is so tied up in like, what are they
Speaker 6:  gonna show us at WDC and is It, is it gonna look like
Speaker 6:  Apple is, you know, putting new coats of paint on old things while everybody
Speaker 6:  is lapping it, building the next
Speaker 6:  thing? Or is there a, like is Apple going to be able to make a
Speaker 6:  compelling case that actually no, this is still the thing and I think it's,
Speaker 6:  it's like no one thinks we're getting rid of smartphones, right? Like Johnny,
Speaker 6:  ive and Sam Altman made their weird video in San Francisco. Even they are
Speaker 6:  like, smartphones are going to continue to exist. But like,
Speaker 6:  is it, I we're on how many years now of the iPhone being
Speaker 6:  basically the exact same thing and everything else getting weirder and
Speaker 6:  stranger and like, I think you could make a pretty strong case that the device
Speaker 6:  at Apple that has gotten the most improvement over the last several years
Speaker 6:  is the MacBook, which is a weird state of affairs for Apple. So it's just,
Speaker 6:  we're at this moment of like, I think people are less impressed with Apple
Speaker 6:  in every facet than they have been in a long time. And if you
Speaker 6:  lose that suddenly all the other like kind of gross
Speaker 6:  shenanigans you used to get away with because you made great stuff becomes
Speaker 6:  a lot harder to get away with.
Speaker 4:  So speaking of new coats of paint, the leaks we've gotten so far, we
Speaker 4:  don't know what's gonna happen. We don't know what's gonna happen. Well,
Speaker 6:  Apple's gonna announce some software apple's,
Speaker 4:  We know what happens at WDC broadly, right? Like they rev all their
Speaker 4:  operating systems every year at WWC to get developers ready for the next
Speaker 4:  turn. Sometimes they, you know, surprise announce a Mac Pro.
Speaker 4:  So we don't know, maybe they'll, they'll surprise all of us. We don't know
Speaker 4:  what's going to happen.
Speaker 4:  But my sense is that this will be very software focused and my sense
Speaker 4:  is that they're gonna announce a bunch of new coats of paint because we have
Speaker 4:  a bunch of leaks already. One of which is that Apple's
Speaker 4:  gonna rename all of its operating systems and that will be part of the big
Speaker 4:  news.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So the, the sort of stack of announcements here is that
Speaker 6:  a Apple is going to rev basically every piece of
Speaker 6:  software that it has in a meaningful way, which is not often the case
Speaker 6:  most of the time. There's sort of like, some get huge changes, some get medium
Speaker 6:  changes, and then they're just like, and TVOS exists and then they move on.
Speaker 6:  So, but this year there is, and we should say most of this reporting comes
Speaker 6:  from Mark Kerman at Bloomberg who is usually right about this stuff.
Speaker 6:  Not always, but usually.
Speaker 6:  And so yeah, the, the top line is basically huge
Speaker 6:  changes to every single surface of operating system
Speaker 6:  that Apple makes. Thing number two is the thing that all of those are gonna
Speaker 6:  have in common it appears, is that they're going to be
Speaker 6:  changed to look a more like each other and B, more like the vision pro.
Speaker 6:  That there is this like layered sort of spacey
Speaker 6:  3D interface thing that Apple is going deep on.
Speaker 6:  I have feelings about that. But then thing number three is to do that, they're
Speaker 6:  going to rename all of them to have numbering
Speaker 6:  schemes that are the same. I was gonna say numbering schemes that make sense.
Speaker 6:  But they don't, they're just the same now and that's something
Speaker 4:  Well no, they, they, they're tied to years, right, like cars.
Speaker 6:  Sure.
Speaker 4:  So this year they're gonna announce iOS 26 this
Speaker 6:  Year they're going Yeah, they're gonna announce, they're gonna announce presumably
Speaker 6:  the iPhone 17 this year right about as iOS 26 comes out.
Speaker 6:  And if you can explain to me how that makes sense, I really, really, really
Speaker 6:  look forward to hearing it.
Speaker 4:  Well,
Speaker 4:  all right, gimme a second because the, the OS is not tied to
Speaker 4:  the phone.
Speaker 6:  No it's not.
Speaker 4:  So you, you got the old phone running in the us that's what you want. And
Speaker 4:  it's this year's os you know it 'cause It is named after the, the year that's
Speaker 4:  to come.
Speaker 6:  What? I don't understand, but
Speaker 4:  That makes sense. Wait, wait, I got it. I got it.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Hit
Speaker 4:  Me. I'm ready. The wheels are turning over here. It's 'cause everyone gets
Speaker 4:  in the OS in like September and October, so you're already onto the next
Speaker 4:  year,
Speaker 6:  But September and October or this year.
Speaker 4:  But you don't wanna get iOS 25 in like September.
Speaker 4:  Right? Because they, it'll come out in like mid to late September. Usually
Speaker 4:  that's when the iPhone hits. So
Speaker 6:  Do you, do you actually, I've always wondered this, do you know the car logic
Speaker 6:  for this? Like is there a an official reason that cars do
Speaker 6:  next year model?
Speaker 4:  Oh it's just a straight arms race.
Speaker 6:  What do you mean
Speaker 4:  It So they cars did not initially have model years associated
Speaker 4:  with them. This is like a big innovation in the fifties and sixties and then
Speaker 4:  it was an arms race. He wanted the newest model so they started releasing
Speaker 4:  the newer models earlier in the year. Oh. And then everyone kind of like
Speaker 4:  standardized and then a bunch of stuff like the insurance industry
Speaker 4:  and car values got tied to Molly years and perceived age. So everyone kind
Speaker 4:  of landed in the same spot. But even right now there's an arms
Speaker 4:  race like the new the new Cadillac SUV the vista
Speaker 4:  is, it's out now. You can go buy one and It is a 2026.
Speaker 6:  That's so stupid.
Speaker 4:  And that usually doesn't happen. It usually happens around the fall where
Speaker 4:  they switch the model numbers over.
Speaker 6:  It's may it, it's closer to 2024 than 2026.
Speaker 4:  But that's what they're, but so their arms race persists. Yeah. But usually
Speaker 4:  cars, they rev the model years towards the end of the year.
Speaker 4:  'cause no one wants to buy last year's model in December. Right. So
Speaker 4:  you in January and you save a 2024, like nobody wants this. So like they've
Speaker 4:  landed in this sweet spot, but then every now and again a company like GM
Speaker 4:  will show up. You're like, screw it in 2026. And like that's, we're just
Speaker 4:  gonna have to deal with it.
Speaker 6:  And that is just like pure psychology. Like all that is is just a, a trick
Speaker 6:  to make you think it's the future when you're buying your car.
Speaker 4:  A hundred percent. And and
Speaker 6:  That's what we're doing here too. But, okay, here's what I don't understand.
Speaker 6:  So you, for forever, I don't know how long this lasted, but you
Speaker 6:  had a MacBook that ran Snow Leopard
Speaker 6:  and you were very proud of the fact that it ran Snow Leopard and you
Speaker 4:  Were like it wasn't Snow leopard. It was, wasn't
Speaker 6:  It Snow
Speaker 4:  Leopard? No. Snow Leopard was 10.4. I ran Snow Leopard when
Speaker 4:  I was in college.
Speaker 6:  Oh okay.
Speaker 4:  It was like El Capitan or something. It was like one of those. Okay. Mountain
Speaker 4:  Lion, that's what it was. Oh,
Speaker 6:  Okay. Fair enough. But you were very proud of this one
Speaker 6:  particular version of, of OS 10, whatever it was. And what I
Speaker 6:  don't understand is Apple has continued this
Speaker 6:  sort of delightful sort of weed infused, according to Craig
Speaker 6:  Federici naming scheme for Mac Os where they just named the operating system
Speaker 6:  something. And what I don't understand is why they wouldn't just do that,
Speaker 6:  just name it all something that's a, it's a much more aply way to do
Speaker 6:  it. Like tvOS 26 doesn't mean
Speaker 6:  anything to anybody. But
Speaker 4:  I don't think TV os means anything to anyone.
Speaker 6:  No,
Speaker 4:  It doesn't os means nothing to anyone. So then the only one that mean anything
Speaker 4:  to anyone are are Mac Os in iOS. So then why name it anything
Speaker 6:  At all?
Speaker 4:  Because they need version numbers. I think all they're doing is they revving
Speaker 4:  immersion numbers. The fact that we are having this conversation, first of
Speaker 4:  all I'm confident is driving some people bananas because It is of no consequence
Speaker 4:  to anyone. And there's probably other tech you used to talk about, but It
Speaker 4:  is also the point. Yeah. Right? Like they don't,
Speaker 4:  what they're not announcing is natural language Siri. Right.
Speaker 4:  What they're gonna announce is it looks different now, which always gets
Speaker 4:  a ton of attention and we've rubbed all these operating system numbers
Speaker 4:  and then It is certain that we will write
Speaker 4:  something about how the operating system numbers work. Well. But, and I will
Speaker 4:  just write like 10,000 words on why they should have stopped at Snow Leopard
Speaker 4:  and that was the greatest time the computers ever had in history.
Speaker 6:  That's what I was thinking of. You love Snow leopards. That's
Speaker 4:  Snow Leopard was the greatest operating system. You were
Speaker 6:  Running Mountain Lion, but you love Snow Leo. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And that was my attempt to just like, stop it. It didn't work. I
Speaker 4:  got a new computer. But I
Speaker 6:  Do wonder like your your point that these are just version numbers. I think
Speaker 6:  I, I wonder if that's telling, like we were talking about this last week
Speaker 6:  with all the Android stuff that Google has sort of hit a point where
Speaker 6:  Android version numbers don't really matter. Not at all. It used to be sort
Speaker 6:  of an event release that the new version of Android would come out and it
Speaker 6:  would have a dessert name and it would've a bunch of new features and they
Speaker 6:  would do a whole thing about it. And now your phone just kind of periodically
Speaker 6:  updates and you don't think that much about it. And I wonder if this is Apple
Speaker 6:  moving towards the same thing where actually this,
Speaker 6:  this annual rev of all the operating systems, which you could argue for a
Speaker 6:  long time has not made sense to, you know, hold features six months just
Speaker 6:  to put them in a release every May.
Speaker 6:  Maybe maybe this is the end of that way of thinking that Apple is like,
Speaker 6:  okay, well actually expecting us to have a wholesale new
Speaker 6:  thing every year is not what we're after. And instead we just call it
Speaker 6:  the year it shipped and it's a version number and that's it.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I I again, I I think this is like of little consequence
Speaker 4:  outside of the one we get to like make some news.
Speaker 4:  We get to harmonize all the numbers across all the things. Yeah. But I,
Speaker 4:  what people want out of Apple right now is to be able to talk to Siri and
Speaker 4:  have Siri do things right. Like, and maybe you hate AI and you don't actually
Speaker 4:  want this, but the broader ecosystem of like the
Speaker 4:  Market Watchers and regular people who are using chat
Speaker 4:  GPT every day are like, why isn't Siri It Chat
Speaker 4:  GPT Advanced Voice mode. Why, why haven't these things just connected together
Speaker 4:  in a real way? Like I don't wanna just use the action button. I think honestly
Speaker 4:  you could level the same criticism of Google. Like Google Assistant is not
Speaker 4:  Gemini. They're gonna get there on some timeline,
Speaker 4:  but it's still weird. That hasn't happened. It appears some people,
Speaker 4:  including our friend Parker or Alani have gotten Alexa plus
Speaker 4:  I, he's the only one I know. If you have it, let us know. We'd love to talk
Speaker 4:  to you about it. 'cause none of us have it yet. But I I think like these
Speaker 4:  assistant interfaces, that that's what a lot of people
Speaker 4:  believe the next turn to be. And Apple doesn't have a
Speaker 4:  move there. So version numbers are just like, that's what I mean by it's
Speaker 4:  a coat of paint.
Speaker 6:  Well, and in that world, if that is in fact the interface of the future
Speaker 6:  version numbers sort of cease to mean anything altogether. I mean I I think
Speaker 6:  back to like when, when Sam Altman said, and this is, I don't know, a
Speaker 6:  year ago now, that he was like, we, we set up the GPT
Speaker 6:  numbers all wrong. That now every time we release a new model, people expect
Speaker 6:  it to be like the leap from GPT three to GPD four and like blow their minds
Speaker 6:  and it's gonna be a whole new thing. And actually what It is, is all this
Speaker 6:  stuff just sort of consistently incrementally gets better and
Speaker 6:  there's no point in having, so they just like made the numbers not make any
Speaker 6:  sense anymore. And like maybe if you're Apple
Speaker 6:  launching Siri two, Siri three and series four doesn't make any sense. No.
Speaker 6:  And so you're just, they're just gonna pull back on all of this
Speaker 4:  First they have to launch Siri. Well,
Speaker 6:  Yeah, but it, but I mean, it, it makes me wonder like if all of that comes
Speaker 6:  true, is this one of the last WWDC that feels this
Speaker 6:  big? I
Speaker 4:  Don know, I think they will always have to rev the, you they
Speaker 4:  have so many devices in the world that I don't think they can do the
Speaker 4:  constant phased approach. Right. I it's like, it would almost
Speaker 4:  be too taxing. Too many things would like kind of always be going wrong.
Speaker 4:  Right. Do you know what I mean?
Speaker 6:  Like drop all the bugs at once instead of like one a week all year.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Right. Like I, I think they can, they can be prepared for something
Speaker 4:  and like, I think that cadence is really important to them. I think it's
Speaker 4:  part of Apple's DNA to be like, we have a roadmap. We ship all the things
Speaker 4:  on the roadmap, we move on to the next part of the roadmap. And they've gotten
Speaker 4:  better at some Delta updates. Like they announce a bunch of features of wwc
Speaker 4:  and then they like things come out months later almost till the next year.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So they, they have started breaking things apart more, but I think
Speaker 4:  they're, they're organized around one big drop in one big announcement cycle.
Speaker 4:  And importantly this is what developers are for, right? Like you need all
Speaker 4:  your developers to support your new features. So when the operating system
Speaker 4:  arrives in September with new iPhone, the apps are ready for it. And that
Speaker 4:  to me is the, like the other big weakness in Apple's
Speaker 4:  universe of weaknesses right now that the developers are mad at the company,
Speaker 4:  they're gonna put out a new design language. This has been the rumor. It
Speaker 4:  will look more like the Vision Pro interface, you know, sheets of
Speaker 4:  glass, I keep calling it Aero Glass, which is the name of the design language
Speaker 4:  and Windows Vista.
Speaker 4:  But like that's what everybody wants. It's it's got a lot of those moves,
Speaker 4:  right? Like transparent glass and layers. And what's fascinating about this
Speaker 4:  is it that design language is not where the rest of the
Speaker 4:  industry is going right now. And Apple traditionally leads, right? They,
Speaker 4:  they take the Boulder steps, they push everyone forward. A lot of people
Speaker 4:  just copy whatever Apple does. And I don't think that's happening right now.
Speaker 4:  No. I I I think there's a generation of designers who came up independently
Speaker 4:  of the iPhone. Like the iPhone was just the thing that existed and they have
Speaker 4:  their own ideas and you can kind of see it like, you know, the new
Speaker 4:  Airbnb icons are like 3D dimensional. Johnny I've
Speaker 4:  helped with that. You see it like opening eyes
Speaker 4:  design language is different than apple's. Google just did Material
Speaker 4:  U Extreme or whatever it's called. It's,
Speaker 6:  I think expressive was the word, but it was
Speaker 4:  Basically extreme. There are a lot of ideas about software design in this
Speaker 4:  new universe and it's not a guarantee that Apple's ideas will win and it's
Speaker 4:  certainly not a guarantee that their developers will exert the effort to
Speaker 4:  redesign their apps to mash apple's design right now.
Speaker 6:  Right. Yeah. I mean, and in fact I think actually Airbnb is an interesting
Speaker 6:  example. 'cause if you look at Airbnb's new design,
Speaker 6:  it's, it's not quite skew morphic, but it's very
Speaker 6:  physical, right? Yeah. Like, and and that's a huge trend in design right
Speaker 6:  now is is making everything feel sort of earthy and
Speaker 6:  tactile and like that's a lot of what is even happening in the new Android
Speaker 6:  stuff is it's designed to like move and bounce and morph and
Speaker 6:  it's like everything wants to sort of feel alive and three dimensional
Speaker 6:  and Apple is just like panes of glass and it's like,
Speaker 6:  I'm I'm sure it will be lovely. And there are a lot of really smart things
Speaker 6:  about the Vision Pro, right? Like the, the sort of big idea behind
Speaker 6:  a lot of the design is that it's, instead of being a bunch of different screens,
Speaker 6:  like a menu lives inside the button and when you tap the button, the menu
Speaker 6:  sort of appears out of it over top of what you're doing instead of launching
Speaker 6:  you into a whole new experience. There's a bunch of that that actually like,
Speaker 6:  makes sense in terms of like helping people know where they are on their
Speaker 6:  device. Sure. But It is a completely
Speaker 6:  different way of thinking about what your technology
Speaker 6:  means to you than this idea of like, we want the
Speaker 6:  physical world and the digital world to look and feel more like each other.
Speaker 6:  And as we're like, especially as everybody is doing augmented reality and
Speaker 6:  thinking about smart glasses, like, it, it makes a lot of sense to me to
Speaker 6:  start thinking about like, how do I make the digital world blend into the
Speaker 6:  physical world a little more? And Apple is like completely the other way.
Speaker 6:  They're like spaceships. It's all spaceships.
Speaker 4:  I, you know, I the Vision Pro, who knows Three, we're gonna talk about the
Speaker 4:  Vision Pro also be very funny if they rev the Vision Pro
Speaker 4:  operating system to 26, like
Speaker 4:  two years in from
Speaker 6:  Two to 26.
Speaker 4:  Like, like Vision os 26. Like here we go. A lot
Speaker 4:  of, and a lot of, a lot of spaces left on the, on the feature chart between
Speaker 4:  here and 26.
Speaker 4:  But you know, if you view the Vision Pro as a simulator and you're like,
Speaker 4:  this is how we will overlay digital information on the real world Pans a
Speaker 4:  glass kinda makes sense. But like we're not, we're nowhere close to this.
Speaker 4:  Right. Like nowhere close. And I think it'd be, it's gonna be
Speaker 4:  interesting to see how that maps to like an iPad, which
Speaker 4:  is like not anywhere close to an augmented reality device, right? Like
Speaker 4:  it's like a big physical device you hold in your hand. Like It is the most
Speaker 4:  screen that can screen in your hand and like how is that
Speaker 4:  gonna play? So there's just like things here about Apple's design language
Speaker 4:  right now where I'm, I'm curious to see what the Rev looks like. I'm curious
Speaker 4:  to see how it plays with their other ambitions. But all of these other,
Speaker 4:  like the digital world is getting more physical. It is like, it's a, it's
Speaker 4:  an interesting trend. You kind of see everywhere. But it, it's a reflection
Speaker 4:  of the fact that that is still happening on screens.
Speaker 6:  Yes. And
Speaker 4:  The Apple's new design language at least is expressed on the Vision Pro is
Speaker 4:  like very much like it's happening in reality and we're not there
Speaker 4:  yet.
Speaker 6:  Sort of, but it's kind of like, it's like what if there was an iPad floating
Speaker 6:  in the air? Not what if this thing were in the world. Like I kind of,
Speaker 6:  I think Apple has pushed like halfway down that road,
Speaker 6:  not all the way down that road. And then again, there's to your point there
Speaker 6:  is the question of like, is that what I want when I'm aware that I'm looking
Speaker 6:  at a screen, right? Like, is that, does that construct make any sense
Speaker 6:  on the screen that I'm holding in my hand? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You know what's gonna happen? Is there gonna play a video of like a a button
Speaker 4:  and Craig Feder is like this button and everyone, the crowd's gonna go wild.
Speaker 6:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  And the developers gonna make the button anyway. That's wwc. Like the leaks
Speaker 4:  are coming. I think what Dave and I are both pointing out, It is like Apple
Speaker 4:  has stakes here in a way. They have not really needed to address the stakes
Speaker 4:  in a long time. Yes. And I don't think they can just paper over it and like
Speaker 4:  muscle through it and be like, we're Apple. Like take it or leave it. I think
Speaker 4:  a lot of people are aware that there is another
Speaker 4:  kind of application model being developed and
Speaker 4:  you might hate it. I know we have listeners who hate ai, but I'm
Speaker 4:  watching people every day build new applications
Speaker 4:  using tools like NAN and Cursor. We get the
Speaker 4:  pitches, we see the investment, there's something
Speaker 4:  meaningful happening there and I, you
Speaker 4:  can't just ignore it. So if Apple participates in that,
Speaker 4:  that's one thing. If they don't, I think there's gonna be a lot of pressure
Speaker 4:  on the company to have an answer as to why. And right now the answer is 'cause
Speaker 4:  we were late. And I I don't think that's great for that.
Speaker 6:  Right. Well and I think it, It is, it's Apple's move always
Speaker 6:  to pretend that nothing else exists and just
Speaker 6:  like live in its own universe where it doesn't acknowledge other companies
Speaker 6:  or other products or other ideas. And I think this time rather than
Speaker 6:  projecting strength, that's gonna look like weakness. We'll see because there
Speaker 6:  is this perception that Apple is way behind and it's either going to have
Speaker 6:  to acknowledge it or it's gonna look like it's just
Speaker 6:  got its head up. Its ass.
Speaker 4:  I'm dying to know. I honestly I too, it's gonna, we there's another week
Speaker 4:  of weeks to come. We'll find out. But that fe it feels like this.
Speaker 4:  That's the frame we're in. 'cause it, they're the last of the developer conferences
Speaker 4:  and we kind of know what everyone else's moves are gonna be. Alright, we
Speaker 4:  should take a break. We'll come back. I want to, I wanna actually pick up
Speaker 4:  the thread from Google and it's confidence when we come back. 'cause it,
Speaker 4:  it's a really interesting contrast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 6:  decoder?
Speaker 4:  It's true. That's all I've tried and I know this has
Speaker 4:  disappointed a lot of people over the years. I have done my best and I have
Speaker 4:  consistently failed to arrest the CEOs of major tech
Speaker 4:  companies When they appear on decoder
Speaker 4:  I, there there's some segment of people that is visibly
Speaker 4:  frustrated with me when every decoder interview does not end with an
Speaker 4:  arrest in jail time. I'm doing my best. I have
Speaker 4:  said you're under arrest at the end of many decoders.
Speaker 6:  I do like the idea that every episode ends with like an animation of just
Speaker 6:  bars coming down in front of their face,
Speaker 4:  Decoder jail. Yeah, you're right. Some people have come close,
Speaker 4:  some CEOs have certainly self emulated on that show. That's true in
Speaker 4:  spectacular ways. And I'm saying this because I I've interviewed Sundar a
Speaker 4:  lot. He is very calm, he's very
Speaker 4:  practiced. He's he is excellent at answering exactly the question he wants
Speaker 4:  to answer exactly when he wants to answer it and not answering the question
Speaker 4:  if he doesn't want to. Yes. And so decoder for me is always a dance, it's
Speaker 4:  always a race against the clock. And there's just a part of it where I know
Speaker 4:  I've hit the wall like it's just not gonna happen. And it's time to
Speaker 4:  try a new wall. Like let's see if I can get through a different wall. And
Speaker 4:  in particular in conversations with sdo, I think you can see me do that faster
Speaker 4:  than ever just 'cause I know him and I, I know when I'm wa I'm just
Speaker 4:  wasting time and I need to find a way to make that clearer. I, I think there's,
Speaker 4:  I don't think it comes through that the way I experience an
Speaker 4:  interview like that is as a clock. Like I'm just running outta
Speaker 4:  time, right. Like from the second the conversation starts, the thing that's
Speaker 4:  happening in my head is that I'm running out of time.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's a tricky balance. The balance between this is the question I
Speaker 6:  want you to answer and so I'm going to keep asking it versus at some point
Speaker 6:  we have to make the rest of this podcast is a, is a, it's a hard balance
Speaker 6:  to strike.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And there was, there's always a lot of stuff to talk about. And so
Speaker 4:  like Sure. But I think the thing that people are really reacting to in that,
Speaker 4:  and I felt it, I feel it this week and there's a reason I wanna talk about
Speaker 4:  this, is I asked Sundar, as I've asked for many years
Speaker 4:  about Google's relationship to the web and he
Speaker 4:  keeps saying this thing, he said it now for many years that Google is sending
Speaker 4:  more traffic out to the web than ever. That they're committed to the web,
Speaker 4:  they want the web to be healthy, they're the only company that cares about
Speaker 4:  the web. He, you know, he always brings up competitors like, you know, Instagram
Speaker 4:  doesn't allow links and captions. Like I think this still bothers him that
Speaker 4:  Google gets all of this pressure to make sure the web ecosystem is,
Speaker 4:  is thriving. And you know, many other platforms send no links out at all.
Speaker 4:  Okay, well Google runs Chrome. Google runs search. Like that is their ecosystem,
Speaker 4:  their creator base, if you wanna think about that way is the web. And the
Speaker 4:  same way that Instagram creators or TikTok creators are always mad at Instagram
Speaker 4:  or TikTok or YouTube creators always mad at YouTube.
Speaker 4:  Website owners are always mad at Google. Like that's just the nature of the
Speaker 4:  relationship. But the economics are different because it's an open
Speaker 4:  ecosystem, not a closed one. Right? So TikTok creators are mad at TikTok.
Speaker 4:  There's a natural connection there. Like TikTok
Speaker 4:  can just make changes and change the lives of TikTok creators. There's an
Speaker 4:  out for Google, which is like, I don't know, do some other stuff. Like why
Speaker 4:  are you so addicted to Google search? Right? So you hear Sendar
Speaker 4:  say we're sending more traffic out to the web and then
Speaker 4:  within minutes a site like Business Insider announces
Speaker 4:  layoffs of 21% of its staff. They announce it just before we went on air.
Speaker 4:  And the memo says, we need to get outta businesses that have traffic
Speaker 4:  dependencies. We cannot control that. We need to, we need to avoid these
Speaker 4:  steep traffic drops we're seeing and what they are talking about is search
Speaker 4:  traffic, right? They're getting out of the commerce business where you know
Speaker 4:  that you list the 10 best mattresses and collect affiliate revenue for clicks
Speaker 4:  because that style of running a commerce business is search
Speaker 4:  arbitrage, right? People search for best mattress, they land on the
Speaker 4:  business insider page, they buy a mattress, and business insider gets some
Speaker 4:  pennies. And if you can wor warm your way
Speaker 4:  up the rankings, you can make more pennies and then you can make pennies
Speaker 4:  at scale. And now you've made money. And we know lots of competitors
Speaker 4:  that basically just do search arbitrage in this way. And the bottom has fallen
Speaker 4:  out of all of those businesses. I
Speaker 6:  Mean, we do some search arbitrage, like we, we can just call that what It
Speaker 6:  is. Everybody does some search arbitrage. It's part of being a business on
Speaker 6:  the internet that is part of the job. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  But we don't do it as ruthlessly as like the slop No buying guys
Speaker 4:  much to
Speaker 6:  The screen of some of the people at Vox Media. It's true. We,
Speaker 4:  There are people who'd love for us to do ruthlessly also. We run like a formal
Speaker 4:  reviews program. Like yeah, we do. It is true. We make some pages for search
Speaker 4:  and we see the demand and we, we try to get that audience. But if you're
Speaker 4:  running one of those verticals that is purely search
Speaker 4:  arbitrage, right? The content farms that do it, their businesses are going
Speaker 4:  away. And some of those content farms are attached to things like Business
Speaker 4:  Insider, which does real journalism, right? And like you see
Speaker 4:  the bottom falling out there. And I, there's a real
Speaker 4:  disconnect and I, I think I felt it on this interview more than ever, where
Speaker 4:  you're saying we're, we're committed to the web, we're gonna keep building
Speaker 4:  on the web, we're gonna keep sending traffic out on the web, and then all
Speaker 4:  of the people building on the web are like, we're dying. And I, I
Speaker 4:  don't think that disconnect is getting smaller. I think It is getting bigger
Speaker 4:  and bigger and bigger by the day. And it, it, you know,
Speaker 4:  I'm not gonna like go all the way out there and say like, the web is dying.
Speaker 4:  Like I think the web is a place where apps are developed the best it's ever
Speaker 4:  been every single day. There's like a hot new web
Speaker 4:  app basically that is doing something that couldn't be done before,
Speaker 4:  or an app like Figma is getting capabilities that never had
Speaker 4:  before. That's an incredible story of application development. Yeah. Like
Speaker 4:  I keep saying this, like It is a giant interlinked, interconnected,
Speaker 4:  worldwide application platform. The web is a miracle.
Speaker 4:  Like it's just, you would never be able to predict that it, something like
Speaker 4:  that could exist. And it does it's scale and everyone just sort of
Speaker 4:  like takes it for granted as a media platform. It it's dying and
Speaker 4:  it's one of the reasons it's dying is 'cause there's no way to get move traffic
Speaker 4:  around it and Google is the last way to move it. And they,
Speaker 4:  I would just say, I don't think they care. Like I, I really have come to
Speaker 4:  the conclusion that they know this is happening. They can see, obviously
Speaker 4:  see it happening and they've just, they, it's just,
Speaker 4:  they're over it. Like I don't think they want the pressure. I don't think
Speaker 4:  they care. There's also a bunch of lawsuits we should talk about, but we're
Speaker 4:  just in a place where I, I think the web
Speaker 4:  we knew is coming to a close in another web
Speaker 4:  that's primarily application based or platform based or whatever It is, is
Speaker 4:  is on the rise. And it might be masking the fact that an old web
Speaker 4:  is is is maybe over.
Speaker 6:  I think that's true. I mean, and I think I, I put this next to the work
Speaker 6:  Google has been doing on its ranking stuff over the last couple of years,
Speaker 6:  including a couple of pretty big ranking changes that like all at
Speaker 6:  once tanked a bunch of publishers. And this is the thing we've covered a
Speaker 6:  lot. The, the, the, you know, small like home
Speaker 6:  goods review site that got absolutely destroyed by
Speaker 6:  some sort of unknowable change in the algorithm that just down ranked a bunch
Speaker 6:  of new stuff. And Google's line and I, I, at a
Speaker 6:  very top level, I believe them that, that this is the goal
Speaker 6:  is the goal is to stop sending traffic to bad websites, right? And so
Speaker 6:  like Google is actively trying to kill bad websites. Like let's
Speaker 6:  let's not be unclear about that, right? Like all the stuff you're describing,
Speaker 6:  all the content farming stuff, Google not only doesn't care if
Speaker 6:  that goes away, it would like that to go away because again, like
Speaker 6:  Google understands as well as anybody that if if all of that stuff gets worse
Speaker 6:  on the web, Google search becomes less useful and it
Speaker 6:  all just like falls apart, right? And this is, this is a thing we've seen
Speaker 6:  happen. Search results get worse because websites are getting worse because
Speaker 6:  they're trying to game Google and it's this like horrible death spiral of
Speaker 6:  search arbitrage. Google is very happy to kill all of that stuff. Like
Speaker 6:  I think all of the things where there's no more money in mattress reviews
Speaker 6:  because they don't rank on Google anymore. I I think inside of Google, they
Speaker 6:  are going to call that a resounding success feel about that however
Speaker 6:  you want. But I I, I don't think Google's stance on that is at all unclear.
Speaker 6:  I think to me the question is like Google is in an
Speaker 6:  unusually active position right now of trying to
Speaker 6:  decide what a good and bad webpage is. And Google has always,
Speaker 6:  always, always, always, always gone way out of its way to say that it doesn't
Speaker 6:  do that. And to say that actually we, we are not remotely
Speaker 6:  interested in trying to decide what's good and bad on the internet. We're
Speaker 6:  just, we're just sending traffic to where people want to go. And then there
Speaker 6:  was this big SEO leak a year ago that made very clear that Google puts its
Speaker 6:  thumbs on the scale in like innumerable ways to decide what it likes and
Speaker 6:  what it doesn't. And now increasingly it's like, okay,
Speaker 6:  in order to take all the shitty stuff that has been created
Speaker 6:  on the web to game the way the system worked, we're gonna build a new system
Speaker 6:  because it's better than that old system. And if all that stuff dies that
Speaker 6:  was trying to game our old system, so be it. And then the question is, and
Speaker 6:  no one will answer this, including Sundar, is what happens when you also
Speaker 6:  kill the good websites? They won't, they won't say that. They will not answer
Speaker 6:  that question. And there is this like big structural belief, and
Speaker 6:  I think it was de that said this, that like we're gonna
Speaker 6:  eventually have a, a web that is mostly for AI agents and
Speaker 6:  may not even need like a front end for people to look at at all most of the
Speaker 6:  time. But what about the good websites? It's like, it's just a question they
Speaker 6:  won't answer. And, and we're in such a like baby being thrown out with the
Speaker 6:  bath water situation where like in a sort of ruthless way, like sure,
Speaker 6:  let all the bad websites die, let 'em all die, whatever.
Speaker 6:  There are a lot of good websites out there that will die as you kill the
Speaker 6:  bad websites in order to make it easier for people to find what mattress
Speaker 6:  to buy. And like Google at least publicly will not reckon with
Speaker 6:  that.
Speaker 4:  So I think one of the ways they are reckoning with It is by saying,
Speaker 4:  well the audience doesn't want this. And I, I don't know how to contend with
Speaker 4:  that, right? Their, their point is like, people are getting media from
Speaker 4:  YouTube and TikTok and whatever else and like
Speaker 4:  podcasts and that's all fine and that's like where the audience is going.
Speaker 4:  And like, if you wanna run a website, great. Get
Speaker 4:  your own audience. Like don't be relying on Google search to get your audience.
Speaker 4:  And I, I mean if anyone has listened to for like the past five years, you
Speaker 4:  know that I, I believe this in my bones, like the the deepest level that
Speaker 4:  being addicted to Google is like bad for the media industry, but
Speaker 4:  it's, the media industry is addicted to Google and there's no like transition
Speaker 4:  plan. It's like, oh, you're, we're just gonna kill you. Yeah. And they're
Speaker 4:  fine with it. And I don't think the
Speaker 4:  audience understands what's happening to the information environment that
Speaker 4:  they're in. Like I, that, that to me is like the hardest part of this. That
Speaker 4:  suddenly Google is full of summaries of things that might be garbage or
Speaker 4:  the AI itself is hallucinating or the good sources of
Speaker 4:  information are now at war with Google and you're not even getting them
Speaker 4:  'cause they're in a fight. So another piece of this is all just
Speaker 4:  a swirl of what is gonna happen to the web, The New York Times
Speaker 4:  today, this morning before we started recording announced they
Speaker 4:  are, they've inked a generative AI deal with Amazon and it broadly
Speaker 4:  tracks the deals that like everyone has made with open ai, Vox Media has
Speaker 4:  a deal with, with open ad. It's like this that Amazon's gonna train on New York
Speaker 4:  Times content, New York Times stuff will appear at Alexa and other Amazon
Speaker 4:  services. It's a licensing deal. Yeah. And a lot of media companies are setting
Speaker 4:  these deals 'cause they wanna set a market for what the license looks like.
Speaker 4:  So again, disclosure, Vox Media is one of the deals with OpenAI. I have no
Speaker 4:  idea what the terms are, but you know, Nick Thompson, the CEO of the Atlantic
Speaker 4:  was on here, was on the coder. And he was like, we need to set a market,
Speaker 4:  like some payments need to be made. So there are some numbers
Speaker 4:  for the inevitable court cases to come to some conclusion about.
Speaker 6:  And Amazon is a very useful rich company to sign one of those deals with
Speaker 6:  in that case,
Speaker 4:  Right? So The New York Times can't sign a deal with Open 'cause they're suing
Speaker 4:  them in Microsoft for copyright infringement. It's in a fight
Speaker 4:  with Google that times executives are on the board of the
Speaker 4:  News Media Alliance disclosure. Our executives are on the board of the News
Speaker 4:  Media Alliance. They're furious with Google about all the changes to search
Speaker 4:  and these traffic drops. They're, you know, a part of the publisher, ad tech
Speaker 4:  lawsuits, all that stuff. So they're in a fight with Google. So who's left,
Speaker 4:  who has big pockets that can set you a rate for a fight? It's Amazon, right?
Speaker 6:  Which also by the way, would like very much to make it more expensive for
Speaker 6:  all the other companies to do this job too.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Amazon wins. If they just set enormous rates for Google and open
Speaker 4:  ai, yeah, it's fine. But like, oh, this is a weird 'cause Amazon
Speaker 4:  doesn't give a shit at the web. They want Alexa to summarize times articles
Speaker 4:  for you every morning proactively or like whatever they think Alexa's gonna
Speaker 4:  do. They're not out here like, what's their browser called
Speaker 4:  on fire devices? Silk. They're not whatever. Like,
Speaker 4:  you know what I mean? Like their thing is like they need the training data
Speaker 4:  for their AI systems. They need to distribute it to their customers in new
Speaker 4:  and interesting ways because they're not gonna win as a web browser company.
Speaker 4:  Right. Which brings me to like the last little piece of the puzzle, which
Speaker 4:  is the browser company, which David, you have talked about
Speaker 4:  and profiled and covered at length. They stopped making their
Speaker 4:  browser, like they stopped making arc
Speaker 4:  because it's, there's no win there for them,
Speaker 6:  Right? They're in the middle of trying to figure out what the next bet is.
Speaker 6:  They have this new browser called dia, which is very much like so
Speaker 6:  far I got into the beta. I was not supposed to get into the beta, but I got
Speaker 6:  out into the beta and like, holy God, is it just chrome with a chatbot?
Speaker 6:  And the thing that's happening is, do you know what's also becoming Chrome
Speaker 6:  with a chatbot is Chrome and also every other browser that
Speaker 6:  exists. And So I think like for, for the browser
Speaker 6:  company, the big bet was like, okay, I if, if we can mix
Speaker 6:  AI with browsing data with like a, a device that you spend a lot
Speaker 6:  of time on, that can be very powerful. Agreed, great call browser company.
Speaker 6:  It turns out everybody else had that idea too. And this is just what's coming.
Speaker 6:  And then the flip side is like that stuff is being, that stuff
Speaker 6:  is being eaten up by the chat GPT app and the Claude app and
Speaker 6:  people using Siri badly and Gemini and
Speaker 6:  all this stuff. And so there is this like, again, it's, it's just what,
Speaker 6:  what is a webpage for anymore? And if, if I'm not
Speaker 6:  in the business of showing you webpages, what am I building?
Speaker 6:  And I don't think anybody knows the answer to that. And I think it's certainly
Speaker 6:  true that you can build a cool browser that a bunch of power users
Speaker 6:  like me will like, I like Arc a lot. I use it all day every day.
Speaker 6:  That doesn't appear to be the next thing. But no one knows quite what that
Speaker 6:  thing is yet because it's, it, it might not be showing you webpages.
Speaker 4:  I don't think It is that de comment at IO
Speaker 4:  about what kind of web do you build for agents first? It's the whole game.
Speaker 4:  It's the whole game.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So whatever you think Google search did to, to Google the web as a media
Speaker 4:  platform and it did a lot of things. It first it created
Speaker 4:  an entire economy for the web as a media platform, right? People search for
Speaker 4:  things. They went to webpages just like revolutionized the internet. Like
Speaker 4:  it created the internet as we know it in like meaningful ways. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Then it created SEO, which was less good then it created
Speaker 4:  the SEO industry and SEO slop and all this stuff. And it made
Speaker 4:  a whole ecosystem that worked and didn't work in whatever ways it worked.
Speaker 4:  And then even before AI showed up, Google started displaying
Speaker 4:  more and more of the content natively, right? What time is the Super Bowl
Speaker 4:  went from being a thing that people fought for to a thing that Google would
Speaker 4:  just tell you. And zero click searches, which is what they were called, were
Speaker 4:  an increasing part of Google's product for just a long time.
Speaker 4:  And the only searches that they would definitely send people to
Speaker 4:  websites for were commercial searches. Stuff where you bought
Speaker 4:  stuff and they were every, if you look at Google IO over the
Speaker 4:  years, every demo has always ended with a transaction because once you're
Speaker 4:  doing commercial searches, you get to charge for advertising. And so you
Speaker 4:  can buy yourself to the top of a commercial search, the top result,
Speaker 4:  you're the winner. You, you bought the AdWords auction for shoes, you
Speaker 4:  get the shoes click, you bought some shoes, right? Everyone's happy in
Speaker 4:  Google's ecosystem. And that has led to other weird outcomes, right? Where
Speaker 4:  you, you search for the name of a product, you get the competitor first because
Speaker 4:  they bought the ad for the name of the product. Weird outcome made Google
Speaker 4:  really rich. That's the web we knew. And then you see what, what
Speaker 4:  AI is doing to that web, right? It it we're, we're just reading the entire
Speaker 4:  web. Maybe that's copyright infringement, maybe it's not. Then we're just
Speaker 4:  gonna summarize it for you and give it to you and businesses will die.
Speaker 4:  Okay? We are gonna run that whole cycle, that 20 year cycle
Speaker 4:  in two minutes with web apps and agents. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  It's gonna run so fast because
Speaker 4:  the first wave of agents were not programmatic,
Speaker 4:  right? It was like, we're gonna go click around on the website for you
Speaker 4:  and Google has these projects, what's it? Mariner projects.
Speaker 4:  Mariner is Google runs Chrome for you in its data center and
Speaker 4:  a robot clicks around on a website for you and does the work.
Speaker 4:  And what Demis is saying is why are we doing this? Like this is
Speaker 4:  stupid. We should use these new AI first
Speaker 4:  protocols, which are basically just APIs but made for AI agents like
Speaker 4:  MCPA two A, there's, there's a whole alphabet
Speaker 4:  soup of these new protocols that are really interesting. And then the
Speaker 4:  agents are gonna go to a website which will just appear like a text prompt
Speaker 4:  database. They'll collect information outta the database and bring 'em back
Speaker 4:  to you. And once you have that web, okay, now you really do have the giant
Speaker 4:  worldwide interlinked application platform,
Speaker 4:  but you don't have websites, right? You just have a bunch of smart databases
Speaker 4:  talking to each other. Right? You're making me think of when I was talking
Speaker 4:  to the Google search team ahead of io,
Speaker 6:  Liz Reed, who runs the search team, basically made the argument
Speaker 6:  to me that the, the Google search ecosystem that we know now was
Speaker 6:  just a construct of the technology that we had.
Speaker 6:  That basically all, all we had the technology to do was
Speaker 6:  look forward words in a place. And it was something else. Had
Speaker 6:  to put them in a place in an order that made sense. And all Google's technology
Speaker 6:  was able to do was look for it, right? It was somebody else's job to
Speaker 6:  make it something human possible. And now we have technology
Speaker 6:  that can make this stuff human possible that maybe we don't need the middleman
Speaker 6:  of somebody building a thing around it that I can look at. And I think
Speaker 6:  that is like, I, I don't think she meant it to seem like a
Speaker 6:  as huge a statement as she did, but to say
Speaker 4:  Like the, and I think
Speaker 6:  It, it reminds me of the thing you always say about Twitter, right? Which
Speaker 6:  is that like criticism of the current Twitter does not
Speaker 6:  absolve past versions of the company from
Speaker 6:  being terrible.
Speaker 4:  Jack Dorsey was also bad. The Neli Patel story,
Speaker 6:  Right? Like I think the, the argument I think Google is, is
Speaker 6:  making, but doesn't quite wanna say out loud is that the way
Speaker 6:  that we've done it for the last 25 years wasn't the right answer. It was
Speaker 6:  just the one that Google came up with and now they think they have a better
Speaker 6:  one. And so they're like, well we, we, we sort of reoriented
Speaker 6:  around one thing and now we have a better thing. Why wouldn't we reorient
Speaker 6:  again? And I think in a, in a vacuum
Speaker 6:  that's like a reasonable thing to say, right? Like, we built a better thing,
Speaker 6:  we're gonna do the thing. But then they're doing the thing that every tech
Speaker 6:  company does, which is just utterly fail to think about the downstream effects
Speaker 6:  of their decisions.
Speaker 4:  Oh, I think they've thought about those effects. You
Speaker 6:  Think,
Speaker 4:  And I think they've come to the conclusion after getting beat up for three
Speaker 4:  years at IO about AI and the downstream effects on the web and
Speaker 4:  being in lawsuits. Like they're like, we don't care. Like if we
Speaker 4:  don't get here, someone else will get here first. And it would be better,
Speaker 4:  it will be better to take the hits and survive than
Speaker 4:  to try to play nice and lose.
Speaker 6:  That's the Mark Zuckerberg joker story. Like that's what happens. Yeah. You
Speaker 6:  get beat up enough times that you, you turn into the joker. And that is,
Speaker 6:  that's what Mark Zuckerberg did. And
Speaker 4:  I think they're also not for nothing. They're looking at the information
Speaker 4:  environment they operate in and be like, well, YouTube is bigger than ever.
Speaker 4:  The information is on YouTube. I
Speaker 6:  Mean, It is probably true that if all the websites went away, Google would
Speaker 6:  be fine. And I think Google kind of knows that.
Speaker 4:  I, I don't know. I I I think that is more of an open question than not.
Speaker 4:  'cause all it's gonna be left is slop like the last domino to fall here.
Speaker 4:  Like really the last domino is some scaled media
Speaker 4:  company opting out of being ranked,
Speaker 4:  right? So The New York Times says to Google, look, we've just had enough
Speaker 4:  stop, stop crawling us, stop ranking us, stop serving our news.
Speaker 4:  And that no one has the leverage against Google yet
Speaker 4:  at some point they will stop sending enough traffic that someone will make
Speaker 4:  that call. And, and, and I don't think they've thought that through, like
Speaker 4:  what happens when the web stops being universally available to Google? Right?
Speaker 4:  And who knows? Who knows, who knows. To answer to that
Speaker 6:  Question, even honestly, like my, my immediate reaction to that was to say
Speaker 6:  the that'll never happen because The New York Times needs Google a lot more
Speaker 6:  than Google needs The New York Times. But like the, the pure
Speaker 6:  perception hit that Google would take as a place that no longer
Speaker 6:  sees the whole internet might change it. Like there's
Speaker 6:  something would happen there.
Speaker 4:  There's some fine grain controls that are like very political here. So like
Speaker 4:  you can opt into Google search but not Google AI training, but there are
Speaker 4:  documents from the various trials. It's, you can see Google executives working
Speaker 4:  through those options, right? And even creating those options and saying,
Speaker 4:  well maybe one day we're gonna get to, if you wanna be searched,
Speaker 4:  you wanna be crawled for the search engine, you have to opt into AI training
Speaker 4:  again, if things continue the way they're going, some
Speaker 4:  big media company is gonna say, take we're out. Yeah, take us out of this.
Speaker 4:  I I don dunno when that's gonna be, but like that's the trend line. And that's
Speaker 4:  when I'm like, the web is a media platform is just under enormous amounts
Speaker 4:  of pressure. It's, it's hard to, it's hard to see the through line, but
Speaker 4:  I, I know when things are changing, you know, like I can't see the
Speaker 4:  finish line. I can't see what it looks like at the end, but I know we're
Speaker 4:  at the beginning of a new phase without any question at all.
Speaker 6:  Yes.
Speaker 4:  Something massive is happening here as, yeah, Google is adding a
Speaker 4:  agents to Chrome. Like that's just a thing that they're trying to do.
Speaker 4:  More and more people are talking about using the web as basically a series
Speaker 4:  of database like sooner than interview. It is like, what is the web at a
Speaker 4:  series of databases? Like
Speaker 6:  I also think you, like you, you said to him a thing you, you say a lot, which
Speaker 6:  is that if you, if we were starting The Verge again today, you wouldn't start
Speaker 6:  a website, you'd start a TikTok channel and he sort of pushed back.
Speaker 6:  But what he said was pretty much in, in as many words he
Speaker 6:  said, sure you'd start a TikTok channel, but it's only like 2%
Speaker 6:  more work to have a web presence. So you'd probably do that too. And it's
Speaker 6:  like, even if that's true, that is such a, I
Speaker 6:  don't think he realized the extent to which he was telling on himself by
Speaker 6:  saying that. Yeah. And I just, I've been thinking about that ever since.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. When
Speaker 4:  We started The Verge, a hundred percent of our effort was the website.
Speaker 6:  Right? But like, oh, but sure you'll, you'll like, you know, do a WordPress
Speaker 6:  template and put it on the internet. Just why not?
Speaker 4:  No, I think his answer is much more like it's 2% more work. 'cause you'll
Speaker 4:  prompt Gemini to read your TikTok channel and stand up a website. Like
Speaker 4:  that's what he meant by 2% more work. And by the way, what I, when I keep
Speaker 4:  saying there's no way we would start a website today, what I mean is that
Speaker 4:  we started the Virgin 2011 when cell phones still had three inch
Speaker 4:  screens. Like we, we launched The Verge as basically a
Speaker 4:  desktop app.
Speaker 6:  Those are the days.
Speaker 4:  Like that's what the venture capital money was for. It was, it was just a
Speaker 4:  very different time. We would just never do that today. Like
Speaker 4:  you would go address an audience in a different way. And that's what every
Speaker 4:  new media company is trying to do, essentially. I don know. I
Speaker 4:  would just say go listen to that, that conversation again. You'll hear more
Speaker 4:  pushback than you think. And a lot of It is
Speaker 4:  kind of predicated around,
Speaker 4:  well it's, it's fine if these things die right? It because other things
Speaker 4:  are growing, which makes sense, like on, on the broadest scale that it's
Speaker 4:  true. That's just life. But you, you see, there's
Speaker 4:  no longer a defense of like, the things are dying. It's, look at all the
Speaker 4:  stuff that's growing. The one thing that could complicate this, and by the
Speaker 4:  time you're listening to this, it'll, it will have probably happened,
Speaker 4:  is that it's closing arguments in the Google search
Speaker 4:  antitrust remedies phase on Friday. Tomorrow
Speaker 4:  as you're listening to this has already happened, that's the case where the
Speaker 4:  government is asking for Google to be forced to sell Chrome. And
Speaker 4:  I asked Sudar about this, I said, can you do all the stuff you can you wanna
Speaker 4:  do if you have to sell Chrome? And he just didn't answer. And his final version
Speaker 4:  of this, when I knew I'd hit the brick wall, he said, that's not even what
Speaker 4:  we're looking at. And I was like, well you should, 'cause it might happen
Speaker 4:  to you.
Speaker 6:  I mean, to be clear, like two things. A, that's clearly a
Speaker 6:  lie and B, he can't tell you anything because it's like ongoing
Speaker 6:  litigation, right? Like that's a, that's a thing a lawyer looks him in the
Speaker 6:  eyes and says, Hey Sundar, you cannot say words about this or
Speaker 6:  everyone goes to jail. But like that's, you're
Speaker 6:  right that that is, that is the question. And I think whether
Speaker 6:  this ends up being good for the web though, is hard to know.
Speaker 6:  It's clearly bad for Google. Whatever's gonna happen is gonna be bad for
Speaker 6:  Google. But does this just give
Speaker 6:  open AI new distribution for chat GPT to do the same kind of stuff?
Speaker 6:  Or is there a version of this that actually accrues back to the idea
Speaker 6:  that the web as a place full of web pages that people go to is a
Speaker 6:  good and valuable idea? 100%.
Speaker 6:  TBD Like genuinely unknown. And I think it's part of what everyone
Speaker 6:  has tried to reckon with in this trial is like, what happens if we do this?
Speaker 6:  There is a sense that like, we're gonna make it possible for
Speaker 6:  a bunch of other companies to build search engines. But if you believe Google,
Speaker 6:  the whole premise of a search engine is going away and all anyone will do
Speaker 6:  is take that search index and build AI products. And if that's what's
Speaker 6:  happening, then we've, we've solved one kind of Google problem,
Speaker 6:  but we've just sped up the killing of the web.
Speaker 4:  We so believing Google there and you know, you have to believe them when
Speaker 4:  they say like, AI overviews are our most used product ever. And it's like,
Speaker 4:  'cause you put them in all the pages. I know no one's picking
Speaker 4:  like they're just doing what's in front of them. So I
Speaker 6:  Punched you in the face, you've been punched like you loved it. I dunno.
Speaker 4:  We'll see, I like, there's a lot here. The reason I
Speaker 4:  wanted to add all these things up together is you can see the change,
Speaker 4:  like, You know, a year from now The New York
Speaker 4:  Times will run a story about how the web changed and I'll be like, yeah,
Speaker 4:  I listened to the, I caught that a year ago. 'cause this is the moment,
Speaker 4:  right? Apple's weird weaknesses, Google's
Speaker 4:  apparent strength all kind of built around. Like where do the apps
Speaker 4:  come from? How do you use them? How is the user interface
Speaker 4:  just gonna be a bunch of natural language? Are the, you know, Google's vision
Speaker 4:  is that you'll search for something, it will build you an app on the fly
Speaker 4:  and make a new interface to data for you, which is pretty cool.
Speaker 4:  Like, that's a cool way to think about interacting with the search
Speaker 4:  engine. Yeah. Many things have to die for that to happen. Like
Speaker 4:  the dinosaurs were cool, mammals were cooler. Like, sorry bro. Like it's
Speaker 4:  over like the asteroids gonna hit you. That's where I
Speaker 4:  I I perceive that as clearly as I can now. Like
Speaker 4:  that's the change that's coming. Yeah. The application models are changing
Speaker 4:  and Apple's weakness is, are they ready for it? And Google's perceived
Speaker 4:  strength is, they're ahead of it, but Google has big questions to answer
Speaker 4:  to and the downstream effects are like pretty huge this time. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And if you're wondering by the way, what is the best possible outcome here?
Speaker 6:  The answer is the fedi verse. Like if you walk this back all the way to the
Speaker 6:  beginning of you and I talking about all of this stuff and like how do we,
Speaker 6:  how do we take the things that are good about this and make it the size of
Speaker 6:  the web and part of the web. That's how you do it. Yeah. That's the stuff.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. Like big interoperability, which we have to
Speaker 4:  demand as consumers this time. Yeah. Like the, I don't think the federal
Speaker 4:  government is gonna demand interoperability although they are in court. You
Speaker 4:  never know. Some settlement could happen. Alright, we gotta take a break.
Speaker 4:  We're gonna come back with a lightning round, which I have been told, I don't
Speaker 4:  know, but I have been told It is sponsored. We'll be right back.
Speaker 4:  we don't do the ads. We refuse to do the ads that we're precious about it.
Speaker 4:  That's our editorial independence coming through loud and clear. But
Speaker 4:  the lightning round is sponsored this week, so someone
Speaker 4:  has to say it. So Eric, our producer, Eric's gonna say it.
Speaker 4:  Eric, go ahead.
Speaker 6:  That was great Eric. Really good job. Well done. I'm really proud of you.
Speaker 4:  So there are gonna be so many reactions to that based on what you're said.
Speaker 4:  Very good. Don't worry though. Still full flavor. 'cause you can't tell
Speaker 6:  What's the flavor rating now, how do you feel?
Speaker 4:  I, I'm gonna, I'm I'll drink through this later. All that's fine.
Speaker 4:  Great. You, you two can sponsor the wedding, right? The
Speaker 4:  problem is when you cover for not getting the sponsors by insisting that
Speaker 4:  the sponsors are bad.
Speaker 4:  I did this to myself, but anyway, still full flavor. 'cause you can't tell
Speaker 4:  us what to do. The Verge subscriptions are on sale.
Speaker 4:  You see what I'm saying? I'm gonna get better at this, David. All right,
Speaker 4:  it's time.
Speaker 6:  Speaking of people who would like to tell us what to do, it's time once again
Speaker 6:  for America's favorite podcast. Within a podcast. A thing I can just say,
Speaker 6:  because you can just say things in America in 2025,
Speaker 6:  Brendan Carr is a dummy neli according to the links I'm seeing here.
Speaker 6:  Kind of a busy week for our man. Brendan,
Speaker 4:  Like busy in, in inconsequential ways.
Speaker 6:  Oh, Brendan's favorite.
Speaker 4:  You know what I mean? Like he, a lot of people had reactions to Brendan this
Speaker 4:  week.
Speaker 6:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  And, you know, Brendan continued to just like break stuff in the way that
Speaker 4:  Brendan breaks stuff. But the, the chair of our nation's Federal Communications
Speaker 4:  Commission, It is sort of busy just breaking stuff. So we
Speaker 4:  ran a big story this week about the bead program. It's the Biden
Speaker 4:  administration's broadband rollout. Lots of criticism of the
Speaker 4:  bead program, which is supposed to bring broadband to many, many more people,
Speaker 4:  especially in rural areas across the country. We have long talked about how
Speaker 4:  rural internet is like a disaster. And so Biden passes this big bill,
Speaker 4:  the bead money is supposed to go out, we're supposed to get internet connections.
Speaker 4:  Everyone's like, where's the money? We didn't connect one person. Ezra Klein
Speaker 4:  has sold millions of copies of his book pointing out that bead didn't sell
Speaker 4:  make one in internet connection. That's, it's fine. It's a, it's a meaningful
Speaker 4:  criticism of this program. The Trump administration is basically shutting
Speaker 4:  this program down on the cusp of it actually starting to do the things it
Speaker 4:  wants to do. So West Davis, his last big piece for us as a reporter
Speaker 4:  here at The Verge, is a deep look at bead where it stands and what's happening
Speaker 4:  to it. And what is fundamentally happening to It is that the
Speaker 4:  money was starting to go out to build fiber connections across
Speaker 4:  the country. And everyone showed up, including our boy, Brendan
Speaker 4:  and Howard Lutnick, the commerce secretary, looked at this and said, no,
Speaker 4:  no, no, no, we want to give the money to
Speaker 4:  Starlink to satellite internet. 'cause when they say satellite internet,
Speaker 4:  they, they only mean one thing. They don't mean Hughes net.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You're not giving it to Kuper. Like, what are, what are we doing here?
Speaker 4:  They mean Starlink. Yeah. So I, we've all this reporting, all these
Speaker 4:  quotes, we did a great job of this story. You know,
Speaker 4:  basically saying they were very close to rolling
Speaker 4:  out like full fiber connections to every single person in West Virginia.
Speaker 4:  Like that's, that was the plan for the bead money. They were
Speaker 4:  gonna be able to do it with $150 million to spare and ahead of its deadline.
Speaker 4:  And now it's gonna shift a bunch of that investment to satellite.
Speaker 4:  And that's fine. Maybe you love Starlink. But the reality is, and I will
Speaker 4:  disclose Comcast through its NBC Universal Arm is an investor parenting
Speaker 4:  company of Vox Media, but they hate me. So that's fine. I, I've not a friend
Speaker 4:  to the ice piece here, but I'm just gonna point out that wired connections
Speaker 4:  are generally superior to wireless ones,
Speaker 6:  Especially when they've already been built and exists.
Speaker 4:  Especially when there's already the infrastructure, especially when the wired
Speaker 4:  connections are so much faster than the satellite connections and do not
Speaker 4:  require line of sight, which Starlink still requires line of sight.
Speaker 4:  So we're just at this place where this program, which
Speaker 4:  there are many, many realistic criticisms of It, is now running into
Speaker 4:  political expediency. And in particular, Brendan loves to talk about
Speaker 4:  Sterling satellite 'cause he loves Elon Musk and he, he's captured
Speaker 4:  moron. So that's one for Brendan.
Speaker 6:  $20 billion by the way, is is the, the number
Speaker 6:  we've seen floating around that this is the bead is a
Speaker 6:  42.6, I think billion dollar program. And
Speaker 6:  the, the reporting is that as much as 20 billion of that could
Speaker 6:  just get thrown directly at Starlink to do
Speaker 6:  something.
Speaker 4:  And it's fine. Look, Wes did a great job of this story. I encourage you to
Speaker 4:  read it. It'll be in the show notes. The, there are lots of
Speaker 4:  people in the story who say, look, fiber is not practical for a hundred percent
Speaker 4:  of population. Of course, we were gonna also do Starlink in satellite and
Speaker 4:  other fixed wireless solutions for a lot of people, there's a
Speaker 4:  administrator in the state of Nevada who says, we, we, this is what we were
Speaker 4:  gonna do there. But the ratios are being flipped to favor strong. It's just
Speaker 4:  like naked correction.
Speaker 6:  We're just gonna put little ultra wideband 5G things
Speaker 6:  everywhere around America. It's gonna solve all our problems. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  As 5G does. Speaking of 5G you'll recall,
Speaker 4:  I think it was last week, a couple weeks ago, we, we had basically a moral
Speaker 4:  dilemma because of Brendan where we couldn't tell who the villain was in
Speaker 4:  a particular Brendan story. Didn't
Speaker 6:  Like that. So
Speaker 4:  Brendan sent a letter to Dish Network saying, Hey,
Speaker 4:  you were supposed to build a nationwide 5G network
Speaker 4:  to compete with T-Mobile at and t and Verizon. And you're supposed to do
Speaker 4:  that because we allowed T-Mobile to buy Sprint and to preserve
Speaker 4:  competition in America. We gave you Boost Mobile and a bunch of
Speaker 4:  spectrum and a bunch of money. And they're supposed to be network and there's
Speaker 4:  no network. And I'm Brendan Carr and I love being angry at stuff. And now
Speaker 4:  I'm gonna yell at you Charlie Ergen, CEO of Dish Network. And it's hard to
Speaker 4:  tell who the villain in that story is, but truly hard. Like you're making
Speaker 4:  the right criticisms for the wrong totally politically motivated reasons.
Speaker 4:  That's Brendan Carr on a good day. Like that's the best we can hope for
Speaker 4:  him. Yes. So Dish Network has chosen to fight back
Speaker 4:  a bunch of partners of EchoStar. A bunch of its vendors
Speaker 4:  are saying that Dish is actually building a network.
Speaker 4:  They say that they have 7 million customers, the majority of
Speaker 4:  whom are still basically roaming on at and t and T-Mobile,
Speaker 4:  but they're their own network is serving 1.3 million people.
Speaker 4:  Oh. Remind either America has somewhere over 300 million people. So
Speaker 4:  as a nationwide competitor to the Bigs not doing great,
Speaker 6:  What's wild is I still that even that number still seems too high to me.
Speaker 6:  Like that 1.3 million
Speaker 4:  Is like, if you are one of the 1.3 million people in America
Speaker 4:  who are getting native 5G service from Dish Network,
Speaker 4:  call me. Yeah, I don't believe you
Speaker 6:  Exist. Call me from your Echo Star phone.
Speaker 4:  That's like a huge 90 satellite. And they're saying they,
Speaker 4:  they gained 88,000 wireless subscribers in April.
Speaker 4:  So that means 88,000 people in April signed up for Dish Network's
Speaker 4:  5G Service. You tell me who you are.
Speaker 4:  I am guessing they mean Boost Mobile, which is their owned and operated
Speaker 4:  prepaid service, right? Sure. Great. That's the
Speaker 4:  state of play Dish is fighting back by claiming it has 1.3 million
Speaker 4:  5G customers running on its network and everyone else is effectively by
Speaker 4:  at t and T-Mobile service reselling on its own name.
Speaker 4:  All that sucks. Like that is not what was supposed to happen. By the way,
Speaker 4:  a deal that Ajit Pie made that Brendan is, and Brendan, you know, he's part
Speaker 4:  of, he was part of that chain and now he's trying to unwind it by yelling
Speaker 4:  at Charlie. So I know what's going on there. I do know that
Speaker 4:  Brendan, what does he wanna do with the spectrum that he wants to reclaim
Speaker 4:  from Dish? He wants to give it to Starlink. Yep. Other
Speaker 4:  satellite companies have also started acting for the spectrum. This is just
Speaker 4:  dumb naked corruption that started with a dumb, naked corrupt deal that
Speaker 4:  Ajit Pie made that Brendan is carrying on. That's life
Speaker 4:  Last, last two little bits of Brendan, like I said, he is just like carrying
Speaker 4:  on breaking stuff.
Speaker 4:  Anna Gomez, who's the last Democratic commissioner on the
Speaker 4:  FCC, they're supposed to, you know, have five and it's supposed to be three
Speaker 4:  two depending on who whose party has the presidency. Right now they're,
Speaker 4:  it's three one. So we're doing great.
Speaker 4:  She's on tour. She's doing this like First Amendment tour pointing out
Speaker 4:  that Brendan is a threat to free speech. So she's like going to college
Speaker 4:  campuses. We've talked about her before. I'm gonna, we're I'm gonna try to
Speaker 4:  get her on one of these shows.
Speaker 6:  Do you think she's our competition in the Brendan Carr as the dummy podcast
Speaker 6:  space? Like I, I hear she's going on tour and I'm like, maybe we need to
Speaker 6:  go on our own
Speaker 4:  Tour. We should go on our own tour. We should combine forces. I mean, she's
Speaker 4:  also a politician and I have a number of questions for why the FCC is totally
Speaker 4:  ineffective and weak that I could direct at her as well. And so I've done
Speaker 4:  to every FCC person that has ever appeared on,
Speaker 6:  All right, so we're gonna go on a tour that exactly matches her tour and
Speaker 6:  we're just gonna be like one building away. Yep.
Speaker 4:  It's gonna be like, you know, they, they all suck anyhow.
Speaker 4:  She's on tour. She's the
Speaker 6:  Us with the party speaker and microphones just yelling at Anna Gomez.
Speaker 4:  We'll get a bigger party speaker. We'll get that JBL man that thing's hot.
Speaker 4:  Anna is saying that it's an administration Wide Effort to chill speech and
Speaker 4:  stifle dissenting voices. And she says it, Brendan is
Speaker 4:  leading a clear effort to quash descent.
Speaker 4:  She's basically picking the fight. She's like trying to get fired. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  She's even saying, I will probably get fired for doing this. And so far Trump
Speaker 4:  hasn't fired her. I don't think that he knows that she exists, but it's coming.
Speaker 4:  This is the next turn. She's gonna make enough noise and get fired. And she's,
Speaker 6:  I mean, you don't do this unless that's the outcome you're assuming is happening.
Speaker 4:  Her quote, she says, I don't know why I'm still in my job.
Speaker 4:  And then she says, if I get fired, it isn't because I didn't do my job, it's
Speaker 4:  because I insisted upon doing it by what she means, protecting
Speaker 6:  Research. So I feel every time you and I record The Verge cast,
Speaker 4:  That's very good. All of this has ended in maybe the most
Speaker 4:  pretzel like logic of all in the pages of the Wall Street Journal
Speaker 4:  opinion section where they have attacked Brendan this week
Speaker 4:  for being an authoritarian censorship machine.
Speaker 4:  And their response because of the Wall Street Journal is that the entire
Speaker 4:  FCC should be shut down and turned over to the private market.
Speaker 6:  Give it to Starlink. He's just like,
Speaker 4:  Just like full horseshoe theory of politics. Like
Speaker 4:  even the most libertarian opinion section that you can get in the Wall Street
Speaker 4:  Journal is like, yeah, that dude sucks. Like he's misusing government power.
Speaker 4:  Shut it all down.
Speaker 6:  I do like the idea of a privatized FCC, what could possibly go wrong?
Speaker 4:  You know, it's not like the, there's not like there's scarce wireless spectrum
Speaker 4:  and you want to protect things like the FAA from people's cell phone emissions.
Speaker 4:  Like whatever. Why would you ever wanna do that? Yeah. But it's great. I
Speaker 4:  love it. I I do love the fact that Brendan has United left and right
Speaker 4:  in just pure hatred of his moronic censor censorship machine that
Speaker 4:  he's building. He's a dummy and it's, it's rare that I'm like,
Speaker 4:  you should read this Wall Street Journal opinion page piece. As
Speaker 4:  always, I remind you the only politics we can we consistently express in
Speaker 4:  the show are that free markets are pretty good competition makes better products
Speaker 4:  and you should be a little bit less racist than Brendan Carr. If you think
Speaker 4:  that's wildly leftist, you are free to believe that. But that's what you
Speaker 4:  get from us. And also now I'm telling you, I agree with the Wall Street
Speaker 4:  Journal subpoena pages
Speaker 6:  Telling you man, strange bedfellows these days.
Speaker 4:  It's weird times here in America. Yeah. As ever, Brendan, you're welcome
Speaker 4:  to come on the show and defend any of this stuff. You can appear via Starlink
Speaker 4:  if you want. You, you too can be sponsored by your buddy Elon, but
Speaker 4:  I don't think you we'll ever do it. 'cause I think you're a coward and a
Speaker 4:  dummy. So if you want to prove me wrong, all of our, all of our platforms
Speaker 4:  are available to you. I will say that David are both having children soon,
Speaker 4:  so the clock is ticking my man. Yeah, yeah. You gotta get, you gotta get
Speaker 4:  on here,
Speaker 6:  Brendan. If you wanna host The Vergecast this summer, get at us. We can talk
Speaker 6:  about it.
Speaker 4:  That door shockingly open
Speaker 4:  dying to know what Brendan
Speaker 6:  Thinks, but you do have to do Brendan Carr a dummy every week.
Speaker 4:  I love it. All right. We need a pallet cleanser. What do you got?
Speaker 6:  It's almost switch time. Are you, are you, did you buy a switch?
Speaker 4:  I did not. Okay. I did not. So I play one video game, Madden and I at
Speaker 4:  the point now where I've, I've mastered last year's Madden just in time
Speaker 4:  for the new one to come out.
Speaker 6:  Oh, that's, I mean, that's, that's the ideal Madden scenario.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I'm also waiting for metal gear, solid snake eater delta force
Speaker 4:  or whatever it's called to come out pins and needles for that one. But that's
Speaker 4:  not switch stuff.
Speaker 6:  Okay. No, but the switch to is coming next week,
Speaker 6:  June 5th,
Speaker 6:  easily to me, the gadget of the year, like not knowing everything we know
Speaker 6:  about the rest of the year. I can't imagine what would have to happen for
Speaker 6:  the switch two to not be the most consequential piece of hardware that's
Speaker 6:  coming out.
Speaker 6:  We're learning a bunch of stuff about it already. As far as I can tell.
Speaker 6:  Nintendo seems to have been pretty tight with like, who's getting, it's not
Speaker 6:  like there's been like a, you know, Casey Nys stat hands-on
Speaker 6:  or like a bunch of like lifestyle influencers getting to use the thing like
Speaker 6:  not that many people seem to have switched to yet, but stuff is starting
Speaker 6:  to trickle out somebody. There was an unboxing video that somebody did that
Speaker 6:  got immediately yanked offline. We've been covering kind of
Speaker 6:  the run up to it a bunch. J Peters wrote a really good story basically being
Speaker 6:  like the switch to is the we you done correctly,
Speaker 6:  which is both like a good point and kind of a sick burn on all of Nintendo's
Speaker 6:  history.
Speaker 6:  But I just think this is like, it's a really interesting gadget moment
Speaker 6:  in that I think if the switch to is everything we think it might be,
Speaker 6:  I kind of think it's a big deal just as a piece of hardware. Like if we
Speaker 6:  have this thing that really makes portable gaming that is
Speaker 6:  high end and long lasting and like the, the fact that the Mario Kart game
Speaker 6:  is like an open world Mario Kart game that you can play anywhere
Speaker 6:  demands a lot of the hardware, it demands a lot of the wireless. Like if
Speaker 6:  this stuff works, I think we're, we get to the point where like
Speaker 6:  there's just a lot of things that suddenly start to feel possible in gadget
Speaker 6:  design that I'm very excited about, which is a lot to say
Speaker 6:  about a slightly bigger switch, but like, it's really how I feel.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I mean, you're all the way in on Gadget of the Year.
Speaker 6:  Oh, hands down. Like, I, I what else could, like, I I, I
Speaker 6:  have such a hard time imagining something be more
Speaker 6:  important than the switch too. Like, if this thing sucks, it's gonna be
Speaker 6:  devastating. But also again, like I think if, if Nintendo
Speaker 6:  just takes all these ideas that it had about the sort of
Speaker 6:  modularity and the portability and this idea that you can have a thing that
Speaker 6:  connects to all of your screens and all of your devices all at once and actually
Speaker 6:  makes that like another tick better in every respect,
Speaker 6:  it's just gonna be amazing. And there's so many ideas that if you just broaden
Speaker 6:  it out slightly starts to change. Like, oh, how do we think about our other
Speaker 6:  gadgets? And like what if Nintendo is doing all the
Speaker 6:  like, handoff stuff that Apple has never successfully done with
Speaker 6:  its devices. Like why can't I dock my iPhone into my television Neli?
Speaker 6:  Why
Speaker 6:  Nintendo figured it out.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It's funny, apple, one of the other coats of paint rumors about Apple
Speaker 4:  is, so we're gonna redo Game Center to make it more like Xbox Live.
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. There's like a, it's, it's a whole app.
Speaker 4:  You can see the convergence here. Yeah. Look, I I think it's possible to
Speaker 4:  switch to is the, the device of the year. I, I think certainly it will be
Speaker 4:  the gaming device of the year and it's the one that people are the most excited
Speaker 4:  about. Certainly the games look great from the coverage we've done and that
Speaker 4:  our reporters have gotten to, to try out, but Cash of the Year is a big one.
Speaker 6:  I I could, I, I mean, as somebody who covers gadgets, I hope
Speaker 6:  I'm wrong. It's fun if I'm wrong, but I just think, I mean, this
Speaker 6:  one's really interesting because the first switch when it came out was like
Speaker 6:  cool and exciting, but it was a, it was a breath of the Wild machine, right?
Speaker 6:  Like that's fundamentally what it was. And this one is making much
Speaker 6:  more of a hardware first play. Like there are lots of new
Speaker 6:  games, but some of the new games are also gonna play in the old Switch and
Speaker 6:  there's nothing as sort of immediately
Speaker 6:  earth shattering as there was with Breath of the Wild. And So I think
Speaker 6:  the idea that this thing is gonna have to sell itself as hardware A
Speaker 6:  seems to be a thing. Nintendo knows and b is going to be super fascinating
Speaker 6:  and they're trying to do all this interesting ecosystem software. They're
Speaker 6:  like, what if we, you know, sell you a third party camera that connects to
Speaker 6:  the thing I'm telling you? Like, I have been wanting modular gadgets for
Speaker 6:  as long as I have known you, and this is the closest thing to properly
Speaker 6:  pulling that off if it pulls it off that I think we've ever seen.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. All right. Maybe I'll buy one.
Speaker 6:  I So here's my question for you is should I go stand in
Speaker 6:  line at a GameStop at midnight to try and buy this thing? Yes. Like, am I
Speaker 4:  Just for the content, do it for the Gram?
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I think I'm going to, obviously I'm dying to know, have you read any
Speaker 4:  of this new Apple in China book, by the way? No, there's just long,
Speaker 4:  it's, it's really interesting. There's a lot of reporting in there, but a
Speaker 4:  lot of It is about how the Apple we know is more shaped
Speaker 4:  by like Chinese resellers standing in line than, than anyone can
Speaker 4:  possibly see. Oh,
Speaker 6:  Interesting.
Speaker 4:  And that's, that's really the story of gadget lines now. Like we've all but
Speaker 4:  stopped covering them because it's basically a bunch of resellers standing
Speaker 4:  in line. Yes. And it's like, it's not like a joyous community. It's,
Speaker 4:  It is kind of gross and, and in a lot of ways. But I think you should go
Speaker 4:  and be like, I'm here for joyous community
Speaker 6:  And then just interview a bunch of resellers, see what happens,
Speaker 4:  See what they're like. I like it. Be like So you're flipping the switch,
Speaker 4:  huh? How much?
Speaker 6:  All right. Well, I will, I will report back next week, but I think, I think
Speaker 6:  I'm gonna do it. I'm gonna go to GameStop and see what kind of trouble I
Speaker 6:  can get into. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  All right. We should end with breaking news. The tariffs have been paused,
Speaker 4:  David,
Speaker 4:  while we, while we were talking, the tariffs are back on the pause of the,
Speaker 4:  while the pause of the tariffs was paused. Do you understand what
Speaker 6:  I'm saying? We've, we've unpaused by, by
Speaker 4:  Pause the Court of Appeals has blocked the pausing of the tariffs.
Speaker 6:  I don't care. I'm
Speaker 4:  Over it. That's, that's what I'm saying. Elon Musk is outta the White House,
Speaker 4:  by the way. Elon Musk, you know, he, they, it's clear that he got himself.
Speaker 4:  No one likes him anymore. So he is been off boarded officially from Doge.
Speaker 4:  He's on a to interview circuit right now. Yeah. He spoke to Ars
Speaker 4:  Technica with CBS news, I think with the Washington Post. He's, he's trying
Speaker 4:  to make a big show of being back at Tesla. Tesla sales are tanking around
Speaker 4:  the world, but like in ways that are like hard to cover,
Speaker 4:  like in, in Europe in one quarter they're down. Right?
Speaker 4:  They're, they've cratered in Quebec. It's like you gotta,
Speaker 4:  whatever, there's a bunch of data that says a story in like weird
Speaker 4:  independent ways and then they're supposed to launch the roboto taxis like
Speaker 4:  soon.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Tweet. He, he's been saying they're like out on the road doing stuff,
Speaker 6:  right? Yeah.
Speaker 4:  There's driverless cars in Austin. So if you're in Austin and you see
Speaker 4:  a party speaker or a robo taxi, let, let me know. If you see
Speaker 6:  A party speaker and a robo in one photo,
Speaker 6:  we will send you VERGE merch. I can't, I don't know what it'll be, but I'll
Speaker 6:  send you something.
Speaker 4:  I will send you a party speaker. That'd
Speaker 6:  Be great. Yeah. But I think the, just the, the one thing I've been thinking
Speaker 6:  a lot about with the, the Musk stuff is the, the thing he keeps saying in
Speaker 6:  all these interviews is that he's like back to sleeping on factory floors
Speaker 6:  and in conference rooms at Tesla. And it's like, it's very much a show
Speaker 6:  of I am back paying attention to my company designed
Speaker 6:  especially to like, you know, appease investors
Speaker 6:  who have been worried about Tesla being completely ignored by its
Speaker 6:  CEO for a long time. I'm very curious to see how
Speaker 6:  that helps Tesla's case
Speaker 6:  versus again, like with, with these sales changes, this ongoing
Speaker 6:  disastrous branding that the company has gone through because of Elon Musk
Speaker 6:  that is like, he is the, the company's greatest asset and
Speaker 6:  worst problem. And that's been true for a long time, but for a long time
Speaker 6:  at least financially asset outweighed problem pretty aggressively.
Speaker 6:  And it really feels like that has flipped. And I, I'm just curious to see
Speaker 6:  if he can change that perception just by being back at
Speaker 6:  Tesla more. But I don't, I don't see it.
Speaker 4:  I don't either. I don don't see it. There's, there's nothing to be done in
Speaker 4:  the factory for him.
Speaker 6:  No.
Speaker 4:  What's he like? He's not, he can't invent a new car to fix it right now.
Speaker 4:  Like Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I think that's also increasingly clear to a lot of people is that the, the
Speaker 6:  sleeping at the factory might have been a bit and maybe not part of my man's
Speaker 6:  day-to-day job.
Speaker 4:  Well, he's gotten more children than father
Speaker 4:  anyhow. The tariffs are are paused. You let me
Speaker 4:  know. There's a lot of updates. If you're out in the world, you let me, me
Speaker 4:  know what the tariffs are doing.
Speaker 4:  It's gonna be a weird iPhone season. iPhone prices are gonna be crazy. It
Speaker 4:  is because of these things. Yeah. All right. That's it. We've, we covered
Speaker 4:  as always. We went long. 'cause there it was a slow news week. This is what
Speaker 4:  always happens to us. It's this fun. It was a good one. We're back next week
Speaker 4:  with much more WDC preview. Lots, lots of
Speaker 4:  stuff. It's The Verge everybody. It's gonna be great. Pay us