# Transcript
ID: a96c78e1-a287-443a-b49f-a694250058d6
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/5576511540620979770/-7214953003380619982/s93290-US-6701s-1742550725.mp3
Description: Starlink is in the White House, Siri is still bad, Pebble is back, up is down, everything is chaos. In this episode, Nilay and David start the show by running through some big gadget news, from a Siri-related shakeup at Apple to the new Google Pixel 9A. After that, The Verge's Lauren Feiner talks us through some of the  latest in tech regulation: Trump's illegal firings at the FTC, the confusing state of the TikTok ban, OpenAI and Google arguing their case for free-for-all AI, and more. Finally, in the lightning round, Nilay and David talk about the latest Tesla recall, the hugely popular book about Meta, some exciting ActivityPub news, and Netflix co-CEO Ted Sarandos gently zinging Apple TV Plus.
Speaker 7:  Hello and welcome to our chest flagship podcast of the Cyber Truck Wiper
Speaker 7:  owners club.
Speaker 7:  It's for people who don't have a cyber truck, but they just have one big
Speaker 7:  wiper.
Speaker 8:  Can you just buy the wiper separately? Like could I just frame a wiper
Speaker 8:  above my, my mantle?
Speaker 7:  I believe so. Okay. And I believe that might be Tesla's fastest growing revenue
Speaker 7:  line. Just giant
Speaker 8:  Wipers. Yeah, like the flamethrower, you know, bad choice for a bunch of
Speaker 8:  reasons. The tequila. Probably not great tequila, but like would I buy a
Speaker 8:  comically humongous windshield wiper and just sort of have it like Yeah,
Speaker 8:  I would.
Speaker 7:  I mean, I'm sending you one right now. We're gonna, we're gonna take a break
Speaker 7:  from this show and I'm gonna figure out how to buy you a cyber truck wiper.
Speaker 7:  Remember when that was the, the story?
Speaker 8:  Well then, then we cracked it. We, you and I at South by Southwest, we cracked
Speaker 8:  the case.
Speaker 7:  People still send me photos of cyber truck wipers. Like if they see a cyber
Speaker 7:  truck driving down the street, wiping rain. I, I get tweeted at
Speaker 7:  it's like very, you make
Speaker 8:  A lot of fun of me for being the person who sold everyone on earth of books
Speaker 8:  Palmer. But yours is weirder. Being the cyber
Speaker 8:  truck wiper guy is weirder.
Speaker 7:  It is. It is also true that the wiper is not very effective. Look, we're
Speaker 7:  gonna talk about the cyber truck later and Eon and the go, all the stuff
Speaker 7:  we have to start. By the way, I'm my friend Eli, David Pierce is here. Hello
Speaker 7:  Warren. Fine is gonna join us for segment two to talk about the government.
Speaker 7:  Our policy reporter is gonna help us talk about the government. You see how
Speaker 7:  that works? We just, we bring in someone who's smarter than us and then she
Speaker 7:  does the show. Well, we tell jokes it's perfect. Highly recommend it if you
Speaker 7:  can pull it off. We gotta start though with breaking news.
Speaker 7:  As we were sitting down to record there is breaking news in the world
Speaker 7:  of Apple. It appears that they have
Speaker 7:  noticed, noticed. Siri isn't very good.
Speaker 7:  Seems great. I can't tell you when this happened or who noticed it, but they're
Speaker 7:  making some changes. David, what's going on?
Speaker 8:  So Apple had its big like executive retreat
Speaker 8:  last week. I don't know exactly what it's, what they call it The
Speaker 7:  Top 100. Is
Speaker 8:  It? Is that, what's very famous is that start of Steve of the thing. Steve,
Speaker 8:  okay. Yeah. So,
Speaker 7:  And I don't know how it how it works now, but the lure at Apple is that
Speaker 7:  Steve Jobs literally picked his top 100 people without
Speaker 7:  regard for rank or hierarchy or org chart. And making that
Speaker 7:  list was a big deal and it was Steve Jobs, so he didn't care about people's
Speaker 7:  feelings and they got left out. I, it's a very different company now, but
Speaker 7:  that was the lore of top 100 back in the day.
Speaker 8:  First of all, you should make several decoder episodes about the
Speaker 8:  top 100 phenomenon. But so basically, so Apple had this meeting
Speaker 8:  and by all accounts, lots of reporting, especially from Mark Germin at Bloomberg,
Speaker 8:  Siri being awful and the sort of general failure of Apple
Speaker 8:  intelligence was one of the big topics.
Speaker 8:  And coming out of this, what has happened is the
Speaker 8:  person who was running Siri, who was this guy, John
Speaker 8:  Gianna Andrea, who was overseeing a lot of their AI stuff at Apple, he's
Speaker 8:  a huge name in this space. He was Google for a long time. He's was a big
Speaker 8:  figure in Google's antitrust trial. He is like a person who has seen where
Speaker 8:  all the bodies are buried in the tech industry for a very long time. Reports
Speaker 7:  Directly to Tim Cook, right?
Speaker 8:  It's like this, this very important person inside of Apple is being taken
Speaker 8:  off of leadership of the Siri Project, which is now
Speaker 8:  going under Mike Rockwell, who until now was the one leading
Speaker 8:  kind of all things Vision Pro. And if I understand Apple's org structure
Speaker 8:  correctly, and I'm only like 60% sure that I do,
Speaker 8:  Mike Rockwell reports to Craig Fedi who oversees all of software,
Speaker 8:  which would mean Craig Fedi now oversees Siri, which is
Speaker 8:  sort of a meaningful coup inside of Apple's work structure.
Speaker 8:  Like that would be a big shift away from this sort of AI
Speaker 8:  project, which we've seen at a lot of companies sort of slowly annex
Speaker 8:  the rest of the companies like Deves who runs DeepMind at Google is
Speaker 8:  like rapidly becoming the most powerful person at Google because everything
Speaker 8:  is becoming AI and they're just giving everything to Demis. And that's very
Speaker 8:  important. This is a shift, big time in the opposite
Speaker 8:  direction inside of Apple. And It is the kind of thing that Apple doesn't
Speaker 8:  typically do except to rectify something that is perceived to be
Speaker 8:  broken.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, we, last week on the show we talked about Apple delaying the next generation
Speaker 7:  of Siri. It's, I think Apple's org chart is like
Speaker 7:  weirder in that everyone has worked at Apple for 500
Speaker 7:  years. Yes. And they all just get paid a lot. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Like I I, it's, it's hard to actually parse out the sort of back and forth
Speaker 7:  between who's in charge of what. Like Apple is very functionally
Speaker 7:  organized. Product marketing, what they call product
Speaker 7:  marketing is what most tech companies called product management. It's all,
Speaker 7:  it's all, it's just different than other tech companies.
Speaker 7:  The thing that gets me at this though is Rockwell was in charge of the Vision
Speaker 7:  Pro. They gave it to him to get it out the door. He kind of insisted
Speaker 7:  like around the time of the Vision Pro, he was a face that was popping up.
Speaker 7:  We saw him at events. He was the one who really insisted that the Vision
Speaker 7:  Pro had to get out the door this way. Right? Mark Garman and Bloomberg has
Speaker 7:  reporting that
Speaker 7:  John Andrea saw Rockwell as his successor, which makes no sense to me.
Speaker 7:  I'm just looking at the judgment that I can see, which is the Vision Pro
Speaker 7:  shipped the way the Vision Pro is
Speaker 7:  and it's fine. It's a beautiful piece of hardware. It is the most state of
Speaker 7:  state-of-the-art VR headset at its price point that works the way it does
Speaker 7:  that you can get It is the best thing of its kind at its price point that
Speaker 7:  has ever existed. It is also not very good.
Speaker 8:  I half agree with that. Right? And I, and I think there's a way to look at
Speaker 8:  this that is Apple saying what we need is somebody
Speaker 8:  who will ship the thing, right? And Yeah, but sort of tacit inside of that
Speaker 8:  is also saying like the Vision Pro and Siri are in
Speaker 8:  roughly the same stage, which I just don't think it Sure at all. Like the
Speaker 8:  Vision Pro is, is a fabulous piece of technology that
Speaker 8:  doesn't have anything to do. Siri is the opposite, right? Like
Speaker 8:  Siri is, is bursting with interesting use cases. It just sucks.
Speaker 8:  It's like the Vision Pro is like not a bad product, it's just sort of a
Speaker 8:  unnecessary one at the moment. Like there's no, it has no jobs to do
Speaker 8:  and Siri is a bad product. And I think those are actually really different.
Speaker 8:  And I think for Apple to treat them as the same
Speaker 8:  thing, like important technology early in its lifecycle.
Speaker 8:  Totally, totally not true. In AI's case, Siri is
Speaker 8:  14 years old. Yeah. And sucks. That is not the same thing as the Vision Pro.
Speaker 8:  It just isn't.
Speaker 7:  Sure. Okay. I I grant you all that. I agree with all of that for the sake
Speaker 7:  of the argument, my response is
Speaker 7:  the Vision Pro shipped for no reason. Like the error
Speaker 7:  in judgment Yes. Was saying we can't figure
Speaker 7:  out true AR glasses, which, which is what we actually want. So we're
Speaker 7:  gonna insist that this VR headset with video pass through
Speaker 7:  that can be effectively defeated by low light
Speaker 7:  is good enough to achieve our vision of mixed reality. And then app developers
Speaker 7:  will flock to us and then when we get to where we're going and we
Speaker 7:  make real AR glasses, the ecosystem will exist. None. None,
Speaker 7:  none of those were the right decisions,
Speaker 8:  Right.
Speaker 7:  That that's the thing that I'm focused on. And it's
Speaker 8:  The developers will save us thing that I think might be the trap Apple
Speaker 8:  is about to run into with Siri because as, as we've talked about many
Speaker 8:  times, this whole promise of Siri is like the the app intent machine that
Speaker 8:  can go use your phone on your behalf. That depends on developers.
Speaker 8:  And so if you're looking at Apple as essentially a company that just makes
Speaker 8:  screens for developers to do stuff on, like that's increasingly what these
Speaker 8:  things are. They're like, here's a chip and a screen. You figure out what
Speaker 8:  it's for and
Speaker 7:  Pay us 30% anytime someone pushes a button,
Speaker 8:  Right? That is like increasingly the story of Apple as a hardware maker.
Speaker 8:  If you take that same approach to Siri and you say, okay, what we need to
Speaker 8:  do is just get a working version of this out the door and then developers
Speaker 8:  will figure out how to make it great.
Speaker 8:  That man that way lies, dragons and madness
Speaker 8:  and disaster. But you, but I agree. You can see how,
Speaker 8:  you can see how Apple would get there in that thought process of like, what
Speaker 8:  we need to do is put this in front of the people who will figure out what
Speaker 8:  to do with it. And it didn't work for the Vision Pro and I don't think it'll
Speaker 8:  work for Siri.
Speaker 7:  The, the big problem is that they very
Speaker 7:  foolishly announced the product that they wanted to make.
Speaker 7:  Right? Right. They showed the concept video wwc, then they've had to delay
Speaker 7:  the, the delivery of the, the product that they showed off in the concept
Speaker 7:  video. So any pivot off of that now
Speaker 7:  requires them to further eat Crow. Not only is it delayed, but we, we changed
Speaker 7:  it or reduce the specs or Right. It'll be different in some meaningful way.
Speaker 7:  And then on top of that, they have to solve what I keep calling the DoorDash
Speaker 7:  problem, which is they have to get the app developers to basically hand
Speaker 7:  their customers away to the robot. 'cause the, the promise here with app
Speaker 7:  intents and all this, it's still the agents, like everybody else is talking
Speaker 7:  about agents, but instead of clicking around on a website, Siri will use
Speaker 7:  the apps on your phone for you. Right. And all of those app developers have
Speaker 7:  to be okay with their apps not being opened. IIII
Speaker 7:  still dunno how any of that works, right?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I mean you could, you could trace a lot of the
Speaker 8:  design of iOS in particular over the last 15 years as
Speaker 8:  aggressively creating more reasons for you to open apps
Speaker 8:  and like, is that the wrong direction for technology to have
Speaker 8:  gone? Yeah, probably from a user experience. But like
Speaker 8:  everything is about giving you more surfaces to show you company
Speaker 8:  logos. Like we were talking about this at the DY dynamic island last week,
Speaker 8:  right? Like one of the reasons developers like It is because now when I'm
Speaker 8:  on my home screen, it's still showing me the Uber icon. And like that's,
Speaker 8:  that's very powerful. And Siri promises, I think for
Speaker 8:  good user experience reasons, but terrible like economy
Speaker 8:  of the internet reasons to just abstract all of that away. So Apple has
Speaker 8:  to get them on board for this increasingly high risk
Speaker 8:  thing, both because it's bad technology and because it's bad business.
Speaker 8:  I just, I I don't see
Speaker 7:  It. Maybe, maybe John and Andrea just like pieced out. He
Speaker 7:  was like, you do it Vision Pro guy,
Speaker 8:  Mr. Vision Pro over here. He's
Speaker 7:  He's
Speaker 7:  drinking outta cups.
Speaker 7:  That's a deep cut reference. I was gonna
Speaker 8:  Say, I wonder what percentage of this audience got that?
Speaker 7:  Not my share, not my problem. If you get that, send us a note. Yes, please.
Speaker 7:  It's very important.
Speaker 7:  It's, it's very important that we all know who we are. If you understand
Speaker 7:  that reference,
Speaker 7:  it's, It is notable that the guy Apple hired from
Speaker 7:  Google to run AI is no longer in charge of the, the
Speaker 7:  thing that AI should do on the iPhone,
Speaker 8:  Right? It
Speaker 7:  Is ai, there's a ai and we know that there's ai I know, right? There's machine
Speaker 7:  learning and neural engines all through the phone and everyone's always excited
Speaker 7:  about the neural engine cores. But the distribution, the reason no one was
Speaker 7:  worried about Apple is that they had Siri ready to be plugged into
Speaker 7:  these systems that people like to use and that appears to have landed them
Speaker 7:  approximately nowhere.
Speaker 8:  Well, yeah, and it's, it's a really interesting
Speaker 8:  way of thinking about Apple too, because like Craig Federighi has
Speaker 8:  a a long standing reputation of like building software that people like,
Speaker 8:  he has good hair and they ship a lot of software.
Speaker 8:  And so now thinking of Siri as like not this sort
Speaker 8:  of many tentacle thing that exists a across your whole phone, which is what
Speaker 8:  Apple talked about Siri for a long time. They're like, Siri is not just an
Speaker 8:  assistant, sir, is everything Siri, the friends we made along the,
Speaker 8:  like, it's the whole thing. And and increasingly
Speaker 8:  it's like, no, maybe, maybe what you need is an app that works. Like maybe
Speaker 8:  you should think about Siri as just like an an app on your phone that is
Speaker 8:  good at things
Speaker 7:  We'll see might work. This is breaking news. Yeah. You heard us react to
Speaker 7:  it in real time. We'll, we'll see. In the meantime,
Speaker 7:  everyone gets a free Vision Pro if you use Siri. That's what I'm taking away
Speaker 7:  from the Snap. They gotta move units. Other big tech news of the week,
Speaker 7:  the new pebble smartwatches are are out or they're coming later this year.
Speaker 7:  David, you talked to Eric Micki, the CEO of Pebble. This is
Speaker 7:  like pretty fortuitous timing to be launching a smartwatch brand for a variety
Speaker 7:  of reasons. What's going on there?
Speaker 8:  So it's very funny because Eric Micki, you might remember
Speaker 8:  before he was doing Pebble 2.0, which is
Speaker 8:  technically a company called Core Devices, but it's just Pebble again, like
Speaker 8:  let's just all just be honest with each other.
Speaker 7:  I do love that one of the watches is called the Core two Duo. It's one of
Speaker 7:  the funniest names in the entire world. It's
Speaker 8:  So funny. I asked him about this, we were talking about it and I was like,
Speaker 8:  and I was looking at, at the little screenshot that he sent me that said
Speaker 8:  Core two Duo. And I was like, isn't Intel gonna sue you? And he was like,
Speaker 8:  eh, it's a watch, not a chip. It'll be fine. I was like, Eric, I don't, I
Speaker 8:  dunno if you understand how this works, but,
Speaker 8:  but yeah. So he, before he started doing the Pebble
Speaker 8:  thing again, made a company called Beeper that got
Speaker 8:  into a big giant fight with Apple because he felt that
Speaker 8:  he should be allowed to interact with the iMessage protocol with a
Speaker 8:  third party app. And Apple did not agree with that
Speaker 8:  sentiment and it became a whole thing. And we talked about it a lot on this
Speaker 8:  show. And he, you know, very loudly proclaimed
Speaker 8:  that it was about freedom on the internet and all this stuff. And that was
Speaker 8:  all well and good. And he's now a little bit picking that same fight from
Speaker 8:  a different direction. So there's two new watches which are
Speaker 8:  in virtually every way identical to the
Speaker 8:  last generation of Pebble watches. So there was the Pebble two and the Pebble
Speaker 8:  Time two, one has a black and white
Speaker 8:  ePaper screen, one has a color
Speaker 8:  ePaper screen, but they're very simple, right? They're, they're designed
Speaker 8:  to be sort of pixely and hackable and, and they're like gadgets. And
Speaker 8:  I mean that in the most gadgety possible way. And Eric's whole theory,
Speaker 8:  he, he has said this to me since we first started talking about this project,
Speaker 8:  his whole theory is that actually the Pebble kind of
Speaker 8:  had it right. And what he wants is not some like brand new spin
Speaker 8:  on a minimalist smartwatch. He wants a pebble. And so he's like, he's rich
Speaker 8:  now. He's sold two companies. And so he's like, whatever, maybe I'm the only
Speaker 8:  one who wants this. I'm gonna go make a bunch more of them. And that's where
Speaker 8:  we are. So yeah, so there's the core two duo, which is
Speaker 8:  150 bucks and is the like very basic one. And the part of
Speaker 8:  that story I liked is there was some factory somewhere. He wouldn't
Speaker 8:  tell me exactly where that literally just had boxes full of pebble, two
Speaker 8:  frames just, just sitting there just like in the warehouse
Speaker 8:  somewhere. So they're just using those, they're literally just making
Speaker 8:  watches out of those frames again. And
Speaker 8:  then so that one's shipping in July and they're basically like, they're using
Speaker 8:  old hardware, new sensors, which is one of the funny
Speaker 8:  things about this. I thought you would enjoy this in particular actually,
Speaker 8:  one of the things that he found in working on these watches again was that
Speaker 8:  just by virtue of how much more efficient Bluetooth has
Speaker 8:  gotten in the eight years since they last made Pebbles, they have quadrupled
Speaker 8:  the battery life of the pebble. And he said it's lots of things, like everything
Speaker 8:  has gotten more efficient and stuff. But he pointed to Bluetooth specifically
Speaker 8:  as like, It is so much better that the battery life on these new devices
Speaker 8:  goes from seven days to 30 without any other meaningful
Speaker 8:  change. That's amazing. Bluetooth man, 2025.
Speaker 8:  It is the year of Bluetooth. We're doing it finally out better. So yeah.
Speaker 8:  And then the other one is the core time two,
Speaker 8:  which is just the pebble time. Two with some of the same upgrades
Speaker 8:  and they're pre-selling them. Now that one's coming out in December and it's
Speaker 8:  230 bucks. But I kind of love this as an approach.
Speaker 8:  He's just like, he's just like, we did it. We made pebbles, they were cool
Speaker 8:  and here we are. But also along with all of that,
Speaker 8:  he published a blog post angrily describing why
Speaker 8:  trying to use a pebble with an iPhone is so much worse than trying to use
Speaker 8:  a pebble with an Android phone. And this gets to, I think what you were talking
Speaker 8:  about with the fortuitous timing of it all. Eric is very interested
Speaker 8:  in picking a fight with Apple again about the openness of its platforms.
Speaker 8:  And as it turns out, so is the eu. Yeah. Which I think like
Speaker 8:  with within the like 48 hour period, was it
Speaker 8:  the same day? It might have even been the same day right on top of each other.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Okay. Put out two different decisions
Speaker 8:  or under the, the, was it the DMA, the digital market tax
Speaker 7:  D. Yeah. It's hard to keep. Look, we're not
Speaker 8:  Your European, there's so many acronyms.
Speaker 7:  All I can tell you what every version of Ford F-150
Speaker 7:  pickup truck look like. I'm, I'm trying hard to keep European tech
Speaker 7:  regulation straight. All right. Like cut me some slack. Yeah, there's the
Speaker 7:  DSA, which is the Digital Services Act, which meta and a bunch of
Speaker 7:  other companies are super pissed about, right? And then there's the Digital
Speaker 7:  Markets Act, the DMA, which regulates gatekeepers
Speaker 7:  and preserves access to markets. So inside of the DMA, the Digital Markets
Speaker 7:  Act, apple is a gatekeeper and they are
Speaker 7:  requirements to open their platforms in various ways so that there
Speaker 7:  can be a functional market for things like smartwatches. And the two decisions
Speaker 7:  that came out just this last week under the DMA are exactly
Speaker 7:  how in particular smartwatches need to interoperate with
Speaker 7:  iOS.
Speaker 8:  Okay. Yeah. And the, the one is essentially Apple
Speaker 8:  is now required to give developers more access
Speaker 8:  to some of the iPhone's features, right? So that like that other
Speaker 8:  watches will be able to do things like seamlessly pair or
Speaker 8:  get notifications or share data back and forth in the same way that the Apple
Speaker 8:  Watch can. And then the other one, I think It is
Speaker 8:  basically just transparency, right? It's just like explaining to developers
Speaker 8:  how these systems work and how they can use them. Apple
Speaker 7:  Hates this, by the way, just to be hundred
Speaker 8:  Percent. Yeah. I mean Apple's whole thing increasingly is that
Speaker 8:  the, it's stuff only works properly if you buy all of its stuff.
Speaker 8:  And like, it's been really interesting to watch Android follow
Speaker 8:  that stuff up in slightly more open ways. Like the Android fast payer system
Speaker 8:  is now very good and it's only good on iOS if you use
Speaker 8:  Apple or Beats headphones. And so the EU is trying to
Speaker 8:  pry all of that open and be like, no, you can't privilege your own devices
Speaker 8:  in your ecosystem. That's the whole point. We are opening this up. And so
Speaker 8:  like, yeah, Apple's, the whole reason to buy an Apple watch is because you
Speaker 8:  have an iPhone, right? Like that's, that's it. Because everything else is
Speaker 8:  trash if you have an iPhone,
Speaker 7:  But there's no market for other smart watches. Right? I think if you're a
Speaker 7:  gadget fan listening to shit, that's kind of a, it's, it's sad. It's just
Speaker 7:  sad. Yeah. It's sad that you don't think about like, what other smartwatch
Speaker 7:  could I buy? You're like, I can only have this one because I can only send
Speaker 7:  an iMessage in return on this one. Right. And you can't even do any other
Speaker 7:  kind of interactivity with a pebble, which is the point of Eric's blog post.
Speaker 7:  Right? They're, they're locked down in certain ways. By the way, when I say
Speaker 7:  that Apple hates this, here's the statement
Speaker 7:  from the EU with these decisions, we are simply
Speaker 7:  implementing the law and providing regulatory certainty to both Apple and
Speaker 7:  to developers. Effective interoperability for third party connected devices
Speaker 7:  is an important step towards opening Apple apple's ecosystem. This will lead
Speaker 7:  to better choice for consumers and the fast gray market for innovative connected
Speaker 7:  devices. This is a total boilerplate. Sure. Here's Apple's response.
Speaker 7:  This is all in our story. You can, you can go read it. Today's decisions
Speaker 7:  wrap us in red tape. Slowing down Apple's ability to innovate for users in
Speaker 7:  Europe and forcing us to give away our new features for free to companies
Speaker 7:  who don't have to pay play by the same rules. It's bad for our products and
Speaker 7:  for our European users. We'll continue to work with the European Commission
Speaker 7:  to help them understand our concerns on behalf of our users.
Speaker 7:  Brutal
Speaker 8:  Furious.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  That's
Speaker 7:  Fury.
Speaker 8:  There's also a real, like we're just gonna take our ball
Speaker 8:  and go home thing inside of that. Like this, this Sapen made me think of
Speaker 8:  in sort of a weird tangential way what Mark Zuckerberg always used to
Speaker 8:  say about content moderation. Where he was basically like, we invest
Speaker 8:  the most, we try the hardest, we do the most, we spend the most money
Speaker 8:  and all being this loud and transparent about it gets us
Speaker 8:  is pain. So we're just gonna stop.
Speaker 7:  And they totally stopped and
Speaker 8:  Then they stopped and, and this is like this to me is Apple being like, oh
Speaker 8:  well we've built all these cool features to make our devices work together
Speaker 8:  and now you're forcing us to give them to other people. Maybe we'll just
Speaker 8:  stop.
Speaker 7:  It would be amazing if they stopped selling the Apple watch in Europe. They're
Speaker 7:  like, fine have this weird pebble. The
Speaker 8:  Threat here is seems to be less that and more the
Speaker 8:  next time we think about inventing a cool fast pairing feature, we just
Speaker 8:  won't because we'll have to give it away. Like, we're gonna make our products
Speaker 8:  worse because any cool thing we do we're gonna
Speaker 8:  have to give away is like, that feels like the threat to me. And that is
Speaker 8:  a bummer. But I also think is a non crazy threat from a company like
Speaker 8:  Apple.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Well we'll see how these things play out. The, in some cases
Speaker 7:  they've played out the way we kind of thought they would.
Speaker 7:  Right? Europe forces Apple to do alternative app stores,
Speaker 7:  emulators show up. Apple immediately caves on letting emulators into
Speaker 7:  the real app store or the, the Apple App store. I should, I should say not
Speaker 7:  the real, I mean
Speaker 8:  The fact that it's called the Real app store is kind of the point, right?
Speaker 8:  Like that is, that is still where we are. So
Speaker 7:  You just see some a a little dash of competitive pressure actually forced
Speaker 7:  Apple to respond within consumers who wanted forever. Right. If that's how
Speaker 7:  it plays out in smartwatches, that's probably good. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  If it plays out that Apple is just like, screw it. No more Apple Watch
Speaker 7:  features. Well they still have a monopoly on the apple. It's like it,
Speaker 7:  there's just, I, I don't know how that one will play out, but you can see
Speaker 7:  the fury it being made to compete and then when, when
Speaker 7:  there is real competition or something that sniffs like competition, you
Speaker 7:  can see them cave like they did with emulators.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Well and you can also tell the EU is learning how this game is played
Speaker 8:  because the, not just the fact that it decreed that this stuff has to happen
Speaker 8:  but actually expressly dictated to Apple. No, you have to tell
Speaker 8:  developers how to do it. Yeah. Give them a timeline for how it's supposed
Speaker 8:  to work and review these things in a predictable and timely way. It's like
Speaker 8:  the EU and Apple are just slowly learning each other's games and are just
Speaker 8:  like constantly trying to fend each other's off from being insane. And I
Speaker 8:  really enjoy it. I
Speaker 7:  Will say, just looking at this, the idea that
Speaker 7:  giving third party smartwatches the ability to pair
Speaker 7:  transfer data or display notifications or take action on them is not like
Speaker 7:  the most innovative technology in the world. You guys like, you know
Speaker 7:  what I mean? But It is, It is
Speaker 8:  The most
Speaker 8:  important thing about the Apple Watch, right? Like the, the difference between
Speaker 8:  the Apple Watch and any other watch is if I get a text I can
Speaker 8:  respond to it from my Apple watch and I can't respond to it from any other
Speaker 8:  smart watch, which is just immediately a crushing blow to
Speaker 8:  anyone who wants to compete with Apple
Speaker 7:  And which is why there's no market for, right.
Speaker 8:  Right.
Speaker 7:  Anyhow, we'll see, I hope Apple does well. We gotta get these things. We'll
Speaker 7:  see if the, you know, the passage of time has made Bluetooth better.
Speaker 7:  Sure, I believe you. But It is, It is, it's
Speaker 7:  well timed that they're launching new smartwatch and then maybe they will
Speaker 7:  be able to better compete, at least in Europe with iOS users, they can already
Speaker 7:  do all this stuff with Android. Right?
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Android has been more open in that way for a long time
Speaker 8:  and I think all that stuff will still work. Eric very proudly told me that
Speaker 8:  you can still side load the original Pebble app and it'll still work on an
Speaker 8:  Android phone. And I was like, cool Eric. I bet a lot of people are doing
Speaker 8:  that.
Speaker 7:  That's our audience.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I mean
Speaker 7:  That's true. They're, they're here for it. Speaking of Android little Pixel
Speaker 7:  news this week, not like major Pixel news, but some weirdness in here. The
Speaker 7:  Pixel nine A is out. What's going on with that thing? So
Speaker 8:  I, I actually kind of think the nine A is a big deal. I think
Speaker 8:  the, a line of phones gets less credit than it
Speaker 8:  deserves where it's basically like Google just showing up
Speaker 8:  and being like, okay, we've now figured out how to make the last
Speaker 8:  phone that we made and it's a little cheaper now 'cause we, we've made lots
Speaker 8:  of them. That's all good. So we're just gonna basically do that. But like
Speaker 8:  at half the price, is that something you're interested in and like Yeah,
Speaker 8:  It is. This is the Google has done this mid-range phone,
Speaker 8:  I think actually substantially better than Apple and
Speaker 8:  Alison Johnson who wrote about the, the nine A made this point very well.
Speaker 8:  The, the 16 e just came out from Apple.
Speaker 8:  I I think we, we largely think it, It is a series of like pretty
Speaker 8:  reasonable trade-offs except for maybe a couple, but at $699
Speaker 8:  it's still pretty expensive. Then Google shows up with the nine A and it's
Speaker 8:  like, okay, it has multiple cameras. 6.3 inch screen looks pretty
Speaker 8:  nice. It actually doesn't have a camera bump, which in general
Speaker 8:  I'm of the mind of like, who cares about camera bumps? Everybody puts cases
Speaker 8:  on. But then I see a picture of this one where it doesn't have a camera bump
Speaker 8:  and I'm like, yeah, that's, that's kind of slick. Like I'm, I'm kind of into
Speaker 8:  it.
Speaker 8:  It's more durable than the last one. It's brighter than the last one. It
Speaker 8:  is a bigger battery than the last one.
Speaker 8:  Slightly smaller camera sensor, which I have a lot of questions about.
Speaker 8:  All of Google's million weird new ideas about ai.
Speaker 8:  Sure. 499 bucks. This is a good deal. Like this
Speaker 8:  is, I I think in the, in the lineup of Android
Speaker 8:  phones, I think the, the a series from Google
Speaker 8:  is actually one of the most compelling in terms of like actual bang for the
Speaker 8:  buck. Allison said in her piece that this is the phone she recommends for
Speaker 8:  dads and like a, I agree. And B,
Speaker 8:  as a dad I'm like, yeah, I'm, I'm into this phone. It is kind hard. That's
Speaker 8:  hilarious.
Speaker 7:  That's hilarious. It's funny 'cause Samsung's Galaxy a line is also the other
Speaker 7:  cheap one that also moves a lot of units that every now and again
Speaker 7:  we're like, oh, we should pay attention to these. Like these are the ones,
Speaker 7:  so the A 35 5G is 3 9 9, so they're a little bit higher than that,
Speaker 7:  but it's a newer phone.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And it's, it's, it, it all gets very complicated. So like
Speaker 8:  Anna, my wife dropped two to two phones and, and destroyed
Speaker 8:  them in the span of 48 hours, which is very impressive and true. Kudos to
Speaker 8:  Anna and I ended up buying her a Pixel eight
Speaker 8:  at Best Buy for $399. And I did that knowing that the
Speaker 8:  nine A was probably coming soon. And I was like, the, the gap between
Speaker 8:  last year's flagship and this year's midrange is like kind of
Speaker 8:  vanishingly small. Which is weird because like
Speaker 8:  ordinarily this, this stuff either sort of lags a couple of generations or
Speaker 8:  there's some meaningful spec difference between them. But now it's like
Speaker 8:  there's just a lot of like same e phones and it's like whatever, any
Speaker 8:  phone from the last two years at a price that makes sense for you is probably
Speaker 8:  going to be very good. Which is both an odd and a cool place to get in the
Speaker 8:  smartphone universe.
Speaker 7:  I think particularly in pixel line. 'cause I mean the point of them is Google's
Speaker 7:  software, right? At the, at the end of the day, the, the point of buying
Speaker 7:  a pixel is to run Google's vision of Android.
Speaker 8:  Right.
Speaker 7:  And that remains fairly constant among these phones.
Speaker 8:  Yes. You know, it doesn't remain constant is Google's ability to make hardware
Speaker 8:  that works. I
Speaker 7:  Would say that in a minor way. Constant. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  that's fair.
Speaker 8:  Google's inability to make hard roast there works. Yeah. So yeah. Okay. I
Speaker 8:  I wanna know what you make of this. So when Google announced the nine a,
Speaker 8:  they also told us, this is Matt Flagal at Google
Speaker 8:  who said, we're checking on a component quality issue that's affecting a
Speaker 8:  small number of Pixel nine A devices. They haven't shipped review units,
Speaker 8:  at least as far as we know to anybody. You can't pre-order the phone and
Speaker 8:  it's not coming out for a few more weeks. All of which are kind of unusual
Speaker 8:  for the way that Google tends to announce phones.
Speaker 8:  This sets off like all kinds of alarm bells for me. What do you, what do
Speaker 8:  you make of this?
Speaker 7:  I think that they had their announced date locked and then they
Speaker 7:  realized the phones were broken and they were stuck
Speaker 7:  and they had to announce this phone and they have no idea when it's actually
Speaker 7:  gonna shut. It's weird to announce it without even a pre-order button.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Well and to me it suggests that It is there, It is not
Speaker 8:  something you can just fix with like a firmware push.
Speaker 8:  'cause what we've seen before is, you know, they'll, they'll ship
Speaker 8:  phones particularly to reviewers and be like, Hey, you know, in a few days
Speaker 8:  you're, we're gonna get an update that fixes X, y, and Z thing. Which is
Speaker 8:  annoying as a reviewer, but as a relatively common thing for a phone right
Speaker 8:  before it ships. But the fact that there
Speaker 8:  is no date, there is no button, no one has seen
Speaker 8:  these things suggest to me that even if it's a small number of phones, which
Speaker 8:  is what they always say, it's gotta be something pretty show
Speaker 8:  stopping, right?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. You've gotta, you've got something that makes the phone not work or
Speaker 7:  work. What? Those are your choices.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Like, oh no, the 5G chip is broken. It's like I it's something, it's
Speaker 8:  gotta be something at that level. Like, we forgot to make a phone that
Speaker 8:  connects to the internet. I, I dunno.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I mean it was, it's supposed to be here and it's, It is just not And
Speaker 7:  there's no time. Right. They're not saying when, so
Speaker 7:  I, there's, there's weirdness with this one, but I, I suspect they, they
Speaker 7:  were locked into the state to announce the thing.
Speaker 7:  'cause Google also has to be nice to its entire ecosystem. Right.
Speaker 7:  So it can't step on everybody else. Right. So for example, this was
Speaker 7:  not announced at Mobile World Congress, which was just a few weeks ago. It's
Speaker 7:  now. 'cause they, they let everyone else have their time. Weird. And so
Speaker 7:  like, that's just gonna keep happening. So I think they, they take their
Speaker 7:  window and let everyone else do what they want. Phone delayed means they,
Speaker 7:  they still have to hit their window.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, that makes sense. And I'll say kudos to Google for actually taking
Speaker 8:  this route if there is a real problem. We've seen a lot of companies ship
Speaker 8:  slightly broken things with the promise of it'll be fixed later. The
Speaker 7:  AI will fix it, David. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Right.
Speaker 8:  So at least for Google to be like, okay we, we are not going to sell you
Speaker 8:  this thing until we're confident that it won't break. It doesn't
Speaker 8:  make me feel great about the quality of this phone or Google's
Speaker 8:  ongoing hardware team. But at least feels like Google doing the right
Speaker 8:  thing.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I just wish they had a date. Yeah. They weren't like we're delaying
Speaker 7:  it by two weeks. They're just like, we're checking.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. A phone, a phone that launches without a release date should, like,
Speaker 8:  technically the nine A is vaporware. The the nine like as of right now, the
Speaker 8:  pixel nine A is vaporware
Speaker 7:  $500 vaporware.
Speaker 8:  At least it's not $600. It's
Speaker 7:  Vapor till it ships. Those are the rules. Yeah. I don't, I don't make 'em,
Speaker 7:  I mean I, I made that one
Speaker 7:  but it's bigger than me now. Yeah. So vapor till ships. No. How
Speaker 7:  mad. How mad you get. Okay, let's talk about my favorite piece of foam. Vaporware
Speaker 7:  Huawei's Pure X, which one will not
Speaker 7:  ship here? Yeah, it's like a weird sort of geopolitical vapor
Speaker 7:  also. It's only a render right now. And then third of all,
Speaker 7:  it's like a wide flip phone.
Speaker 7:  Like a very, it's a very like imagine a flip phone but then make it
Speaker 7:  really wide.
Speaker 8:  Make it sideways.
Speaker 7:  It's not even sideways. It, it, it, when it unfolds it's,
Speaker 7:  it's still the wrong shape. I love it. It is, It is very
Speaker 7:  good. I want it very badly. This phone is
Speaker 8:  Thoroughly fascinating. It really is like a, it's
Speaker 8:  I think Huawei's first phone with no Android app compatibility, it's like
Speaker 8:  full on harmony os they're, they
Speaker 8:  have had to do their own thing again because of geopolitical insanity.
Speaker 8:  And so this is, this is sort of the beginning of a
Speaker 8:  new era of Huawei trying to build its entire ecosystem for itself. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  It's not even open source Android. It's it's new.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. It's a completely different operating system from the, from the ground
Speaker 8:  up. And I really appreciate that instead of being like, here's a phone you
Speaker 8:  really like with new software, let's see how this goes. They're just like,
Speaker 8:  what if we reinvented literally everything all at once?
Speaker 8:  This is also, I should say justice for the Surface
Speaker 8:  Duo, which was the other bookish unfolding
Speaker 8:  phone. That was a ridiculous idea that I nevertheless loved and used all
Speaker 8:  the time.
Speaker 7:  No, but this one you, it's, it's wide but you
Speaker 7:  open it sideways and then you're supposed to rotate it.
Speaker 8:  It goes 90,
Speaker 7:  It goes 90. So you get this weird vertical tablet but
Speaker 7:  then you close it and you're supposed to use it sideways again. I don't understand
Speaker 7:  a piece of it. I just know that I love it. Yeah. And I wanna run Harmony
Speaker 7:  os next
Speaker 7:  in Chinese I suppose if I have to, but I'm ready to go.
Speaker 8:  Do you remember that phone, the LG wing, the one with the sort of like
Speaker 8:  the, with the, it opened up into like a T shape? Yeah. That, that's
Speaker 8:  what this reminds me of. Where they're just like, we're, we're just going
Speaker 8:  to come up with every possible way you could use a phone and we're gonna
Speaker 8:  make it slightly weird in every orientation. Like do you want that?
Speaker 7:  I love it. I love the fact that it runs its own weird operating system
Speaker 7:  that we basically China had to build 'cause of trade restrictions. And there's
Speaker 7:  its own weird AI system in there that even Jensen Wong. It is like, yeah,
Speaker 7:  that's pretty good. Yeah. All right. If you wanna send us a weird Huawei
Speaker 7:  phone, legally, illegally,
Speaker 8:  You know, if it arrives we'll we'll use it. I'll just say that
Speaker 7:  Actually I think Dom Preston in the UK is probably gonna get this for us.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, we'll find a way. But I'm excited about weird phone form factors
Speaker 7:  as always. Lastly in this segment we should talk about Nvidia a little bit.
Speaker 7:  They just had a big conference. It was GDC and Nvidia had GTC.
Speaker 7:  Jensen was on stage, made a lot of noise about chips. David,
Speaker 7:  you said you had a theory here or
Speaker 8:  Hot. I do have a theory here. A I have a recommendation then a theory. The
Speaker 8:  recommendation is that everybody should go watch these Groot n
Speaker 8:  one humanoid robot videos. Yeah. Nvidia is putting out,
Speaker 8:  they're wild. And I think we, we all have spent,
Speaker 8:  what, 10 years seeing the Boston Dynamics videos where the, the robot
Speaker 8:  that looks like a dog can do back flips and it's like, that's all, well this
Speaker 8:  is like a whole other thing. This is like, we didn't write about
Speaker 8:  a demo we saw of these because we just assumed it was a person in a
Speaker 8:  suit. Like that's, and I'm still not convinced
Speaker 8:  that's not what's going on, but that's how convincing some of these demos
Speaker 8:  have gotten and they're really fascinating. But the theory I want to throw
Speaker 8:  at you is I think Nvidia has stolen
Speaker 8:  Apple's Thunder as the most important product launch
Speaker 8:  company right now, which is bonkers for a
Speaker 8:  company that mostly announces chips. But in terms of like,
Speaker 8:  I, I don't think you, you're gonna tell me it hasn't hit the, like they cover
Speaker 8:  it on the local news thing and that's true, but in terms of like people who
Speaker 8:  care about technology, there is so much enthusiasm now around
Speaker 8:  everything that Nvidia does. And they have these things in like
Speaker 8:  stadiums with thousands of people. And it's this huge personal
Speaker 8:  event in a way that Apple now just like releases infomercials. Which I think
Speaker 8:  has sort of hurt the excitement of those announcements. But Nvidia
Speaker 8:  is like deeply like sexy and cool in a way
Speaker 8:  that I think Apple used to be when it talked about new products.
Speaker 7:  Yes, I agree with this. I also think that
Speaker 7:  it's a small community of people like
Speaker 7:  who really care about it. And then there's like a lot of people who own Invis
Speaker 7:  Nvidia stock who wanna see number go up.
Speaker 8:  That's fair. And what I wonder about this is, do you think until
Speaker 8:  Nvidia starts making itself some kind of like mainstream
Speaker 8:  hardware, can it ever be that cool mostly as a chip
Speaker 8:  maker? 'cause I look at these things in like the, the, what was it,
Speaker 8:  project Digits is now the spark, this little like AI supercomputer thing
Speaker 8:  that they're making. And I'm like there, there's a world here where Nvidia
Speaker 8:  like really wants to make a consumer product that people care about to get
Speaker 8:  that next level of like interest and excitement.
Speaker 7:  But then all, all their money is in data centers. I think their consumer
Speaker 7:  product is chat GPT. That's fair. You know what I mean? Like yeah.
Speaker 7:  Their consumer product is gr or whatever else is running a bunch of Nvidia
Speaker 7:  chips in data center. Like they're happy with that. The the comparison that
Speaker 7:  I would make to you is Intel, which just as week got a new CEO who's
Speaker 7:  gonna try harder I suppose. But Intel's years in the
Speaker 7:  woods were marked. Like I, we knew the end was coming for
Speaker 7:  Intel 'cause they didn't do the iPhone. They were bad at mobile. And then
Speaker 7:  every year we would go to CES or whatever and Intel would be like, here's
Speaker 7:  a vision of the future powered by Intel chips. Andd be like, are you gonna
Speaker 7:  make any of this stuff? And they're like, no, that would be the end of it.
Speaker 7:  Right? Like every time it would be the end of it. And they couldn't make
Speaker 7:  the leap to being a consumer company 'cause they don't think that's in their
Speaker 7:  DNA at all. And then nobody wanted what they were selling. Like
Speaker 7:  quite literally nobody wanted what they were selling. And so you, you ended
Speaker 7:  up at a place where it's like, I saw the future of
Speaker 7:  10,000 drone firework shows.
Speaker 7:  That's Intel's future. That's what they were showing for years. 'cause they
Speaker 7:  had the technology to make that stuff, but that wasn't the next turn. I don't
Speaker 7:  think Nvidia wants to be in that place where they're like, here's a vision
Speaker 7:  of what you might build with our stuff. There are
Speaker 8:  Like small hints that it does though. There's like
Speaker 8:  the, the Shield is a consumer, a weird consumer product, but consumer product
Speaker 8:  and they're like doing the GForce thing and and they have the, the Digits
Speaker 8:  of, it's like there are, it seems like there is like one executive
Speaker 8:  inside of Nvidia who's like, what if we made the products ourselves and they
Speaker 8:  keep losing the fight in the meetings. But then,
Speaker 8:  I don't know, it just feels like
Speaker 7:  That's, well first of all, the Nvidia Shield hasn't been revved in 500 years.
Speaker 7:  And I know by, even by talking about it, we've summoned the Nvidia Shield
Speaker 8:  People. Yeah. We're getting good. Get emails
Speaker 7:  Welcome. You know, we, we love you. You're safe here.
Speaker 7:  It's, it's old. I'm just letting you know it's old. It was always a little
Speaker 7:  bit crankier than any of you wanted do to, to admit
Speaker 7:  also you have to, the plex just changed its rates. I don't know what you
Speaker 7:  all are gonna do now. They're increasing prices. It's stuff out there.
Speaker 7:  They're the big, big news. I I see that They wanted to package
Speaker 7:  some of their core technology in ways to indicate
Speaker 7:  like, oh, there's a real market here, but the shield was never gonna go after
Speaker 7:  the Roku. Right. Like that was Yeah. I was not gonna happen. And
Speaker 7:  I think it's the same. Like that's what I, that the intel comparison I'm
Speaker 7:  making is Intel kept trying to invent a new market because it had lost the
Speaker 7:  old one. Right. Whereas NVIDIA's, It is this market, right?
Speaker 7:  It literally, he's Jensen standing on stage
Speaker 7:  talking about the price performance ratio of inference on
Speaker 7:  Nvidia GPUs and how no one can compete with him.
Speaker 8:  Right. And so maybe the fact that it has become such a huge event is
Speaker 8:  less about how important Nvidia is and more about how
Speaker 8:  much it owns that market that everyone is obsessed with.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And and I think the point he's making is you can't compete with us.
Speaker 7:  Like it,
Speaker 8:  It was like, what if, what if everyone on earth cared about laptops when
Speaker 8:  Intel was like at its peak?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And, and I and there's a lot of hype in ai. Yeah. So
Speaker 7:  I, I just feel like there, it would be a, I think it would be a miss for
Speaker 7:  Nvidia to be like, you can run the models locally. I think what Nvidia wants
Speaker 7:  most of all is for Amazon to feel like they have no choice but
Speaker 7:  to buy Nvidia GPUs for their data centers. And
Speaker 7:  that's, that was kind of the argument. You should go watch the thing 'cause
Speaker 7:  it's cool. But that was more or less the argument Jen was making on stage.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I buy that.
Speaker 7:  Alright, we gotta take a break. We're gonna come back with Lauren Finer the
Speaker 7:  Boy. Boy. A lot of things happened in what I have taken to calling the computer
Speaker 7:  coup.
Speaker 8:  these tweets and stuff that are like, doge has infiltrated the NIH and
Speaker 8:  they talk about it like it's this like marauding band of bank robbers who
Speaker 8:  are just like running in with masks on and causing all kinds of
Speaker 8:  ruckus. And they're like, they've infiltrated the building and it's just,
Speaker 8:  it's become this very strange like militia that is just
Speaker 8:  like running around DC entering buildings. And I'm realizing as
Speaker 8:  I say this that all these metaphors actually kind of work and are true. But
Speaker 8:  it's, It is a very strange phenomenon.
Speaker 7:  You can see the realization just coming over your face as you were talking
Speaker 7:  out loud. I will say this week the theoretical
Speaker 7:  administrator of Doge Amy Gleason revealed in a
Speaker 7:  filing with the court. This is true. She said Doge has 89 people,
Speaker 7:  but they have no formal org chart or front office
Speaker 7:  Look, I don't, I'm not saying I host a podcast about org charts on the side.
Speaker 7:  I'm not saying that's my hobby. I'm not saying I've asked virtually every
Speaker 7:  co in this industry how their company is structured. I'm saying
Speaker 7:  I started The Verge with a bunch of friends. David was like employee number
Speaker 7:  one, and we got to 10 people and we were like, oh, we need
Speaker 7:  some fucking structure.
Speaker 7:  Like you cannot have a totally flat 89 person organization
Speaker 7:  that is infiltrating the government. Like it's, it's
Speaker 7:  nonsensical on its face. That's all I'm saying. But it's true. They're
Speaker 7:  infiltrating things. Can actually, Lauren, before we go into the computer
Speaker 7:  coup can I, can I briefly talk about my favorite nonsensical
Speaker 7:  the Doge related story? Please do you mind? Okay.
Speaker 7:  So as you might expect
Speaker 7:  Elon's real hype on putting starlink everywhere in the government.
Speaker 7:  It's just, it's just what he wants. I don't know. It's what he wants. I,
Speaker 7:  Lauren, I, I've never lived in DC My sense of our
Speaker 7:  nation's capital is that ISPs are thick on the ground. Like you can get
Speaker 7:  internet access in Washington DC Yeah,
Speaker 12:  I am talking to you from an internet connection right now.
Speaker 7:  There you go. I'm, it just seems, yeah, very easy to get inter access in
Speaker 7:  DC like in most places you're not in the woods or in on
Speaker 7:  the battlefield. Yeah, no, it's
Speaker 8:  Like, it's like a city. Like we Yeah, we they they solved that problem. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  David lives there too. Yeah, it's like a whole thing. Yeah. So
Speaker 7:  they've added Starling to the White House,
Speaker 7:  the New York Times reported this week. They've added starlink to the White
Speaker 7:  House, but they haven't actually added starlink
Speaker 7:  dishes to the White House. The starlink dishes are in a
Speaker 7:  data center that's miles away. And then the access to
Speaker 7:  starlink is being piped in over existing fiber to the White House. And
Speaker 7:  then there's a starlink network at the White House
Speaker 7:  already confusing, right? Isn't
Speaker 8:  That just nothing?
Speaker 7:  And then we asked the White House and Carolyn Levitt, who I'm
Speaker 7:  sure all of you have seen on social media or television, she responded that
Speaker 7:  the goal is to improve wifi connectivity at the White House.
Speaker 7:  The White House is working to improve white wi wifi connectivity
Speaker 7:  nonsensical on its face. Like I
Speaker 7:  don't, I knew when we wrote this story that our audience would be mad
Speaker 7:  if you wanna improve wifi connectivity, you just add more access points.
Speaker 7:  You, you know, you run, maybe you, you do some mesh networking
Speaker 7:  like if you like, it's really wild. But I'm confident the White House has
Speaker 7:  the ability to run cables through the White House complex and put up more
Speaker 7:  access points. Do you
Speaker 8:  Think if the New York Times had run a story that was like the White House
Speaker 8:  put up a bunch of heroes around the West Wing, we would've been like, ah,
Speaker 8:  cool.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, they put up that new outdoor hero, pro seven Pro, everyone loves
Speaker 7:  it. It's great. It's inexpensive, but you get all the bands. Yeah, no, I
Speaker 7:  don't know. Like, but, and I'm confident the federal government has it contractors.
Speaker 7:  So if your goal, like, just think about this. My goal is to improve
Speaker 7:  wifi connectivity at the White House. That's what I'm going to say. I'm gonna
Speaker 7:  have Carolyn Levit email The Verge dot com and
Speaker 7:  say the goal is to improve wifi connectivity at the White House. And the
Speaker 7:  mechanism by which we're doing that is we're putting Starling dishes
Speaker 7:  miles away at a different data center. What
Speaker 7:  it's just, it's, it's, it's every part of covering this
Speaker 7:  administration involves this like, just
Speaker 7:  straightforwardly this where you have to, you have to look at it and say
Speaker 7:  that, you know, it doesn't make sense, right? And then, and then they,
Speaker 7:  they bluster back at you and that's the end of that conversation. Anyhow,
Speaker 7:  there's Starling to the White House now it's probably insecure. It's probably
Speaker 7:  being hacked by the minute. And the goal is to improve wifi
Speaker 7:  connectivity to Sure. If anyone,
Speaker 7:  by the way this, the story got posted to Reddit, thousands of comments
Speaker 7:  from angry tech nerds on Reddit being like, that's not how you would improve
Speaker 7:  wifi connectivity. You would just add access points. That's what you would
Speaker 7:  do. So I think Elon just wants his own network. That's my firm belief is
Speaker 7:  that he wanted a network outside of the, the, the government's sort of IT
Speaker 7:  security protocols.
Speaker 8:  Maybe he realized his, his gaming PC wasn't getting quite
Speaker 8:  the, the lag he was hoping for. So he is like, I can, I can upgrade my
Speaker 8:  ping if I could just get the starlink gun
Speaker 7:  Fucking use satellite internet. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I dunno man. It's a weird one. Speaking of starlink, more importantly,
Speaker 7:  the guy who ran the bead program, which is the, the federal rural
Speaker 7:  broadband program that was part of the Inflation
Speaker 7:  reduction Act that Biden passed. He quit,
Speaker 7:  you know, as you do, his name is Evan Feinman, and he said that the Trump's
Speaker 7:  administration's overhaul of the bead program would lead to deeply negative
Speaker 7:  outcomes because they would favor starlink. Lauren, I know you've been kind
Speaker 7:  of poking around at this. What, what's going on with this one?
Speaker 12:  Yeah, I, I mean I think this is, you know, one of the
Speaker 12:  things that everyone is keeping an eye on to see, you
Speaker 12:  know, is Elon Musk's involvement with the government going to have
Speaker 12:  tangible effects on, you know, how his
Speaker 12:  business's fair when it comes to interactions with the federal government.
Speaker 12:  And, you know, I think how broadband is deployed
Speaker 12:  across the country is one of the most obvious areas to look for that.
Speaker 12:  So, you know, this is a, a major program that's
Speaker 12:  meant to expand broadband access in rural areas. And,
Speaker 12:  you know, it's kind of placed a lot of emphasis on fiber.
Speaker 12:  So the more that we see that shift to satellite,
Speaker 12:  the more that SpaceX stands to benefit from that.
Speaker 7:  In his email, when he announced he was leaving, Fineman said, the overhaul
Speaker 7:  of the program to favor starlink would strand all or
Speaker 7:  part of rural America with worse internet so that we can make the world's
Speaker 7:  richest man even richer yet another in a long line of betrayals by Washington.
Speaker 7:  The thing that strikes me at this is it's not like the bead program
Speaker 7:  has of yet been a stunning success, right? The criticism
Speaker 7:  is you spent all this money on broadband and no one got any broadband. And
Speaker 7:  then the argument, Lauren, as far as I understand It is, well, we gave out
Speaker 7:  the money and now they gotta do it. What's the holdup?
Speaker 12:  Yeah, I mean, I, I think the holdup is, there's kind of a lot of
Speaker 12:  red tape here. It's, you know, this is a big
Speaker 12:  undertaking for the government. There's a lot of different ideas about how
Speaker 12:  to do things. So this has been a, a long process in general,
Speaker 12:  not just because of all the changes recently, but I think there's a
Speaker 12:  lot of fear that, you know, in adding more changes
Speaker 12:  at this stage will just drag things out
Speaker 12:  even further, which no one really wants.
Speaker 7:  All right, well we'll keep an eye on this. I do think, and I know everyone's
Speaker 7:  gonna, the Starling people will find me, they're gonna team up with the Nvidia
Speaker 7:  Shield people. It's true that I think wired internet connections are
Speaker 7:  superior to wireless internet connections. I'm sorry. We like wires and
Speaker 7:  we like buttons. Yes. These are like two of the foundational beliefs of The
Speaker 7:  Verge. It's also true that Comcast is an ISP and it's an investor and our
Speaker 7:  parent company Box Media, but they hate me. So it's like
Speaker 7:  just, I'm just, I, I just think ethernet is a superior, more
Speaker 7:  reliable than wifi and I think fiber is more secure and reliable than
Speaker 7:  satellite. It's just, it's just how it works, man.
Speaker 7:  So we'll see. Right. I think Lauren, we're, we're on the like wait and see
Speaker 7:  phase of what's gonna happen with Bead.
Speaker 12:  I think that's right. Alright.
Speaker 7:  There's a number of other things that are sort of in this Wait and see zone.
Speaker 7:  TikTok is one of those, right? The Supreme Court said it was
Speaker 7:  banned, like it was constitutional for the law that banned it to have banned
Speaker 7:  it. And then Trump took office and he said, nah, don't worry about that until
Speaker 7:  April 5th. It's almost April 5th. What's happening there,
Speaker 7:  Lauren?
Speaker 12:  Yeah, so I think the short version is that
Speaker 12:  we haven't really seen anything come of this so far,
Speaker 12:  tiktoks in the same ambiguous position. But, you know, all the
Speaker 12:  companies that service it have decided they're, you know,
Speaker 12:  pretty much good enough with the legal
Speaker 12:  protections that the Trump administration has offered so far, even
Speaker 12:  though it's technically illegal to service the company at this
Speaker 12:  point, now that it's passed the ban deadline.
Speaker 12:  But we're hearing that Oracle
Speaker 12:  is trying to swoop in and save TikTok from a US
Speaker 12:  ban. And if that sounds familiar, it's because it kind of tried to
Speaker 12:  do this before you might remember a
Speaker 12:  thing called Project Texas, which was this whole plan
Speaker 12:  for Oracle to work with TikTok and,
Speaker 12:  you know, make sure that all of the US data,
Speaker 12:  the source code was all good. And, you know, there was nothing
Speaker 12:  nefarious happening. And, you know, after TikTok rolled
Speaker 12:  off, wrote, rolled out this huge presentation about
Speaker 12:  Project Texas lawmakers were like, well, you know, we're, we
Speaker 12:  still don't think this is enough. So, you know,
Speaker 12:  I, we obviously don't know what exactly a potential
Speaker 12:  deal with Oracle, assuming that's what Trump is
Speaker 12:  looking at here would look like. But from everything that's been
Speaker 12:  rumored, it, it sounds pretty similar to Project Texas, which
Speaker 12:  begs the question, you know, what change
Speaker 12:  and will lawmakers get on board with this this time?
Speaker 7:  There's a JD Vance quote he said to NBC news.
Speaker 7:  There will almost certainly be a high level agreement that I think satisfies
Speaker 7:  our national security concerns and allows there to be a distinct American
Speaker 7:  TikTok enterprise.
Speaker 7:  I don't actually know what that means.
Speaker 8:  That doesn't mean anything. Wait, can I, can I read you a slightly longer
Speaker 8:  version of that quote that is more words and says even less.
Speaker 8:  He says, we'd like to get it done without the extension. I think the question
Speaker 8:  is what is the equity ownership of the new joint venture? How do you do the
Speaker 8:  contracts for all the investors, the customers, the service providers? The
Speaker 8:  deal itself will be very clear, but actually creating those thousands and
Speaker 8:  thousands of pages of legal documents, that's the one thing I worry could
Speaker 8:  slip. Do you know what that list comprises the deal he
Speaker 8:  just described. We're gonna have the deal done, we just might not have the
Speaker 8:  deal done.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, exactly. Yeah. And you know, actually we're
Speaker 12:  interestingly starting to see some warning from some
Speaker 12:  Republicans in Congress. John Lennar, who
Speaker 12:  leads the House select committee on China, actually
Speaker 12:  said, you know, the law, he said, quote, the law is clear, any deal must
Speaker 12:  eliminate Chinese influence and control over the app to safeguard our
Speaker 12:  interests. And he also said that, you know, ance has to
Speaker 12:  fully divest control of TikTok and have no say in its operation. So
Speaker 12:  he is pretty clear that, you know, there has to be a clean break
Speaker 12:  from by dance, which doesn't seem to be what Trump has
Speaker 12:  indicated he's going for in his past public statements.
Speaker 8:  Is it possible that this just works out to be essentially a
Speaker 8:  redux of the whole project Texas Oracle deal, but they're gonna
Speaker 8:  spin it in a more politically advantageous way
Speaker 8:  and then just ram it through whatever they have to ram it through because
Speaker 8:  they feel like they can, like th this feels to me like they're just gonna
Speaker 8:  say, Oracle, fix it and then just yell loudly at whatever Congress
Speaker 8:  people they need to make that workable.
Speaker 12:  I think it's certainly possible. I, I think it puts a lot of
Speaker 12:  Republicans in a really tough position because I
Speaker 12:  think the whole concern with Project Texas before was like, this
Speaker 12:  doesn't get at the fundamental issue we have with by dance owning
Speaker 12:  TikTok and you know, potentially still having a say over their
Speaker 12:  operations and, you know, potentially as the argument goes, giving
Speaker 12:  the Chinese government some sort of access point to us user
Speaker 12:  information or to, you know, kind of change the levers that
Speaker 12:  are being pulled over, you know, what content is surfaced to Americans.
Speaker 12:  So, you know, if that doesn't change, then
Speaker 12:  it puts a lot of Republicans who I think, you know, despite what you
Speaker 12:  might believe about the validity of that argument, I think do seem
Speaker 12:  to really believe that puts them in a tough spot
Speaker 12:  to just, you know, go against the President if what he wants is very different
Speaker 12:  from that. It's
Speaker 8:  All just so weird. The politics of this is just so bizarre
Speaker 8:  that like Trump tried to ban TikTok the first time so much of this
Speaker 8:  happened because Trump tried to ban TikTok the first time and then it
Speaker 8:  became this incredibly bipartisan thing. Like Neli,
Speaker 8:  you and I have argued about this on the show a hundred times now, but like
Speaker 8:  the, the fact of the matter is a bunch of senators got this briefing and
Speaker 8:  then voted 50 to zero to ban it. Like
Speaker 8:  it's, everybody wanted this to happen. And then Trump changed his mind during
Speaker 8:  the election season and became like the great crusader to save TikTok
Speaker 8:  and now might just give it to Oracle because he and Larry Ellison are buddies,
Speaker 8:  by
Speaker 7:  The way, while he is hiking tariffs on China every single
Speaker 7:  day, right? Like he's a Trump is a China hawk, he's not,
Speaker 7:  this isn't it, It is incoherent like on its face, right? And
Speaker 7:  so
Speaker 8:  Even if you're just trying to do what you think the Trump
Speaker 8:  administration wants you to do to stay in the good favor of the President,
Speaker 8:  I don't even know how to figure out what that is. If I'm a member of Congress
Speaker 8:  who has to figure out what to do at this right now.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, I think it's gonna be really tough for,
Speaker 12:  I, I don't know how they're going to kind of square that circle. I think,
Speaker 12:  you know, it's a a lot of different moving pieces
Speaker 12:  and you know, so far we haven't seen many
Speaker 12:  Republicans go, you know, directly against Trump. So
Speaker 12:  in a sense it's kind of like, you know, why would they
Speaker 12:  start doing that? Now on the other hand, this is something that
Speaker 12:  an overwhelming number of lawmakers, including Republicans
Speaker 12:  voted for and, you know, seem to really believe in even
Speaker 12:  despite pushback from their own constituents. So you know
Speaker 12:  it to just completely do an about face on that would be really
Speaker 12:  stunning. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  We'll see there, we there's a big April coming up, right? It's TikTok ban.
Speaker 7:  There's the big antitrust trial for meta where the, the,
Speaker 7:  the stakes are splitting off Instagram and WhatsApp. Where's the Google search
Speaker 7:  remedies trial? A lot of things are gonna happen.
Speaker 8:  More tariffs,
Speaker 7:  More more tariffs are gonna hit. Can't forget tariffs. Dear sweet
Speaker 7:  tariffs. Soon all of Canada will be illegal. From what
Speaker 7:  I understand. It'll just be criminal to even know about Canada.
Speaker 7:  That'll be ironic. Another deep cut right there.
Speaker 7:  Sorry, I thought of a famous Canadian and that's what happened to me. I
Speaker 7:  am so sorry. We're gonna see we we a couple weeks from now.
Speaker 7:  I think the world will go a a wee bit topsy-turvy, especially Israeli sec.
Speaker 7:  The world is already topsy-turvy. Lauren, I think the
Speaker 7:  big story of this week is what happened at the FTC. So if you're
Speaker 7:  staring at, okay, next month we've got some big antitrust trials.
Speaker 7:  One of them is the meta trial, that one is being led by the FTC. We've got
Speaker 7:  some enforcement actions against Amazon. The Trump FTC
Speaker 7:  Federal Trade Commission has not been soft on these companies. They've been
Speaker 7:  pretty aggressive. They've held up Le Kahn's merger guidelines,
Speaker 7:  but at the same time, Trump illegally fired two Democratic commissioners
Speaker 7:  this week. Like the law there is very clear and he just did it. Anyway, what
Speaker 7:  is going on there?
Speaker 12:  Yeah. So yeah, this week Trump
Speaker 12:  fired the two remaining Democrats on the Federal Trade Commission,
Speaker 12:  which was, you know, a really sudden and shocking
Speaker 12:  thing to do because there is Supreme
Speaker 12:  Court precedent where, you know, a president had tried to
Speaker 12:  do pretty much exactly that and the Supreme Court said you can't do that
Speaker 12:  because the Federal Trade Commission is an independent agency
Speaker 12:  even though it's, you know, technically a part of the executive branch
Speaker 12:  and you know, FTC commissioners have to be fired for
Speaker 12:  cause essentially. But that doesn't seem to be what was done
Speaker 12:  here. And now there's two remaining Republican
Speaker 12:  commissioners at the FTC. Just to be clear, the
Speaker 12:  democratic commissioners say, you know, they don't think they can really
Speaker 12:  be fired. So they're, you know, pretty much saying we're still
Speaker 12:  commissioners or we should be. And then we have a
Speaker 12:  third Republican commissioner who's set up to be
Speaker 12:  confirmed at some point to the role. So, you know, what makes
Speaker 12:  this even more confusing is that Republicans already
Speaker 12:  would have a majority on the commission. So Democrats wouldn't really be
Speaker 12:  able to sway how a lot of decisions come out.
Speaker 12:  But you know, it's kind of just getting rid of this dissenting voice
Speaker 12:  or you know, maybe a voice that would be able to sway some commissioners
Speaker 12:  a little bit, one way or another.
Speaker 7:  It does seem like one of the reasons for this firing is
Speaker 7:  to set up the Supreme Court challenge that would overturn,
Speaker 7:  I think it's a hundred year old Supreme Court precedent called Humphrey's
Speaker 7:  executor Sarah Jung, our features editor. And I keep joking
Speaker 7:  that everything we learned in law school is, is valueless. Like
Speaker 7:  you learn this case in law school, it's just like how does the government
Speaker 7:  work? And like it's on the list of cases you read about what you can and
Speaker 7:  can't do. And this one is very much, it's like on the nose the president
Speaker 7:  can't fire FTC commissioners, you just can't do it unless there's cause
Speaker 7:  and here he didn't have cause you just fired them. So it's illegal, like
Speaker 7:  the law is clear and he did the thing that the case says you can't do,
Speaker 7:  but you do that on purpose 'cause you wanna go to the Supreme Court and get
Speaker 7:  the law of return, which this Supreme Court is very willing to do. So it's
Speaker 7:  a very odd limbo. Right. The thing that gets me though
Speaker 7:  is this FTC is still set up
Speaker 7:  to be extraordinarily hostile to tech companies. Like
Speaker 7:  what, outside of we're, we're running this legal challenge
Speaker 7:  to chase down this idea of the unitary executive where the president
Speaker 7:  is basically a king, which is a thing like the federal
Speaker 7:  society isn't pushing this idea for a long time. Outside of that, doesn't
Speaker 7:  it seem like they're, they're losing their credibility to go after
Speaker 7:  the tech companies the way that they've already wanted to. Like Bedoya one
Speaker 7:  of the fired commissioners is like, I got fired 'cause I'm, I criticized
Speaker 7:  Jeff Bezos. But then you turn around and Trump loves to criticize
Speaker 7:  Jeff ba like I, I I kind of don't understand the goal here.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, I think that's been kind of a big conundrum with this one. You know,
Speaker 12:  I think on the one hand maybe Trump
Speaker 12:  kind of made this decision outside of those considerations and said, you
Speaker 12:  know, I just wanna make sure I have full control over the FTC. On the other
Speaker 12:  hand, it's concerning because if, you know you have an FTC
Speaker 12:  that does want to go after legitimate issues in the
Speaker 12:  tech industry, and you have a Republican chair who says he
Speaker 12:  wants to take on the tech companies, I think one of the
Speaker 12:  commissioners actually
Speaker 12:  said something to the effect of, you know, Ferguson, the
Speaker 12:  Republican chair is interested in going after tech, but what happens
Speaker 12:  if he gets a call from the White House saying, you know,
Speaker 12:  don't go after this executive who is
Speaker 12:  becoming friendly with the White House. So, you know, I think
Speaker 12:  it, it just calls into question the whole idea of the independence
Speaker 12:  of the agency, which is something that Trump has already tried to
Speaker 12:  assert power over in, you know, issuing an
Speaker 12:  executive order, kind of trying to exert more supervisory
Speaker 12:  influence over independent agencies. So, you know, I I think
Speaker 12:  this is just, it's more about it being another step in the direction
Speaker 12:  toward controlling what are supposed to be independent
Speaker 12:  agencies that are able to kind of follow the facts where they lead and issue
Speaker 12:  enforcement actions. And the, you know, continuance of
Speaker 12:  that is being called into question now.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it seems dead certainty that this case will end up back before
Speaker 7:  the Supreme Court and we will end up writing an explainer about a hundred
Speaker 7:  year old Supreme Court precedents that get overturned. But the context is
Speaker 7:  this is how the government goes and regulates a meta or an Amazon
Speaker 7:  or seeks a breakup of these companies in one way or another. And it,
Speaker 7:  if you make that politics, then you get real corrupt
Speaker 7:  real fast, right? You get real stupid real fast. If that is now a like a
Speaker 7:  horse traded negotiation as opposed to here's the
Speaker 7:  antitrust law that's being applied. Like I I I, I'm struggling
Speaker 7:  to articulate this, but it just, the thing I wanna say is like if you make
Speaker 7:  everything this political, you get stupid. Like there's
Speaker 7:  like, you just start, you just lose your grasp on reality. 'cause everything
Speaker 7:  has to be politically expedient or politically coherent, not logically
Speaker 7:  coherent. And this one to me is just like they have the votes anyway. But
Speaker 7:  if you're
Speaker 8:  The, if you're the Trump administration and you're in a phase of testing
Speaker 8:  your own invincibility, maybe it's pretty useful to make
Speaker 8:  everything politics because then everything runs through you specifically
Speaker 8:  and, and you get to horse trade anything you want. And I think like one of
Speaker 8:  the strange things about this is
Speaker 8:  the, the Trump administration in certain ways is incredibly business friendly.
Speaker 8:  And a lot of the reaction to this has been, this is what an incredible
Speaker 8:  victory for all the rich people out there who are now not going to be regulated
Speaker 8:  in any meaningful way except the tech companies like the FTC
Speaker 8:  would loves business and wants to tear big deck to the ground. And I think
Speaker 8:  that that, that whole cognitive
Speaker 8:  dissonance is, is very loud inside of all of this decision for me. It's very
Speaker 8:  strange.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, and even the, you know, we mentioned that Google remedies phase
Speaker 7:  of the search antitrust trials coming up, that case was started in Trump
Speaker 7:  won, carried out under the Biden administration. Phase one
Speaker 7:  was won under the Biden administration and now the remedies
Speaker 7:  phase, what are we gonna do to Google will be handled by a new Trump administration
Speaker 7:  that is just like a meaningfully different footing. Like
Speaker 7:  the last Trump administration antitrust posture was
Speaker 7:  literally, we will find a way to broker a deal for T-Mobile
Speaker 7:  to buy Sprint. Like we will arrange this to happen.
Speaker 7:  Boy, do I have feelings about that? Have you guys all been using your dish
Speaker 7:  network 5G, everybody did that work? That'd be great. I love it.
Speaker 8:  I have Ting internet, which I think is Dish, so,
Speaker 7:  But that was the first Trump administration's posture and they are the ones
Speaker 7:  who started the Google antitrust trial. This new Trump
Speaker 7:  administration is way more aggressive, right? They, they've picked
Speaker 7:  up a lot of the pieces from the Biden administration's posture towards the
Speaker 7:  tech industry and they're carrying it out and it just, there's a part of
Speaker 7:  this where, oh, that's great co-regulate tech companies and there's a part
Speaker 7:  of, it's, we've been calling it gangster tech regulation where
Speaker 7:  they're just gonna, I don't like where Mark Zuckerberg's gonna show up and
Speaker 7:  like, I made you a solid gold Porsche and that'll be the end of it. You know,
Speaker 7:  like he gets to keep Instagram and I just, this level of politics I think
Speaker 7:  makes you dumb. Speaking of dummies, Lauren,
Speaker 7:  welcome to the, now you can see me can play about Brendan Carr.
Speaker 8:  Wait, can I, can I tell you something very fun? Yeah. So I, I like to
Speaker 8:  call this America's favorite podcast within a podcast because It is that,
Speaker 8:  and it's very exciting. We heard from a number of fans of the podcast, my
Speaker 8:  brother, my Brother and Me, which is a podcast that I love very much. And
Speaker 8:  they also have a podcast within a podcast called Munch Squad, where they
Speaker 8:  talk about fast food and, and brand eating. So
Speaker 8:  we now have a podcast enemy and it's Munch Squad. And I just wanted to tell
Speaker 8:  you that because it's very exciting. These are now we, it's a heated race
Speaker 8:  for America's favorite podcaster than a podcast. And
Speaker 8:  I vote Brendan Carr.
Speaker 7:  I, I can't believe I can pull this transition off, but I can do it.
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna do it. You ready? So I believe
Speaker 7:  on the Munch cast, they have talked about Reese's Peanut butter
Speaker 8:  Cups. They have, yeah.
Speaker 7:  We'll get to Brendan in a second. Welcome to Brendan Carr's dummy America's
Speaker 7:  favorite podcast within a podcast. FCC Commissioner Brendan Carr is a notable
Speaker 7:  dummy, his predecessor a Jeep Pie. And Trump won,
Speaker 7:  loved to drink outta a giant oversized novelty. Reese's Peanut butter
Speaker 7:  cup. They, they had a huge coffee cup, Reese's logo on it. It went everywhere
Speaker 7:  he went as he tore down consumer protections across the country, made
Speaker 7:  internet access more expensive and worse for everybody. Literally, one of
Speaker 7:  the first things he did was he got rid of the privacy rules that ISPs were,
Speaker 7:  were made to operate under. So now they can share your data. Great. Love
Speaker 7:  it. But the mug, it made him, you know, charming.
Speaker 7:  Hey, guess who? The new president of the CTIA, the wireless
Speaker 7:  lobbyist group is.
Speaker 8:  Wait, really?
Speaker 7:  Yep. He's back. The Wireless Industry Association New president,
Speaker 7:  a Jeep pie, effective April one doors just spinning
Speaker 7:  baby. You just leave the government agency that's supposed to regulate the
Speaker 7:  wireless industry land at the top of the wireless
Speaker 7:  industry's lobbyist group.
Speaker 8:  Fantastic.
Speaker 7:  He's honored to lead CTIA, by the way, the wireless industry is a key driver
Speaker 7:  of technology innovation investment in the United States.
Speaker 7:  He's got a huge check think mug
Speaker 8:  Goes with
Speaker 7:  Oh yeah. There's no way
Speaker 8:  You don't think the mug is like technically a government property.
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna mail him a grape and be like, do surgery on this.
Speaker 8:  No, but you can't mail it to him. You have to leave it at your house. You
Speaker 8:  have to send him a picture and you have to say, do surgery on this
Speaker 7:  5G come and get it, dude.
Speaker 7:  I'll be here waiting. All right, so Brendan, this week it was revealed that
Speaker 7:  he sent a letter. He's investigating 13
Speaker 7:  public radio stations, including WBEZ, which
Speaker 7:  is this American life, right? Yeah. It's this American life. It is
Speaker 7:  WBEZ. Yeah. So this American life is under investigation from Bren and Carr
Speaker 7:  over what he says is illegal advertising because they do this thing called
Speaker 7:  underwriting where you know, it says this program is brought to you by da
Speaker 7:  da da da. That's advertising. And if you're doing advertising then you can
Speaker 7:  get your funding cut.
Speaker 8:  That's like the thing that NPR r has been doing forever and ever.
Speaker 8:  Always.
Speaker 7:  That's what they do. Like,
Speaker 8:  Yeah, that's like NPR R'S whole thing.
Speaker 7:  We do not give enough public dollars to these radio stations to rate so you
Speaker 7:  underwriting to cover the gap and never gets to feel good about themselves.
Speaker 7:  And there's a gala at the shed Aquarium or whatever in Chicago.
Speaker 8:  But the argument is because they say the name of the underwriter on the thing.
Speaker 8:  Now that's advertising.
Speaker 7:  Here's what Brendan said. I'm concerned that NPR and PBS broadcast could
Speaker 7:  be violating federal law by airing commercials. It is possible that
Speaker 7:  NPR and PBS member stations are broadcasting underwriting announcements that
Speaker 7:  cross the line into prohibited commercial advertisements. I do not see a
Speaker 7:  reason why Congress should continue sending taxpayer dollars to NPR and PBS
Speaker 7:  given the changes in the media marketplace. So he's just
Speaker 7:  looking for an excuse to cut funding to NPR and PS That's what that sounds
Speaker 7:  like. You think, sir, to woke for its part. WBEZ
Speaker 7:  says they received the letter on February 28th. We can confirm. We received
Speaker 7:  the letter. They said in statements they've requested detailed information.
Speaker 7:  We adhere to the FCC underwriting guidelines. We're confident that
Speaker 7:  we'll demonstrate compliance. I should note here just a disclosure, it's
Speaker 7:  like a, it's not actually a disclosure, but WBEZ is part of
Speaker 7:  Chicago Public Media, the CEO of Chicago Public Media
Speaker 7:  is our old publisher. Melissa Bell. She co-founded rock.com.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, she's fan boss. I I sent her a text. She hasn't responded to me.
Speaker 7:  I'm gonna try to get her under coder. Melissa, if you would like to come
Speaker 7:  dunk on Brendan. Yeah, that's a choice. I suspect she will Not
Speaker 7:  just to put that out there. I suspect she will not. But there, there's your,
Speaker 7:  there's your disclosure. This is just noise, right? This is
Speaker 7:  Brendan once again going after media that he dislikes 'cause it's too
Speaker 7:  woke or too liberal or too bad or whatever he thinks
Speaker 7:  concocting some bullshit to ex to express
Speaker 7:  his power. And then he's attacking this American life by saying, I will make
Speaker 7:  sure the government stops funding you because I have decided that you're
Speaker 7:  underwriting sponsorships are illegal advertising and Congress
Speaker 7:  shouldn't fund you anymore. And that is just again, Brendan Carr trying to
Speaker 7:  chill speech in America that he disagrees with. And he does this week in
Speaker 7:  and week out. I, I barely even have to research this segment. I start
Speaker 7:  typing Brendan Carr into my laptop. It auto completes. And then there's a
Speaker 7:  list of bullshit this man does to chill speech in America every week
Speaker 7:  without fail. So we're gonna keep covering what's going on here. We're looking
Speaker 7:  for the other stations that received this letter. If you know who they are,
Speaker 7:  if you work, you can tip us. We, we'd love to talk to you about this, but
Speaker 7:  this is just nonsense. Like the First amendment in this country is directly
Speaker 7:  under attack and a huge variety of ways. We've covered what's
Speaker 7:  going on on campus with protests and protestors being removed at Columbia.
Speaker 7:  We have a great story this week about what's happening to immigrants who
Speaker 7:  are landing at airports and having their social media searched and then being
Speaker 7:  kicked outta the country for no reason whatsoever. And, and like a weird
Speaker 7:  combination of databases that Gabby, our reporter wrote that story called
Speaker 7:  a panopticon. Like there's just real pressure on freedom of speech
Speaker 7:  in this country right now. And Brendan remains the tip of that spear
Speaker 7:  because he goes after media organizations, specifically media organizations
Speaker 7:  that he disagrees with over and over and over again. He using power that
Speaker 7:  he does not actually have, he concoct bullshit to express his power. So Brendan,
Speaker 7:  as always,
Speaker 7:  I know you listen, I know you get the alerts, I know that there's some intern
Speaker 7:  who sends you a read out of this. I know that you like it. I do.
Speaker 7:  You're welcome to come on the show and I'll humiliate you to your face anytime
Speaker 7:  you want. You can come onto coder as well, but you should answer for this
Speaker 7:  'cause it's real bad. That's when Brendan Carr is a dummy. Everyone's favorite
Speaker 7:  podcast within
Speaker 8:  A podcast. Wait, I have a, I have a, Brenda Carr is a dummy follow up question.
Speaker 8:  Is he connected at all to what happened with the Trump administration and
Speaker 8:  Voice of America this week? The, the sort of full shutdown of that entire
Speaker 8:  arm?
Speaker 7:  I don't think so. Okay. Lauren? I think that's somewhere else. I think Voice
Speaker 7:  America is somewhere. I think so, yeah.
Speaker 8:  Okay. It's very much like of a political piece though. This this
Speaker 8:  like just relentless shutdown of anything
Speaker 8:  that they perceive to be against them politically. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And It is funny 'cause Voice America is meant to be it like the export of
Speaker 7:  American cultural values. Like It is sort of meant to be propaganda.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. But they landed at we should do, we should tell the truth.
Speaker 7:  And that is uncomfortable when everything is this political and stupid. And
Speaker 7:  so now they're shut down. It's fine. Just let it be propaganda the
Speaker 7:  24 hours a day be like, you know what rules America, that's fine. I
Speaker 8:  Know, right? Like, go make your own propaganda. Don't shut it down.
Speaker 7:  Very stupid.
Speaker 8:  I guess that's what Joe Rogan is
Speaker 7:  For. All right, last one we should talk about. This one is, it seems
Speaker 7:  complicated 'cause I don't know exactly what anyone is trying to get except
Speaker 7:  yelled at,
Speaker 7:  but you know, the Trump administration is new. They've got new ideas about
Speaker 7:  ai. They got David Sachs AI Czar doing something
Speaker 7:  somewhere, and Lauren both open AI and Google this week
Speaker 7:  basically said, Hey, what if, what if there wasn't copyright law? What?
Speaker 7:  That's basically how I read these letters. What's going on here?
Speaker 12:  Yeah. So basically the White House was asking
Speaker 12:  companies to kind of submit comments about, you know, what should
Speaker 12:  we do about AI and open ai? And Google's
Speaker 12:  response was like, let us train on copyrighted work.
Speaker 12:  Let's like have some, you know, application of like fair use for
Speaker 12:  ai. And obviously the
Speaker 12:  copyright holders, like the entertainment industry
Speaker 12:  did not feel so great about that. And you know, a lot of
Speaker 12:  celebrities were speaking out against this kind of idea.
Speaker 12:  So, you know, just setting up kind of this big fight over
Speaker 12:  copyright and AI and what the government should do about it.
Speaker 7:  It's weird to me because there are so many pending lawsuits,
Speaker 7:  right? The a bunch of celebrities have sued open ai. It feels like everyone's
Speaker 7:  a little bit twitcher with Google. It's a harder company to sue
Speaker 7:  for a variety of reasons. Everyone's tied up with Google for a variety of
Speaker 7:  reasons. Every, every celebrity has their podcast on YouTube for God's sake.
Speaker 7:  What are you gonna do that without Google? But there are all of these lawsuits,
Speaker 7:  our company has sued cohere, there's a disclosure. We also have to deal with
Speaker 7:  OpenAI another weird disclosure. None of that has anything to do with us.
Speaker 7:  I'm just saying, you can see how even in the this tiny little context,
Speaker 7:  everyone's like playing different games and we'll see how these lawsuits
Speaker 7:  play out. And these letters feel like, Hey, what if we
Speaker 7:  didn't do all that and Trump just said it was okay? Like,
Speaker 7:  I don't understand that. Do they think they're gonna get that?
Speaker 7:  Like, that's what it feels like they're asking for.
Speaker 12:  I mean, I guess they think it's worth a shot. I mean, I think it's
Speaker 12:  almost like what we've seen with TikTok. You know, the courts say
Speaker 12:  one thing and then Trump comes in and says, no, actually I'm gonna give
Speaker 12:  an extension that's not written into the law. So I think, you know,
Speaker 12:  they're trying to go at this from all different dimensions in
Speaker 12:  the courts and policy, you know, in, in like actual
Speaker 12:  laws out of Congress. And we'll see kind of what gets
Speaker 12:  there first. I think
Speaker 8:  It actually strikes me as like a perfectly reasonable thing to try. If you're
Speaker 8:  one of these companies. Like, it, it, it might work. Like, and,
Speaker 8:  and the the thing I think is so funny about all this is they're all making
Speaker 8:  mistakes so high. And it's like the, both Google
Speaker 8:  and OpenAI were like, if we, if you don't let us do whatever we want
Speaker 8:  with everything that has ever been created in human history, China
Speaker 8:  will win.
Speaker 8:  It's like, that's, that's the stakes that they're making. And then everybody
Speaker 8:  in Hollywood is like, if, if you don't stop them from doing this, no
Speaker 8:  creative act will ever occur in the future ever again. And
Speaker 8:  it's like, what if we all just settled down a little? Like can
Speaker 8:  we all, it's, it's just, let's
Speaker 7:  Wait. In this case I kind of agree with Hollywood. I think mean I wanna be
Speaker 8:  Like, if, if you want me to pick a side, I'm on Hollywood's side. It's not
Speaker 8:  close, but
Speaker 7:  Like It is true that the number of movies is going down, right? Like
Speaker 7:  it's true that we all have to, we're like pretend severance is like 10 times
Speaker 7:  better than It is 'cause it's the only good
Speaker 8:  Thing. Okay. Okay. Do you know what I mean? How dare you? First of all,
Speaker 7:  Like there's nothing as good as that to compare it to except the White Lotus.
Speaker 7:  And now we all have to pretend that shows in which nothing happens are like
Speaker 7:  the peak of all cinema. Throw that out there.
Speaker 8:  I
Speaker 7:  Say
Speaker 8:  I Nila, you know, I hate you. So this, this, this brings me great
Speaker 8:  pain to say, but after like two episodes ago of Severance
Speaker 8:  Nila posted on Blue Sky, something to the effect of they made a 40 minute
Speaker 8:  episode of Severance in which the first 12 minutes is her going to a place
Speaker 8:  asking for a ride to a place to get another ride to another place. And I
Speaker 8:  have, I, I have laughed thinking about that post every single day
Speaker 8:  since then. Ben, Ben still have replied to that
Speaker 7:  Post. Ben Stiller did not laugh at that post. Feel great. Very good. Ben,
Speaker 7:  you're also welcome on the road cast. It'll go, it'll go better for you.
Speaker 7:  I like severance. I like the show. My point is just, we make so fewer
Speaker 7:  shows that the bar is like, we have to
Speaker 7:  pretend that like asking for a ride is like the peak of all
Speaker 7:  television art and like maybe it isn't. Yeah. And so I'm just, I'm just saying
Speaker 7:  Hollywood might have a point here. We should make some more stuff. We should,
Speaker 7:  we should not be in this situation.
Speaker 8:  True. But Lauren, to your point, like if, if I'm one of these
Speaker 8:  companies, I would very much like to be excluded from the
Speaker 8:  deep hate toward big tech. And I have to like all that is
Speaker 8:  still coming for these companies. And I, I if, if I'm open ai, I would super
Speaker 8:  love to just kind of be over here. It's like, maybe, maybe use all the deregulation
Speaker 8:  you're doing again on me and not, I
Speaker 7:  Would big, I just dunno what the outcome. Isn't it like, can you imagine
Speaker 7:  Trump issuing an executive order that's like, I have decided that AI is fair
Speaker 7:  use.
Speaker 8:  Yes.
Speaker 7:  But like
Speaker 8:  A hundred Yes. Whatcha talking about?
Speaker 7:  Sure, sure. We
Speaker 8:  It's the Gulf of America now.
Speaker 7:  Whatcha
Speaker 8:  Talking about?
Speaker 7:  Sure. But like, all right, I just, there's
Speaker 7:  a part of me that where he knows he still gets royalties from The Apprentice,
Speaker 7:  you know what I mean? Like he knows where his money comes from
Speaker 7:  and that one's particularly hard. Like I have personally like,
Speaker 7:  intervened in a bunch of active court cases I don't really care about. He
Speaker 7:  is, it's much more likely that he would do Gulf America. I dunno. Lauren,
Speaker 7:  what do you think the end game is here? Just like give it a shot?
Speaker 12:  I think so. I mean, I think they're gonna try to say
Speaker 12:  something on AI one way or another. So the company is want to
Speaker 12:  make sure that their point of view and you know, to David's point,
Speaker 12:  maybe the most hysterical version of that point of view is heard.
Speaker 7:  All right, we'll see, I mean, I'm very excited for Trump to weigh in on 17
Speaker 7:  USC 1 0 7 specifically by statute. Look, there's a bunch of other
Speaker 7:  politics stuff on the website. It is a heated time in
Speaker 7:  America. It should be obvious to anybody who's paying attention. We have
Speaker 7:  a great story to speak about. Doge straining all the US A ID workers with
Speaker 7:  like work laptops full of data with no plan to recover them. We got stories
Speaker 7:  about this Tesla Takedown protests, which are starting to have a real effect
Speaker 7:  on that, on that stock price.
Speaker 7:  One of the dumbest things that keeps happening in this administration is
Speaker 7:  they just keep removing webpages by searching
Speaker 7:  for words that mean other things. And so like
Speaker 7:  a bunch of black soldiers got removed from the Department of Defense website
Speaker 7:  because they just added the phrase DEI to the URLs and then broke all the
Speaker 7:  URLs. Like all this stuff is just like relentlessly happening. We're covering
Speaker 7:  it. I know a lot of our listeners and a lot of our audience
Speaker 7:  would like a break from it. We're gonna add some filtering to the website,
Speaker 7:  but we're not gonna stop covering it. I, I wanna say that as clearly as I
Speaker 7:  can. This is the story the government is breaking and a lot of It is breaking
Speaker 7:  because the tech industry is insisting that it get broken in the form of
Speaker 7:  Elon Musk. Yes. But also in the form of Google just writing a letter saying,
Speaker 7:  what if Cop lab go away. What do you think?
Speaker 7:  And it just, it it, all of that keeps relentlessly happening. So we're gonna
Speaker 7:  keep covering it on, we have to build some stuff, we have some big ideas
Speaker 7:  about how to filter through the site. So we're gonna build those tools for
Speaker 7:  you as well. We'll do some RSS stuff. We can do that pretty fast, but I just
Speaker 7:  wanna say clearly we're gonna keep covering it. Lauren is doing a great job
Speaker 7:  of leading a bunch of that coverage. So thank you so much Lauren. Lauren,
Speaker 8:  I should also warn you that you're, you're gonna be on this show a lot in
Speaker 8:  the next six weeks. And I'm really sorry in advance. You're also gonna be
Speaker 8:  in courtrooms a lot in the next six weeks. And I'm also really sorry in advance.
Speaker 8:  Yes, thank you. But it's, it's about to be a wild spring for
Speaker 8:  you in particular. And, and we're, we're gonna be hanging out a lot.
Speaker 12:  April's gonna be a crazy month.
Speaker 8:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Will we make tiktoks about it? Who knows? We'll find out on April 6th.
Speaker 7:  Lauren, thank you so much for being on.
Speaker 12:  Thanks.
Speaker 7:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 7:  it's getting more embarrassing every time. The
Speaker 8:  Calls for t-shirts keep coming in and they've gotten to the point where there
Speaker 8:  are several people who are now annoyed at me for bringing up t-shirts and
Speaker 8:  not making the t-shirts. If you have an unsponsored
Speaker 8:  for flavored t-shirt design, I would love to see it.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I I that's, that's all I can tell you. I don't know. I have no promises
Speaker 8:  on what will happen with it,
Speaker 8:  but I, I personally want both an unsponsored for flavor
Speaker 8:  shirt that looks like I'm an unsponsored skateboarder and I want an everything's
Speaker 8:  computer t-shirt. I can't promise that either of those will exist or that
Speaker 8:  we will do them, but I want them both in my life very badly.
Speaker 7:  I understand. I mean, you know, the implication is that when we're
Speaker 7:  sponsored there's less flavor, which is just not, it would repeat to
Speaker 7:  everyone that it's fine because we exist in the, you know, the, the
Speaker 7:  creator economy writ large. And I, I think for
Speaker 7:  many folks the sponsorship does reduce flavor.
Speaker 7:  But that's not us. 'cause we, we have this annoyingly precious ethics policy.
Speaker 7:  Right. It's just a difference. And what,
Speaker 8:  That's all.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it's still, I still directly challenge
Speaker 7:  FCC commissioners to humiliation rituals on the show. You can sponsor it
Speaker 7:  or not. It's gonna keep happening no matter what. All right. I was gonna
Speaker 8:  Brought to you by the FCC,
Speaker 7:  If we can ever pull like the, an executive from an ISP on one
Speaker 7:  of our shows, I'll be like, have you unsponsored.
Speaker 7:  Alright. I wanted to stop talking about Elon in politics, but the first item
Speaker 7:  in the lightning round, it demands it. There's no other place in the show
Speaker 7:  for this sentence to go. Tesla recalls more than
Speaker 7:  46,000 Cybertrucks after trim starts falling off.
Speaker 7:  Is that all of them?
Speaker 7:  It seems like a lot of them It does. It it sure does. I don't think
Speaker 7:  they sold a lot. They, they've been sitting on lots. We've known the trim
Speaker 7:  has been falling off for seven months. YouTubers have making videos
Speaker 7:  about the trim. You know, it's the triangle piece. It's just glued on there,
Speaker 7:  like the part that goes over the window. It's been flying all these cars
Speaker 7:  since the first day. Like we've known for a long time that this piece
Speaker 7:  falls off the cars and we're only getting the recall now.
Speaker 7:  Cool. A recall applies to every cyber truck manufacturer between
Speaker 7:  November 13th, 2023, February 27th, 2025. It's
Speaker 7:  the eighth recall. A lot of them were software, but
Speaker 7:  a similar recall was announced last summer regarding a trim fault and a truck
Speaker 7:  bed that also risked coming loose.
Speaker 8:  This car is not super well made. It does not seem to
Speaker 8:  be the, the, the takeaway here.
Speaker 7:  It does not seem great. I think one of the more interesting things about
Speaker 7:  Tesla right now, and we don't have to overdo It, is that the bloom is coming
Speaker 7:  off the roads such that YouTubers are starting to chase the company.
Speaker 7:  So there's, you know, there's a Mark Rober video this week about
Speaker 7:  autopilot and lidar and there's a lot of weirdness with that video. We don't
Speaker 7:  have to like over talk it, but there's just some, like when he drives
Speaker 7:  the car through the, the wall, if you've seen the video, he drives
Speaker 7:  Tesla through a wall that's like a Wiley Coyote painting of a more
Speaker 7:  road. 'cause the cameras, 'cause the thesis is the cameras won't be able
Speaker 7:  to detect the wall because they, they just use visions Sea Road
Speaker 7:  when he drives through it, it like is a Looney Tunes cutout of like a
Speaker 7:  thing you would drive through. Like there's, it's an entertainment piece.
Speaker 7:  You can tell that it's an entertainment piece. But there's that you can see
Speaker 7:  jig, everything has been really harsh on the cyber truck lately.
Speaker 7:  Marquez has been posting about his Roadster pre-order that It is never
Speaker 7:  shipping. I think he wrote age like milk over screenshot of it. You're just
Speaker 7:  seeing, it's like, it's fine now in a way that, you know, they're still getting
Speaker 7:  intact and there's quite a lot of angst about it. But it, it's just
Speaker 7:  fine now to point out the problems with this, these this, this company
Speaker 7:  and its cars. And that is, that's a pretty big change.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. John Herman at our, our friend at New York Mag wrote a really good
Speaker 8:  piece about this this week basically looking at that turn
Speaker 8:  and at, at how long Tesla
Speaker 8:  kept this thing where it was sort of a universally praised
Speaker 8:  thing in that space. And it was, it was considered sort of this
Speaker 8:  standard thing to do to like Tesla, like every tech
Speaker 8:  YouTuber loved Elon Musk and loved Tesla. And it was like, it represented
Speaker 8:  everything that people in that space believed in.
Speaker 8:  And that has completely shifted.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It just totally flipped. Yeah. And you know the, the protests, I think
Speaker 7:  we, I interviewed Ed Meyer who wrote ludicrous the inside story of Tesla
Speaker 7:  Motors. He's one of the leaders that Tesla Takedown protest movement. And
Speaker 7:  I'm just gonna say this clear, he said on the show he disavows any vandalism
Speaker 7:  or violence. I asked him directly, he said it this is is like the bot comment
Speaker 7:  of the day about Tesla protests. Yeah. I asked him and he said don't do
Speaker 7:  vandalism or violence, but those protests are having an impact 'cause people
Speaker 7:  are starting to, the bloom is coming off the roads of the brand and now investors,
Speaker 7:  big investors are starting to say things like, Elon needs to pay attention
Speaker 7:  to Tesla. We'll see how it plays out. I'm just, I'm just
Speaker 7:  pointing out the cyber truck continues to be one of the funniest cars ever
Speaker 7:  made.
Speaker 7:  Big silly wiper. You my guys. Alright David, do you know
Speaker 7:  what's going on with this book? This Careless People book it, it's like
Speaker 7:  it keeps crossing my path. I have a copy of it. It just seems like Meta
Speaker 7:  wanted this book to go away. 'cause it's a book about Mark Zuckerberg and
Speaker 7:  Meta and now it's at the top of the New York Times best
Speaker 7:  list.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I mean it It is, It is like an all time streisand effect moment
Speaker 8:  where Sarah Wynn Williams writes this book about her time at
Speaker 8:  Meta
Speaker 8:  that meta I think perceived to be, you know,
Speaker 8:  disastrously terrible and full of lies. And so entered
Speaker 8:  into this big fight to try and issue an injunction to prevent her
Speaker 8:  from, from promoting and distributing the book. It became this whole thing.
Speaker 8:  The publisher came out and said, you know, we, we defend what's in the book.
Speaker 8:  This has been carefully vetted. Increasingly people
Speaker 8:  who are reading the book seemed to be
Speaker 8:  a vouching for a lot of it. That that what she is writing is, is true.
Speaker 8:  I have not read the book so I can't say for sure, but I know Alex Heath on
Speaker 8:  our team has one and has been talking to people about it. The book is just
Speaker 8:  out, you can just read it. I should read it this weekend. But
Speaker 8:  by all accounts, it It is actually, it's it's a good book
Speaker 8:  full of real allegations and implications about
Speaker 8:  the workplace at Meta. Some of them about, you
Speaker 8:  know, harassment and real problems.
Speaker 8:  Meta has just played this exactly the worst possible way if you're meta and
Speaker 8:  don't want people to read this book because now like you said, It is a number
Speaker 8:  one bestseller, which for I would say for even a pretty
Speaker 8:  splashy like memoir of a person's experience inside of a company is pretty
Speaker 8:  unusual. Yeah. To to be a number one bestseller is not an easy thing to
Speaker 8:  pull off.
Speaker 8:  And now this, this book is a huge story. It is, I think
Speaker 8:  the book itself is a bigger story than anything in the book at the
Speaker 8:  moment, which is really interesting. Like the, this fight I think has subsumed
Speaker 8:  some of the conversation about like the allegations of what has gone gone
Speaker 8:  on inside of meta, which is a weird way to have
Speaker 8:  this conversation go. But it's, it's, it's very much out there
Speaker 8:  now and I suspect I like many others will be reading
Speaker 8:  this book much more carefully and enthusiastically than I would've
Speaker 8:  otherwise.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. The the weird thing about It is that meta, they
Speaker 7:  pulled out her like arbitration agreement went to an
Speaker 7:  arbitrator and said she's not allowed to promote the book and then the publisher
Speaker 7:  of the book and then the meta completely
Speaker 7:  overstated that ruling and they're like, we've in vindicated this book as
Speaker 7:  lies, which is not what the ruling said. And then the publisher of the book
Speaker 7:  is like, look, that has nothing to do with us. We're gonna continue promoting
Speaker 7:  the book. So we're in this weird limbo, we're meta you know,
Speaker 7:  we're doing free speech now. We're gonna use community notes. Everything's
Speaker 7:  wide open on meta platforms, is actively trying to shut down speech. And
Speaker 7:  the thing that happens when you actively try to shut down speech is definitely
Speaker 7:  happening. Which is everyone is curious about the thing they're not supposed
Speaker 7:  to read.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, right.
Speaker 7:  It just never works.
Speaker 8:  No,
Speaker 7:  And I, it of all of the companies who should know this meta should know this
Speaker 7:  and they're like Andy Stone, like meta comms is like on threads
Speaker 7:  every day being like replying to anyone who says anything about this book
Speaker 7:  being like, this book is lies Right. How
Speaker 8:  Dare you.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And it's just like, what are you doing? Like what, what, what has you
Speaker 7:  so worked up? And maybe It is all lies but this isn't,
Speaker 8:  But then you get people like Dustin Moskovitz, one of the co-founders of
Speaker 8:  Facebook saying essentially that he
Speaker 8:  encourages everybody to read the book and that there are lots of allegations
Speaker 8:  in there. But that actually inside of all of that is a really interesting
Speaker 8:  and telling Reid about how the company works and how the
Speaker 8:  personalities inside of the company operate. Like there's a lot about
Speaker 8:  Sheryl Sandberg and a lot about Joel Kaplan and like, it, it seems to be,
Speaker 8:  again, I have not read the book, we should talk about this once we've both
Speaker 8:  read it. But that there is a lot of just
Speaker 8:  sort of interesting business memoir inside of here that is not super flattering
Speaker 8:  to meta that now an awful lot of people are going to be exposed
Speaker 8:  to. 'cause there is, there, there is I think a really interesting
Speaker 8:  version of this story that is like there are big
Speaker 8:  problematic allegations that will get talked about and we'll get run through
Speaker 8:  the, the press and will be become the story. But then there are,
Speaker 8:  I think the sort of lingering legacy of books like this is they do
Speaker 8:  start to big picture change the way you understand how companies like
Speaker 8:  this work. And I think we might get to that
Speaker 8:  legacy much faster because this has become such a big story that It is like,
Speaker 8:  oh if for meta to be this upset about this must mean she's telling the truth.
Speaker 8:  And that becomes really powerful. Yeah. And I, I think like we're, this book
Speaker 8:  is going to have really interesting different impact even from
Speaker 8:  the sort of immediately headline grabbing allegations that it makes.
Speaker 7:  You know what's interesting is, you know, I flipped through the galley, I
Speaker 7:  haven't read it closely, but I flipped through the galley and I've read a
Speaker 7:  bunch of stories about the book and some of the experts and what's fascinating
Speaker 7:  about It is it makes meta seem really small and personality driven. Like
Speaker 7:  Mark Zuckerberg is fiddling with individual content moderation decisions.
Speaker 7:  Various executives are very personally driving the company,
Speaker 8:  Which is the opposite of how Meta wants you to think about it.
Speaker 7:  Right? Meta wants to be a government. Right. Right. Like that's how they,
Speaker 7:  they set up a Supreme Court for God's sake. Nobody cares about, I
Speaker 7:  would compare that to Mark Bergen, who's a great journalist, I think It
Speaker 7:  is a Bloomberg. He wrote a book about YouTube called Light Comment, subscribe.
Speaker 7:  He was on decoder. You can listen to the interview. I love this book. It's
Speaker 7:  a good book because it makes YouTube seem big like the scale
Speaker 7:  of the problem that YouTube has to solve with content moderation, with what
Speaker 7:  It is with the interface. All this stuff, particularly under Susan Moki,
Speaker 7:  it, the book doesn't shy away from the problem and it's deeply reported.
Speaker 7:  It's in the weeds of YouTube and it makes the case somewhat
Speaker 7:  persuasively that YouTube has a shitload of problems and that like
Speaker 7:  all these people are stressed to the max every single day. But the reason
Speaker 7:  YouTube is perceived to be slow is because they're taking it seriously.
Speaker 7:  Right. I can issue criticisms of YouTube all day, all night and maybe
Speaker 7:  we'll do that in another episode of the show. But it was just interesting
Speaker 7:  comparing contrasting these, these two books and what you're saying about
Speaker 7:  the narratives that take hold of a company like that book is very, very
Speaker 7:  critical of YouTube. And I really do encourage people to radio or listen
Speaker 7:  to Episode of Coder, but it, you just, it it conveys the
Speaker 7:  scale of the problem and it makes YouTube seem big in comparison to that
Speaker 7:  scale. And I think the reason Meta hates this book is it makes 'em all
Speaker 7:  seem small. Hmm. And Alex is, Alex Heath is reading,
Speaker 7:  he is doing some reporting to try to figure out what's happening. Some of
Speaker 7:  these claims we'll have more of that. We'll probably have him come talk about
Speaker 7:  the show next week or a week after when he is done with that process. But
Speaker 7:  that's just my, my read of It is like, oh these guys hate it when you make
Speaker 7:  'em seem small. Yeah. Speaking of meta, there's a little bit of activity.
Speaker 7:  Pub news, ugh. After a big run for Blue Sky
Speaker 7:  Activity Pub. Well some glimmers. So the May maybe the most important one
Speaker 7:  in terms of meta threads by the way Sports Activity Pub threads is now gonna
Speaker 7:  let you set your following feed by default. Just five years
Speaker 7:  too late. But they're gonna do it
Speaker 8:  Five years too late for a 2-year-old product.
Speaker 7:  It feels right they're gonna do it. I think that's, I think that's smart.
Speaker 7:  I think they've lost a lot of juice to Blue Sky.
Speaker 8:  Yes. I think threads in a really funny way. I think
Speaker 8:  I thought Threads was sort of speed running Instagram where it was gonna
Speaker 8:  go and become this sort of central platform. Everybody was very quickly
Speaker 8:  and what it actually looks like it's doing is, is speed running Facebook
Speaker 8:  where it becomes the thing that everybody is on but no one pays attention
Speaker 8:  to really quickly. And I think
Speaker 8:  Meta does not wanna build another Facebook, even though Facebook has been
Speaker 8:  very good to meta for a really long time. Like that is a dying thing and
Speaker 8:  you don't want to get to the end state of that very quickly.
Speaker 8:  And yeah, I think they are desperate to make threads a place people want
Speaker 8:  to hang out in the way that Blue Sky is a place people want to hang out.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And the size advantage it has is real,
Speaker 8:  right? Like they continue to dominate in terms of like raw
Speaker 8:  number of users and people who and whatever. But like Blue Sky is more fun
Speaker 8:  and, and like I we're in so many ways
Speaker 8:  what Facebook was to Twitter, which is vastly bigger and
Speaker 8:  totally irrelevant threads now risks becoming to Blue Sky.
Speaker 8:  And if I'm Mark Zuckerberg and Adam Aria, I am like fighting tooth and
Speaker 8:  nail to make sure that doesn't happen. And the best thing that that has led
Speaker 8:  to is better product. This truly like this thing
Speaker 8:  where you can just see your following feed does not happen if
Speaker 8:  Blue Sky doesn't exist. And without question it just doesn't because this
Speaker 8:  company has very specific ideas about what it believes is best and is best
Speaker 8:  for engagement and the following feed is not good for
Speaker 8:  engagement. It just isn't. And it doesn't matter because they need people
Speaker 8:  to use the platform. Yeah. And, and it's so, it's so
Speaker 8:  good that this, that there is real meaningful competition here because it's
Speaker 8:  forcing everybody's hands to actually build better products.
Speaker 7:  I honestly think one of the, the biggest successes of the TikTok
Speaker 7:  algorithm is that It is divorced from time, but it
Speaker 7:  still manages to feel relevant. Mm. Right. The the, there's something
Speaker 7:  really good about that algorithm where you're like, some
Speaker 7:  news happened today and like you see it on TikTok in the algorithm pretty
Speaker 7:  much right away, right? Like it just happens every day. Like
Speaker 7:  Yeah whoever's on tour right now, you see clips from the concert of that
Speaker 7:  night like in real time every day
Speaker 7:  Threads is so divorced in time. Yes. Right. It like
Speaker 7:  never feels relevant. So even you get the big algorithmic juice,
Speaker 7:  which is what everyone wants to copy from TikTok, but you lose
Speaker 7:  all of the relevance and then Blue Sky is just a fire hose of nonstop
Speaker 7:  apocalyptic relevance. Yeah. But at least it's funny, you know, like yeah
Speaker 7:  I don't think they've nailed that. 'cause once you lose the relevance then
Speaker 7:  you're like Twitter like becomes meaningless.
Speaker 7:  So you can have everybody there, but it's like, what's the point? And in
Speaker 7:  particular the thing that they, I think they've utterly biffed on is sports.
Speaker 7:  'cause if you don't want politics right? They keep saying they don't want
Speaker 7:  politics, they want to pol it's like dude, just like build great,
Speaker 7:  like hire every sports beat writer in America
Speaker 7:  and pay Adam Shefter to put the trades there first. Right.
Speaker 8:  Well the the problem is sports might
Speaker 8:  move faster on the like new to irrelevant timeline than
Speaker 8:  anything else. Yeah. Because like play by play and signing by set,
Speaker 8:  like all that stuff happens so fast and It is, it ceases to be timely and
Speaker 8:  new seconds after it happens. And so I think
Speaker 8:  for threads to try and be more like Instagram where they're a little more
Speaker 8:  timeless and they can show you older stuff that is still interesting doesn't
Speaker 8:  work with any of that stuff. And like what, what I think Threads is slowly
Speaker 8:  learning that Blue Sky learned really fast is that there is no middle
Speaker 8:  ground between like Twitter and Instagram. You just have to do Twitter. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Like you can't do Twitter on an Instagram
Speaker 8:  pace. Like you, the only way to do It is at Twitter pace and Blue Sky
Speaker 8:  figured that out really fast. And I think to its benefit,
Speaker 7:  It's it do you post to both every now and again I post to both in my experiences
Speaker 7:  you just see that
Speaker 7:  anything on threads just lives a life free of constraints.
Speaker 7:  It's so free. Like random people find it, they get mad at you
Speaker 7:  for reasons that are impossible to understand. 'cause they're seeing your
Speaker 7:  posts like six months after it happened. Blue Sky is a very tight
Speaker 7:  constrained amount of anger and then it, it dips, right?
Speaker 8:  Everybody gets mad at you for 10 minutes and minutes outta their feet.
Speaker 7:  Like a threats post that goes is like three weeks of just Randos being like,
Speaker 7:  I bought a Mac five years ago and it's like, I don't remember what we were
Speaker 7:  talking about at all. Yeah. Speaking of Activity, pub
Speaker 7:  Ghost, the so Open source rival the Substack newsletter
Speaker 7:  platform, they have completed the first switch of their
Speaker 7:  activity pub integration. It's, I think it's still in beta. You have to go
Speaker 7:  enable it. But they, so now you can ghost newsletters can go out over activity
Speaker 7:  pub to platforms like Pixel Fed to threads to MAs on. And then
Speaker 7:  importantly if you're a ghost person, you can feed all those things
Speaker 7:  back into Ghost. This is the one, you know, it's,
Speaker 7:  I don't think it's gonna set the world on fire, but especially 'cause it's
Speaker 7:  just in beta it's very small, but the part where the content comes back in
Speaker 7:  and if you're a ghost newsletter writer, you can look at Mastodon
Speaker 7:  and then like republish that and get engagement.
Speaker 7:  That's the part that I'm dying to see happen. 'cause that's the promise of
Speaker 7:  all these services and none of them it's come true nowhere yet.
Speaker 8:  Right. And that's also like, this is, if you wanna understand what
Speaker 8:  makes the Fedi verse interesting, it's this stuff, right? Because it's not
Speaker 8:  my Twitter clone can talk to your Twitter clone is one thing that's fine
Speaker 8:  and that's exciting and that's part of the solution here. But this is,
Speaker 8:  I can publish a newsletter that goes to my website, your email
Speaker 8:  inbox and their Mastodon feed. And if they respond to my email
Speaker 8:  or like on their mastodon or comment on my blog,
Speaker 8:  that actually all ends up as one conversation. And like
Speaker 8:  that is the thing that is hard to wrap your head around, but is ultimately
Speaker 8:  what makes this stuff work. Yeah. Is, is that it's
Speaker 8:  just stuff and it, you write where you want and I read where I
Speaker 8:  want and we both talk to each other in different places, but have the same
Speaker 8:  conversation. It's like, that's the magic of it.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I can, It is concretely, you know, we talked about that starlink
Speaker 7:  and the White House story that was on Reddit. It got
Speaker 7:  hundreds if not a thousand comments. It it just did big numbers over
Speaker 7:  there. And the people on our site never saw that, that that whole set of
Speaker 7:  engagement had happened. Right. And if I could just connect those communities,
Speaker 7:  maybe not directly. 'cause I think there's value to having distinction between
Speaker 7:  communities, but if I could just let you see, like there's a huge conversation
Speaker 7:  about this story happening somewhere else and that's built into the piping
Speaker 7:  of the internet, then I, we all kind of get more value out of all of it.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. As opposed to being like, we basically just like gave Reddit a thing
Speaker 7:  to generate free content about like, if we can all pull that together,
Speaker 7:  there's something strong there. So I'm happy if the ghost has done this,
Speaker 7:  I'm watching it. I do think there's a protocol fight between Activity Pub
Speaker 7:  and at Protocol, which is what Blue Sky runs on. But like that's pretty fun.
Speaker 7:  I agree. Green shoots of innovation. Okay. Last one. I just
Speaker 7:  wanna, I wanna read you this quote head Sandos, the co CEO of Netflix.
Speaker 7:  The, the, the content. CEO gave the interview
Speaker 7:  to Variety and then they asked him about Apple TV and here's what he said
Speaker 7:  about Apple TV plus, I don't understand it beyond a marketing ploy, but they're
Speaker 7:  really smart people. Maybe they see something we don't,
Speaker 7:  that's a pretty good dunk.
Speaker 8:  I love this so much. He dunked on everybody in this one interview.
Speaker 8:  He like came at David lov and
Speaker 8:  Warner Brothers of Discovery for going with the Max name instead of the HBO
Speaker 8:  name. He dunked on Amazon. He was like, they're good at football, but I don't
Speaker 8:  what else are they doing? But I agree this was, this was the best one that
Speaker 8:  he's basically like, I don't know. They can, they can throw some money at
Speaker 8:  this if they want to. Did you see also the information had a story
Speaker 8:  I think today that said Apple's streaming is losing
Speaker 8:  over a billion dollars a year.
Speaker 8:  That It, is it, it it like maybe Ted Sarandos is right, like
Speaker 8:  maybe this is just Apple wanting to
Speaker 8:  have an in with people and be able to bring Oprah Winfrey up on
Speaker 8:  stage at events to talk about a billion pockets. And
Speaker 8:  I, I do think there is more to it than just that, but
Speaker 8:  It is, It is not obvious what Apple is in this for at
Speaker 7:  Particular moment. Wait, you don't, don't think it's obvious. I think it's
Speaker 7:  totally obvious. I
Speaker 8:  Think I, I can Galaxy brain my way into a theory,
Speaker 8:  but it, It is clearly not just
Speaker 8:  trying to build a competitive streaming service. Like No, it's,
Speaker 7:  It's definitely not that.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. So, okay. What do you think It is? You think it's obvious?
Speaker 7:  I think it's, I think it's obvious. I think Apple's money doesn't come from
Speaker 7:  the iPhone anymore, right. iPhone sales are declining, max sales are growing,
Speaker 7:  but like, it's not enough. Apple's money comes
Speaker 7:  from Candy Crush Whales.
Speaker 8:  Sure. Yeah. Like
Speaker 7:  Meaningfully, that's the money. It comes from the base
Speaker 7:  tier of iCloud being way too small and everyone having to pay for more storage.
Speaker 7:  Right. And then they upsell you into services. But like it's in-app
Speaker 7:  purchases, it's the, it's the app store tax, right? It's 30% on Candy Crush
Speaker 7:  whales. That is the bulk of Apple's revenue now. It's the thing that's
Speaker 7:  growing every year. It's growing and you cannot be like, okay,
Speaker 7:  we're the richest company in the world. We're the most innovative company
Speaker 7:  in the world. The money is from Candy Crush Whale.
Speaker 7:  They can't, they, they have to put a, a better face on
Speaker 7:  services.
Speaker 8:  Interesting.
Speaker 7:  And so you get severance and you're like, we're the company that makes severance.
Speaker 7:  That's a service. Don't you love Apple TV plus the service, we're a services
Speaker 7:  company and then hidden under that
Speaker 7:  are some Candy Crush wheels.
Speaker 8:  So it's the, it's the sexy lost leader in the bundle
Speaker 8:  that like, makes the bundle seem cooler than just payment processing
Speaker 8:  and Candy Crush whales.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Because I think if they're that company then they, they lose
Speaker 7:  their, their like sense of self. Right, right. Like what
Speaker 7:  we are is Stripe, but we have a gun. You know, like
Speaker 7:  and the gun is your app doesn't exist anymore. Right? Yeah. I don't,
Speaker 7:  that's not Apple. I think they're we're That's interesting. We're the creative
Speaker 7:  company and we make the Mac Pro. And don't you, this video music
Speaker 7:  video was shot on an iPhone. Like they're that company. I think they have
Speaker 7:  a lot of consternation about how much money all this is losing. Yes.
Speaker 7:  But I think at the end of the day, all of it exists to,
Speaker 7:  to make them the art company, not the billing company.
Speaker 8:  That's a good take. And It is, I think would, would Apple spend
Speaker 8:  a billion dollars a year on maintaining its identity
Speaker 8:  as a company that does and loves creative stuff? Absolutely. No
Speaker 8:  question. Yeah. Which is why like there was all this talk when Severance
Speaker 8:  season two was coming out about how, you know, super delayed and super over
Speaker 8:  budget. And now It is, It is probably the
Speaker 8:  busiest show out right now. I would say
Speaker 8:  you hate it, but you're, what do you know, I'm
Speaker 7:  I, I watched this show religiously. I think It is beautiful. It is
Speaker 7:  beautifully made. I'm just saying we have
Speaker 7:  landed in a time when there are so few beautifully
Speaker 7:  well-crafted things to watch that we have to
Speaker 7:  pretend that this is the best one that's ever been. Sure. But
Speaker 8:  But I, this is all ancillary to my point, which is I think your argument
Speaker 8:  would suggest that the brand value of how much people
Speaker 8:  loved Ted Lasso and how invested people are in severance
Speaker 8:  makes the rest of the thing irrelevant. That like, it's not quite
Speaker 8:  marketing, but it, It is like, it's, it's like a love engine for Apple that
Speaker 8:  kind of doesn't exist anywhere else right now.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And again, they get to show up on their earnings calls and say,
Speaker 7:  once again, services led the quarter with our award-winning
Speaker 7:  show Ted Lasso. Right. Not with our Candy Crush whale,
Speaker 7:  extremely ruthless collection of taxes from Candy Crush Whales.
Speaker 8:  We extracted more value from all of our app developers.
Speaker 7:  Every developer in the world is pissed at us. Yeah. Because our people call
Speaker 7:  them up and demand that we add in-app purchases to their apps
Speaker 7:  and that's our money. Like you, have you heard about Ted Lasso? He's so
Speaker 7:  cheerful.
Speaker 8:  No, I I I buy that. That's a good theory.
Speaker 7:  And I I I do think they'll reconcile costs along the way. 'cause
Speaker 7:  I mean, what am I pointing out? There's less competition for beautifully
Speaker 7:  made shows. So I they will find a way to bring things.
Speaker 7:  You can see it. What's that movie they just made The Gorge
Speaker 7:  don't do that. They're, they're bad at that. Like they should stop
Speaker 7:  spending that money. I think have they made a movie that's like, like Good
Speaker 8:  Coda won Best Picture
Speaker 7:  But they didn't they bought that movie. True.
Speaker 8:  No, I of the like big Apple originals F1
Speaker 8:  is the Big swing coming this summer. That's gonna be
Speaker 8:  the one I would guess it's either going to be a big monster
Speaker 8:  hit or It is going to make a lot of heads roll inside of Apple
Speaker 8:  because that is, I think by, by some accounts like one of the most expensive
Speaker 8:  movies of all time, they've been talking about it forever. It is, it's it's
Speaker 8:  a huge deal for Apple. And if it doesn't hit, I think a lot of people
Speaker 8:  get fired.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I watched the trailer.
Speaker 7:  It it,
Speaker 8:  It's not a very good trailer.
Speaker 7:  It, it doesn't seem like it has a lot to do with one.
Speaker 8:  No, it's just Brad Pitt like being beautiful. Yeah. And he's very good at
Speaker 8:  that.
Speaker 7:  That said like even at this point Drive to Survive doesn't have a lot to
Speaker 7:  do with F1. No. Like I, what I think was Toto Wolf was like,
Speaker 7:  this show is basically Top Gun. And I was like, yeah. Rules. So
Speaker 7:  that's fine. Yeah. Got right. Yeah. Anyhow,
Speaker 7:  they'll reconcile their costs. But you can see, I think Ted
Speaker 7:  Sarandos knows that Apple has this to dress up its services line and he's,
Speaker 7:  I think he's willing to take that dunk.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And I don't think, I don't think Netflix feels pressure
Speaker 8:  from any of the companies. Ted Sarandos named here. Like yeah,
Speaker 7:  He's not worried about that. There was that one moment where they accidentally
Speaker 7:  lit up universal search on the Apple TV and everyone thought they caved and
Speaker 7:  they're like, Nope, no, we, we, we mis set a feature flag.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. I kind of like they did that on purpose just as a flex. They're like,
Speaker 8:  wouldn't it be cool if we did this too bad?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Alright. We're way over like way, way, way, way over. Thanks again
Speaker 7:  to Lauren for joining us. There's like a million stories on our site about
Speaker 7:  all kinds of things. Tech cos, Netflix.
Speaker 7:  It's a good website. You should read. It's at The Verge dot com. We
Speaker 8:  Have the show notes will be lively this week.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, there's a lot going on. That's it. That's for Chest.
Speaker 9:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 9:  you. Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one. The
Speaker 9:  Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network.
Speaker 9:  Our show's produced by Will Poor Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer.
Speaker 9:  And that's it. We'll see you next week.