# Transcript
ID: 5e5d43bf-632d-429e-b4c1-1d34d920d960
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/3505758132638545451/365666520029439524/s93290-US-4719s-1742176993.mp3
Description: In this episode, what's old is new again, and what's new is... AI again. The Verge's Allison Johnson and Dominic Preston join David to discuss their experience at Mobile World Congress 2025, where they saw the latest devices from Xiaomi, Samsung, Realme, and others — and found themselves confronted with some big, surprising new ideas about how our smartphones should look and work. After that, Kevin Rose and Justin Mezzell talk about the process of bringing Digg back, and how AI can improve the way social networks operate. Digg got a lot of things right two decades ago, and plans to do it all over again now. Finally, we answer a question about printers from the Vergecast Hotline (call 866-VERGE11 or email vergecast@theverge.com!), with some help from Framework CEO Nirav Patel.
Speaker 1:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of Camera Bump
Speaker 1:  functionality. I'm your friend David Pierce, and I am sitting here trying
Speaker 1:  to decide which iPad is the best. So I
Speaker 1:  have the new mini, which came out last fall. I have the New Air, which is
Speaker 1:  coming out this week. I have the M four Pro,
Speaker 1:  which came out like roughly this time last year. And then I have the M two
Speaker 1:  Air, which is now last year's model, which also came out about a year ago.
Speaker 1:  So basically I have in my hands every iPad you can buy except for
Speaker 1:  the new base iPad. I've not tried that one yet. I have
Speaker 1:  lots of questions, but I generally think that the base iPad is the right
Speaker 1:  iPad for most people. So I both have to review the
Speaker 1:  new ones and I have to go back and update our iPad buying guide on the site.
Speaker 1:  So it requires a lot of like existential thinking about tablets that
Speaker 1:  I found myself not ready for. So If you have thoughts on how
Speaker 1:  you use an iPad and how to basically pick between them for people,
Speaker 1:  I would love to hear them. But until then, I'm just gonna be playing games
Speaker 1:  on all of these iPads and that's just what I do now. This is
Speaker 1:  my life anyway. We are mostly not gonna talk about iPads on this episode.
Speaker 1:  We're gonna come back and do some more iPad stuff once I've had a chance
Speaker 1:  to try the base iPad, which will hopefully be soon. Today on the show,
Speaker 1:  we're gonna do two things. First, we're gonna catch up with Alison Johnson
Speaker 1:  and Dom Preston on our team. They were both at MWC Mobile World Congress
Speaker 1:  last week, seeing all the weirdest and newest ideas in mobile. Gonna catch
Speaker 1:  up with them, see what they learned. And then I'm gonna talk to Kevin Rose
Speaker 1:  and Justin Metzel, who are two of the people responsible for bringing back
Speaker 1:  Dig. Dig, an OG Social Network coming back for real
Speaker 1:  in 2025. Right now it's just a landing page and a wait list, but
Speaker 1:  it is, it is coming. It's a real thing. And we had a really interesting conversation
Speaker 1:  about community and how to build the social internet with
Speaker 1:  AI and how we can do this better than we did the first time. And so I figured
Speaker 1:  you guys should hear it. It's really interesting stuff. We also have a hotline
Speaker 1:  about printers that I'm very excited to get into. All of that is coming up
Speaker 1:  in just a second. But first, I think I have between
Speaker 1:  one and 16 software updates to do on these iPads.
Speaker 1:  Developer beta's, deeply terrifying thing when you're a product
Speaker 1:  viewer. Anyway, this is The Vergecast, we'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  I just, it's too many tablets. I can't keep them straight. They all look
Speaker 1:  the same. We'll worry about that later. Let's get into MWC. So MWC Mobile
Speaker 1:  World Congress for many years has been the kind of the biggest
Speaker 1:  show in mobile in the way that CES is like TVs and Cars.
Speaker 1:  MWC is phones. And for a few years, MWC got
Speaker 1:  kind of boring. Frankly, the phone market kind of died because no one else
Speaker 1:  could get into it. It was just Samsung and Apple and then a bunch of stuff
Speaker 1:  in China and kind of nothing else. But the mobile industry is actually
Speaker 1:  really interesting right now. And there are a lot of companies with new ideas
Speaker 1:  about smartphones, particularly as we get AI and particularly
Speaker 1:  as cameras become important in an AI world. Again, there's just a lot of
Speaker 1:  new ideas about phones. And so two folks on our team, Alison Johnson
Speaker 1:  and Dominic Preston went to MWC. They saw all this stuff
Speaker 1:  and I have lots of questions about all the stuff that they saw. So let's
Speaker 1:  just get into it. Here we go. Alison Johnson. Hello,
Speaker 6:  Hello.
Speaker 1:  And Dom Preston, welcome to The Vergecast. Hello. Thank you. Happy to be
Speaker 1:  here. Alison, I'm really sorry for not being as enthusiastic about you. Oh,
Speaker 6:  It's all
Speaker 1:  Right. I'm like, I'm also happy that you're here. I get it. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  I'm just, it's Dom's first time. I want Dom to feel welcome on The Vergecast.
Speaker 6:  It's exciting. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  I'm the shiny new thing. So you got, you two were just at MWC.
Speaker 1:  It seems like kind of an interesting year. Like tell me first just sort of
Speaker 1:  the, the vibes in Barcelona at MWC this year. What was it like?
Speaker 6:  It was kind of two things. There's like the phones and
Speaker 6:  they were sort of boring. And then there was everything
Speaker 6:  else, which was like
Speaker 6:  laptops that fold, a whole bunch stuff you put on your phone,
Speaker 6:  stuff you used to charge your phone, you know, it's a cool kind of like
Speaker 6:  reprieve from the, the moment we're in of like, yeah,
Speaker 6:  phones are boring, they're, they're good now. You know, like
Speaker 6:  there's Xmi 15 Ultra, which Dom tested
Speaker 6:  is incredible by all accounts. So it
Speaker 6:  was nice. It's, it's nice to go see like weird cool stuff.
Speaker 1:  Dom, what was your experience like?
Speaker 7:  It similar, I think even the biggest phone phone launch
Speaker 7:  is the Xiaomi 15 Ultra. And it's a great phone. It's a very cool phone. I
Speaker 7:  was really impressed by it, but it's a super iterative update on last year's
Speaker 7:  January 14 ultra. So like the most exciting phone launch of the show
Speaker 7:  wasn't all that exciting, right? But as Allison said, we just had all these
Speaker 7:  weird little odyssey going around accessories, concept
Speaker 7:  devices, concept, everything this time fo all
Speaker 7:  things, weird cameras, all sorts of stuff. And then the, the like
Speaker 7:  smaller brands playing around with just odd versions of phones like
Speaker 7:  Nubia releasing a few strange kind of a hundred dollars phones that
Speaker 7:  no one in the states can even buy that have rotating camera rings and giant
Speaker 7:  speakers on the back and, and weird stuff like that.
Speaker 1:  What's y'all sense? I wanna talk mostly about some of these specific gadgets,
Speaker 1:  but looking through the stuff that you guys covered, I found myself wondering
Speaker 1:  how real these companies think these products are.
Speaker 1:  I had this experience a bunch of years ago. I was in a, in a Lenovo
Speaker 1:  briefing at one of these trade shows, and they had this very cool looking
Speaker 1:  orange laptop, and the product person I was talking to was
Speaker 1:  like, oh, we're not gonna sell any of those. They're just there. So people
Speaker 1:  will come look at it and then they'll buy the black laptop. And that is like,
Speaker 1:  I have thought about that nonstop ever since. And what I wonder about so
Speaker 1:  many of these gadgets is like, yes, we're in a very sort of
Speaker 1:  iterative moment with smartphones. And so if I am Samsung or
Speaker 1:  Xmi or Huawei or Lenovo or any of these companies that you're seeing make
Speaker 1:  this stuff, are they actually seriously
Speaker 1:  making these things as in like this, this might be the next phone that you
Speaker 1:  want. Or are these like wild science projects that somebody built in the
Speaker 1:  lab that they're showing you so that we will cover them on The Verge dot
Speaker 1:  com even though they know absolutely no one ever will buy them?
Speaker 6:  I think it's like a range of stuff. And Lenovo's a good example because
Speaker 6:  they, the briefing we got, they literally had two rooms.
Speaker 6:  They're like, here are the real laptops, you have to go to the
Speaker 6:  other room. And that's where the weird laptops are interesting that like
Speaker 6:  fold and charge with solar panels and there's like a weird little
Speaker 6:  guy you put on your, your computer. So,
Speaker 6:  and I think even in that room there's degrees of like, this might be a real
Speaker 6:  thing. They had that weird, like, see,
Speaker 6:  it's like extra screens for your laptop that you kind of
Speaker 6:  like magnet to the back of your computer and then you
Speaker 6:  have like the, the wildest desk set up at a coffee
Speaker 6:  shop ever.
Speaker 6:  I don't know, I don't see that. Like it'll be strangely
Speaker 6:  if I can go to Best Buy and and pick that up someday.
Speaker 6:  But other stuff I think is, is like
Speaker 6:  plausible. The, the question is,
Speaker 6:  yeah, like in the US especially at something like Mobile
Speaker 6:  World Congress, are we gonna get these things or are we gonna
Speaker 6:  get even just the like $200 phone that that
Speaker 6:  company sells that like, kind of has some features.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it's kind of all over the place, I think.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Dom playing with these phones, you're, you're like standing there attaching
Speaker 1:  an enormous camera lens to a smartphone. Like are you, are you looking at
Speaker 1:  these things being like, this is a real thing that maybe people will have
Speaker 1:  in the real world on their phone someday? Or are you just like, neat thing
Speaker 1:  that you made that I'll never see again,
Speaker 7:  Trying to do a little bit of both. I guess you'd always know, okay. Especially
Speaker 7:  with ones like that, those concept devices where someone, they're explicitly
Speaker 7:  saying, this is not yet a product or at least and, and maybe never will be.
Speaker 7:  You're partly trying to assess how cool is it? Is it cool, is it fun?
Speaker 7:  Does this like solve some hypothetical version of a problem, even if it's
Speaker 7:  not practical in any way? But then there is that bit of you looking, you
Speaker 7:  know, sometimes versions of these concept devices do come out, you know,
Speaker 7:  the big DSLR lens on the back of a camera is maybe a less practical version.
Speaker 7:  But then, you know, XMI had this concept where they had a much
Speaker 7:  smaller lens that attached to the back of a phone via MagSafe style
Speaker 7:  connection. And that's still a concept that's absolutely not
Speaker 7:  a product will not be a product anytime in the next two
Speaker 7:  to three years. But I could imagine a world where it was, and you're kind
Speaker 7:  of playing around with that one and you, you start going, oh, this kind of
Speaker 7:  does work. This is kind of practical. Like I could imagine a world where
Speaker 7:  this is a product that comes out and this is maybe one I would actually want.
Speaker 7:  Okay.
Speaker 1:  I I, I'm hopeful that you guys are right. I think you might've just both
Speaker 1:  been very nice about a bunch of things that are definitely nonsense, but
Speaker 1:  I'm some of, I'm hopeful that you're right in that there is at least,
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah, there's nonsense.
Speaker 7:  The the 200 mil telephoto DSLR is is not, yeah.
Speaker 1:  Let's, let's start there Tom, because I wanna run through a bunch of,
Speaker 1:  I think the wildest things you saw and just hear about your experiences with
Speaker 1:  them. And I feel like Dom, your, your beat was just weird ideas about cameras
Speaker 1:  at MWC
Speaker 7:  Accidentally. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  So take me through some of the strangest cameras you saw.
Speaker 7:  Okay, so I mean the two of the big concepts, so you kind of to around 'em
Speaker 7:  a little already, Realme showed off something we've basically
Speaker 7:  kind of seen before already from other brands, including Xiaomi a couple
Speaker 7:  years ago. But they showed a concept phone where you could put
Speaker 7:  A-D-S-L-R-M mount adapter on the back of the camera
Speaker 7:  and then strap your big real DSLR lens
Speaker 7:  to the phone. It actually had a, a one inch type sensor in
Speaker 7:  the camera module, but with no lens on top of it. So basically the only lens
Speaker 7:  was whatever DSLR you, you threw on the top of it. This
Speaker 7:  is cool for people who own DSLRs already and think, wow, wouldn't it
Speaker 7:  be fun to, you know, throw this lens on a phone sometime you,
Speaker 7:  you know, it's nonsense because they made a point of demoing it with
Speaker 7:  this giant, giant telephoto lens and they actually
Speaker 7:  brought a smaller portrait lens too. And I kind of would've liked to try
Speaker 7:  that and I didn't get the chance to, because that might have felt almost
Speaker 7:  practical. Like I can imagine a more compact lens strapped on the back of
Speaker 7:  a phone halfway towards something I might ever use.
Speaker 7:  Having this huge tele photo that's like three, four times the size and weight
Speaker 7:  of the phone itself strapped to one end of the device, like
Speaker 7:  weighing the whole thing down and with no like meaningful camera body to
Speaker 7:  grab onto. It's frankly a terrible experience. It was,
Speaker 7:  it was really awful. It's cool. Again, this is in that space of concert,
Speaker 7:  you're like, this is cool, this is fun. I'm shooting with this massive lens
Speaker 7:  on a phone and the photo comes out really lovely, but awful, awful experience.
Speaker 7:  You'd never ever wanna use that in a million years. And then the xmi equivalent
Speaker 7:  was a little more practical.
Speaker 1:  I just love the theory that you're like, okay, carrying a big lens around,
Speaker 1:  totally doable, but carrying a whole big camera around way too much
Speaker 1:  that's like,
Speaker 7:  Oh, that's where we draw the line. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Who
Speaker 7:  Would wanna do that? Who'd wanna carry a camera body around God awful.
Speaker 7:  It's finally someone's come along and solved that problem. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  But you said the Xiaomi one is a little more reasonable.
Speaker 7:  Yes and no. I think it gets around a couple problems with this.
Speaker 7:  One is they had much smaller lenses, which immediately one may over
Speaker 7:  their solution is like much more proprietary, much more custom. They basically
Speaker 7:  have this, this small lens they built for themselves that
Speaker 7:  magnetically attached to the back of a custom version of one of their phones.
Speaker 7:  So it didn't actually attach to the existing camera. It goes right in the
Speaker 7:  middle of the phone's body, which immediately makes it a lot more balanced.
Speaker 7:  You don't have the lens all in one end, it's in the middle. It feels a bit
Speaker 7:  more like a real camera set up, a little bit more comfortable to hold. The
Speaker 7:  magnetic attachment is quicker, it's easier, it's less bulky, it just feels
Speaker 7:  a lot cooler and a lot more sci-fi. They also,
Speaker 7:  because it attaches to the body of the phone rather than the the camera,
Speaker 7:  it can't take advantage of the image sensors in the phone. So what they actually
Speaker 7:  did instead was put a sensor into this lens. It's this one little self-contained
Speaker 7:  unit that has lens and sensor and then magnets to the phone. The
Speaker 7:  perk of that is you can get a bigger sensor in there. So they had a four
Speaker 7:  thirds type sensor rather than the, the one inch that is the biggest
Speaker 7:  you're gonna find in any phone right now. So you're getting a bigger sensor
Speaker 7:  and a bigger lens. The lens was still something that could actually fit in
Speaker 7:  your pocket pretty comfortably. It MagSafe, well not, not
Speaker 7:  MagSafe MagSafe, but it basically mags safes to the phone pretty
Speaker 7:  immediately and then uses an optical connection to transfer the data. And
Speaker 7:  then the phone handles all the actual processing. So that I get,
Speaker 7:  because it immediately felt like, oh, this is just like
Speaker 7:  a lens add-on, like someone like moment does, but a lot better. It's a bit
Speaker 7:  like Allison pointed out this line of Sony cameras from like 12 years ago
Speaker 7:  or something that clamped onto a phone. And this is
Speaker 7:  ultimately, it's just that again, more than a decade later, they just replaced
Speaker 7:  the clamp with a magnet. But, you know, it works,
Speaker 7:  it's cool. Obviously it'll come down to price and things like that. And this
Speaker 7:  is so conceptual that we're, we're nowhere near anything like that though.
Speaker 1:  Alison, my, my stake in the ground on Friday show is that I think
Speaker 1:  this is an extremely good idea, really. And I sincerely hope that somebody
Speaker 1:  actually makes and ships this thing. But you're a, you're more of a camera
Speaker 1:  person than I am in general. What do you think of this hole? What If you
Speaker 1:  just, okay. Shoved a camera onto your phone idea. You,
Speaker 6:  You lived through the Sony qx? I did because we
Speaker 6:  looked it up on The Verge dot com and it was a David Pierce review.
Speaker 6:  I don't know, I just like, I saw that come and go, this is the,
Speaker 6:  the clamp thing
Speaker 6:  and you're at first you're like, this great, this is cool, like big sensor
Speaker 6:  for your phone. You just take it out, put it on. And I was obviously like
Speaker 6:  way more clunky than something on magnets on your phone. But the thing
Speaker 6:  it did not solve is that you're, you're carrying around an extra thing. You're
Speaker 6:  still like carrying and at that point do you just carry
Speaker 6:  a camera and, and that, that's where it falls apart a little bit for
Speaker 6:  me. I think it's cool as hell. Like yeah, I wanna try that. I
Speaker 6:  want a mag save lens on my phone and I'll give it a shot.
Speaker 6:  But I just had such deja vu where I was like, we're
Speaker 6:  doing this again. Oh my God.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. There are no new ideas. Just new attachment systems I think is like
Speaker 1:  basically where we are with technology right now. Yeah. Allison, the
Speaker 1:  gadget that you saw that I would say I have the most questions about is the,
Speaker 1:  the Noal AI phone, which I have now spent a lot of
Speaker 1:  time staring at and don't understand at all. And I would like you to explain
Speaker 1:  this thing to me please.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I have a similar feeling about it. So
Speaker 6:  this is a company called Noal. They're based
Speaker 6:  kind of in blockchain stuff. The first thing they said to me in
Speaker 6:  my briefing was that they never sold cryptocurrency and they were emphatic
Speaker 6:  about that. So that sets the stage for this. It's a little,
Speaker 6:  a kind of rectangle phone, like a small phone
Speaker 6:  runs Android. There's sort of two parts to the screen. There's
Speaker 6:  this like top little display and then the bottom
Speaker 6:  one where the normal phone stuff is. And on the top part of the display
Speaker 6:  is your avatar. Like it creates
Speaker 6:  a version of you based on your, you know,
Speaker 6:  some photos, video, you talking, whatever. And
Speaker 6:  that is your AI assistant. And the idea
Speaker 6:  is you upload, you like go around
Speaker 6:  to to meta and you know, Google download all your
Speaker 6:  data because they all have a system for like data
Speaker 6:  portability and you bring it over to the Noodle
Speaker 6:  os and you upload it there and you train this,
Speaker 6:  you know, AI version of you on all your stuff. They even
Speaker 6:  have this like in the onboarding, I didn't see this, but they
Speaker 6:  described it that you can describe the things you want in the future
Speaker 6:  and kind of like input that as like, here's the kind of thing
Speaker 6:  I'm interested in doing. Wow. It's so wild.
Speaker 6:  Like, so this little version of you when you summon it
Speaker 6:  on the phone kind of pops up and just stares back at you
Speaker 6:  and you tell it to do stuff. And that was the, like
Speaker 6:  there, there's a lot of the like similar, you know, call an Uber was like
Speaker 6:  the thing every AI assistant was doing on the show. We're just calling
Speaker 6:  Ubers all over the frigging place. Sure. But like, write a letter
Speaker 6:  or you know, someone calls and your,
Speaker 6:  the AI version of yourself answers the phone and, and talks to that
Speaker 6:  person and answers questions. They're like, oh, Allison's in a meeting
Speaker 6:  right now, blah, blah blah. And you, he could be like,
Speaker 6:  ask about some my availability to do something and
Speaker 6:  it would answer. So the one that really got me,
Speaker 6:  they showed me some live demos on this
Speaker 6:  device. They had it by a car insurance policy.
Speaker 6:  And the thing they told me was that they actually bought a
Speaker 6:  secondhand car so that they could run through this demo.
Speaker 6:  And it was going through, it's, it's very kind of rabbit
Speaker 6:  R one in that like you tell it to do something and then it's, you see it
Speaker 6:  clicking through the Geico website and I asked you, but
Speaker 1:  It's actually doing it on your phone.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. As far as I understand. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I asked the question of like, is this doing this for me? Is it on
Speaker 6:  a computer somewhere else? And I'm, I'm not a hundred
Speaker 6:  percent clear on it, but sure. Saw it all happen.
Speaker 6:  It answered the question. It was like, how much do you commute every day?
Speaker 6:  And it, it, the idea is it shows you where it's getting its answers.
Speaker 6:  It kind of like shows you its work as you go. So it would like go to
Speaker 6:  Google Maps or whatever and be like, you commute 40 miles a day
Speaker 6:  or whatever it is and then went through and paid for the insurance
Speaker 6:  policy and they were like, we need to go cancel this now.
Speaker 1:  Oh my gosh.
Speaker 6:  It was wild. Like I, I just don't even, I
Speaker 6:  saw it with my own eyes. I'm like, I have a hard time believing this.
Speaker 6:  Like, so yeah, it was, it was one of the,
Speaker 6:  the wilder things at the shell. I think
Speaker 1:  There are two parts of that that I find incredibly interesting and
Speaker 1:  one of them I also find incredibly weird. The one is, I actually
Speaker 1:  think the idea of like having you train your own assistant by going and
Speaker 1:  doing the, the various exports from all the other apps is actually very clever.
Speaker 1:  Total privacy nightmare. Yeah. But in terms of like, If you wanna sort of
Speaker 1:  s solve the cold start problem of how do you train an ai if you're willing
Speaker 1:  to do that, that's actually like an incredibly smart way to do that
Speaker 1:  is just go ingest all the algorithms from all your social platforms and
Speaker 1:  let them just go to work again. Don't do that.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But if you're going to, it's a pretty smart way to do it. The thing
Speaker 1:  that I don't understand is, is why this company decided that what I want
Speaker 1:  when I summon my virtual assistant is me. Yes. Staring at
Speaker 1:  me doing this. That's like, it seems so
Speaker 6:  Weird to me. I know. Yeah. It it, I would feel awkward
Speaker 6:  looking at myself on my phone. Like,
Speaker 6:  am I bothering you? Were you doing something important? Yeah. I
Speaker 1:  Dunno, Dom, did you get to try this thing? I
Speaker 7:  Did not. I I am kind of sad now that I didn't get to see some tiny
Speaker 7:  terrifying Allison. Did you, did you get to see a tiny AI Allison?
Speaker 7:  Did they make one for you?
Speaker 6:  No, no, but they're, they say they're shipping
Speaker 6:  this thing, it's gonna go on sale in May. It's like
Speaker 6:  $375
Speaker 6:  and then, then it's going, they said two months After that it's gonna be
Speaker 6:  a product that ships in the wild people have and they're training their own
Speaker 6:  ais on. So I don't know, it may not be long.
Speaker 1:  I'm gonna go ahead and bet the over on the release date on that one. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  may, May 1st I'm gonna guess is gonna come and go. But hey, I hope
Speaker 1:  I'm wrong on this one.
Speaker 1:  Dom, you saw a bunch of other
Speaker 1:  weird phones with weird ideas about things on the back is I guess how I would,
Speaker 1:  I would say it including one I think the company was, was
Speaker 1:  Nubia, is that right? You found a phone with like a, with a, a
Speaker 1:  scrolly circular dial on the back? Yes. I love a good
Speaker 1:  circular dial, but I don't understand what this thing is doing
Speaker 7:  It. Sovia is part of zte. They're the company that make the Red Magic gaming
Speaker 7:  phones as well that people may be more familiar with. That's kind of the
Speaker 7:  biggest brand. And yeah, they, they, they announced
Speaker 7:  absolute ton of devices this year and they had a few really weird ones. I
Speaker 7:  think the camera ring was, was the strangest, it was on a, I think it's called
Speaker 7:  the Focus two Ultra if I've got that sort of sounds the right way around.
Speaker 7:  And it was a very cheap looking mid-range phone, but it just has this round
Speaker 7:  camera module with a kind of brass ring around the edge
Speaker 7:  that is a rotating crown just like you would get on, you know, like rotating
Speaker 7:  crowns or watches or something. So the, the bezel of the camera can rotate.
Speaker 7:  The main way they had this set up was just that it works as a zoom dial in
Speaker 7:  the camera so you can hold the phone and just with like one finger on the
Speaker 7:  back, just rotate that dial and it zooms in and out. So it's a bit more
Speaker 7:  natural than the sort of clunky pinch to zoom or swipe to zoom that you
Speaker 7:  tend to have on phones these days, which work fine, but they're slightly
Speaker 7:  awkward movements. It definitely felt more natural than I thought it would
Speaker 7:  to just have my finger resting on the back swiveling this thing, it was a
Speaker 7:  very kind of, it was very easy to move it, it had a little bit of a ratchet
Speaker 7:  to it, but not too much and it didn't require a lot of force to move. So
Speaker 7:  it was a very kind of quick, easy, smooth rotate this wheel
Speaker 7:  and the camera just zoomed in and out. I, I'm not sure If you can actually
Speaker 7:  adapt it. What I hope you could do is customize that to do other stuff either
Speaker 7:  within the camera changing like exposure or something would be cool outside
Speaker 7:  the camera scrolling by just swiveling this wheel on the back of the phone.
Speaker 7:  That's the kind of thing I'd like to see from it. And I'm not sure if that's
Speaker 7:  in there or if that ever will be, but yeah, I, I, I
Speaker 7:  like this, this is a real product. It is actually a thing people can go and
Speaker 7:  buy. Definitely not in the US but elsewhere in the world. I think this will
Speaker 7:  be real and available and I don't think the phone as a whole like a total
Speaker 7:  winner, but this is fun. I I I like that as a concept.
Speaker 1:  I'm sort of intrigued by this one 'cause I think like we're, we're definitely
Speaker 1:  in the age of wild camera bumps on phones, right? And I like
Speaker 1:  everybody's trying to either make them sort
Speaker 1:  of the whole aesthetic of the phone. Like that's the pixel idea, right? Is
Speaker 1:  like what if the whole look of this thing was the camera bump or
Speaker 1:  just like, pretend they don't exist, which is like what Apple's doing. They're
Speaker 1:  like, what camera bump, there's no camera bump. Don't, don't worry about
Speaker 1:  the camera bump. There's no camera bump. You've never seen a camera bump
Speaker 1:  in your life. But this I think is very cool 'cause it's like, okay, there
Speaker 1:  is, there is hardware on the back here and you're gonna feel it with
Speaker 1:  your finger. And I like the idea of actually making it
Speaker 1:  useful in some way, even honestly if it did nothing, but it was just like
Speaker 1:  a little fidgety thing on the back. Yes. There's still something about like,
Speaker 1:  you've made this phone more tactile in a way that I actually really, really
Speaker 1:  like
Speaker 6:  A fidget spinner built into the back of the phone. I love it.
Speaker 1:  I mean that's like 60% of what this pop socket on my phone is, is just a
Speaker 1:  little fidget spinner. Yeah. And I think that kind of thing. But Dom, I totally
Speaker 1:  agree. Like If you could map that to other stuff on the phone the way that
Speaker 1:  you can, like on some phones map the volume buttons to scroll up and down
Speaker 1:  or like Yeah. You know, turn pages in the Kindle app or whatever. Like little
Speaker 1:  bits like that I think are very cool and should come back to more smartphones.
Speaker 1:  Alison, did you see any other cool phones? I feel like there's a bunch of
Speaker 1:  like the nothing phone seems fine, there's like the the solar
Speaker 1:  smartphone concept, but was there anything else that like really jumped out
Speaker 1:  to you on the mobile side of things?
Speaker 6:  I gotta give a shout out to the coffee phone. I
Speaker 6:  dunno. Which was a concept. This was from techno
Speaker 6:  and I went over there like techno Chinese brand. They,
Speaker 6:  they had a bunch of concepts on their booth and there's like a trifold,
Speaker 6:  they had a slim phone because we're doing slim phones, but
Speaker 6:  there's, you could actually like pick up and use, which was cool. So
Speaker 6:  I went over there, I was like in line to see the slim phone and I got
Speaker 6:  kind of the rundown on this. They had these like sustainable concepts
Speaker 6:  where the back of the phone was made out of like some kind of coconut fiber
Speaker 6:  and the woman showing them to me, she was like, this one is made out of coffee
Speaker 6:  grounds and you can smell it and it smells like coffee. And I
Speaker 6:  smelled it and it smells like coffee.
Speaker 1:  Whoa. I know. Is that cool or is that I
Speaker 6:  Thought it was horrible as hell. I loved it. I mean,
Speaker 6:  standing around me smell the phone, I was like, Julian smell this phone and
Speaker 6:  made it my whole personality for the 30 minutes.
Speaker 6:  I don't, I dunno. I was like, that's so fun. That's not a thing I'm ever
Speaker 6:  gonna be able to buy. But I, so like the most practical
Speaker 6:  cool thing I saw I think was at HMD
Speaker 6:  they had a whole thing. It was wild. It was at the
Speaker 6:  FC Barcelona Stadium.
Speaker 1:  Oh sure, okay. HMD is the company that makes Nokia phones now. Right. That's
Speaker 1:  like in the us They're the, they're the Nokia one.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Nokia. And they're launch they cell phones as
Speaker 6:  HMD now. Okay. Which you, you can actually buy one in the us
Speaker 6:  but they have, it's some earbuds that come in this kind of
Speaker 6:  rectangular case and it mags safe
Speaker 6:  chee twos to the back of a phone and it doubles as a little
Speaker 6:  power bank. So it's got like, it's somewhere,
Speaker 6:  it's like 1300 milliamps or something like that. Not huge, but there's
Speaker 6:  like more of a battery in it than your typical like
Speaker 6:  AirPods case. The earbuds just kind of like pop outta
Speaker 6:  the sides. They're real chunky and kind of weird looking I think
Speaker 6:  because they need to fit into this case. But I think
Speaker 6:  that's genius. Like you, I'm used to charging my AirPods, I'm
Speaker 6:  used to carrying those around with me. Wouldn't it be cool if that did something
Speaker 6:  else for me? Like if my phone's running outta battery, you just
Speaker 6:  slap it on there and you get a little more charge. I was like,
Speaker 6:  I love it.
Speaker 1:  I a that's a very good idea. And B I'm looking
Speaker 1:  at this photo that you took of it now and it kind of looks like you've
Speaker 1:  magnified a vape onto the back of your phone. That's
Speaker 6:  Kind look like a vape. Oh no. How many, how far away are we from CHI
Speaker 6:  two vape?
Speaker 1:  Not far. Clearly Not far.
Speaker 6:  Oh, it's gonna happen.
Speaker 1:  This is come you can vape and charge your phone and also there's headphones
Speaker 1:  inside. It's like that's the, that's how you get the teens onboard with CHE
Speaker 1:  two,
Speaker 6:  The ultimate multitasker. Oh
Speaker 6:  no. Well thank you for that David.
Speaker 1:  You're welcome. We've really done something here. Okay, so there's one, one
Speaker 1:  more gadget I want to ask you about and then I'm just curious to hear
Speaker 1:  favorite things from the show and then I'll let you get outta here. This,
Speaker 1:  this Nintendo switch looking thing that Samsung made.
Speaker 1:  What, what is this thing? I, I feel like this, this was like an image that
Speaker 1:  got passed around the internet and people were like, oh my god, what a cool
Speaker 1:  thing that Samsung made. It's like a foldable Nintendo switch. Did you guys
Speaker 1:  see this thing? What is this thing?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, this was at Samsung display and
Speaker 6:  their, their booth is full of concept devices like,
Speaker 6:  like very much like we don't make these things, these are just ideas,
Speaker 6:  aren't they cool? Maybe someone could adapt them and tell them.
Speaker 6:  So they had all kinds of stuff, all kinds of folding displays. But
Speaker 6:  the coolest one was this gaming handheld that was sort of
Speaker 6:  set up with a very small sign that said, you know,
Speaker 6:  it was like, do not touch. Everybody wanted to come over and touch it.
Speaker 6:  It was, it was like very difficult not to just pick it up and touch it and
Speaker 6:  someone would yell at you. But it just, it does what it sounds like.
Speaker 6:  It's like a little switch looking thing that folds in half and
Speaker 6:  you open it up and play your games and you fold it up when you're done. It's
Speaker 6:  green and yellow so it's not a switch, but it's definitely a
Speaker 6:  switch. Yeah, I thought it was one of the coolest things. I like
Speaker 6:  never travel with the switch because it just kind of seems like that
Speaker 6:  bit too bulky. I'm like, what if it folded?
Speaker 6:  Maybe I would take it around then.
Speaker 1:  There is something about this that I find like irresistibly cool. I, I don't,
Speaker 1:  I don't like, I have no idea what I would use it for or if it would change
Speaker 1:  anything for me or it would just stick a giant crease in the middle of all
Speaker 1:  of my video games. Yeah. But like I, it's very cool. Yeah, there's something,
Speaker 1:  there's something about it that I'm like, I'm in on all foldables as you
Speaker 1:  well know, but this one I'm in on as well. Yeah. Like
Speaker 7:  Immediate, immediate appeal. I, I mostly wanted to touch it just
Speaker 7:  to try the D pads because the way this is designed is that the
Speaker 7:  analog sticks have to go somewhere when it folds. So the D pads are kind
Speaker 7:  of just like holes with buttons around the edge so that the analog stick
Speaker 7:  can slot into these holes and they look like the worst DPAs
Speaker 7:  ever made. And I'm fascinated to try them just to
Speaker 7:  feel what those buttons are like and how that would work to play anything
Speaker 7:  on.
Speaker 1:  Oh, I hadn't even understood that. Looking at this picture, they're like,
Speaker 1:  they're like down sloping buttons so that the stick has somewhere to go
Speaker 1:  in the center of them. Yes.
Speaker 7:  On the inside edge of a ring. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Right. Yeah, that's probably not a great idea.
Speaker 1:  Doesn't seem like it's gonna work, but I like it. Alright, before I let you
Speaker 1:  guys go, I want you each to tell me just your, your favorite thing that you
Speaker 1:  saw. It doesn't have to be real, it doesn't have to be plausible, it doesn't
Speaker 1:  have to be a thing you're gonna buy, but what's the thing you saw at MWC
Speaker 1:  that you were most like just into
Speaker 1:  for good reasons or for bad dom? You go first.
Speaker 7:  For me it is the, the Xiaomi camera concept. That lens that
Speaker 7:  magnets onto the back of a phone. I, I agree David. I'm, I'm
Speaker 7:  now all in on this. I want this to exist. I say that as someone who's a sucker
Speaker 7:  for the, the Xiaomi photography kit that they have for the ultra phones,
Speaker 7:  which is a little camera grip that has a battery pack and slaps on the side
Speaker 7:  and gives you a shutter button and zoom dial and stuff like that. They didn't
Speaker 7:  show those things off together and I'm kind of shocked they didn't have a
Speaker 7:  version that had that because then it really is just like a mirrorless camera.
Speaker 7:  You pull apart, you pop the lens off, you pull the grip off, now it's your
Speaker 7:  phone. You slap those back on and you've got a full-size camera and
Speaker 7:  I love that. It's very cool. I genuinely do see the potential in this.
Speaker 7:  I very, very expensive potential I'm sure. But potential, I, I
Speaker 7:  would, I would buy this if it existed.
Speaker 1:  I honestly like what If you had a really good camera that had
Speaker 1:  Instagram and TikTok installed on it just makes sense to me.
Speaker 1:  I just, it just makes sense to me. And I think the answer is probably just
Speaker 1:  your smartphone camera is good enough on its own, but like no it's not.
Speaker 1:  We can do better.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. That's the closest hesitation I have is like the camera is
Speaker 7:  almost that good. Right? Like the 15 ultras is such a great camera that you
Speaker 7:  almost look at Well when they're doing that well anyway, do they need this
Speaker 7:  whole other lens to slap on the back? But yeah, why, why not? Even bigger
Speaker 7:  sensors. Even bigger lenses. Let's keep going
Speaker 1:  A hundred percent. Alison, what about you? What was your favorite,
Speaker 6:  Not to be boring, but like the 15 Ultra I think just that
Speaker 6:  really? Yeah, the like the, the upgrade
Speaker 6:  and it's a minor one kind of on a spec page
Speaker 6:  is the periscope Zoom is like they, they were
Speaker 6:  like, what if we took a telephoto camera on a smartphone and made it good
Speaker 6:  and you're like, wow, that, that would be awesome. And they did it.
Speaker 6:  It's like massive and it makes the whole back of the camera look silly.
Speaker 6:  But I haven't really tried it out myself. I'm dying to like
Speaker 6:  what if a telephoto camera was good Is is such a like
Speaker 6:  radical thought for a phone. You know,
Speaker 6:  take, take portraits in inside where
Speaker 6:  your subject is moving a little bit and like that might actually
Speaker 6:  work with this phone. I don't know. I'm thrilled. I wanna
Speaker 7:  Try it. I also love that the pitch for it isn't what if a telephoto was good
Speaker 7:  at at a hundred times Zoom? 'cause we've had that pitch again and again and
Speaker 7:  again and again. Yes from Samsung. It's what if the telephoto or periscope
Speaker 7:  was good at four times? Like it's just really, really good at four times.
Speaker 7:  Yeah and it's great there and it can go up to 120 times and you should never
Speaker 7:  do that. And the photos are awful but they're not pitching it on that. They're
Speaker 7:  not pitching on on the fact that you can shoot a skyscraper from the other
Speaker 7:  side of a city. They're just saying like yeah, what If you could shoot something
Speaker 7:  on the other side of the room and it would actually be a nice photo that
Speaker 7:  you want to use with bouquet and beautiful colors and all of that.
Speaker 6:  Exactly.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I love that. And I think the message that Allison and I have been yelling
Speaker 1:  into the universe that digital Zoom is not Zoom, it's cropping,
Speaker 1:  is finally seems to be giving us some real benefits and they're actually
Speaker 1:  starting to solve this problem. And Allison, I think you and I specifically
Speaker 1:  deserve real credit.
Speaker 6:  We didn't. We got the W.
Speaker 1:  We did. I'm proud of us. I also think, by the way, it's very cool to see
Speaker 1:  Xmi back to doing like really cool, interesting weird smartphone stuff like
Speaker 1:  that company was out in front of so many smartphone trends.
Speaker 1:  It was doing the all screen stuff really early. It was doing foldable stuff
Speaker 1:  really early. It's like they've been pushing
Speaker 1:  interesting trends kind of out ahead of a lot of companies for a long time.
Speaker 1:  So I think this is the kind of thing that like, it seems weird but might
Speaker 1:  start to pop up other places and Jam's history of doing this
Speaker 1:  well and early is pretty strong. So it's, it was cool to see
Speaker 1:  Xiaomi like back at the forefront of fun ideas about smartphones, but
Speaker 1:  we'll never get to buy them.
Speaker 6:  No we won't.
Speaker 1:  Alas Dom, you're gonna have to get all of them and, and we're just gonna
Speaker 1:  live vicariously through your experiences with cool phones that we're not
Speaker 1:  allowed to have.
Speaker 6:  Can you send me one please? Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Awesome. Well thank you both for doing this immediately after flying one
Speaker 1:  of you, not a long time and one of you a very long time, but it's nice to
Speaker 1:  see you both. Thank you for doing this. Yeah, thank you.
Speaker 7:  Thank you.
Speaker 1:  Alright, we gotta take a break and then we're gonna come back and talk about
Speaker 1:  dig. We'll be right back.
Speaker 8:  It's been reported that one in four people experience sensory
Speaker 8:  Burnett
Speaker 1:  Welcome back. About a year ago, Kevin Rose and I got on the phone to talk
Speaker 1:  about Dig Back then we were mostly reminiscing The Verge did this big package
Speaker 1:  of stories about 2004 and all the tech that happened that year
Speaker 1:  and DIG was one of the things that launched in 2004. So we were talking about
Speaker 1:  the early days of dig and how community has changed online and how
Speaker 1:  the like button changed everything and on and on. But I asked him at the
Speaker 1:  very end of our chat if he'd given any thought to bringing Digg back
Speaker 1:  and he kind of said no, but he said no in a way that made it clear. He actually
Speaker 1:  had given it a lot of thought. And it turns out that not that long after
Speaker 1:  our conversation, he started to give it a lot of thought. Like a
Speaker 1:  lot of thought. And now it's coming back. So dig after,
Speaker 1:  I don't know it, it's still technically around, but it's changed a lot over
Speaker 1:  the years and it is definitely not the dig that you remember, If you remember
Speaker 1:  the original dig. But now Kevin Rose along with Justin
Speaker 1:  Metzel, who's gonna be a CEO at Dig, and people like Alexis Ohanian,
Speaker 1:  who's the co-founder of Reddit and is now gonna be an advisor and an investor
Speaker 1:  in Dig. The goal is to bring it back and to make a new
Speaker 1:  kind of social network out of it. They have big ideas about how
Speaker 1:  AI can make it easier for moderators. They have big ideas about how we can
Speaker 1:  do community better. These are people who have learned kind of every lesson
Speaker 1:  there is to learn about social and the internet. And
Speaker 1:  their goal is to get it right this time. So originally when I
Speaker 1:  talked to Kevin and Justin, I didn't actually intend to use it for the show.
Speaker 1:  We were just having kind of a product briefing, but I enjoyed the conversation
Speaker 1:  so much that I figured I'd just play it for you here. So this is Kevin
Speaker 1:  and Justin and me and we pick up when I essentially asked them
Speaker 1:  why now, right? Kevin said he had been approached by
Speaker 1:  various owners over the years about whether he wanted to buy the dig domain
Speaker 1:  and buy the website and buy the whole thing back and try it all again. And
Speaker 1:  it always said no and the timing was wrong, just didn't feel right. But this
Speaker 1:  time it felt right. And so I asked him why and specifically
Speaker 1:  what changed between then and now That got you back in.
Speaker 1:  Here's what he said.
Speaker 14:  Listen, the, the big obviously we all know that the, the
Speaker 14:  hottest thing to talk about these days is, is ai, right? And and
Speaker 14:  when
Speaker 1:  We talked about that, when we talked last time that you were like that, that
Speaker 1:  might be the thing that makes some of this stuff sort of newly
Speaker 1:  possible,
Speaker 14:  Right? A and and I think that that is,
Speaker 14:  it is, it is a very delicate topic to cover
Speaker 14:  largely because one of the things that I believe that made
Speaker 14:  dig and makes Reddit a special place on the internet is that, you know,
Speaker 14:  there are humans behind the scenes with real opinions, real, real
Speaker 14:  conversation going on, real stories that they find interesting
Speaker 14:  and you don't, the second you start to sterilize
Speaker 14:  that, then you're just an aggregator of,
Speaker 14:  of information. You're a fancy RSS reader with some voting on it. And it,
Speaker 14:  it's like nobody wants that or thinks that's the future.
Speaker 14:  And so if anything, we want to figure out how to reinvent and
Speaker 14:  reimagine what it means to build communities and bring people
Speaker 14:  together. And we see AI as a partner on a,
Speaker 14:  a variety of different fronts. But the first front
Speaker 14:  that we'll tackle is, is
Speaker 14:  very much like how can we remove the janitorial
Speaker 14:  work of, you know, moderators and
Speaker 14:  community managers and convert what they do every day
Speaker 14:  into more of a kind of director of vibes culture
Speaker 14:  and, and community builder than someone that is just sitting there
Speaker 14:  doing the the laborious, crappy stuff that,
Speaker 14:  you know, comes in through, through the front door.
Speaker 14:  And that's a lot of tooling that needs to be built in. And
Speaker 14:  we did some pressure testing there to see, you know,
Speaker 14:  what different models are out there, how they handle different types of
Speaker 14:  content, how we can surface that stuff,
Speaker 14:  what kind of knobs and dials can we expose to different moderators and
Speaker 14:  different community managers so that, you know, they're able
Speaker 14:  to have a more honed and completely transparent,
Speaker 14:  you know, version of what they're building. And, and I I am speaking to
Speaker 14:  the future a bit and not all this will be there on day one. That
Speaker 1:  Strikes me as the kind of thing in sort of broad strokes that a lot of these
Speaker 1:  LLMs are actually like really well set up to be good at. Yes. In a way that
Speaker 1:  I feel like a lot of people tell me things that I'm like maybe in a decade
Speaker 1:  LLMs will be able to do that. This one where it's like basic kind of content
Speaker 1:  understanding and sorting and shuffling is like
Speaker 1:  actually pretty well within the Realme of what a lot of this stuff can do,
Speaker 1:  right? Yeah.
Speaker 14:  That that's exactly right. And and also just, you know,
Speaker 14:  these, these models can also be discreetly defined and there
Speaker 14:  could be multiple agents working on your behalf. So
Speaker 14:  we very much see a world where, you know, and I'm just making
Speaker 14:  stuff up here for the sake of whatever, for random banter, but
Speaker 14:  there's everything from an AI agent that that converts your entire
Speaker 14:  sub-community into clinging on. And you know, there's another
Speaker 14:  one that, you know, you have a meditation group and you don't allow
Speaker 14:  a certain type of profanity and that's, you know, automatically auto
Speaker 14:  moderated, right? If and or at the very
Speaker 14:  extreme end. And I think this is something that, you know, without giving
Speaker 14:  away too much, you'll see down the road. But you know, I I
Speaker 14:  think of dig less like rebuilding a content management platform
Speaker 14:  and more like creating the next version of Figma. Like it's almost like
Speaker 14:  akin to the shift from Photoshop to Figma where you went
Speaker 14:  from, I'm defining the pixels as a 800 by
Speaker 14:  800 square and as by file new
Speaker 14:  to a, I have a blank canvas and I'm just going to allow the
Speaker 14:  dynamic rearrangement of information
Speaker 14:  in a very flexible way as driven by multiple members of the
Speaker 14:  community. So if we can create more of a dynamic canvas
Speaker 14:  where, you know, agents are layered on top of that
Speaker 14:  to assist, to help, to do wild things, to create games,
Speaker 14:  to do whatever they want that that community wants them to do,
Speaker 14:  then we have something and we have the ability to wake up one morning and
Speaker 14:  be completely surprised by what, you know, our
Speaker 14:  audiences create. And I think that marching towards that end goal is,
Speaker 14:  is gonna be a wild ride. You know,
Speaker 1:  That's a really fun way to think about it. That's also like huge, right?
Speaker 1:  Like what you just described is you could be sort of anything up to and including
Speaker 1:  like the whole internet.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. I mean If you think about it, it's like
Speaker 14:  forms have been, and conversation has been such a
Speaker 14:  a, a kind of like as defined by CSS kinda world.
Speaker 14:  Totally. And and it's like those things get updated or refreshed
Speaker 14:  or changed, you know, whatever, once every few years
Speaker 14:  by the platform owner or you know, you install a new WordPress
Speaker 14:  theme or whatever it may be, right? But you know, if I'm in a,
Speaker 14:  a eventual later sub community on dig that's about stocks,
Speaker 14:  you know, and I want a realtime stock taker, I should just ask my bot to
Speaker 14:  go make one and drop it in there for me. You know, it's like
Speaker 14:  that's all gonna be possible, right? And, and, and, and that kind
Speaker 14:  of flexibility and malleability of, of a future version of Dig
Speaker 14:  is what ultimately gets us really, really jazzed and excited.
Speaker 14:  And the thing that Alexis has said about Justin is
Speaker 14:  that, you know, and it's very clear and that I know this quite well in working
Speaker 14:  with them, is that you need somebody running these social platforms with
Speaker 14:  a high degree of integrity and someone that's always going to point to that
Speaker 14:  North Star and say the community eats first. This is all about the
Speaker 14:  community. This is all about the likes. Like serving those people and
Speaker 14:  creating the best possible experience for them. Because from
Speaker 14:  my point of view in watching all the rebellion that happened
Speaker 14:  against DIG and the rebellion that's happened multiple times on Reddit,
Speaker 14:  largely a lot of that is driven by those people that put
Speaker 14:  in so many hours of their life as being,
Speaker 14:  you know, treated as second class citizens and not really,
Speaker 14:  you know, being taken their needs being taken seriously. And so, you
Speaker 14:  know, one of the first things I did when even before buying Dig, is I went
Speaker 14:  out and personally bought thousands of dollars of Reddit ads and I
Speaker 14:  targeted all of the moderation communities and I
Speaker 14:  put in forms, some
Speaker 14:  of them targeted, some of them open-ended questions asking
Speaker 14:  moderators what they were missing were their pain points,
Speaker 14:  were they struggling? What do they wish existed that isn't being
Speaker 14:  built for them? And I got thousands of responses that
Speaker 14:  of course I dumped into AI and, and themes started to
Speaker 14:  emerge. And it's, and it's that level of
Speaker 14:  attention that we need to be giving these people and helping them build
Speaker 14:  the tools so that the back office and the suite of tools that they have
Speaker 14:  looks as good as the front does. And that's just never been done.
Speaker 14:  And that's something that's on us to build.
Speaker 1:  Totally. And it's interesting to hear you talk about paying attention to
Speaker 1:  the community as paying attention to the moderators, which I think is like,
Speaker 1:  like I spent a bunch of time with Reddit mods during not this most recent
Speaker 1:  Reddit mod revolt, but the one before that it's like every, every
Speaker 1:  two years this happens all over again. And the thing they were saying is
Speaker 1:  like, Reddit actually takes pretty good care of its users and horrible care
Speaker 1:  of the moderators who are the ones who actually spend all of their time taking
Speaker 1:  care of their users. And they really felt that, and they were like, the reason
Speaker 1:  our users have a good time is not because of Reddit, it's 'cause of us. And
Speaker 1:  like appreciating that the middleman there, I think is, is a hard thing
Speaker 1:  to do because you, most people don't notice it. But I think it ends up kind
Speaker 1:  of being the job in a lot of ways.
Speaker 14:  I mean, I, I wholeheartedly agree with that. And then I also think that
Speaker 14:  we can, it's not just about building them good tools, but it's also about
Speaker 14:  giving them agency in a way that they haven't had before. Hmm. And
Speaker 14:  what I mean by that is like, it just like, it's a real
Speaker 14:  bummer to me as a, as a creator, like if I step outside of the Dig Realme
Speaker 14:  for a minute and I say like, listen, like a, a good example
Speaker 14:  is like, you know, I own my email newsletter list, right?
Speaker 14:  And in some sense, until they take it away, I can
Speaker 14:  export all of my Twitter data and take it with me, right? Like,
Speaker 14:  how do we make sure that if a community comes
Speaker 14:  along and they want to have a deeper, more real connection with these people,
Speaker 14:  that they spend so much time building up these communities.
Speaker 14:  Like it's not all for nothing. It's not like just some big corporate entity,
Speaker 14:  you know, controls that. So we think deeply about
Speaker 14:  these questions on how we can give them more real ownership
Speaker 14:  and all the things that we build and do versus just making them
Speaker 14:  unpaid, you know,
Speaker 14:  moderators that, that don't get a lot of recognition, you know?
Speaker 15:  Well, and I think the thing that was really interesting as we've even thought
Speaker 15:  about it was it was like, it's like that question you can ask like, what
Speaker 15:  would I do different if I was to do something like this again?
Speaker 15:  And having both Kevin and Alexis with their own stories,
Speaker 15:  their own paths that each of these things have taken. I mean, it feels like
Speaker 15:  I have the game guide to like look at and and, and play really well from
Speaker 15:  the beginning and I know where the secrets are. I know I, I know where to
Speaker 15:  look. And, and again, that doesn't mean that every single thing is super
Speaker 15:  clear. And, but that's mostly because both, you know, Kevin, myself and
Speaker 15:  Alexis very much value human-centered design. We want the community
Speaker 15:  to dictate a lot of these things. But the difference was like, how do we
Speaker 15:  square up from day one to let them know that it's like this is a
Speaker 15:  place for people to gather for communities. And we recognize
Speaker 15:  that people are able to gather when people catalyze and,
Speaker 15:  and like make it happen by building communities online. And I think it's
Speaker 15:  even more important now that we think about those things and how it's working
Speaker 15:  and how to do it in a healthy way.
Speaker 1:  What's your sense of what you're kind of wading into with that conversation?
Speaker 1:  Because on the one hand I feel like there is more need for that than
Speaker 1:  ever and people are really aware of kind of how important community is,
Speaker 1:  but also we've spent most of the last decade just being
Speaker 1:  burned by that over and over and over and every different way. So I feel
Speaker 1:  like you're gonna run into a group of people who both desperately want what
Speaker 1:  you're talking about and are also more skeptical every day
Speaker 1:  of whether you will actually do it and deliver it to them in the long run.
Speaker 15:  Well it's, it's a balance because it's like a lot of, you know, modern social
Speaker 15:  media with the algorithm. Like, it's like outrage culture. It's just like
Speaker 15:  what can we serve you that is so counter to
Speaker 15:  what you believe that you'll see it and you'll just like want to throw your
Speaker 15:  your phone across the room. And so it's like, one of the things we have
Speaker 15:  talked about is like, how do we, obviously we're gonna use
Speaker 15:  AI to be able to make things more efficient. And hopefully that means there's
Speaker 15:  relevancy service there and there's, there's interest that you have and
Speaker 15:  the, and the spaces that you follow, and we can, you know, branch out from
Speaker 15:  there to grow some of those things. But like, there has to be a balance
Speaker 15:  where it's like, instead of doing it behind closed doors, or, you know,
Speaker 15:  really just saying, well, if you're mad, you're gonna click a lot more.
Speaker 15:  So let's just get everybody really mad. We can really start
Speaker 15:  thinking about like, how do we get people into communities as the first,
Speaker 15:  but then also like when you're in there, like what does it mean to show
Speaker 15:  up in a community? Like, like who are you in that community? You'll have
Speaker 15:  people that post content, like post original content. You're gonna have
Speaker 15:  people that make comments and they're, they're funny and they're, and they're
Speaker 15:  enjoyable. You have people obviously that make other kinds of comments and
Speaker 15:  those people exist too. But it's like, you also have people that like,
Speaker 15:  just support other things. They're not the ones finding the stuff, but they're
Speaker 15:  up voting it and they're, they're, they're sourcing, you know, from like
Speaker 15:  the earliest stuff. How do we get that to the top here? And those people
Speaker 15:  deserve to be celebrated as well. So one of the things that Kevin and I
Speaker 15:  talked about from the beginning is like, you know, there's like all these
Speaker 15:  very simple, you know, systems that we already have for like, commenting
Speaker 15:  systems and branching and all that stuff. But it's like, even if
Speaker 15:  we start there, we cannot stop asking the question about how to like,
Speaker 15:  give people the respect for being really insightful, for being
Speaker 15:  really encouraging, for being really funny at times or just even saying
Speaker 15:  like, Hey, this isn't really adding to the conversation. And maybe that's
Speaker 15:  okay and people do need to see that a bit. So I think for us, it really
Speaker 15:  is just about when people create communities, they should have control on
Speaker 15:  what kind of community they're looking to create. It should be efficient
Speaker 15:  and easy, and it should be something that like other people have a real
Speaker 15:  understanding of like, what does it mean to show up here? What are we talking
Speaker 15:  about? What are we sharing and how are we doing it? Hmm.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. And I think just adding on top of that, the, the one thing
Speaker 14:  that you'll see, you know, and, and I
Speaker 14:  think this is important to, to hit in, in, in, in, in Hit Home with you
Speaker 14:  is that, you know, dig Day one is very much our, like MVP,
Speaker 14:  let's just ship this. Lots of lots of bugs, lots of broken things,
Speaker 14:  like we're rushing this out, we're gonna get it out, but we're gonna fast
Speaker 14:  fall that every couple weeks with just like, just new stuff all the time.
Speaker 14:  So when we get there, what you'll see that
Speaker 14:  is a radical transparency that you'll see you won't have seen anywhere else.
Speaker 14:  There will be no such thing as Shadow banning. You will see a full
Speaker 14:  audit log of what's happening to who and
Speaker 14:  why. And I think this is where, you know,
Speaker 14:  we can kind of lean on AI to be a helpful participant here
Speaker 14:  in that there's, there's a couple different ways you can imagine this. You
Speaker 14:  can say, okay, I'm a I'm a community manager and I run
Speaker 14:  this community. I generally want this type
Speaker 14:  of conversation to be happen
Speaker 14:  here, and I wanna disallow this type of conversation. Okay. Those rules
Speaker 14:  are written and available for everyone. You can see when
Speaker 14:  AI takes action to enforce some of those rules.
Speaker 14:  And If you even feel like it, you can add an extra
Speaker 14:  agent on top of that, that grades the
Speaker 14:  moderator's own actions and says, I agreed or disagreed with what this
Speaker 14:  moderator actually did. Right. And so there's layers of this
Speaker 14:  in a transparency that I think a lot of the people
Speaker 14:  that are very skeptical of these secret algorithms that
Speaker 14:  promote agendas or do different things, I, I think they're really gonna
Speaker 14:  enjoy seeing
Speaker 14:  that audit trail and exactly what's happening behind the scenes
Speaker 14:  because we just think that's such an important piece of trust here
Speaker 14:  is to, to let them know that one, be very clear
Speaker 14:  about how to show up. But two, when action does happen, which ultimately
Speaker 14:  when you get to tens of millions of people all playing in the same sandbox,
Speaker 14:  there will be
Speaker 14:  being very transparent about wh why and how these these things happened.
Speaker 14:  You know? Yeah.
Speaker 1:  It just seemed like part of what you're gonna have to figure out how to square
Speaker 1:  is making something that is very fun and interesting and exciting to
Speaker 1:  be part of, but isn't like a game to be won. Yes. And I think
Speaker 1:  a lot of the mistakes dig made in its first iteration, and Kevin, you and
Speaker 1:  I talked about this too, is like, dig kind of became a game you could win.
Speaker 1:  And so people figured out how to win it and win it, even with
Speaker 1:  things that shouldn't have won it. And it's just starts to become this impossible,
Speaker 1:  like SEO spiral into madness and bad content.
Speaker 1:  That's right. And I feel like that's a, that just strikes me as a really
Speaker 1:  tricky but important thing to get right? Like, this has to be fun, but you
Speaker 1:  can't win at it. And I feel like the internet doesn't have that much of that
Speaker 1:  right now. Everybody's trying to win on the
Speaker 14:  Internet. That's right. And we, we think deeply about this and I I think
Speaker 14:  you'll notice this, I don't want to get into unreleased features,
Speaker 14:  but on day one you'll, you'll notice a couple of very obvious things
Speaker 14:  that on user profiles that you've never seen before,
Speaker 14:  there's, well, we might as well just like say it 'cause it'll come out when
Speaker 14:  it comes out. But like there's no such thing as following in, in dig. Hmm.
Speaker 14:  And we've, we've replaced some of the core what have been
Speaker 14:  considered to be quote unquote vanity metrics in the past, which with what
Speaker 14:  we believe to be our first attempt at things that are much more tangible
Speaker 14:  and real and inspire you to do positive things
Speaker 14:  inside of the ecosystem versus a game that's just one
Speaker 14:  versus who's got the biggest follower account. And
Speaker 14:  that's what we're really excited to, to continue to tweak after we get it
Speaker 14:  out there.
Speaker 1:  Man, If you can fix the social metric thing, you, you will have done
Speaker 1:  the internet a great service. Yeah. Like truly we, we don't have a thing
Speaker 1:  that's better than likes and followers and I know Yes. Both of those are
Speaker 1:  bad.
Speaker 14:  Yes. And, and we've, we that's, you know, going back to Justin's point,
Speaker 14:  like when you, If you were a fly on the wall and the, the Alexis,
Speaker 14:  Kevin Justin Hangout space, yes there are the,
Speaker 14:  the the kind of table stakes like lessons learned, stuff that we need to
Speaker 14:  pay attention to and are just going to continue to hold true today from
Speaker 14:  the past. But a lot of it is like, okay,
Speaker 14:  screw what we know to be true. Let's go back to first principles. If we
Speaker 14:  were designing this from today, let's just, ima imagine a world where
Speaker 14:  let's let's challenge all these assumptions that we had previously
Speaker 14:  had, not just for the sake of challenging them, but really, truly sit
Speaker 14:  with them for a minute and say, what might we do differently? And that's
Speaker 14:  led to some really different outcomes already.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that's cool. So Justin, I'm particularly curious for, for your
Speaker 1:  perspective on like the nostalgia versus newness Yeah. Thing because like
Speaker 1:  my sense is like, like you guys are saying, there is a real group of people
Speaker 1:  out there who loves dig and remembers, dig and will care about it and will
Speaker 1:  come back for it. But I feel like that only gets you so far and
Speaker 1:  especially in terms of like the product you guys are describing, it sort
Speaker 1:  of rhymes with old dig, but it's very much not old dig. So like, I don't
Speaker 1:  know, how are you thinking about the, the balance of those two things?
Speaker 15:  Yeah, you know, we had a, a different version I think of
Speaker 15:  this that was probably a little more of a departure from the dig that people
Speaker 15:  know that we were kind of actively working on as we spun things up earlier
Speaker 15:  this year and we were at an offsite together all like doing a hacker house.
Speaker 15:  And what I ended up just like waking up one night and I
Speaker 15:  couldn't fall back asleep because I was just like, I am, I
Speaker 15:  don't want to go out the door with a product that is duct taped together
Speaker 15:  that does not feel like an enjoyable space to be in. Of course. But also
Speaker 15:  just like the people who knew dig walk in and they go, oh, digs
Speaker 15:  back. Oh, that's great. You know, and we've seen so many threads on, you
Speaker 15:  know, various platforms, people talking about dig and it's always like,
Speaker 15:  oh man, I miss it, it's time to bring it back. And of course just because
Speaker 15:  we want to bring surge soda back does not mean surge is as good as we remember.
Speaker 15:  And I get that what we want to do is really build a
Speaker 15:  platform that really works for our modern world that we exist in as well.
Speaker 15:  So what we've really done, and at least here in the beginning that you'll
Speaker 15:  see is like, there are a lot of things that feel
Speaker 15:  innately like dig and it is a very stripped down experience. This
Speaker 15:  isn't like you can do anything and everything. It's, it's a very tight
Speaker 15:  experience on day one, but the goal is two week iteration release
Speaker 15:  cycles. So it's like discovery and delivery happening in two weeks and going
Speaker 15:  out the door because we have a group that is
Speaker 15:  tenacious, they are really hungry and they're really passionate about what
Speaker 15:  we're building. Okay.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I mean there's an interesting thing where it's like, I do feel like
Speaker 1:  you're gonna get a lot of people who just go to the website because it's
Speaker 1:  dig Absolutely. Right? And that, that is like a very powerful thing to have
Speaker 1:  going for you.
Speaker 1:  But it comes with weird expectations, right? Like if it looks like, if it
Speaker 1:  looks like it did 20 years ago, that is both good and bad. Yes. In a way
Speaker 1:  that is I think, really hard to sort through.
Speaker 14:  Yeah. And, and I think that's, but I don't think it's like we have to throw
Speaker 14:  out all the nostalgia. Like I think, I think it's like, you know, if
Speaker 14:  If you come on day one it's 99.9% nostalgia
Speaker 14:  and you're like, damn, this is like a, a slightly updated version of Dig
Speaker 14:  that I
Speaker 15:  Can confirm though it's not a skew morphic website. I can confirm that.
Speaker 15:  Okay. That's good.
Speaker 14:  That's fair. But, but I, I think that the, you know,
Speaker 14:  the one thing we didn't want to do that Justin's alluding to when he said
Speaker 14:  that he stayed up that one night, 'cause I got the call the next day or
Speaker 14:  maybe two days later and he's like, Hey, I just, I just trashed.
Speaker 15:  I'm blowing everything up. I'm blowing everything up.
Speaker 14:  I threw away a bunch of stuff and I was like, okay, let's talk about it.
Speaker 14:  Like what's up? And, and the insight that he had there
Speaker 14:  that I thought was, was super sharp was that, you know,
Speaker 14:  let's get that, let's get that nostalgia bump that we get. We all will know,
Speaker 14:  we know we're gonna get on on day one and, and what we can ride that for
Speaker 14:  a couple weeks and that trust
Speaker 14:  with any of these communities and, and, and ultimately
Speaker 14:  like playing the long game here, it, it's built up week over
Speaker 14:  week, month over month feature over feature.
Speaker 14:  And this is a multi-year adventure for us.
Speaker 14:  This is not something where, you know, Dick's going to eat 50% of
Speaker 14:  Reddit's traffic on by the third month. You know what I mean? Like this
Speaker 14:  is, this is us being, trying to stay
Speaker 14:  as nimble as possible to have as many different wild shots
Speaker 14:  on goal, all with a very
Speaker 14:  important direct line of communication with the user base so that we're
Speaker 14:  listening and, and rolling that into everything that we do.
Speaker 15:  Well the thing too that I, I really do wanna bolt on here is like, I, I
Speaker 15:  love what you're saying about like, we're we're gonna get this thing going
Speaker 15:  and it will be some of the nostalgia, but like, like at the same time,
Speaker 15:  like the reason why we made that decision was it was like if we
Speaker 15:  brought people back to dig and they were like, man, I just wanna dig back.
Speaker 15:  And then they get it and they're like, oh, this is not what I wanted at
Speaker 15:  all. Like, like, okay, yeah, no, this is a totally new thing now. It's a,
Speaker 15:  a chat app or something. That's, that's where we'd feel like we kind of
Speaker 15:  duped just like took the name or like, let's just do whatever we want on
Speaker 15:  this thing. Yeah, yeah, yeah. And so the spirit of it, but then on the other
Speaker 15:  side is like, I also don't want, you know, Reddit folks to come
Speaker 15:  over on that first day and just like, okay, so this is like, just like
Speaker 15:  Reddit with worse features, less stuff and less people. And so it's like
Speaker 15:  we really need to like figure out what is the first step that it looks
Speaker 15:  like to build dig, and then we'll figure out the rest of the steps
Speaker 15:  from it. Yeah,
Speaker 14:  I think it's, I think it's like, you know, this is a horrible analogy Justin
Speaker 14:  come up with something better, but like in my head I'm like, okay, the old
Speaker 14:  dig users were used to Photoshop four, we're giving them Photoshop
Speaker 14:  six and in 18 months they'll have Figma, you know, and it's like, okay,
Speaker 14:  it's, it's, it's, it's kind of that world where, and, and we're gonna bring,
Speaker 14:  bring them along every step of the way, right? And so
Speaker 14:  if we would've just dropped Figma on day one, people would've been like,
Speaker 14:  what the hell is this? Right. You know, and, and, and, and
Speaker 14:  it, it, it, it's gonna happen not because we're just gonna
Speaker 14:  roll out features that we expect will just work flawlessly.
Speaker 14:  It's gonna happen because we roll back features that didn't work and we
Speaker 14:  roll out the next thing. You know, that's, that's how we're gonna figure
Speaker 14:  out this, this whole thing. And, and then the future. It's, it's that
Speaker 14:  it it's that agility that a big competitor won't be able to
Speaker 14:  have. And it's the, it's the fact that we've written
Speaker 14:  the backend from scratch in a way that is so nimble
Speaker 14:  it allows for rapid experimentation in a way that a competitor won't have
Speaker 14:  that is gonna give us the edge here.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah. It sure helps to not be a public company in
Speaker 1:  need of giant growth at this particular moment. A hundred percent the social
Speaker 1:  universe.
Speaker 14:  A hundred percent. That's why you, you nailed it. Like we're, you know,
Speaker 14:  we don't even have ads on the site. Like there's no, there's no, there's
Speaker 14:  no plan for ads anytime soon like that. And, and, and if
Speaker 14:  we do, we're gonna do it in a way that's completely different, you know,
Speaker 14:  and, and we've already got ideas around some of that stuff. But it is worth
Speaker 14:  saying, it's like as we're we're, we're breaking in
Speaker 14:  this new vehicle and we, we booted up and we kind of like, you know,
Speaker 14:  we got that fresh new car smell and everything is like, you know, we're
Speaker 14:  just trying to make sure like the, the panels are bolted on correctly.
Speaker 14:  It's gonna be a fixed taxonomy of topics and, and that that'll
Speaker 14:  be day one. We are gonna very much fast follow that into
Speaker 14:  open-ended, build your own, whatever you like. And so when
Speaker 14:  that happens, you know, to your point about smaller
Speaker 14:  micro communities, If you just care about knitting,
Speaker 14:  like Damnit, we wanna have the best home for you to go build a community
Speaker 14:  about knitting and you may need very specific things for that community
Speaker 14:  that we're just not even aware of. Right. But, you know,
Speaker 14:  we wanna make it as flexible term so that you can
Speaker 14:  describe those things and have those kind of like happen.
Speaker 14:  So it, it's gonna be a lot of steps to get there. But, but
Speaker 14:  to, to your point about, you know, will there be logged out people that
Speaker 14:  just come for the homepage 'cause they're like, show me the homepage of
Speaker 14:  the internet today. Absolutely. Right.
Speaker 1:  I was just gonna say, you're, you're trying to sort of do both of those things.
Speaker 1:  You want to have the one sort of shared experience but also let people kind
Speaker 1:  of define their own inside of
Speaker 14:  It a hundred percent. It's like if you've got a niche weird thing,
Speaker 14:  then you, you'll have a a pocket in the home for that that, you know,
Speaker 14:  I have been into lately into Japanese denim
Speaker 14:  and I would love to have a community that just talks about that all day
Speaker 14:  long. That would be, I'd, I'd be all about that, right? And so
Speaker 14:  it, it it is, it is a world where we will get to e embrace and
Speaker 14:  open it up to, to anything and everything, you know, so
Speaker 1:  Why, why launch this? Now I'm gonna let you guys go here in a minute, but
Speaker 1:  like to your point, you could sort of build this thing in secret forever
Speaker 1:  or you could just like launch the thing the minute you have a
Speaker 1:  website and say, coming soon and have a wait list. Like why,
Speaker 1:  why now? Why is this the right moment?
Speaker 14:  Well, I think, I think it's because it, somebody is, is gonna
Speaker 14:  connect these dots here. A a new startup will connect these dots and that
Speaker 14:  they'll see that we have competition in market right now
Speaker 14:  that has largely neglected the user
Speaker 14:  base. And I, I'm not just talking about Reddit here, but across the board
Speaker 14:  that it's been largely driven by, by people that
Speaker 14:  it's a top down development approach and that these are the features you'll
Speaker 14:  like them and they are what they are and you know,
Speaker 14:  If you don't like it, leave. And I think that
Speaker 14:  we have the ability to flip the script there
Speaker 14:  and then also it's just the most opportune time to lean
Speaker 14:  into all these advancements that we're seeing on the technology front. You
Speaker 14:  know, it's like when I built the first version of Dig I was
Speaker 14:  rack mounting my own servers because AWS didn't exist. That's how
Speaker 14:  ancient I am. And when AWS came out, I was like,
Speaker 14:  oh my God, if I had only built it now, how much easier would this have been?
Speaker 14:  Right? And this is another one of those moments where I'm like,
Speaker 14:  I said, you know, Alexis and I look at each other and, and we, we were like,
Speaker 14:  oh my God, if now is another one of those moments where
Speaker 14:  it's
Speaker 14:  the light of day and we're like, damn,
Speaker 16:  brought to you by defender.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Let's get to The Vergecast hotline as always. The
Speaker 1:  number is 8 6 6 VERGE one one. The email is vergecast at The Verge
Speaker 1:  dot com. Send us all of your questions about everything all the time. That's
Speaker 1:  just the best thing we do here is try and answer your questions.
Speaker 1:  Like I mentioned, we have some really fun sort of bigger picture stuff coming
Speaker 1:  out of hotline questions that I'm very excited about. So stay tuned for that.
Speaker 1:  For now, we have a question about printers
Speaker 18:  Bridge cast. It's David from the center
Speaker 18:  of the United States, again in Missouri. And I'm not
Speaker 18:  actually sure, I haven't called about this before,
Speaker 18:  but here's what I need you to do. Before I missed
Speaker 18:  all this talk about how Apple is declining as
Speaker 18:  a company, as if it's new. I need you to get Apple to do their
Speaker 18:  thing, to work their magic on the whole concept
Speaker 18:  of home printing. I'm not even sure if I have to
Speaker 18:  explain do I? I feel like they're the only people
Speaker 18:  who might actually be able to make it
Speaker 18:  acceptable and not a blight
Speaker 18:  on the rest of our consumer electronics lives. If anyone's listening
Speaker 18:  and if not, I need you to make some calls. Thank you.
Speaker 1:  This is the thing I've actually done a fair amount of research on at this
Speaker 1:  point. I talked to Cory Dro on the show a while ago about
Speaker 1:  printers and the mess that is HP and other companies starting
Speaker 1:  to DRM, the ink so that you can't use third party ink. It's a real
Speaker 1:  like razor and blades situation where they sell you the thing pretty cheap.
Speaker 1:  But then the thing you need to actually use the thing is what's expensive
Speaker 1:  and they lock you in and it's a, it's a crappy business. And the
Speaker 1:  thing about printers is everybody also hates their printers. So it's not
Speaker 1:  even like it's a predatory market in which you still get a good product for
Speaker 1:  too much money. It's a predatory market in which the product sucks.
Speaker 1:  But here's what I figured out and I think this is just the answer, it's
Speaker 1:  not an answer I like, but I think it is the answer. There just is no business
Speaker 1:  in consumer printers as far as I can tell. There is just
Speaker 1:  simply no way in 2025 for a company to make
Speaker 1:  a very good printer and come with the cost that it
Speaker 1:  would require to make a very good printer that people would buy
Speaker 1:  and that would make any money for the company that made it. I think it's
Speaker 1:  just that simple. This is why you see that there are super, super expensive
Speaker 1:  printers at the high end of the line and then there are cheap,
Speaker 1:  awful, crappy printers at the bottom. I think of it a little like the TV
Speaker 1:  market actually, in the sense that there's this
Speaker 1:  high-end world in which you can buy a high-end television for tons of money.
Speaker 1:  That market, we talk about it a lot, but that market is like this big. The
Speaker 1:  much bigger market is big, cheap, crappy screens.
Speaker 1:  That's where we are. And the way that all of those companies make money is
Speaker 1:  not by selling you the television, it's by selling you ads.
Speaker 1:  It's just the market. Now you get companies like tele who are like, look,
Speaker 1:  we don't need a dime from the TV because we're gonna make so much money on
Speaker 1:  ads. You get companies like Roku and Amazon that are deep in the TV
Speaker 1:  business now because it's an advertising business.
Speaker 1:  TVs are not a hardware business, they're an advertising business. And in
Speaker 1:  the same way, printers are not a printer business, they're a, they're
Speaker 1:  an ink business, they're a subscription business, which sucks,
Speaker 1:  but seems to be the case. And realistically If you think about it, you're
Speaker 1:  like, okay, I hate my printer. Would I pay three times as much for my printer
Speaker 1:  to be awesome? I think the answer's just no. I think for almost everybody
Speaker 1:  the answer is just no. I've been talking to people about this for a while
Speaker 1:  and that is the only conclusion I have been able to come to. But before we
Speaker 1:  get out of here, I wanna play you a chunk of an interview that Sean Hollister
Speaker 1:  and I did with framework CEO, nav Patel for last week's show.
Speaker 1:  We didn't actually run this clip on the show last week because it didn't
Speaker 1:  really fit the other stuff we were talking about, but one of the things people
Speaker 1:  always ask framework to make is a printer. It's, it's
Speaker 1:  a perfectly good idea, right? You want something that's upgradable, that's
Speaker 1:  repairable that just kind of works that you can fix yourself really easily.
Speaker 1:  Like printer print, just what if somebody made a good printer? So
Speaker 1:  we asked what would a framework printer look like? And his explanation
Speaker 1:  was really interesting. So before we go, let me just play you this chunk
Speaker 1:  of our interview. And the reason we are not building a
Speaker 1:  printer is actually that we haven't identified a plausible
Speaker 1:  path for us to recoup the investment that we would take for
Speaker 1:  us to build a printer. It's not like a laptop or a desktop
Speaker 1:  where we see that clear path. It's actually very easy for us to recoup the
Speaker 1:  investments we're making in these products. We actually, you know, easily
Speaker 1:  have already on the framework laptop. 13, as we look at a
Speaker 1:  printer,
Speaker 19:  HP do tomorrow to fix their printers other than get rid of all the DRM?
Speaker 1:  Sure, if we knew the answer for that, actually we would go and enter that
Speaker 1:  category.
Speaker 1:  Unfortunately, I don't think we're getting better printers anytime soon.
Speaker 1:  Just doesn't seem like that's in the cards. Whatcha gonna do? All right,
Speaker 1:  that's it for the show today. Thank you so much to everybody who came on
Speaker 1:  and thank you as always for listening or watching. I should say we've been
Speaker 1:  getting better and better at putting more stuff on the Tuesday show
Speaker 1:  on video. I can't promise we're gonna do it every week. I can't promise we're
Speaker 1:  gonna do it for everything, but that's the goal. We want to do as much of
Speaker 1:  this on video as we can. We know that you like watching it on YouTube. We've
Speaker 1:  heard from a lot of folks who want more video. That is the plan. We're working
Speaker 1:  on it and we're getting better at it, frankly quicker than I expected. So
Speaker 1:  it's pretty awesome. If you wanna find us on YouTube, please do. If you just
Speaker 1:  wanna listen to the podcast, rest assured that the video thing is not going
Speaker 1:  to make the podcast worse. It'll always be a listening experience first
Speaker 1:  and foremost. I promise. That's the plan. Alright, that's it.
Speaker 1:  It's time to get outta here. As always, you can continue to hit us
Speaker 1:  up on The Vergecast hotline with all of your thoughts, questions, feelings,
Speaker 1:  whatever. 8 6 6 VERGE one, one Vergecast at The Verge dot com. We want all
Speaker 1:  your feedback on the video. We want all your feedback on all the stuff that
Speaker 1:  we're talking about. Seriously. If you have an interesting iPad use case
Speaker 1:  you wanna tell me about, I'm all yours. This show is produced by
Speaker 1:  Eric Gomez, Wil Poor and Brandon Kiefer. The Vergecast is VERGE Production
Speaker 1:  and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neil, and I'll be back on Friday
Speaker 1:  to talk about AI news, politics. It's
Speaker 1:  just, it just continues to be gadget season too. There's just more gadgets.
Speaker 1:  I'm hoping I'm gonna get this space iPad. We got lots of stuff to talk about.
Speaker 1:  We'll see you then. Rock and roll