# Transcript
ID: 667ac264-ab4b-4d7b-bd70-f18170765fb0
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-4219485121670256839/-4523873305035685200/s93290-US-5879s-1737714029.mp3
Description: Nilay, David, and The Verge's Allison Johnson run down all the biggest news from the latest Samsung Unpacked. The S25 Edge had everyone excited, but the other new Galaxy S25 models feel a little familiar. Then, The Verge's Lauren Feiner updates us on the many goings-on in the first days of the new Trump administration, from the TikTok ban delay to the executive orders on citizenship and AI. Finally, in the lightning round, David and Nilay talk about Netflix's price increase, smart-home standards, and more.
Speaker 1:  Hello and welcome to Vergecast the flagship podcast of whatever the hell
Speaker 1:  is going on right now. Does that feel right, David? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I, I don't know the answer and there are thousands of answers all at the
Speaker 5:  same time.
Speaker 1:  Whatever it is, we're here for you.
Speaker 1:  It's gonna be great. We're super into it. We have a lot talk about this week.
Speaker 1:  I think we're talking on what day day three of a flurry of
Speaker 1:  Trump and big tech merger. We'll get to that later. That's basically a
Speaker 1:  lightning round. We're, we're just gonna have to get through that every week
Speaker 5:  Like I was going through and putting the rundown together. And it's an unusual
Speaker 5:  number of things that we just have to say out loud in a row.
Speaker 5:  There's like, there's just, this is kind of the moment that we're in is a
Speaker 5:  lot of things are happening and I don't know what to make of any of them,
Speaker 5:  but it feels useful to say all of them out loud.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So we're gonna do that in like two minutes and then David's gonna talk
Speaker 1:  about Netflix increasing prices for an hour and a half.
Speaker 5:  Oh, good. We, we, we have the same idea. This is great.
Speaker 1:  Okay. That's, that's how that's gonna go. Well let me just start by saying
Speaker 1:  it's, it's my first Friday virtual house of 2025. It's nice, it's nice to
Speaker 1:  be back with all of you. There's quite a lot going on. And
Speaker 1:  we should start, I think with Galaxy unpacked of all the things. I think
Speaker 1:  that's right. We looked around and it is Samsung
Speaker 1:  Galaxy unpacked. That's where we should start this vergecast because there's
Speaker 1:  new phones and like truly what is The Verge except new phones.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. If you listen, you, you boil any of the other stuff that's happening
Speaker 5:  down far enough and you get to new phones, which I think is like the whole
Speaker 5:  theory of The Verge.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So this works out. It's actually, I will say this, this is very true.
Speaker 1:  We have a lot of very smart, very capable reporters on our policy desk reporters,
Speaker 1:  senators, and every now and again they're like, yeah, we work for the phones
Speaker 1:  website. And every now and again they also point out that only the phone
Speaker 1:  website can do some of the policy coverage they do. 'cause you have to understand
Speaker 1:  the phones to do the policy coverage. It all makes sense in the end. It's
Speaker 1:  gonna be a little whiplash here, here at the top. But let's start with Samsung
Speaker 1:  Galaxy Impact. 'cause it was a big one, not
Speaker 1:  a big one. There's a lot to say about Gemini and what Gemini means to people.
Speaker 1:  And then it was also apparently very exciting.
Speaker 1:  And to tell us about the excitement level, I wanna actually bring
Speaker 1:  in Allison Johnson who is, I believe we've called her in from
Speaker 1:  the side of the road. Hello, Allison, are you here?
Speaker 6:  Hello.
Speaker 1:  How you doing?
Speaker 6:  Great. It's beautiful in California. Who knew?
Speaker 6:  But I'm on my way back to Seattle, so it's gonna be short-lived.
Speaker 6:  I think
Speaker 1:  We'll see how that goes. I feel like in the Annals of VERGE casting, pull
Speaker 1:  over in your car and call us to talk about Samsung Galaxy impact is, this
Speaker 1:  is a high water moment. Literally what has happened here. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  So you were there. They, they announced the Galaxy Edge, which is the
Speaker 1:  really thin one. I hope people saw the video you made from there.
Speaker 1:  The vibes were high. Just a ton of excitement at Samsung Galaxy
Speaker 1:  Impact. Tell us what was going on.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it was kind of a, a rollercoaster ride because
Speaker 6:  the, the bulk of unpacked, you know, The S 25 Ultra,
Speaker 6:  the regular, the Plus, they are very, very minor
Speaker 6:  updates, like in the most extreme way. 'cause that's been the case
Speaker 6:  for a long time. But this is, it's gonna be a review
Speaker 6:  of one UI seven, let's put it that way. So
Speaker 6:  we kind of get through the presentation where like, these phones
Speaker 6:  are mildly interesting, I'm not gonna lie.
Speaker 6:  And then right at the end it was like a, and one more thing,
Speaker 6:  the Galaxy S 25 Edge, and then it was like curtains
Speaker 6:  and then run out to the, they had this
Speaker 6:  area set up behind kind of where they did the presentation and had
Speaker 6:  the, had an some sort of phone there, The S
Speaker 6:  25 Edge phone. So it was, yeah, it was full
Speaker 6:  on. And
Speaker 5:  If I understand correctly, the the salient things that we know about
Speaker 5:  this phone are that it is a phone and it's very
Speaker 5:  thin. Yes. Is that, am I missing anything?
Speaker 6:  Those are the two things I confirmed viewing it from
Speaker 6:  a distance. Okay. No, it was a really funny experience,
Speaker 6:  kind of like coming off of this announcement of like some pretty
Speaker 6:  familiar devices and then I think we were all just thirsty for something
Speaker 6:  different. And so they had this, this slim
Speaker 6:  phone out there and it was a full on
Speaker 6:  like see us from 10 years ago kind of
Speaker 6:  scrum where we're all trying to get in and get photos of it.
Speaker 6:  So yeah. But that's, we were not allowed to get close to it. We were not
Speaker 6:  allowed to touch it. We weren't allowed to breathe too close to it.
Speaker 6:  But it's very thin. It's, you can say that
Speaker 6:  it has two cameras instead of three. We, we could tell that.
Speaker 1:  Did they say why it's so thin or why that's important?
Speaker 1:  Like if, if Samsung was like, this phone is twice
Speaker 1:  as thick as last year's phone, but the battery lasts for four days,
Speaker 1:  I'd be like, let's talk, let's get in there. Yeah. It's way thinner
Speaker 1:  to me. It's like we, we all lived through the Johnny Ive
Speaker 1:  experience once we're just doing it again. What, what's
Speaker 1:  happening here?
Speaker 6:  It feels a little bit of that. It feels like a style thing. I
Speaker 6:  just, from the very, very little we know of it,
Speaker 6:  supposedly it'll be lower price than, well than
Speaker 6:  the Ultra, which is like the most expensive phone you can buy anyway.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It's kind of a, a curiosity. I think it's, it's sort of
Speaker 6:  an answer to like, phones are all the same, you know,
Speaker 6:  folding phones aside, what do we do that's different? And I guess they
Speaker 6:  can make the phones slimmer now. So that's,
Speaker 6:  that's what we're gonna have.
Speaker 5:  I will say to Samsung's credit, and I've only seen this on the video, but
Speaker 5:  the, the way that they showed this thing off is extremely
Speaker 5:  cool. It was on this, this big table and the phone
Speaker 5:  itself looked like it's, it's sort of suspended from a little chain. And
Speaker 5:  then there are like thin slabs of what looked like stone in
Speaker 5:  the, it's this very like earthy cool, like
Speaker 5:  thousands of years ago kind of vibe on this table. Yeah. It
Speaker 1:  Looked like they were painting cabinet doors. What are you talking about?
Speaker 6:  Oh, right. That's how you would hang a like cabinet.
Speaker 1:  It looked like at any moment someone was gonna come up with like a spray
Speaker 1:  paint
Speaker 6:  Can. Yeah. So the, the
Speaker 6:  other little slabs, it was like the,
Speaker 1:  Is that it? So that's the whole thing. It's it's thin they didn't
Speaker 6:  It's thin. Go
Speaker 1:  Ahead. You go ahead Allison.
Speaker 6:  No, they were saying that the, the other little slabs were the,
Speaker 6:  the previous phones, The S 24 and I don't think The
Speaker 6:  S 20 fives. It was like thick phone. Thick phone, slim
Speaker 6:  phone for comparison. And yeah, I think that's
Speaker 6:  the whole vibe. It's just a, a phone that's slimmer and they're like,
Speaker 6:  isn't that cool?
Speaker 6:  So we'll see. Sure.
Speaker 5:  Can I throw a thing at you that might be a bit of a problem for Samsung?
Speaker 5:  I didn't clock that. These three things were different thicknesses. Like
Speaker 5:  even even looking at them in the video and even in the pictures now, I thought
Speaker 5:  they were all the same thing.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Wow.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So we should just mention there's a, there's a big rumor
Speaker 1:  that in September, apple will do an iPhone error
Speaker 1:  that will be very thin. Do we think that this is Samsung
Speaker 1:  just showing off like vaporware to get ahead of Apple, which is a, you know,
Speaker 1:  thing people believe, or is it just something about the modern
Speaker 1:  smartphone supply chain is like, you can make thin phones now,
Speaker 1:  so everyone's just gonna do that. It
Speaker 6:  Feels like a little bit of both. I think Samsung absolutely
Speaker 6:  is always thinking about Apple and they're like, we can sneak
Speaker 6:  this one in ahead of whatever, you know,
Speaker 6:  Tim Cook is gonna do. I do think it's a supply chain
Speaker 6:  thing of like, well we can do this now. So this is what we have.
Speaker 6:  I I think it's interesting that they, they call it an S 25,
Speaker 6:  so it should ship this year in 2025. You
Speaker 6:  would, you would presume. But that's, yeah, that's all we got.
Speaker 1:  What year did Zoolander come out? I feel like we're in on the Zoolander curve.
Speaker 6:  Oh no,
Speaker 1:  Do Zoolander is 2001. So we're, we're we're exactly
Speaker 1:  25 years later and we don't remember that there was a movie
Speaker 1:  in which one of the main jokes is that phones were super tiny and so now
Speaker 1:  we're just gonna do, we're gonna do marketing that's like, this one's really
Speaker 1:  thin and it's, we're gonna be like, yeah, does it bend a lot like that? The
Speaker 1:  iPhone six was really thin and it bent a lot.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  That's Did they say anything about durability?
Speaker 6:  They said they did not say one word about this phone except play
Speaker 6:  like a sizzle reel of, of some like metal
Speaker 6:  pieces coming together. We really just coasted on vibes,
Speaker 1:  But the vibes were high. Like I, that was the thing that really struck, I
Speaker 1:  watched your video, you're like, this is, people are stoked about this phone.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Did anybody say why while you were there?
Speaker 6:  I think it really was from, were
Speaker 1:  They just like, it was a thing to take a picture of
Speaker 6:  It? I think it was a thing to take a picture of. We were all kind of starved
Speaker 6:  for like, I think in the pres end of the presentation was like,
Speaker 6:  is this it? Like these s 25 phones, like
Speaker 6:  they're not much to write home about. And then it was like,
Speaker 6:  no, here's this other thing you can all take pictures of. And it was so crowded.
Speaker 6:  Like they had security for the thin phone and they were like pushing us
Speaker 6:  back. I saw Dieter, he was like trying
Speaker 6:  to get in line too and he just gave up. I was like, yeah,
Speaker 6:  this is,
Speaker 6:  this is old school.
Speaker 1:  Lemme just ask you for a vibe comparison. Unscientific,
Speaker 1:  they had the thin phone and then they had the new headset. The
Speaker 1:  Wuhan. Yeah. Which is not a great name, but it's their headset,
Speaker 1:  right? It's their Apple Vision Pro competitor with Google, like
Speaker 1:  embedded, they're gonna do a whole thing.
Speaker 1:  What were people more excited about?
Speaker 6:  A hundred percent. The skinny phone. It was like, not
Speaker 6:  even, it wasn't even hard to, it wasn't even hard to get up and
Speaker 6:  take a picture of the headset and there were just a lot of people kind of
Speaker 6:  standing around going, oh, it looks like a vision pro. And
Speaker 6:  you're kinda like, yeah. And we, same rules. We couldn't
Speaker 6:  approach it. We couldn't touch it. You would get yelled at If you moved your
Speaker 6:  camera too close to it. But yeah, the, the slim phone,
Speaker 6:  the Edge won the day. I think
Speaker 1:  It says a lot. I I would just say that that might be the entire story of
Speaker 1:  the tech industry is they are desperate to get a computer on your face
Speaker 1:  and then you show up with like skinny phone and everyone rushes to skinny
Speaker 1:  phone.
Speaker 6:  We're like, yes, this is it.
Speaker 5:  We talked a little bit about the, the iPhone air on the
Speaker 5:  show last Friday.
Speaker 5:  I continue to think there is nothing particularly interesting or compelling
Speaker 5:  about like an eight tenths of a millimeter thinner phone.
Speaker 5:  But you use all of these phones all the time. You, you, you can sense eight
Speaker 5:  tenths of a mil millimeter in a way that very few can Is this exciting?
Speaker 5:  Like is the idea if 2025 is going to be the year all of our phones get thinner,
Speaker 5:  is that like a good cool, exciting thing? Are we happy about this? I'm,
Speaker 6:  I'm not entirely sure. The thing I come back to is
Speaker 6:  the Pixel nine Pro fold, like the second pixel fold
Speaker 6:  was one of those things you read about on paper and they were like, we changed
Speaker 6:  the dimensions.
Speaker 6:  I was like, sure, sure. And I went and picked it up at the event and
Speaker 6:  immediately was like, oh no, this is right. Like this feels so much
Speaker 6:  better, much better. I don't know if a thin phone is gonna have that same
Speaker 6:  kind of like, you pick it up and use it and you're like, oh, this is
Speaker 6:  different. Like it, I don't know. I'm not, I'm
Speaker 6:  not like committing one way or the other. I'll reserve some,
Speaker 6:  some hope. I guess I'm, I'm mostly
Speaker 6:  skeptical, but I think it, it'll be a, a thing. We have to,
Speaker 6:  to pick up the phone and live with it and see if it, it cracks in half If
Speaker 6:  you sit in a sit on it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. All right. We will let you get back in the car. Alright. You flew,
Speaker 1:  made you pull over. Thank you so much for joining us Alison. I, I
Speaker 1:  eagerly await the th the thin phone review. Oh,
Speaker 6:  Me too. Thanks for having me.
Speaker 1:  Right as we were hanging up in Allison there, the police came.
Speaker 1:  So this is what you do for podcasting.
Speaker 5:  This is the last time anyone will hear from Allison on The Vergecast. This
Speaker 1:  Is how devoted Allison is. The Vergecast, I feel like left unsaid
Speaker 1:  in that conversation is the fact that the other phones are tremendously boring.
Speaker 5:  It's a weird year. So one of the things about unpacked is that
Speaker 5:  every year Samsung shows up to unpacked and launches what are basically
Speaker 5:  guaranteed to be the bestselling Android phones of the year. Yeah. Every
Speaker 5:  year. It's just, it just is what it is. It is clockwork.
Speaker 5:  This is maybe the least interesting phone announcement
Speaker 5:  I can remember, period. Like for all the
Speaker 5:  pomp and circumstance, these phones literally aren't
Speaker 5:  upgrades. Like they, the, so there's The S 25, The
Speaker 5:  S 25 plus and The S 25 Ultra. And they are in,
Speaker 5:  in every meaningful and meaningless way, the same as
Speaker 5:  The S 24 with a slightly newer revved chip
Speaker 5:  from Qualcomm. They bumped up the ram a little bit in,
Speaker 5:  in, I think all of them, but at least a couple of them. The prices are the
Speaker 5:  same. The cameras are the same except for one camera on the Ultra
Speaker 5:  the, they look the same. Like they just shipped the same phones again. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And I'm like, I'm sort of blown away by that fact and
Speaker 5:  e especially, you know, they had this big arena event, they talked a ton
Speaker 5:  about AI and then like, oh, we're actually rolling all that stuff back to
Speaker 5:  The S 20 fours again. And so part of me is like, why ship
Speaker 5:  new phones? Just have a software event. Just, just be like AI
Speaker 5:  and be like, oh, we are the first company ever who made our old phones,
Speaker 5:  new phones with ai. Like that would've made more sense to me
Speaker 5:  than we just made more of these with a new name
Speaker 1:  Or, or lower the price than that's 24. We're one year into this cycle.
Speaker 1:  We're actually do, taking the radical step of making their phones a little
Speaker 1:  bit cheaper and adding more software to them. Now I know why they can't do
Speaker 1:  it. There are carrier executives who are furiously sending me emails
Speaker 1:  right now. Yeah. Because the carriers need the full spectrum
Speaker 1:  of all the price points from all their partners. And Samsung maybe more than
Speaker 1:  any company, just does what the carriers want. Actually, maybe Motorola
Speaker 1:  does it more like Motorola made the phone for like the dish network 5G. True.
Speaker 1:  But like Samsung has to be on a cadence of all these, like
Speaker 1:  there's all this machinery that is built around the
Speaker 1:  notion of a new phone coming out every year. Yes. We're just at the point
Speaker 1:  where the phone doesn't matter to the machinery. Like
Speaker 1:  to just unlock the T-Mobile's marketing spend for Q4,
Speaker 1:  something has to be called a new phone.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think that's right. It just has to be a thing. You have to, it doesn't
Speaker 5:  it and it matters much less what that thing is, or honestly in
Speaker 5:  Samsung's case, if it's any good, like it, it's the same thing as the
Speaker 5:  iPhone in so many ways. Like people who have iPhones at
Speaker 5:  this point will buy the newest iPhone when their current iPhone
Speaker 5:  stops being viable. That is the upgrade path, right? You almost
Speaker 5:  everybody gets the latest iPhone uses it until they
Speaker 5:  can't anymore and then gets the latest iPhone. And so if you're, if you're
Speaker 5:  Samsung, that is, it's the same path and it, it has I think
Speaker 5:  made phones boring, all of them. But
Speaker 5:  this just felt like a real, I don't know, low moment. Or maybe
Speaker 5:  just like saying the quiet part loud of like, yeah, there's nothing left
Speaker 5:  to do here anymore. So here's the same phone again.
Speaker 1:  It's thinner now. Yeah, yeah. Even like the YouTubers who are have a lot
Speaker 1:  of incentives to pretend thing. Nothing. Yeah. Just total flat across the
Speaker 1:  board. The thing that really struck me about all of this is the
Speaker 1:  AI of it. You wrote about Gemini sort of being the winner in the assistant
Speaker 1:  wars because it's just bundled in the Samsung phones now. But I was watching
Speaker 1:  the, the demos of ai, like we're year two
Speaker 1:  into it, essentially. Like here's the AI stuff you can do with our phone
Speaker 1:  maybe year 10 If you, you know, count Google for years.
Speaker 1:  Like not shipping it, it's talking about it. It's, yeah, but it's like year
Speaker 1:  two of like we're shipping it on phones, right? And we're sort of past now
Speaker 1:  the Apple intelligence moment where I think the newest version of the software,
Speaker 1:  the newest version of iOS that's in release candidate right now, it's on
Speaker 1:  by default. So we've like, we've hit the point, right? It's, this is just
Speaker 1:  part of phones now and I'm watching the demos and there are no new ideas.
Speaker 5:  No.
Speaker 1:  Like
Speaker 5:  Everyone has the same like four ideas,
Speaker 1:  Right? They they did the, you can search your photos, which is very smart.
Speaker 1:  I'm very excited about that one. Great idea. Yep. But they spent
Speaker 1:  a long time being like, so what happens is you say a
Speaker 1:  name, location, person and clothing and then the AI
Speaker 1:  understands you and it's like, yeah, we, people have fallen in love with
Speaker 1:  robots,
Speaker 5:  Right? Yeah. Like we got that one pretty covered at
Speaker 1:  This point. We're like, we're really good on that
Speaker 5:  Actually. Yeah. People are doing a lot of illegal stuff with those things.
Speaker 5:  Like we, we know, we understand. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Then there's the, like you can change a setting by just
Speaker 1:  talking, which Samsung to its credit dog
Speaker 1:  with shoes, Bixby, that was the whole point of Bixby, right?
Speaker 1:  And no one cared. So like getting rid of it and then doing it again with
Speaker 1:  Gemini. I don't, but you can do it now. Maybe it'll work better
Speaker 1:  if it works better. Maybe maybe people will use it. But that's the other
Speaker 1:  demo. And then everything else is kind of the same. Like it does
Speaker 1:  transcriptions, it can record phone calls. Like
Speaker 1:  we can just process language a little bit better than we could before. Right?
Speaker 1:  Did you catch anything that was like, oh, this is a step change because we
Speaker 1:  have this capability.
Speaker 5:  The one thing that feels meaningfully new
Speaker 5:  is this multi-step, multi app thing that
Speaker 5:  Gemini can now do where it, it can, it can essentially
Speaker 5:  direct actions to multiple apps at a time. It can just do several things
Speaker 5:  with one prompt. It doesn't work very well because
Speaker 5:  of course it doesn't, I'll give you an example. So right before we're getting
Speaker 5:  on here, one thing I think Gemini in particular
Speaker 5:  is actually very good at is as a YouTube research tool
Speaker 5:  because it, it has an extension into YouTube and you can just say like, find
Speaker 5:  me popular YouTube videos about whatever. And it,
Speaker 5:  it does a pretty good job of that in a way that like regular YouTube search
Speaker 5:  actually doesn't. So I use it for that all the time when I'm just like, I
Speaker 5:  wanna watch a bunch of videos about how GPUs work. Gemini is actually very
Speaker 5:  good for that. So I was like, okay, cool. Two step thing I'm gonna
Speaker 5:  say Gemini, go find a bunch of videos about
Speaker 5:  how GPUs work on YouTube and then put them all into a note in
Speaker 5:  Google. Keep two steps, right? That's the thing that this stuff
Speaker 5:  is supposed to be able to do now. And it plugs into WhatsApp. So you can
Speaker 5:  be like, find me a restaurant to go to and then, and then text it to Anna.
Speaker 5:  That's where we're going tonight. This is like, these are the kinds of things
Speaker 5:  they're starting to put together. And again, this is the idea everybody has.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, this is open AI's operator, this is series app intents. Like this is
Speaker 5:  the agentic thing everybody is talking about. But anyway, So I do this in
Speaker 5:  Gemini, the first thing it does is pull back five titles of videos
Speaker 5:  and it's like, do you wanna save these to keep? And I go, sure, sounds great.
Speaker 5:  It says Okay, I've created your notes. The notes it created were the titles
Speaker 5:  of the videos and nothing else. Five individual Google
Speaker 5:  keep notes with just titles.
Speaker 1:  Wait, wait, you made individual notes, you made
Speaker 5:  Individual notes. So then I'm like, okay, let's try this a different way.
Speaker 5:  So I go and I'm like, okay, can you just find me a bunch of YouTube videos
Speaker 5:  about GPUs? And it's like, sure. And I was like, okay, next step.
Speaker 5:  So we're already out of the interesting multi-step thing here. And I'm like,
Speaker 5:  what if we just do the simple thing? Great, you found all these videos looks
Speaker 5:  good. Can you put all that into a note for me in Google
Speaker 5:  Keep? And it's like, sure. Done. So now what it does is create a list with
Speaker 5:  a title like videos about how GPUs work and five empty bullets.
Speaker 5:  Like we've done nothing here. And I think like
Speaker 5:  the, the, the point I keep making and I, I said a snarky thing about
Speaker 5:  Apple intelligence on threads a few days ago that was like, I can't wait
Speaker 5:  till iOS 21 when the only feature is getting rid of Apple intelligence and
Speaker 5:  it's the best upgrade in the years. And, and people like raped me over the
Speaker 5:  calls for it and I just, I keep coming back to none of this is actually useful
Speaker 5:  for much of anything. Yeah. And even the things that are useful aren't useful
Speaker 5:  reliably enough to be worth trying to use. Like the, the
Speaker 5:  Samsung Bixby thing was a good idea, right?
Speaker 5:  The idea of like, most people don't know how to find the Bluetooth switch
Speaker 5:  on their phone. And so to be able to just ask my phone how to turn on Bluetooth
Speaker 5:  is like a good and useful idea and it just didn't work enough.
Speaker 5:  So people would just go find Bluetooth on their phone and If you can't, If
Speaker 5:  you can't beat the reliability of swiping up through
Speaker 5:  a settings menu until I find the thing labeled Bluetooth, you have nothing.
Speaker 5:  And we're now 10 years into that problem and I don't think we have meaningfully
Speaker 5:  solved it. So like this, this thing Google keeps demoing, which is like
Speaker 5:  the, the multi-step multimodal multi action stuff is
Speaker 5:  like, it's cool. It's the, the idea is very cool. It feels like the right
Speaker 5:  thing. My phone can just sort of take in all the information that I need
Speaker 5:  it to and then give it back to me in ways that are useful and natural. That
Speaker 5:  all makes sense. It just doesn't work and I'm so stuck on it. None
Speaker 5:  of this matters until it works and we're just not there yet.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. The piece of the puzzle that I think just really alludes me
Speaker 1:  is
Speaker 1:  I like, I do know how to turn Bluetooth on on my phone. Like I'm
Speaker 1:  cursed with this knowledge as, as is are most of our listeners.
Speaker 1:  And it is so much faster for me to learn how to use the
Speaker 1:  thing than to fight the other tool that will do it for me
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent.
Speaker 1:  And maybe that, and like I understand that that again, I think The
Speaker 1:  Vergecast audience and The Verge staff is like a uniquely
Speaker 1:  positioned group of people in that we also all like figuring
Speaker 1:  it out and most people would just like to move on with her day. But I,
Speaker 1:  the danger is you're gonna bounce off of it doing it badly
Speaker 1:  and then you will never try again. Right. Which is with Siri and Alexa
Speaker 1:  in history, why they're perceived to be bad products.
Speaker 5:  Yep. And I think these companies have estimate underestimated how high
Speaker 5:  that bar is for people of like how quickly
Speaker 5:  it will feel like I'm fighting this thing and I will just go back to the
Speaker 5:  definitely less efficient and hacker way that I can figure
Speaker 5:  out how to do.
Speaker 1:  Okay, so here's the flip side of that, which I have been thinking about a
Speaker 1:  lot. There is the section of the
Speaker 1:  audience that's like, please shut up about ai. We don't care about it. We
Speaker 1:  well, I I can hear you already. You're screaming at me and coming back
Speaker 1:  through the internet as you listen to this, I, it resonates in my heart.
Speaker 1:  I hear you. It's the same group of people that whenever we write about semi
Speaker 1:  ai feature on The Verge dot com, they, they're, you're in our comments. You're
Speaker 1:  like, I hate this. Make it go away. I just wanna turn off Apple intelligence.
Speaker 1:  I'm there with you. It's all fraud. Great. Then
Speaker 1:  there's the people who ferociously read everything we write about ai.
Speaker 1:  Dude, they're out there, they, they love it. And then there's the companies
Speaker 1:  who are all telling us that their own usage statistics
Speaker 1:  suggest people are using the hell outta these tools. Right? So the example
Speaker 1:  I'll give, which is old now, but it's just the one that is in my brain all
Speaker 1:  the time.
Speaker 1:  The CEO of Adobe Han Ryan came on decoder and you can go listen
Speaker 1:  to it. He's like, the usage of generative fill in Photoshop is as high
Speaker 1:  as layers. Which is basically I opened Photoshop.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's what Photoshop is for the
Speaker 1:  Right. Like that's where he is at. He's like, the take rate on generative
Speaker 1:  fill is as high as layers. So yes, everyone's yelling, everyone's
Speaker 1:  mad, everyone hates it. And then everyone's just using the hell out of it.
Speaker 1:  We can see it on our site. People reading about it like crazy. And then you,
Speaker 1:  I wanna bring this to Gemini specifically on these phones. Gemini's gonna
Speaker 1:  be the default on the Galaxy phones. Samsung's not gonna do its own thing.
Speaker 1:  And Google's like, Gemini is more popular than Chatt now 'cause it's just
Speaker 1:  there and people are using it. Right. And I dunno how to square that with,
Speaker 1:  it's not very good. Like most of the time it's not very good. The cha
Speaker 1:  pt the day we're recording this on, on Thursday, it was down this morning.
Speaker 1:  And there are people being like, I'm not getting any work done because I,
Speaker 1:  I've just like rely on this so much. And I'm like, well you're, I hope your
Speaker 1:  work is good. But like you can see it's, it's, it's wound
Speaker 1:  its way into so many different places. Even though I think
Speaker 1:  the core criticism, boy you hit a wall of this not being very good
Speaker 1:  is still very real.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think like generative fill is actually a really interesting one because
Speaker 5:  it's, it's the kind of feature that is ai but it's not
Speaker 5:  in the way that we mostly talk about ai. Like everybody wants us to think
Speaker 5:  about AI as these like, you know, all knowing all
Speaker 5:  purpose omnipresent companions that can just do
Speaker 5:  everything. I, I think that is like completely the wrong
Speaker 5:  way. We should be developing these things like AI as a
Speaker 5:  tool, which is basically a, a smarter thing to plug into
Speaker 5:  generative fill makes a lot of sense. And so it totally tracks me this working.
Speaker 5:  And I think even in chat gt, like I'm very
Speaker 5:  compelled by the stories I hear about people who use it as like a force
Speaker 5:  multiplier for writing code. I think that's real, even if it doesn't write
Speaker 5:  very good code. Like I have talked to enough people who
Speaker 5:  are like, it is so much faster for me to take
Speaker 5:  middling code and make it good than it is to start
Speaker 5:  from scratch and write the like incredibly basic stuff that is
Speaker 5:  required in order to write good code. Like all good code
Speaker 5:  involves lots of bad code and So I can do the bad code automatically and
Speaker 5:  then I just have to do the good code. Like that kind of thing I think is,
Speaker 5:  is really powerful. The problem is for like regular people
Speaker 5:  in their day-to-day lives, these companies have not yet
Speaker 5:  identified a ton of good versions of that. And this is
Speaker 5:  why we keep landing on, like, it'll help you write email and summarize email.
Speaker 5:  That's like, that's the only
Speaker 1:  Normal
Speaker 5:  Person use case any of these companies can think of for what this stuff can
Speaker 5:  do. So I think while in the background, all this interesting stuff is
Speaker 5:  happening in, in like back offices are being
Speaker 5:  reinvented by AI that can do some of this work for them. All this
Speaker 5:  stuff is happening, but the idea that like there's a button on my phone that
Speaker 5:  I'm going to press and it's gonna do things for me a hundred times a day,
Speaker 5:  we just haven't figured out yet. And we haven't, we never figured it out
Speaker 5:  with Siri. We never figured out with Alexa. Like the take rate is high
Speaker 5:  because it's so present. But I think the, the thing these
Speaker 5:  companies know and have figured out and are pushing so hard towards is that
Speaker 5:  If you don't stick it in front of people's face, they won't by and
Speaker 5:  large go looking for it.
Speaker 1:  Right. There's nothing compelling about it that makes you go be like, I need
Speaker 1:  to get this app.
Speaker 5:  Right.
Speaker 1:  I I buy it Except chae is the most popular app,
Speaker 1:  right? The fastest growing consumer product around.
Speaker 5:  I I have, I have many theories about chat g pt, but I, I continue
Speaker 5:  to think that the novelty of chat GPT
Speaker 5:  is a huge part of its appeal. And that's, that's, that's not nothing but
Speaker 5:  like we are still so deep in the,
Speaker 5:  like it's wild that this thing works at all that I think
Speaker 5:  we're not yet really having to reckon with the use cases here. Like
Speaker 5:  chat, GT's search stuff doesn't really seem to be
Speaker 5:  setting the universe on fire. This operator thing that they launched
Speaker 5:  to the $200 a month folks today
Speaker 5:  seems interesting. But like,
Speaker 5:  I dunno, people like chat GBT in theory, I think more than they are spending
Speaker 5:  a lot of like useful day-to-day phone time
Speaker 5:  with it.
Speaker 1:  All right. So that's my prompt to the audience. 'cause I, I
Speaker 1:  disagree with you. Okay. I think we are just old guys who are good at writing.
Speaker 1:  Like I Sure. I think, I think we are just like out of the audience we will
Speaker 1:  do voice disguises If you don't wanna admit it, but call
Speaker 1:  the hotline and and tell us how you're using chat v 'cause I'm
Speaker 1:  very curious. I think there's, there's just a weird split here.
Speaker 1:  There's like a very vocal minority. It's like screw this all, I hate it.
Speaker 1:  There's a lot of people who are just using this stuff and then there's like,
Speaker 1:  again, there's, there's sort of the middle. I think a lot of people are in
Speaker 1:  the middle where you're indifferent 'cause it's not very good. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And I, but the caveat is, I, I don't want to hear stories about how it makes
Speaker 5:  you better at your job because there, there are lots of those and I think
Speaker 5:  that's, that's fine and good and all of that is really interesting. I'm talking
Speaker 5:  about like stuff that you would press the side button on your phone to do
Speaker 5:  with ai. Like that's, that's the stuff I want to know.
Speaker 1:  All right. Like I'm said voices. We'll we will, we will protect you. The
Speaker 1:  Verge has always protected its sources. And now in this time of
Speaker 1:  increased threat against the First Amendment, I promise you, you can admit
Speaker 1:  to us that you use ai. Yeah. And I'll protect you
Speaker 5:  And we will love you anyway.
Speaker 1:  We should break. But before we do, I just actually want, I I want you to
Speaker 1:  talk about Gemini for one second. 'cause you wrote this piece about how it's
Speaker 1:  won, which is a big claim, especially 'cause se like real
Speaker 1:  ai Siri isn't here yet, but Google was behind and
Speaker 1:  now they've, I mean they're the default on the most popular
Speaker 1:  Android phone, which is a big deal. Do you think Gemini is good
Speaker 1:  as an assistant or do you think it's just won by default of the placement?
Speaker 5:  I think it won by default of the placement, but I actually don't think the
Speaker 5:  difference between those two things is all that big. Like I I,
Speaker 5:  I've been thinking so much in the last couple of weeks about the
Speaker 5:  Google search trial, which essentially amounted to If you have
Speaker 5:  a good enough product that people want to use it and you can put it in front
Speaker 5:  of everybody. Like everybody, you almost immediately
Speaker 5:  build an insurmountable lead. Because what you need is you need data on how
Speaker 5:  people are using your product that you can use to make the product better,
Speaker 5:  which makes more people use it, which means you get more data, which means
Speaker 5:  more people like on and on and on. I mean, like, I, I will never forget
Speaker 5:  Satya Nadella sitting up there being like, I will give Bing to Apple for
Speaker 5:  free. Like they can just have it. We don't just
Speaker 5:  take all, keep all the money. I just want the query data. Like
Speaker 5:  that's real. And we're going through that with AI too. This stuff gets better
Speaker 5:  the more people use it. And what Google has is a
Speaker 5:  unstoppable distribution advantages because it has things like Chrome
Speaker 5:  that it can just stick it in the address bar. It has things like a
Speaker 5:  very popular Google app. It has Google Maps, it has Gmail. Like Google can
Speaker 5:  both use Gemini underneath all of those things and get you
Speaker 5:  to interact with Gemini on top of them. Then you make it the
Speaker 5:  side button on essentially all of the Android phones that matter at
Speaker 5:  this point. And you've built yet another place where you're
Speaker 5:  essentially untouchable and then throw in the fact that
Speaker 5:  Amazon just seems unable to get its shit together with this new Alexa. Like
Speaker 5:  what, whatever that is going to be. It, it is, it does not seem like it's
Speaker 5:  gonna be very good or ship anytime soon at this point.
Speaker 5:  Siri, TBD. But nothing about the history of Siri suggests that it's going
Speaker 5:  to be great. Nothing
Speaker 1:  But the present of Apple intelligence suggests well right. That Siri
Speaker 5:  Will be great. Yeah. There is nothing, there is nothing that leads me to
Speaker 5:  believe there is some radical reinvention of that assistant coming anytime
Speaker 5:  soon. So Google is in a place where it's, it's
Speaker 5:  pretty good. I think Gemini by all accounts is at least in
Speaker 5:  range of Chachi, BT and Claude, which I think have been
Speaker 5:  kind of the, the two gold standards for a while now. And the difference between
Speaker 5:  the two is like personal taste and some one's better at some things
Speaker 5:  and the other's better at other things. But the thing neither of those have
Speaker 5:  is the distribution. They don't have a gadget they can be part of, they don't
Speaker 5:  have web browsers that they can be built into by default. Google has
Speaker 5:  a pretty good product and every other advantage you could possibly want
Speaker 5:  in this space and that that just feeds
Speaker 5:  itself. And so we're hitting a point where Google is going to get this like
Speaker 5:  escape velocity before anybody else can build themselves
Speaker 5:  the things that they need that Google already has
Speaker 1:  Or make a dollar from them. Like the other thing Google has is like a cash
Speaker 1:  machine in search,
Speaker 5:  Right? That is now just shoves Gemini into,
Speaker 1:  I, this is gonna, we're gonna figure this out over the next four years.
Speaker 1:  But this is where like the weirdness of the Trump administration just runs
Speaker 1:  right into the reality of the tech products, especially in now in Trump too.
Speaker 1:  Like Sam Altman's standing on stage of the White House, not stage, just around,
Speaker 1:  they were just in a room I
Speaker 5:  Kept saying it looked like an SNL set. Yeah. It's just like
Speaker 1:  Here's,
Speaker 5:  Here's a wall and like a podium. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Standing there. They were just like, here's, here's a, here's a sitting room
Speaker 1:  that we're in
Speaker 1:  announcing these quote raised $500 billion to build data centers.
Speaker 1:  Google isn't talking about raising money to do ai. Like they have the data
Speaker 1:  centers. And actually what Char talks about most of all is bringing the cost
Speaker 1:  of inference down. He's like, we're great at this. And so you're, you can
Speaker 1:  just see they're starting from like two radically different positions.
Speaker 1:  I don't know if any of those open AI announcements are real. Certainly Elon
Speaker 1:  Musk does not think they're real. Donald Trump thinks you're real. Like there's
Speaker 1:  a lot of that just like weirdness embedded in there. But you're just, look,
Speaker 1:  I'm just looking at this much more broadly and abstractly from who are the
Speaker 1:  competitors? How are they funded? How long will they last? Who can sustain?
Speaker 1:  And Google is just in a position where, yeah, maybe it's not the best
Speaker 1:  one. There's an argument that it's it's very good at some things compared
Speaker 1:  to the others. Yeah. But maybe it's not the best one overall,
Speaker 1:  but it's in so many different places that are already popular and Google
Speaker 1:  can just lose money on it in a way that Sam Altman has to
Speaker 1:  go raise half a trillion dollars of weird laundered
Speaker 1:  money for Middle Eastern states through SoftBank and then announce data centers
Speaker 1:  that may or not. Like he's gotta do a whole other thing. And Google just
Speaker 1:  has to be like, would you like to buy ads on on YouTube? Right. And that's
Speaker 1:  different,
Speaker 5:  Right? The, I mean like in a very real way, Sam Altman has to build
Speaker 5:  Google and all Google has to do is convince people that Gemini is
Speaker 5:  as good as chat GBT. And that thing is not nothing like, I think the, maybe
Speaker 5:  the biggest thing chat GT is going for it right now is like a huge
Speaker 5:  perception advantage. Like it, it was first it blew people's
Speaker 5:  minds. It it is the thing when people think about this space, like it is,
Speaker 5:  it is the closest to the like Kleenex
Speaker 1:  Alright, we're back. Lauren Finer is here. Hello Lauren. Hi
Speaker 1:  S sorry that you're our policy reporter.
Speaker 12:  Thank you. I'll accept the condolences.
Speaker 1:  You have been very busy. The Trump administration
Speaker 1:  kicked off on day one with a flurry of executive orders, some of which
Speaker 1:  are fully nonsensical, some of which have already been put on hold by courts.
Speaker 1:  Like literally as we're speaking. The birthright citizenship order was,
Speaker 1:  I think the court was like, this is stupid. I don't think I've ever seen
Speaker 1:  a judge just say this is stupid. And he was like, this is stupid. So there's
Speaker 1:  all this activity happening. Trump, as everyone remembers from the first
Speaker 1:  Trump administration, talks a lot. And then you have to evaluate whether
Speaker 1:  what he's saying is real. So I would start with
Speaker 1:  Stargate announcement. We were just talking about OpenAI. They announced
Speaker 1:  this $500 billion plan to build data centers
Speaker 1:  with Oracle, with Nvidia.
Speaker 1:  It was very odd. SoftBank is involved, Maan was in the White House next
Speaker 1:  to Larry Allison and Sam Altman. Sam Altman did the thing that people have
Speaker 1:  to do when they announced anything with Trump. They're like, we can only
Speaker 1:  do this because of you. There's some amount of like, you were already planning
Speaker 1:  on doing this and there's some amount of like, is this real? Like did you
Speaker 1:  just do a foxcon? I got huge foxcon vibes from this. And then on
Speaker 1:  top of all of that
Speaker 1:  is Elon Musk, who is a senior White House advisor in charge of Doge
Speaker 1:  tweeting. They don't have the money. Lauren, can you
Speaker 1:  just like over under how long do you think Elon's gonna last? Is a government
Speaker 1:  advisor criticizing the president's steals?
Speaker 12:  Yeah, I mean it seems like there's gotta be an, an
Speaker 12:  expiration date on this. I mean, it's hard, it's been hard enough
Speaker 12:  that, you know, it's two big egos in a room and now,
Speaker 12:  you know, Musk is really clashing with things that Trump himself is
Speaker 12:  putting out there as these like big accomplishments. And I feel like that's
Speaker 12:  really where we're gonna see a potential for a break.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I mean the, again, when I say get Fox Sun vibes,
Speaker 1:  we have some new listeners. It, it, it has occurred to me several times over
Speaker 1:  these past few days that Trump won was eight years ago. And that we have
Speaker 1:  listeners who were in their twenties now who were teenagers then. So If you
Speaker 1:  don't remember the things that happened in Trump won, lemme just catch you
Speaker 1:  up. They took golden shovels to my hometown in Rac, Wisconsin and announced
Speaker 1:  an LCD factory and Trump ceremony obviously, you know, broke
Speaker 1:  ground with a golden shovel. They, they never built the factory.
Speaker 1:  We'll put some links in the show notes. We did a lot of coverage on this.
Speaker 1:  It was, it was a substantial portion of my life. They built a dome, there's
Speaker 1:  a dome, they built a dome. They, they continue to claim as a da data
Speaker 1:  center and is actually just a party zone.
Speaker 5:  What's the difference really?
Speaker 1:  There's a, there are some servers in a shipping container outside the,
Speaker 1:  the dome anyway, but that it's like real vibes here, right? Like we're just
Speaker 1:  gonna make big announcements about building stuff in America's back and eventually
Speaker 1:  all you get is a dome in Wisconsin and Microsoft's saying it will build a
Speaker 1:  data center there. And that's all that happened. This to me had
Speaker 1:  all that right? OpenAI and Microsoft are like headed towards this breakup.
Speaker 1:  They're announcing this other funding. We're gonna stand in the White House
Speaker 1:  and announce this big deal. And then right next to it you have
Speaker 1:  Doge and Elon being like, no, that's fake. I like,
Speaker 1:  I'm better. Like I hate Sam Alman. Like he's like jealous. Like, I don't
Speaker 1:  know how else to describe it. He's jealous of Sam Altman getting to stand
Speaker 1:  in the White House to make an announcement
Speaker 5:  And they've been like beefing and subtweeting each other ever since. I mean
Speaker 5:  it, it is a remarkably like juvenile thing that's happening here. But
Speaker 5:  I think at the risk of asking a really stupid question, if
Speaker 5:  this is a real thing and, and I think one thing that we have learned
Speaker 5:  is that Sam Altman's ability to raise money is not to
Speaker 5:  be questioned. That man can raise any amount of money for anything at
Speaker 5:  any time. Just seems to be the case. What is the point of
Speaker 5:  standing at a podium in the White House and doing this with Masa Sun and
Speaker 5:  Larry Ellison Like just, just go spend the $500 billion
Speaker 5:  on open AI infrastructure. Like why, why does the Trump White House have
Speaker 5:  anything to do with this at all?
Speaker 12:  I mean I think Ellison makes sense for sure because
Speaker 12:  he's been a Trump ally for a while now and I think, you know, maybe
Speaker 12:  Trump kind of wants to get his buddies in a room and make a deal.
Speaker 12:  So I think he just likes the optics of having all of them up there, having
Speaker 12:  people working together for him in a sense
Speaker 12:  on this project that he is championing.
Speaker 1:  Allison also, by the way, C of Oracle, which is
Speaker 1:  technically operating TikTok illegally right now.
Speaker 5:  Is it? Well it's what's legal Neil to find legal,
Speaker 1:  Right? And at that same Stargate Press conference, Trump was like, Larry,
Speaker 1:  are you gonna buy it? Let's negotiate in front of the media. And so there's
Speaker 1:  just a, there's a weirdness here.
Speaker 1:  We should talk about Doge for maybe one second. Like the
Speaker 1:  executive order creating Doge Renames an existing part
Speaker 1:  of the White House called the United States Digital Service to the United States
Speaker 1:  Doge Service, which means it's a nesting acronym, I want to kill myself.
Speaker 1:  And it basically says what we're gonna put Doge people throughout the
Speaker 1:  government and you have to tell them all your unclassified information. Weird
Speaker 1:  spot for Elon to be in to run that. He kicked out the VA
Speaker 1:  ramaswamy, which is very funny before he even started.
Speaker 1:  If you don't know about The S ds, the digital service, they're basically
Speaker 1:  the product management organization of the government. Like they built
Speaker 1:  healthcare.gov and they ran the VA website. I have no idea what Elon is
Speaker 1:  gonna do to those websites. Like those are very important websites.
Speaker 5:  The S DS has had a lot of very smart people over the years doing interesting
Speaker 5:  work. I suspect it will be different now.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So we'll see. And then, you know, Elon is doing like Nazi sluts and
Speaker 1:  so like how long will this last? Like how long can this last
Speaker 1:  when he is the focal point for all of his stuff and he is attacking the president
Speaker 1:  and he might hurt the VA website, like
Speaker 1:  I'm giving it 90 days. That's my call. Lauren, what do you think?
Speaker 12:  I'm gonna say
Speaker 12:  may I think after the first a hundred days he's out.
Speaker 1:  Okay. But he's, I think, I think he's only got until July 4th, 2026. So it's
Speaker 1:  that's that's his own deadline. It's in the eo.
Speaker 12:  Oh, okay.
Speaker 5:  Okay. But just just to logic this out for a second,
Speaker 5:  I I I feel like the over under on this has to be like five days.
Speaker 5:  Like I I, if there's no recrimination or
Speaker 5:  change from what has happened so far, including a Nazi salute on
Speaker 5:  inauguration day two of them, in fact
Speaker 5:  what's, what's, what problem is there going to be that that undoes this?
Speaker 5:  I think like we have already seen what this looks
Speaker 5:  like. We like this is just what it's going to be and if
Speaker 5:  everyone is comfortable with it now, why would they get uncomfortable with
Speaker 5:  it later?
Speaker 1:  Hang on. I feel like I have to very pedantically note, he
Speaker 1:  did a thing that looked like a Nazi salute. That Nazis believe it was a Nazi
Speaker 1:  salute governments around the world. The German press believes it's Nazi
Speaker 1:  salute. His fans say it's not, the
Speaker 1:  point is to make us argue about the ambiguity. That's the point of the troll.
Speaker 1:  We don't
Speaker 5:  Know what was in Elon Musk's heart, but the thing he did looked more like
Speaker 5:  a Nazi salute than any other thing that exists on Earth. Yeah. Than
Speaker 1:  He supports the Chairman Fire party. Like you can just add it up. But the
Speaker 1:  point is to make everyone yell about the equal sign. You know what I mean?
Speaker 1:  Like, anyway, but that is how he gains attention.
Speaker 1:  But the person that wants the most attention is his nominal boss.
Speaker 1:  So you, you might be right about five days, I'm just saying it might be more
Speaker 1:  like 90 'cause Trump is busy just like lecturing the World Economic
Speaker 1:  Forum.
Speaker 5:  He might just like forget Elon is there for a while and then, and then this
Speaker 5:  will happen.
Speaker 1:  Wait, So I just wanna be clear. I said 90 Lauren said a hundred and you say
Speaker 1:  five. I'm
Speaker 5:  Gonna, I'm I'm gonna go 15. I'm putting the over hundred at 15 days. Like
Speaker 5:  I think if, if we get to Valentine's Day and Elon Musk is still has an
Speaker 5:  office in the West Wing, I will be surprised.
Speaker 12:  Okay. I think he's had remarkable staying power so far. So I
Speaker 12:  I'm just bet that he's gonna continue to surprise us.
Speaker 1:  Alright, that's Elon. That's Doge. We'll see if how that turns into reality.
Speaker 1:  It just, I think for The Verge cast audience, for The Verge audience, you
Speaker 1:  should go listen to the administering the, the administrator
Speaker 1:  that, well outgoing administrator of the digital service on decoder. Like
Speaker 1:  that's a software company. There's a, a tiny little software consultancy
Speaker 1:  in the government that makes all the websites go. And now it's Doge. So
Speaker 1:  I, I think I say this a lot. Like you can't know how something is changing
Speaker 1:  unless you know what it was. It's a go listen. If you're interested, go listen
Speaker 1:  to that episode. 'cause how Doge changes is gonna be, I've seen a lot of
Speaker 1:  USDS people say, actually this is the right place for it to go because they're
Speaker 1:  the software consultancy. And this is like, software helps you find
Speaker 1:  efficiency. I suspect those people are coping like they're,
Speaker 1:  they're processing. But anyway, go listen to that.
Speaker 5:  Wouldn't that also mean that the, the job of Doge would be to decide if the
Speaker 5:  government should use like Microsoft Teams or Slack for its communication
Speaker 5:  systems? Like is that, is that where we're headed?
Speaker 1:  I don't, I've, I've met a few PMs in my life. I I don't think that's how
Speaker 1:  they spend their time. But
Speaker 5:  Wait, Lauren, before we move away from this, can I just ask you one like
Speaker 5:  big broad question that I have been having all week and
Speaker 5:  there's this flurry of executive orders and, and my
Speaker 5:  impression of what this moment looks like in a
Speaker 5:  presidency is some mix of like real
Speaker 5:  policymaking and some like Michael Scott in the office
Speaker 5:  yelling, I declare bankruptcy. Like how,
Speaker 5:  how real should we be thinking about all of this stuff is he's talking about
Speaker 5:  everything from like the, the Paris Climate agreement to AI safety, to
Speaker 5:  all this stuff on electric cars. Like how real are you tracking this stuff
Speaker 5:  in your head right now?
Speaker 12:  Yeah, I think that's definitely the perfect analogy for it. I think it's
Speaker 12:  a mix. I think, you know, there's some things that are going to have real
Speaker 12:  implications or at least we really have to see a big fight
Speaker 12:  play out over it to know where it's gonna end up. And then I think there's
Speaker 12:  other stuff that's either like, all right, well this kind of already existed,
Speaker 12:  like the executive order basically saying the first amendment is a thing.
Speaker 12:  And then other things that, you know, are just obviously
Speaker 12:  not inconsistent with the constitution, like ending
Speaker 12:  birthright citizenship. So I think a lot of it
Speaker 12:  is, you know, just shouting something, just declaring that things
Speaker 12:  exist but, you know, mixed in, there are things that will at least
Speaker 12:  have to be dealt with in the courts in and, you know, in
Speaker 12:  people's lives. So I think it is definitely a mix.
Speaker 5:  Okay.
Speaker 1:  This brings us inevitably to TikTok. I just wanna write That's
Speaker 5:  True. Oh yeah, there was a TikTok EO wasn't there? Yes,
Speaker 1:  There
Speaker 12:  Was
Speaker 1:  It. It's there's too many It, well let's just focus, can
Speaker 5:  AI summarize The S the all the executive orders
Speaker 1:  From, well I think AI wrote a lot of them.
Speaker 1:  I'm kind of not joking.
Speaker 1:  The TikTok one I think synthesizes everything you're saying Lauren, right?
Speaker 1:  Like it's, some of it is just yelling, some of it is just pointing out things
Speaker 1:  that already are true. Some of it is gonna get litigated. Some of it is like,
Speaker 1:  does the president even have this power? I guess we're gonna find out,
Speaker 1:  describe what's going on with with the TikTok EO and, I mean
Speaker 1:  TikTok is running, but like, in a weird way.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. So the TikTok executive order is basically Trump
Speaker 12:  saying that for 75 days, I'm gonna tell my enforcers
Speaker 12:  back off, don't enforce this law. And like actually even the
Speaker 12:  day preceding my presidency when the band took effect, like, don't
Speaker 12:  go after the companies for that day
Speaker 12:  and basically saying to the companies like, don't worry,
Speaker 12:  we got you. We're not gonna prosecute you If you bring TikTok
Speaker 12:  back online. Which sounds great, except that
Speaker 12:  it doesn't really mean anything when you have a federal law on the
Speaker 12:  books that the Supreme Court has upheld that all of these
Speaker 12:  companies risk facing billions of dollars in fines, if they violate,
Speaker 1:  It's like $5,000 per user. You have
Speaker 1:  170 million user. Like it's just billions of dollars. And it's weird because
Speaker 1:  Oracle, If you recall, when TikTok was trying to save itself during
Speaker 1:  the first Trump administration, when he threatened to ban it, they built
Speaker 1:  this thing called Project Texas, where Oracle ran its data
Speaker 1:  centers and it was all walled off from China, or by chance or however they
Speaker 1:  were, project Texas to me, always felt like a kids museum.
Speaker 1:  You know, like you could go there and they'd be like, here's how content
Speaker 1:  moderation works. And like nothing was real. So Oracle runs it, Akamai, who's
Speaker 1:  their CDN, you know, moves the data actually around the internet and delivers
Speaker 1:  content people. And then Apple and Google obviously distribute it in their
Speaker 1:  stores. And by the way, so does Amazon. So does the Samsung store. It's not
Speaker 1:  in the Samsung store, in case you're wondering. So it's really interesting
Speaker 1:  to me that Oracle, which hosts the data project, Texas Akamai, which delivers
Speaker 1:  the data, have decided this is fine, they're gonna take the risk. TikTok
Speaker 1:  is back, and then the app stores have decided it's not worth
Speaker 1:  the risk. Like If you search for TikTok in the app store today, it's not
Speaker 1:  there. I, I have not yet figured out why
Speaker 1:  some people think it's okay. I, I actually think Oracle and Akamai have more
Speaker 1:  liability because it, TikTok is already on the phones,
Speaker 1:  right? So like Apple isn't delivering it to more people, I guess software
Speaker 1:  updates or something. But every time all of those people
Speaker 1:  open the TikTok app, like Oracle's liable for it.
Speaker 12:  Exactly.
Speaker 1:  And so that's where I get to like Larry Ellison standing in the room, right?
Speaker 1:  Like Larry Ellison delivered this win to Donald Trump and that
Speaker 1:  means he's a little bit more secure that he won't be prosecuted.
Speaker 12:  Right. And Larry Ellison appears to be one of the only people
Speaker 12:  in the US to be comfortable enough relying on
Speaker 12:  Trump's promise here in this executive order that doesn't
Speaker 12:  really hold the force of law more than the actual law on the book
Speaker 12:  status to believe it.
Speaker 1:  You went and talked to some lawyers about this. I think I want you to explain
Speaker 1:  their read. My, my read was, well, If you read the
Speaker 1:  executive order at the bottom, it's got the same boilerplate that every executive
Speaker 1:  order has on it, which is this does not create liability for
Speaker 1:  the United States. And you're like, well, If you make a promise that you
Speaker 1:  won't enforce a law that you know, kind of like squint that looks like a
Speaker 1:  contract and at the bottom of the contract you're like, you cannot rely on
Speaker 1:  this contract. Well you shouldn't rely on it.
Speaker 12:  Exactly. I mean, I think it's pretty straightforward from the
Speaker 12:  legal analysis that I've seen where it's just, it's basically
Speaker 12:  just, you know, this does not negate the fact that there is a
Speaker 12:  law that finds all of these service providers for TikTok
Speaker 12:  $5,000 per user for accessing the app. And that can
Speaker 12:  amount to, you know, hundreds of billions of dollars in fines
Speaker 12:  for these companies. And even if you're like one of the richest companies
Speaker 12:  in the world, that's a lot of money. And while it
Speaker 12:  might insulate you in the long run from actually having to
Speaker 12:  pay those fines because you can make a decent
Speaker 12:  due process argument that there's some sort of, you were
Speaker 12:  operating under this kind of promise from the executive branch
Speaker 12:  that you wouldn't be prosecuted for this. I think ultimately
Speaker 12:  it's a big risk to take when you know the penalties are that large.
Speaker 1:  I keep trying to figure out why Apple and Google aren't like, do like
Speaker 1:  distributing this app. And I, I guess, you know, if Oracle doesn't play ball,
Speaker 1:  there is no TikTok if Apple and Google don't play ball well, people still
Speaker 1:  have the app, right? And like, so maybe they're just like, look, this isn't
Speaker 1:  worth it. The people who have it already have it and all, all that's really
Speaker 1:  happening is people aren't gonna download this app for a while.
Speaker 12:  Right. And I imagine what Trump would notice more is like,
Speaker 12:  can people see content on TikTok or not?
Speaker 12:  Versus like, can a marginal few who don't already have it on
Speaker 12:  their phones? I mean, there's 170 million people in the US who already have
Speaker 12:  been using TikTok can like a marginal few, like
Speaker 12:  get it now. And you know, eventually if Apple and Google
Speaker 12:  don't bring it back to their app stores, the app is going to degrade
Speaker 12:  and you know, it won't work as well as it you'd expect it to.
Speaker 12:  But how long will that take? We don't really know. It might be a long enough
Speaker 12:  time that it doesn't really matter in the end. Well,
Speaker 1:  Yeah, yeah. 75 days. Like I, I know when I know when
Speaker 1:  something ends. Right. Two really interesting things about that. One,
Speaker 1:  some people did delete TikTok from their phones. They are very sad 'cause
Speaker 1:  they can't get it back. There's a weird black market for phones with TikTok
Speaker 1:  on them on eBay where they're selling for thousands of dollars. And then
Speaker 1:  we had the very weird experience of
Speaker 1:  our posts saying TikTok is not available in app stores. Like a little quick
Speaker 1:  post ranked in Google. It was the number one search result for
Speaker 1:  TikTok app store. Weird and flawed of comments.
Speaker 1:  Thousands of comments from people who thought, well we were a social network
Speaker 1:  and we posting things like what app is this? Where'd everybody come from?
Speaker 1:  Which is a lot, was a lot like, we were like, is this a bot attack? And then
Speaker 1:  our like head of community is like, it's teens. It's teens who
Speaker 1:  have never seen a website before and we just trying to find TikTok. Yes.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. I have seen that some people have found a workaround for
Speaker 12:  downloading TikTok if they somehow deleted it.
Speaker 1:  What's the, wait, what's the workaround?
Speaker 12:  From what I saw, it has to do with like logging out of your
Speaker 12:  iCloud account and then like logging in like you're in another country and
Speaker 12:  downloading it. So I'm not endorsing this, but that's something that I've
Speaker 12:  seen.
Speaker 1:  There's a, you know, there's like a lot of like controversial science around
Speaker 1:  like cell phone addiction. Like, and you can have a lot of arguments and
Speaker 1:  it's like, well,
Speaker 1:  would you, like, do you see what's happening here?
Speaker 12:  The teens will find a way,
Speaker 1:  The teens, it was just like really, like someone was like, this post is getting
Speaker 1:  thousands of comments. Like we must, it must be a bot attack.
Speaker 1:  It is, it is currently the most commented post in our new commenting system.
Speaker 1:  Wow. More comments than my endorsement of comma.
Speaker 1:  Like, I got a note that was like, your record has been broken. It's teens
Speaker 1:  making friends in the TikTok post. Very good. I hope
Speaker 1:  maybe Trump was right to save it after all. Well, no, it helped us,
Speaker 1:  you know, this is a new Trump too is very transactional. All right. We should
Speaker 1:  keep TikTok shut down so teens can make friends in our comments on
Speaker 1:  quick post. So there's, there's, that's the shape of it,
Speaker 1:  right? We got seven, five days. There's also the politics of, of TikTok
Speaker 1:  where they, you know, they took the app down. They said, we are thankful
Speaker 1:  for President Trump working on a solution. They brought the app up. They
Speaker 1:  said, thanks to President Trump we're back. They thought they were
Speaker 1:  getting 90 days. 'cause in the bill, there's this provision to extend
Speaker 1:  the deadline by 90 days. If there's a sale in the works, there is no
Speaker 1:  sale in the works as far as we know. They didn't even get 90 days. They got
Speaker 1:  75 days. Trump shaved 15 days off their deadline,
Speaker 1:  which is very funny. And now, you know, he, he's given a number of
Speaker 1:  press conferences since, and he talks like a real estate developer.
Speaker 1:  He, he has, you know, shoved all of this into his
Speaker 1:  internal framework. He's an 80 something year old real estate developer.
Speaker 1:  He's got one framework and it's real estate. And he is like, oh, TikTok needs
Speaker 1:  a permit,
Speaker 1:  which is not the case. But he keeps saying, I have to give them a permit
Speaker 1:  to operate. If I don't give them a permit, it's worth nothing. If I give
Speaker 1:  them a permit, it's worth a trillion. They have to do a deal with me.
Speaker 12:  Right. So there's like a, a bunch of things in there. I think
Speaker 12:  first of all, the 75 days is interesting 'cause it kind of just goes
Speaker 12:  to show how like not a thing this
Speaker 12:  executive order is, because in the law it says that the
Speaker 12:  president can give TikTok 90 days if
Speaker 12:  there's like very much a deal happening. If the
Speaker 12:  president is certifying that there's a deal happening and
Speaker 12:  you know, then they can get 90 days. And it was like a little ambiguous,
Speaker 12:  like could that 90 days be granted once the ban takes
Speaker 12:  effect or not. But it seems like it's like ambiguous enough that it
Speaker 12:  might've been available to Trump. Trump didn't do that. He did something
Speaker 12:  totally different, pulled out 75 days and said
Speaker 12:  just like, let's not enforce this for 75 days.
Speaker 12:  And then, you know, we also have that like,
Speaker 12:  it, it just is a completely different way of going about this. So
Speaker 12:  I, it just kind of shows that this is not really something that's like
Speaker 12:  following the law itself. And nothing in the law says like
Speaker 12:  permits. And we don't know that, you know, it's not just like
Speaker 12:  Trump can decide to sell it and then the deal will happen. The main,
Speaker 12:  you know, point of blockage here is China. And we still
Speaker 12:  don't know if China will really ultimately agree to a deal that would
Speaker 12:  put TikTok in compliance with the law.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And there's been a lot of reporting that China is like open to it,
Speaker 5:  thinking about it, but there's like, it's, it's all so squishy that it's
Speaker 5:  hard to make anything out of right now. It, especially when you have
Speaker 5:  President Trump now running around saying that what he actually wants is
Speaker 5:  a joint venture with the United States of America in which it owns half of
Speaker 5:  TikTok, which a, what? And BI can't imagine
Speaker 5:  is a thing that is going to be palatable to the Chinese government.
Speaker 12:  And it also doesn't seem like it would put it in compliance with
Speaker 12:  this law anyway. It just kind of does this like other third thing
Speaker 12:  because under the law, it seems like it most likely ance
Speaker 12:  could not be involved. You know, we still couldn't have like more than
Speaker 12:  20% ownership by a Chinese entity. So I
Speaker 12:  don't know how exactly this works. Is the US government owning a
Speaker 12:  speech platform? Like it's not really clear if Trump himself knows the answer
Speaker 12:  to these questions.
Speaker 1:  We said this a lot in sort of the Elon Twitter takeover
Speaker 1:  era where criticism of the current administration is
Speaker 1:  in no way praise of the previous administration. And I feel like
Speaker 1:  that's just very clear on all sides here. Like
Speaker 1:  the, this is pure Trump chaos, right? Like I invented an executive order
Speaker 1:  at the end of seven, five days. If this thing isn't sold,
Speaker 1:  he doesn't get to pull the 90 day lever because the
Speaker 1:  expiration date has hit, right? You can't delay a
Speaker 1:  deadline 75 days after it's passed by 90 days. Like the
Speaker 1:  law isn't written that way. So we're, you know, by the time you're listening
Speaker 1:  to this, we're down to 73 days, 72 days. Like
Speaker 1:  you gotta sell TikTok. Like that's what you have to do.
Speaker 1:  April 4th
Speaker 5:  Is the day,
Speaker 1:  By the way. Right? So by April 4th, TikTok has to be sold. That's a huge
Speaker 1:  transaction that two world superpowers have to agree upon
Speaker 1:  in some way that Trump has to, right? That they're gonna give
Speaker 1:  him a big novelty permit to hand over. Like he runs City Hall. Like, I don't
Speaker 1:  know what he is gonna do inside of that. Like, like
Speaker 1:  TikTok itself has to change ownership. It does feel like
Speaker 1:  TikTok misplayed this completely. And this is what I mean about like, it's
Speaker 1:  not praise for any other administration. Like TikTok thought they could roll
Speaker 1:  the Biden administration, which totally blew this. Like the Biden administration
Speaker 1:  should have been pressuring TikTok to sell every single day. Yeah. And they
Speaker 1:  just didn't, they did not communicate well. The Biden administration, the
Speaker 1:  failure of Biden administration is they fundamentally like did not communicate
Speaker 1:  very well, but they didn't. So then
Speaker 1:  TikTok thought it could run and Biden signed it on the day, which set off
Speaker 1:  the clock, which landed it on the day that it did, which is effectively in
Speaker 1:  between administrations. So he,
Speaker 1:  I, I'm sure they could count, but he signed it on day knowing
Speaker 1:  what day the ban would hit. And he landed it right in the middle creating
Speaker 1:  this weird vacuum where he was like, I'm handing enforcement over to the
Speaker 1:  Trump administration. And Trump was handed this ability to just say like,
Speaker 1:  I'll figure it out. Sure. And then TikTok had no plan
Speaker 1:  B, they have no deal in the works. And the fact that they have no plan
Speaker 1:  BI think is the, like the most essential failure here
Speaker 1:  because you might think Trump is gonna save it. And certainly he saved it
Speaker 1:  for 75 more days, sort of because it's the, the app stores. But it's
Speaker 1:  so obvious that he wants to make this deal, right? Right.
Speaker 1:  That he wants to be like, there's a transaction and now the, the US government
Speaker 1:  owns a 50% or whatever we can, we haven't even talked about how bananas that
Speaker 1:  is, but like there will be a sale.
Speaker 1:  And so TikTok is maybe not gonna sell to who it wants to on its terms.
Speaker 1:  They're gonna sell to who Trump wants on Trump's terms. And I don't know
Speaker 1:  that the Chinese government is super down with that idea.
Speaker 12:  I think there's an arc, there's a way to see this where by dance
Speaker 12:  didn't misplay it, they played it the only way they were going to
Speaker 12:  play it, which is to ride out the legal process. And
Speaker 12:  you know, if it doesn't work, China's not gonna let them
Speaker 12:  sell in a way that complies with this law. And you know, the Chinese
Speaker 12:  government might be okay with that because they might think that this makes
Speaker 12:  the US government look bad in the eyes of other governments around the world.
Speaker 12:  So I think it's possible that that's one, that's still one
Speaker 12:  way it goes. And I think there's a lot of, I've been surprised just how
Speaker 12:  quickly people on TikTok have been cheering that it's back and like
Speaker 12:  kind of taking it for granted all over again. But I think it's a very real
Speaker 12:  possibility that this goes away again.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. It's, and it'll be even more fascinating as we get towards
Speaker 5:  that, that deadline in April because there is
Speaker 5:  now such a sense of, this was all a nonsense
Speaker 5:  misdirect, this isn't real. Tiktoks never gonna actually go away. Like the,
Speaker 5:  the we're so back vibes on TikTok are just everywhere.
Speaker 5:  And I think the, if it does happen and
Speaker 5:  if it does go away in some meaningful way in April, it's gonna weirdly,
Speaker 5:  I think hit even harder the second time because
Speaker 5:  it doesn't seem like people are leaving, all these other apps are desperately
Speaker 5:  trying to get people to come. Like X launched a videos
Speaker 5:  thing, blue Sky launched a videos thing, Instagram is out here like
Speaker 5:  redesigning the app and trying to pay people to come make reels like
Speaker 5:  all these other companies sense a moment. And as at least as far as I can
Speaker 5:  tell, that moment did not materialize except for the one day everybody went
Speaker 5:  and made jokes on Red Note.
Speaker 5:  Which means I think that if it comes crashing down, it will crash even harder
Speaker 5:  the second time.
Speaker 12:  Oh, totally. I think people are not prepared for the
Speaker 12:  possibility that it could go away again. And just like, there were such
Speaker 12:  short memories the first time because, and you know, I'm not blaming anyone
Speaker 12:  for feeling this way. 'cause it, we've heard over and over, oh, tiktoks
Speaker 12:  gonna be banned, tiktoks gonna be banned, and then it doesn't happen. But
Speaker 12:  I think it's always been a much more real threat than
Speaker 12:  anyone really processed. It just has been a, you know, a
Speaker 12:  far amount of time off. And I am really curious what Trump
Speaker 12:  is gonna do when those 75 days expire and more likely than
Speaker 12:  not, if there is any kind of deal, it's probably not gonna be
Speaker 12:  completed. And then does he extend it again?
Speaker 12:  Well,
Speaker 1:  He can't. He can't. That's what I mean, like Right.
Speaker 12:  He
Speaker 1:  He can't Right. But like he can write another executive order being
Speaker 1:  like, I hereby give you another 75 days. But triggering
Speaker 1:  the 90 day deal clause is, I I think that's an immediate
Speaker 1:  like state attorney general lawsuit. Like Tom Cotton who is a
Speaker 1:  Republican, like the most Republican.
Speaker 1:  He's like, I will, I will bring down ruinous liability in these companies.
Speaker 1:  Like, I want this app gone. I want China outta my country. Right. And you
Speaker 1:  can agree or disagree with con like strange bedfellows in the second Trump
Speaker 1:  administration. Right.
Speaker 5:  But he, and in the TikTok ban, like it's, it's useful to remember that this
Speaker 5:  is about as bipartisan a thing as we have had in
Speaker 5:  this government for a very long time. Like part of me wants to respond to
Speaker 5:  all of what you're saying, Eli, with you're assuming like a rational government
Speaker 5:  operating in a rational way and there's no evidence that that's what the
Speaker 5:  second Trump administration is going to be. But
Speaker 5:  every Republican wanted to ban TikTok and every Democrat wanted to.
Speaker 5:  So it's, it's really like, it, it's not, it's not a
Speaker 5:  sort of swinging back in the new administration. Like
Speaker 5:  everybody in Congress voted for this already.
Speaker 1:  Wait, let me just, let me just offer you, this is a Lauren Finer quick post.
Speaker 1:  I'm just gonna read it to you. The repeal TikTok Ban Act was introduced
Speaker 1:  by Senator Rand Paul and Representative Rohan
Speaker 5:  Speaking of strange bedfellows
Speaker 1:  That it's weird. That is a weird combo platter of people.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. Yeah. And I think another kind of weird combination
Speaker 12:  that's coming up on the other side of things is like, people who actually
Speaker 12:  supported TikTok in their case, who wrote
Speaker 12:  amicus briefs are now saying like, yeah, we don't like this.
Speaker 12:  But also it's like generally bad to just like, ignore
Speaker 12:  a law and just like not follow the process.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But seem like if you're in Congress, you should be pro laws general.
Speaker 5:  Like that's like one of their main things is doing laws. No,
Speaker 1:  But like, it's, it's the EFF that wrote that one. It's like one of the major
Speaker 1:  digital civil liberties groups is like, this law is bad. The
Speaker 1:  Supreme Court is bad, all this is bad. But then having a
Speaker 1:  law that the president can be like, that law doesn't exist equally bad.
Speaker 12:  Right. And I think people are like banking a lot on Congress just
Speaker 12:  like realizing like, this is such a mess. But at the same time,
Speaker 12:  like hundreds of lawmakers voted for this in the first place.
Speaker 12:  And you know, these are people who have egos. They don't wanna just like
Speaker 12:  undo their own work. So I think like
Speaker 12:  relying on something like that happening even after all this is like a,
Speaker 12:  a really big leap of faith.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I just wanna say this literally for the tape.
Speaker 1:  The United States government owning a social network is one of the stupidest
Speaker 1:  first amendment, first year law school hypotheticals I
Speaker 1:  can possibly come up with. It will, it will not be possible to
Speaker 1:  run a social network if the government owns it in this country. Especially
Speaker 1:  with Trump doing his like big EO that's like, I've circled the
Speaker 1:  First Amendment,
Speaker 1:  you know, what's legal under the First Amendment spam?
Speaker 1:  Just straightforwardly spam is legal under the First Amendment. So the
Speaker 1:  government can't filter spam on the TikTok it owns,
Speaker 1:  pretty much brings an end to TikTok. I'm gonna go
Speaker 13:  Ham on this social network.
Speaker 1:  I'm
Speaker 13:  Just, you, you have, you don't even know what I'm capable of
Speaker 1:  On the government, on social, there's a whole bunch of other stuff. TikTok
Speaker 1:  the, by the way, the most moderated social network, right? The social network
Speaker 1:  that gave the world the word segs because people are afraid
Speaker 1:  to say sex. That's TikTok.
Speaker 1:  You know, what is, and because there's so many kids on it, do you know what
Speaker 1:  is legal on the First Amendment? Just pornography, all kinds.
Speaker 1:  It's available. The United States government cannot, they would have to come
Speaker 1:  up with some straightforward, like digital
Speaker 1:  version of a time place and manner restriction. This is all like very technical
Speaker 1:  First Amendment lawyering that doesn't exist if the government wants to own
Speaker 1:  a social network and filter anything, and it probably can't.
Speaker 1:  So I'm just like that. I'll just set that aside. We, it
Speaker 1:  hasn't happened yet. I don't know if it's gonna happen. But someone should
Speaker 1:  explain to Donald Trump that the, the government taking interest in TikTok
Speaker 1:  in this way would actually result in the destruction of TikTok.
Speaker 12:  I think that actually kind of goes to the idea that I think
Speaker 12:  like TikTok users are just expecting now that
Speaker 12:  tiktoks back, it's gonna stick around, it's gonna be kind of more or less
Speaker 12:  like it's always been. And like under a lot of these
Speaker 12:  scenarios it would look very different. Like if the US government
Speaker 12:  owns it and can't moderate content, if like Elon Musk owns it. And
Speaker 12:  I've seen people commenting If, you know, if Musk buys this, I'm leaving
Speaker 12:  TikTok, which who knows if people actually would, but you know, it's not
Speaker 12:  gonna be most likely the same TikTok that
Speaker 12:  you're using today.
Speaker 1:  Just to put this in perspective for folks
Speaker 1:  in what, 2017 after Trump, Trump won became president, he
Speaker 1:  blocked people from his Twitter account and that was a First Amendment lawsuit
Speaker 1:  that went for Oh right. Five years. Like just that, like can
Speaker 1:  the president block people was a Supreme Court level
Speaker 1:  First Amendment challenge and eventually vacated. 'cause he, he lost, right?
Speaker 1:  Like he, he lost the election. He wasn't president anymore and he gave up.
Speaker 1:  But like that is the amount of lawyer just on the block button
Speaker 1:  alone. That was the amount of lawyering that occurred about the First amendment
Speaker 1:  in social networks. Can the president block someone from his official account?
Speaker 1:  The government owns a social network as like a nuclear
Speaker 1:  Armageddon of First Amendment issues. It's, it's just such a
Speaker 1:  deeply bad idea. All right.
Speaker 5:  You've talked me into it. Let's do it. I'm ready. Joint venture, 50% China,
Speaker 5:  50% us. Let's go. Alright,
Speaker 1:  I'm in. Alright. That's enough to, we'll see what happens, right?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. We got April. Yeah, a April. April is upon us already.
Speaker 1:  But it just, it all, everything about the Trump administration, like it comes
Speaker 1:  together in the TikTok. Like why is Larry Sen in, in the White House talking
Speaker 1:  about a data center project? 'cause he's running TikTok and
Speaker 1:  like he, the TikTok CEO is running around the inauguration being like,
Speaker 1:  don't ban me please. It's a lot. There's
Speaker 1:  other stuff. It's, it's a lot. We're gonna end up covering it.
Speaker 1:  We're gonna find ways to cover it here on The Vergecast and on the site.
Speaker 1:  In, in ways that split up the beginning of any presidential
Speaker 1:  administration, as David was saying, is a flurry of activity.
Speaker 1:  Trump administrations are typically very chaotic activity the whole time,
Speaker 1:  as we know from the first one. Poor Lauren, I want to hear from everybody
Speaker 1:  like how you want us to handle it. Like, again, in Trump one, we spent a
Speaker 1:  lot of time talking about Foxcon because Foxcon was just such a big symbol
Speaker 1:  of a lot of things all at once. This time
Speaker 1:  there's a bunch of climate science impacts. There's a bunch of EV impacts.
Speaker 1:  Brendan Carr is in charge of the FCC. You'll be hearing this man's name a
Speaker 1:  lot on this show. He wants to censor the internet. He
Speaker 1:  just straightforwardly does.
Speaker 1:  There's, as Lauren was saying, the birthright citizenship question, which
Speaker 1:  a lot of our listeners and readers care about. 'cause they are H one B visa
Speaker 1:  holders in the United States of America work tech companies. And whether
Speaker 1:  or not they're children, our citizens is a pretty meaningful question that
Speaker 1:  I I think we we're gonna end up talking about. And then there's tariffs.
Speaker 1:  Trump announced what, 10% tariffs on China, Lauren? Yeah. Or he at least
Speaker 1:  floated it. Sure. So everything is made in China.
Speaker 1:  Like how will Apple deal with this? What trade will Apple make
Speaker 1:  to reduce tariffs on the iPhone? Tim Cook managed it the last time.
Speaker 1:  We're gonna end up having to talk about it because at the same time, I think
Speaker 1:  it was today, Trump gave a speech where he was like, these
Speaker 1:  cases they're losing the eu. That's a i'm that's a tax on our great American
Speaker 1:  companies. That's a lot. That's just, that's a lot of moving pieces
Speaker 1:  that all like literally he's talking about Apple.
Speaker 1:  So I wanna hear from all of you again. I, I think
Speaker 1:  If you want to call us and send us a note about how you want us discover
Speaker 1:  Trump, I'd like you to begin that note with a formal apology to Lauren.
Speaker 1:  I think I might might be nice to just send her all those, but I, we have
Speaker 1:  to strike a balance here. There's a lot. It's gonna be really noisy and
Speaker 1:  you know, our goal is to always do good rigorous journalism and also to make
Speaker 1:  sure like we're pointed at places that matter, not just all of the noise.
Speaker 1:  Right. Because If you do all the noise, you're just gonna burn out. But that
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I rem like it was eight years ago. It's a long time ago, but it wasn't
Speaker 1:  so long ago and I wanna make sure we get it right. So let us know.
Speaker 1:  We're obviously gonna keep covering the TikTok band, but there's just a whole
Speaker 1:  bunch of other stuff happening. So let us know what you think is important.
Speaker 5:  Neil, do you still think it's gonna be Walmart?
Speaker 1:  Oh, the Vice TikTok? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's got like 71 days to pull it off.
Speaker 1:  There's the Project Liberty with Frank McCourt, which I think is really interesting.
Speaker 5:  And Mr. Beast now apparently.
Speaker 1:  Oh, is Mr. Beast in that one? Apparently
Speaker 5:  He's part of it.
Speaker 1:  Is he part of that one? That one's interesting just because I think on a
Speaker 1:  technical level they're interested in like Federating TikTok.
Speaker 1:  I have no idea what that means. Right. But he's like, we are gonna rebuild
Speaker 1:  the tech stock and give you your own algorithms and each, it's like federation
Speaker 1:  noises.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I'm reading for that one. Like that's as, as much as I can
Speaker 1:  pick anything that that seems that one has Mr. Wonderful. It's just like,
Speaker 1:  there's just characters just like opening doors and being like, I'll buy
Speaker 1:  TikTok. Like I think Amazon's in the mix. I think Jeff Bezos is
Speaker 1:  sitting on that stage.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, IIII if I were Walmart, I would be
Speaker 1:  They were Lauren weren't they in the mix the first time? It was like Microsoft,
Speaker 1:  Oracle and Walmart were like a consortium, right?
Speaker 12:  They were, yeah. Yeah. I think the Mr. Beast one might be separate
Speaker 12:  from Project Liberty. So just a bunch of, bunch of different
Speaker 5:  Characters. No, they, they at least were talking.
Speaker 12:  Are they the same? Okay.
Speaker 5:  I don't know if they're like technically in it, but they, they, they, they
Speaker 5:  had a confab.
Speaker 12:  Okay. As, as,
Speaker 5:  As least you know, maybe there was like lunch lease stock involved
Speaker 5:  in the, I don't know. I don't know all the details, but I'll do it. Mrs.
Speaker 5:  Beast and Wonderful are both part of this somehow.
Speaker 1:  None of it's good. None of it's good.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I
Speaker 5:  I think they don't sell and I think it actually goes dark in April in, in
Speaker 5:  a way. I agree. That's, that's my current stake in the ground.
Speaker 12:  I agree. I think there's a possibility that some like crazy
Speaker 12:  deal comes out of nowhere after it goes dark eventually.
Speaker 12:  But I do think I, if I had to predict now it does go dark after
Speaker 12:  the 75 days.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I just, I I wanna believe you. I also know that
Speaker 1:  Donald Trump wants nothing more in his life than to hand a novelty permit
Speaker 1:  to someone like a, like a big red ribbon.
Speaker 5:  There will be big scissors for sure.
Speaker 1:  You know what I'm saying? Yeah. So I, I'm betting on novelty permit. I don't
Speaker 1:  know who the buyer will be or whether that will actually be effective under
Speaker 1:  the law. The novelty permit is happening. Alright, we gotta take a break.
Speaker 1:  Lauren, thank you so much for joining us again. We're very sorry. We'll have
Speaker 1:  you back very soon.
Speaker 12:  Thank you so much.
Speaker 16:  All
Speaker 1:  Right, we're back. We're already over. It's, it's, we're
Speaker 1:  again, we, we gotta figure this out.
Speaker 5:  I don't think every week is going to be like this, but I think we
Speaker 5:  also kind of spent four years saying that the last time Trump was
Speaker 5:  in the White House. So I don't know. I'm
Speaker 5:  tired
Speaker 1:  The last time this happened, and again, I I recognize this was a long time
Speaker 1:  ago. We got to the point on the show where I was getting angry
Speaker 1:  anonymous letters from Foxconn employees telling me to leave the company
Speaker 1:  alone. And then our, our listeners were turning those letters into songs.
Speaker 1:  So I just wanna set know
Speaker 5:  We we have a long road to go. That's what you're saying.
Speaker 1:  It's like no one's broken out a guitar yet. You know, like we're, it's a
Speaker 1:  long way. All right. Lightning round unsponsored.
Speaker 1:  You know, we're starting here off slow.
Speaker 1:  It's
Speaker 5:  Q1,
Speaker 1:  It's, it's q1, it's way goes. Everyone blew their extra
Speaker 1:  Q4 budgets sponsoring lightning round in 2024.
Speaker 1:  And and here we are in 25 where it's gonna happen again though. We got some
Speaker 1:  ideas. All right. Netflix is raising prices again. I said it was a
Speaker 1:  lightning round, but I think David is best to talk for one full hour. I just,
Speaker 5:  It's, this is the most
Speaker 5:  like mafia thing that has happened this week. And that's a pretty high bar.
Speaker 1:  Like, so the,
Speaker 5:  The thing that happened in the last
Speaker 5:  month, really, and I think, I think this is even more true than I realized,
Speaker 5:  I I spent some time with some Netflix folks talking about how they're thinking
Speaker 5:  about live ahead of the, the football game kind of between the
Speaker 5:  Paul Tyson fight and the Christmas Day football games. I spent some time
Speaker 5:  with the NFL folks or, but the Netflix folks wrote a story about it and came
Speaker 5:  away from it being like, okay, they're, they're really committed to this
Speaker 5:  like always on live programming. What I didn't realize is Netflix is
Speaker 5:  pretty sure it has already won television.
Speaker 5:  They, they have proven now that this sports thing can work and drives
Speaker 5:  real audience. They've proven that they can manufacture huge
Speaker 5:  events out of nowhere, essentially. Like they had a YouTuber fight an old
Speaker 5:  man and 65 million people watched like just on his face.
Speaker 5:  That is nuts. And that's not a thing you can do infinitely,
Speaker 5:  but it is a thing that Netflix continues to prove it can do whenever it wants.
Speaker 5:  And so now if you're Netflix you say, okay, we have a bunch of big hit shows
Speaker 5:  that people like 2024 was kind of a down year
Speaker 1:  For those shows. And I, stranger
Speaker 5:  Things is huge. Wednesday is huge and coming back, there's a
Speaker 5:  third one that I can't remember the name of.
Speaker 1:  Sure. There you go. Keep going. I think
Speaker 5:  Ryan Reynolds is probably doing stuff.
Speaker 1:  None of those count, those are all, those are all so wait list as
Speaker 1:  to not exist.
Speaker 5:  I think Stranger Things is actually the only one I would, I would put like
Speaker 5:  in the it in on the list of like biggest things on television.
Speaker 5:  I think Stranger Things belongs there. Sure. But what Netflix actually has
Speaker 5:  is just an infinite library of c plus stuff
Speaker 5:  that people will watch, which actually turns out to be very important because
Speaker 5:  that's most of what people watch. Yes. Like I will watch as
Speaker 5:  many seasons of the ultimatum as you wanna watch, as you wanna make Netflix.
Speaker 5:  Like sure I'm into it. But, so anyway, so Netflix is now in this
Speaker 5:  position where like it is making money in a time where it's very hard for
Speaker 5:  entertainment companies to make money. It is more powerful than ever. It's
Speaker 5:  driving more audience than ever. It is just winning. And so what
Speaker 5:  they used to do is like make these grand cases for why they had to,
Speaker 5:  you know, raise the prices because they wanted to reinvest in amazing tech
Speaker 5:  and now they're just like, yeah, we're raising the prices. It went up a dollar,
Speaker 5:  whatcha gonna do about
Speaker 1:  It. I have two things to say about this. One, it occurs to me that you have
Speaker 1:  a garbage TV and you watch garbage tv. Correct. And I haven't,
Speaker 1:  those things, haven't those puzzle pieces never been before.
Speaker 5:  We can't all have Bravia Core
Speaker 1:  Patel. Right? That's what I'm saying. Yeah. I'm like, I'm gonna watch one
Speaker 1:  movie a week at 75 glorious megabits of streaming. Right.
Speaker 1:  And fun. I'm, I'm, I'm worried about you, but it finally clicked
Speaker 5:  Into me. I, me, I turn off steel or Node islands to watch to make this podcast
Speaker 5:  and that's it.
Speaker 1:  It's just generally worried about you.
Speaker 1:  The other thing is, I think Casey posted this on
Speaker 1:  Blue Sky this week. He's like, Netflix had better content when it costs 7 99.
Speaker 1:  Like, and that I think it's straightforwardly true. When they were playing
Speaker 1:  the big prestige TV game, they were
Speaker 1:  making better stuff when they're like, we're HBO, like, and now
Speaker 1:  the quality has just dropped.
Speaker 5:  Sure. But you know, what happened in the interim is Netflix went from losing
Speaker 5:  billions of dollars to making billions of dollars. Which it turns out If
Speaker 5:  you Netflix is a pretty good trade, we made our content
Speaker 5:  worse and our money bigger is is the thing they are happy with.
Speaker 5:  But the other thing is there's this big macro trend
Speaker 5:  away from premium high res
Speaker 5:  streaming to ads. And, and that that is the push here.
Speaker 5:  And what Netflix is doing is a thing that I have been saying for a while
Speaker 5:  that it was doing it is just going to price you out.
Speaker 5:  Like it it is, it went from, so the ad supported tier, which is now
Speaker 5:  the base tier of Netflix went from 6 99 a month to 7 99 a month. A dollar
Speaker 5:  a month is a lot, but whatever the standard
Speaker 5:  ad free tier, which is standard Netflix, which used to be 7 99 a month,
Speaker 5:  went from 1549 to 1799 a month. That's a $2 and
Speaker 5:  50 cent increase. That's a big number. Yeah. And then the premium tier,
Speaker 5:  which I think is how you get 4K, I don't know, my TV doesn't do any of that
Speaker 5:  stuff, So I don't even know. It's horrible. Went from 2299 to
Speaker 5:  24 9 a month. So to have the best possible Netflix experience, just
Speaker 5:  Netflix is $25 a month. Netflix
Speaker 5:  does not want you to pay that. Like, I, I cannot be clear about this. Netflix
Speaker 5:  is trying to price you out of every tier except the ads
Speaker 5:  ones. And it is going to keep raising those prices as fast as it can
Speaker 5:  until it does. So, because it makes more money when you do ads and the
Speaker 5:  more people go to ads, the bigger a scale advertising business Netflix can
Speaker 5:  build, which is what it needs to go after, who it really wants to be, which
Speaker 5:  is YouTube. That's where the, those two companies are
Speaker 5:  on like a collision course with each other. And Netflix needs to get bigger
Speaker 5:  in order to like really try to play YouTube's
Speaker 1:  Game. Yeah. And YouTube's growth is on television, which they've said over
Speaker 1:  and over again to you, to me, to anybody who will listen. Right. We're growing
Speaker 1:  faster on smart TVs
Speaker 5:  Anywhere else.
Speaker 1:  This actually hilariously Netflix raised prices
Speaker 1:  by $2. YouTube announced this week a price decreased by
Speaker 1:  $2 ish, but only, but only
Speaker 1:  If you also buy Google one, which you have to pay more money for. And it's
Speaker 1:  like, this is the one of the saddest announcements of all time. And the way
Speaker 1:  that I know it's one of the saddest is in the press release, they didn't
Speaker 1:  say how much the bundle would be cheaper. And we had to go ask them
Speaker 1:  and they were like, it's $2. And we're like, all right, it's $2.
Speaker 5:  Cool, I'll take two bucks. Like sure.
Speaker 1:  They don't ask so much of other features. You get higher quality audio streaming,
Speaker 1:  they're gonna let you do picture and picture. They basically, you can run
Speaker 1:  like their two of their beta features at once. Now, you know, wait,
Speaker 5:  Can I just say my favorite thing about this is one of the experimental features
Speaker 5:  that they have is you can automatically download recommended
Speaker 5:  YouTube shorts to watch offline, which is like,
Speaker 5:  if I were to make you a list of features that YouTube users do not
Speaker 5:  want download shorts to my phone without
Speaker 1:  Asking me just like fill up my storage YouTube shorts.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Everybody wants a thousand YouTube shorts just taking up space on their
Speaker 5:  phone. That's definitely what YouTube users are asking for.
Speaker 1:  I guess if I could tell one of those platforms, like my subway
Speaker 1:  ride from Grand Central to the office is about 22 minutes. Like
Speaker 1:  just make sure I have 22 minutes of garbage to watch. You know,
Speaker 1:  like I could see it
Speaker 5:  If there was a button called download garbage, I would take that
Speaker 5:  like I have,
Speaker 1:  But no, it would've to be like a dial. Like I, I need about
Speaker 1:  25 minutes of garbage. How
Speaker 5:  Much time do you have to kill? You just spin the tile
Speaker 1:  And you like, just, just make sure it's here. All right. Like I don't, it
Speaker 1:  should actually, it should be like a system wide setting that all of the
Speaker 1:  social garbage apps can feed into. So you're like, you know,
Speaker 1:  I'm gonna bounce between like Instagram and TikTok and YouTube, like
Speaker 1:  just between the three of you. I'm giving you about 25 minutes of garbage
Speaker 1:  storage. I figure it out.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. You know what's great is in a fedi verse world that can happen. You
Speaker 5:  could film that app on activity, put
Speaker 1:  20, 25 minutes of garbage finally
Speaker 1:  an app idea. That's really sticky.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, no, I agree with you. The, they're, they're on a collision course.
Speaker 1:  I just, I think YouTube has better economics because they don't pay
Speaker 1:  anyone. Like I understand some people make money from YouTube Premium, but
Speaker 1:  again, the math on YouTube is just so staggeringly good. Like
Speaker 1:  they make much, so much more money than they pay out that net. Netflix
Speaker 1:  just has a pro, like Netflix has headed to a place where
Speaker 1:  it makes no content and everyone in America watches like
Speaker 1:  TV shows made in Korea and Australia because those markets have better
Speaker 1:  economics for content. Yep. And reselling it to America is cheaper.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean I think Netflix in a really interesting way
Speaker 5:  is going to like, eat the business of Hollywood
Speaker 5:  and then discover how actually small that business is in the scheme of
Speaker 5:  things. Like, like If you add up all of the movie studios and all
Speaker 5:  of the TV studios and all of the like interesting distributors, you're
Speaker 5:  not at Google sized, you're not, you're probably not even at
Speaker 5:  YouTube size as it comes to the business. So like Netflix I
Speaker 5:  think is desperately trying to figure out how to do Hollywood
Speaker 5:  at tech money and scale and
Speaker 5:  it's, it's gonna, it's gonna get to the end of that quickly and it's going
Speaker 5:  to be very expensive for us as the viewers. But I think the question
Speaker 5:  of whether Netflix can get beyond that kind of ceiling of Hollywood
Speaker 5:  remains to be seen. Right.
Speaker 1:  And then Google has, you know, a million kids every
Speaker 1:  day being like, I'm gonna be a YouTuber.
Speaker 5:  Right. YouTube is the, that's the strange thing about it is it is, it is
Speaker 5:  a completely different game that is also competing increasingly on the
Speaker 5:  same screen as Netflix, which I think is a, is a
Speaker 5:  scary thing if you're Netflix. Right.
Speaker 1:  Again, IIII say this but, but it's
Speaker 5:  A lot scarier if you're anybody other than Netflix.
Speaker 1:  Right. By the way, CNN today after
Speaker 1:  launching a streaming service and then killing it immediately four years
Speaker 1:  ago announced a streaming service.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. By the way, we're way outta practice on disclosures. This is where
Speaker 5:  we have to tell the people that Comcast is a minority
Speaker 5:  investor through,
Speaker 1:  We haven't talked universal about Peacock exists. It sucks you
Speaker 5:  Eped a Netflix show That actually, actually came up in my recommendations
Speaker 5:  not that long ago. That was pretty exciting.
Speaker 1:  Did it have my face on? It was like, hey this
Speaker 5:  No, it was like the animated poster.
Speaker 1:  Oh sure. Yeah. No, I, it's called The Future of You should Go watch it. It
Speaker 1:  was very good. We, Netflix doesn't pay residuals, So I, I'm not biased
Speaker 1:  by telling you go watch it. I didn't get paid the first time
Speaker 1:  straightforwardly. It was just like a fun side project we did.
Speaker 1:  Sure. That's how that was supposed to work. We only made one season disclosure.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I think that's it. Oh, we Comcast owns it. Oh. And we talked about
Speaker 1:  OpenAI some somewhere. Our, our work is RSS
Speaker 1:  fed into some chat CPT database. Do you ever
Speaker 5:  Use the search thing?
Speaker 1:  No. This is why I always forget to do the disclosure.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  It just doesn't matter in that way. That
Speaker 5:  Seems to have kind of come and gone in everybody's mind pretty fast. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Is it copyright infringement? Who knows? But there, there's a deal in the
Speaker 1:  background. Great. We don't pay any attention to it. Yeah. Okay. Two more
Speaker 1:  lightning round things there, like the same thing but also
Speaker 1:  different.
Speaker 1:  The entire tech industry is figuring out how to make light bulbs. Watch
Speaker 1:  you,
Speaker 1:  I dunno, I dunno what else to
Speaker 5:  Optimistic to say about this then? I was hoping for, okay.
Speaker 1:  Okay, so Jen has the scoop on Sens five Gen
Speaker 1:  two A has a scoop on fy, which is tech that can turn
Speaker 1:  ZigBee radios into motion sensors. So light switches,
Speaker 1:  plugs, whatever,
Speaker 1:  notably Philips HU bulbs are ZigBee devices. So If you have a lot of Phillips
Speaker 1:  HU bulbs in your life,
Speaker 1:  the FY people are saying like, this is a firmware update away. Like there
Speaker 1:  are, they're ready to go put in the firmware update and something the ZigBee
Speaker 1:  radios can do motion sensing, which you know, solves a lot of problems like
Speaker 1:  smart home problems. Like you walk into a room, the lights know you're there,
Speaker 1:  they turn on. Right. This is very cool also, you're like bulb are
Speaker 1:  watching you.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I feel like this is a
Speaker 5:  yet another hard to remember name on top of all of the other smart home standards.
Speaker 5:  So that's exciting. But I would, I would argue if this
Speaker 5:  works, it's on balance a good thing, right? Because like, like you're saying
Speaker 5:  this, this sort of ambient awareness of
Speaker 5:  you in your home has always been a requirement of making the smart homework.
Speaker 5:  Like if, if my home is very smart but has no idea that I
Speaker 5:  exist Yeah. It, it can't actually do that much. So like we've signed
Speaker 5:  up for this already and it's weird because it's your light
Speaker 5:  bulbs, but if it's not your light bulbs, we everybody would have to eventually
Speaker 5:  put some other sensor in their living room. So like it might as well be the
Speaker 5:  light bulbs.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And I, I call this that all the time. The way you know, the way my
Speaker 1:  hack together Smart Home works is like the motion sensor in
Speaker 1:  my Eco B thermostat is wired into an automation that turns
Speaker 1:  on lights in the morning when it senses that my family is awake. That's
Speaker 1:  too much. Like that's No, no. Normal human should
Speaker 1:  figure out how to do that. But it works for us. Having the
Speaker 1:  bulbs themselves do it is great. I will say to your point about the smart
Speaker 1:  home being very complicated, I'm just gonna read you this full sentence from
Speaker 1:  Jen's piece. There's been speculation that Hugh is working on a
Speaker 1:  ZigBee sensing technology since its sister company. Whiz
Speaker 1:  w debuted a similar attack called Space Sense in 2022,
Speaker 1:  which uses WNS over wifi.
Speaker 1:  Did you know Wiz ran Space Sense?
Speaker 5:  The only words in that sentence I understand are like the prepositions.
Speaker 1:  It's very good. It's, it's, it's all, it's all very good. Okay. So that,
Speaker 1:  that's right. So Hugh Bulbs might be doing wins over
Speaker 1:  ZigBee.
Speaker 5:  I mean that, I've been waiting for that for years. And
Speaker 1:  Then at the same time it was
Speaker 1:  Samsung did have its event and so they had a bunch of sort of other things.
Speaker 1:  They're bringing ambient sensing to smart things. Oh, okay. So
Speaker 1:  Samsung TVs, speakers, fridges, air conditioners
Speaker 1:  will become motion sensors for smart things. If you run a smart thing, smart
Speaker 1:  house, unclear if they're using the Wiz supported
Speaker 1:  technology space sets or this new FY
Speaker 1:  thing that is running on, like this idea has been around for a long time.
Speaker 1:  I've, I feel like I covered it in, in gadget years ago where
Speaker 1:  If you have wireless radios, they can detect disturbances
Speaker 1:  and, and Sure. The radio waves that they're sensing. So this
Speaker 1:  idea has been around for a while. So I think we're just getting to a place
Speaker 1:  where you can do it at scale. And so there's different ways of doing it.
Speaker 1:  So Samsung is doing it in a different way for smart things and because they
Speaker 1:  have TV speakers, fridges, all this other stuff, it will just be in your
Speaker 1:  house. Now. I think it is weirder if your TV is the motion
Speaker 1:  sensor for a lot of reasons, but
Speaker 1:  I will point out Samsung TV's, the Frame TV
Speaker 1:  famously a motion sensing product because it lights up and does the frame
Speaker 1:  thing when you walk into the room. So they, you can see they're kind of like
Speaker 1:  building towards the puzzle pieces I already have.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Well it's a fun run because the, the usefulness factor
Speaker 5:  and the creepiness factor are perfectly correlated on
Speaker 5:  all of this stuff, right? Like the idea that I could just walk
Speaker 5:  into my living room and flop down on the couch and the TV turns on and I
Speaker 5:  don't even have to find the remote nifty, terrifying,
Speaker 5:  like yeah, it's all, it's all the same thing. Like, do I want
Speaker 5:  to be able to walk into the room and have my lights automatically turn on?
Speaker 5:  Like, yeah, that's, that's a like fundamentally good thing in the smart home
Speaker 5:  that it knows when I'm there and it turns the lights on and it turns them
Speaker 5:  off and I'm gone. Also, a constant reminder that I am being watched by my
Speaker 5:  house
Speaker 1:  By Samsung. Let me just read you another paragraph from Gun Story
Speaker 1:  for example. Samsung says, motion sensors and a Samsung TV
Speaker 1:  can quote, detect what kind of exercise you're doing, guide you on your form
Speaker 1:  and provide the optimal exercise time for maximum results.
Speaker 5:  Can you imagine your fridge just suddenly going three more
Speaker 1:  Knees out. I'm gonna keep going. If you sit down
Speaker 1:  in a chair,
Speaker 1:  smart things can automatically turn on the nearby reading lamp and adjust
Speaker 1:  the room to your preferred temperature. Samsung says it can also quote,
Speaker 1:  identify your miniature pincher jumping onto the couch,
Speaker 1:  activating the air purifier to remove allergens from the air.
Speaker 1:  And If you are drying your hair a device for the speaker,
Speaker 1:  like the music frame can hear the hair dryer and tell the Samsung
Speaker 1:  robot vacuum to come vacuum up the hair. You have shed
Speaker 5:  Utopia and dystopia. That is the smart home story.
Speaker 1:  I, I just want to point out, these were Samsung's own
Speaker 1:  examples. Someone was like, all right, I've got a little dog in an air purifier.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like what's, maybe brush your dog. I don't know. Air purifier doesn't
Speaker 5:  need to do that much work. I don't
Speaker 1:  Think it's, I'm just telling you the, the, we're we're headed towards a place
Speaker 1:  where like having to demonstrate that
Speaker 1:  linking up everything in your house in a smart home, it, all these companies
Speaker 1:  are gonna start making up just absolutely absurd scenarios. Yeah. Just
Speaker 1:  the lights are watching you. It's, it's
Speaker 5:  The, it's the, the hairdryer one that really does it for me. Like can you
Speaker 5:  imagine just, you like plug in your hair dryer and it's, it's like set
Speaker 5:  to on and so it, it automatically goes on for a second and your robot vacuum
Speaker 5:  has to be like, ah, shit, here we go again. And just like comes rolling in
Speaker 5:  from the other room.
Speaker 1:  Well no David, because obviously Samsung's AI platform will be involved.
Speaker 1:  You'll I see. Yeah. Right. You'll be like, Hey, I've got this hairdryer problem.
Speaker 1:  Can you get the, can you get every time I do this, can you get, make the
Speaker 1:  vacuum come in and then we're gonna sit through another in terminal demo
Speaker 1:  that's like the computer understands language and you know what I mean? Like
Speaker 1:  it's happening. It's happening.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And then we're all so screwed.
Speaker 1:  I will say, I mean, I, I love a smart home. I just, the lights are watching
Speaker 1:  you is that's what you have like apple's, like, we're gonna do a door lock.
Speaker 1:  It's like step one, but to, we're gonna put a motorized
Speaker 1:  iPad on a stick in your house. You need, you need all this other
Speaker 1:  stuff to be there. Yeah. Because otherwise your house is gonna be very smart
Speaker 1:  at all.
Speaker 5:  And then there's gonna be a software bug and it's gonna beat you to death
Speaker 5:  when you try to use your hairdryer. That's, that's where we're headed. Welcome
Speaker 5:  to the future.
Speaker 1:  I do love that. It, they specify that it was a miniature pincher.
Speaker 5:  It's very, yeah. Other dogs, whatever, they're, they're not a problem.
Speaker 1:  Our hair purifier, our air purifier isn't strong enough. All right. That's
Speaker 1:  it. That was lightning round. For what it's worth, like I said, we want your
Speaker 1:  feedback on how to manage all this coverage. I know that
Speaker 1:  it's polarizing. Some of you want a lot of it, some of you would prefer that
Speaker 1:  we filter all of it on the homepage. We're gonna find ways to do that on
Speaker 1:  our website. We need to calibrate it on this podcast. So let us
Speaker 1:  know. We're gonna, we're gonna work it out, but we're, we
Speaker 1:  can't ignore it because all of the products you make are downstream of some
Speaker 1:  of these politics. Like that's, they were all sitting there. Yeah, they were
Speaker 1:  all sitting there. Mark Zuckerberg was sitting there.
Speaker 1:  He was looking at stuff.
Speaker 7:  Yep.
Speaker 1:  That's it everybody. That's The Vergecast Rock and roll.
Speaker 7:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 7:  you. Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one.
Speaker 7:  The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network.
Speaker 7:  Our show is produced by Will Poor Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer. And
Speaker 7:  that's it. We'll see you next week.