# Transcript
ID: 7ae83d1f-c660-4855-811b-24103221d636
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-3701131980461434292/-8130743035916934478/s93290-US-6844s-1744969534.mp3
Description: We promise, this episode is only a little bit about header bidding. Nilay and David are joined by The Verge’s Alex Heath to talk about some big news in tech regulation: Google lost its ad-tech monopoly trial, which could reshape both Google and the internet altogether. And that’s not the only monopoly news! Meta’s trial also started this week, and Alex was there to see Mark Zuckerberg and others try to defend Instagram, WhatsApp, and the company as a whole. After all that, we talk about OpenAI’s plans to build a social network, and how this company seems to never run out of ambition. Finally, in the lightning round, it’s time for another round of Brendan Carr is a Dummy, and some news about viral cameras and the Switch 2. Which we’ll be yeeting into our homes as soon as possible
Speaker 5:  Hello and welcome to Vergecast the flagship podcast. Knowing what Facebook
Speaker 5:  is just surprisingly complicated.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna, we're gonna explain that in great detail. I'm your friend Neli
Speaker 5:  David Pierce is here. Hey,
Speaker 6:  It's gonna be a very short podcast if we have to attempt to explain what
Speaker 5:  Facebook is or the world's longest podcast,
Speaker 6:  Podcast ever. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Alex Heath is here direct from the the Meta and Antitrust trial.
Speaker 5:  What's up Alex? I'm just over here on me. We guys come on in.
Speaker 5:  The water's warm.
Speaker 5:  The best part of any antitrust trial is when the accused monopoly
Speaker 5:  insists that insane things are true competitors.
Speaker 5:  So Comcast will be like, yes, like infrared internet
Speaker 5:  is a real competitor to our fiber network. Whenever it's like that's not,
Speaker 5:  and they're always like, we're so helpless and weak. And that's very much
Speaker 5:  what Meta is doing in the, in the courtroom with other networks like me.
Speaker 5:  We, so we gotta talk about that. Alex was in the courtroom with Lauren finer.
Speaker 5:  Mark Zuckerberg was on the stand for a long time this week.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna talk about all that. But what's wild
Speaker 5:  is that while all that was happening, the Google
Speaker 5:  Ad Tech antitrust case got a decision and the court
Speaker 5:  ruled that Google has a monopoly in ad tech. And I don't even remember this.
Speaker 5:  We forced David to go to that trial way back when
Speaker 5:  David just briefly sum up what that trial was like.
Speaker 6:  Sure. I should, I should say poor Lauren Finer had to go to a lot more of
Speaker 6:  that one than I did. Yeah. I just had to go for a couple of days
Speaker 6:  because she couldn't or just didn't want to. Or like, I think at
Speaker 6:  some point you spend enough time listening to people explain how ad exchanges
Speaker 6:  work and you're like, I can't do this anymore and I have to leave. But
Speaker 6:  anyway, so basically this case was about
Speaker 6:  three things.
Speaker 6:  One was, did Google acquire its way
Speaker 6:  into a monopoly in advertising technology?
Speaker 6:  Two was is Google basically putting all
Speaker 6:  the different pieces of its advertising puzzle together in a way that
Speaker 6:  is illegal? And three is basically
Speaker 6:  does the sort of breadth of Google as a, as a search engine,
Speaker 6:  as a publishing engine for the rest of the internet, like is Google
Speaker 6:  so big that it should not have this much power over how advertising works?
Speaker 6:  And they spent, I mean just, just like weeks litigating
Speaker 6:  like the deep tech of the ad stack. But what it really came down to
Speaker 6:  is Google owns advertising on the internet in like a really real
Speaker 6:  way.
Speaker 5:  Wait, on the web. I wanna be careful about on the web. 'cause it's,
Speaker 5:  it's, this is right up against Meta and like advertising
Speaker 5:  in Meta apps.
Speaker 6:  Well, and and not in substantial part of go Google's argument
Speaker 6:  is that Meta exists. Yeah. But yeah, for the, for
Speaker 6:  the open web in particular, Google essentially is the
Speaker 6:  advertising engine behind everything. And it, it
Speaker 6:  increasingly has controlled every piece of the advertising puzzle. It has
Speaker 6:  controlled every market in this space for many, many years. And
Speaker 6:  the overwhelming question was
Speaker 6:  is is it a monopoly? And it actually turned into one of the more sort of
Speaker 6:  straightforward monopoly cases we've had. I think like the
Speaker 6:  question of is Google search a monopoly is really complicated. The question
Speaker 6:  of is Meta a monopoly is really complicated in ways that we're gonna talk
Speaker 6:  about. But like just sort of definitionally
Speaker 6:  what Google has and did with It is
Speaker 6:  like right down the middle of what we talk about when we talk about monopolies.
Speaker 6:  Which is super interesting. And I think is part of the reason I think I certainly
Speaker 6:  left the case being like, I think Google is gonna lose Yeah. This case.
Speaker 5:  And we should also compare and contrast this to the other
Speaker 5:  antitrust case Google Lost, which was about its dominance and search,
Speaker 6:  Right?
Speaker 5:  So Google was declared an illegal monopoly in search
Speaker 5:  a while ago by a court. That case is headed to a phase called the Remedies
Speaker 5:  trial, where you figure out what to do with it. Also this month, also this
Speaker 5:  month the government wants Google to sell Chrome and maybe some
Speaker 5:  other stuff. Google would not like to do that. And then this
Speaker 5:  trial reached its opinion by the judge. Google has a
Speaker 5:  monopoly, an illegal monopoly in advertising and in various ways will, which
Speaker 5:  we'll talk about. And then that will proceed to a remedies trial. All of
Speaker 5:  that is against, while the Meta antitrust case is like literally
Speaker 5:  happening in real time, like it's, it's happening while we are talking, it'll
Speaker 5:  be happening while you are listening to this. It will always be happening.
Speaker 5:  And then sometime down the line there's gonna be an Apple antitrust case.
Speaker 5:  So this is a lot of like Lena Khan and Jonathan Cantor stuff
Speaker 5:  happening all at once inside the Trump administration, Which we can talk
Speaker 5:  about. But Google in particular has now
Speaker 5:  gone over two. Yeah. In like big ways, big meaningful ways.
Speaker 5:  You'll note Google also when Epic sued Apple and Google for antitrust
Speaker 5:  issues, Google was the one that lost there, which I think is, and Apple kind
Speaker 5:  of got away with it still on appeal in various ways. Does
Speaker 6:  Google just have bad lawyers? Like is that really the takeaway here?
Speaker 5:  Again, I'm really interested in comparing, contrast this with Meta. My read
Speaker 5:  on this is that Google's commitment to openness, and I'm
Speaker 5:  putting openness in quotes, but it openness in Android on the web
Speaker 5:  means that it has to influence lots of things that aren't Google. Hmm.
Speaker 5:  Right. So with Android it has to convince Samsung what to do or whatever.
Speaker 5:  With search, it has to convince a bunch of websites to like operate in search
Speaker 5:  and be indexed or whatever. With ad networks, it has to convince a bunch
Speaker 5:  of publishers and advertisers to play ball. And so it does that, it like
Speaker 5:  uses its influence and there's emails and then there's
Speaker 5:  deals and there's meeting notes and there's contracts and there's all this
Speaker 5:  stuff you can go look at. And it's Google executives being like, if I turn
Speaker 5:  this knob, the publishers will do that. And you have all this evidence
Speaker 5:  they, they did the thing. Whereas, you know, with Apple or Meta
Speaker 5:  Tim Cook or Mark Zuckerberg is like, I dunno, make number go up. And like
Speaker 5:  some product manager does it and that's the end of that. And so I think Google
Speaker 5:  is just like structurally at a disadvantage all the time. 'cause it's, it
Speaker 5:  has to make deals to get what it wants.
Speaker 7:  The business success of Google over the last 20 years could really be tied
Speaker 7:  to tying this idea of monopoly, tying, tying products
Speaker 7:  together to get leverage in another area, which is why the DOJ is pushing
Speaker 7:  for Chrome specifically and changes to Android. We should
Speaker 7:  probably also clarify though, this ad tech case, this doesn't attack Google
Speaker 7:  ads on Google search. This is actually a much smaller part of
Speaker 7:  their business. I think the status saw was it's like 10 to 12% right?
Speaker 7:  Of the ads that they serve on other websites. That's specifically what
Speaker 7:  this case is about.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And that it, that number's getting smaller too, right? Google makes
Speaker 5:  its money on search. It makes its money in shopping, it makes its money on
Speaker 5:  YouTube. Increasingly it's the part of the ecosystem where they monetize
Speaker 5:  the entire web, which is what David was talking about. That number is getting
Speaker 5:  smaller, but it's also under the most pressure because Google, well now we
Speaker 5:  know Google has been a monopoly there.
Speaker 6:  Right? But this is what I mean by it's, it's a more sort of straightforward
Speaker 6:  monopoly case. 'cause the, the thing that a lot of these other ones have
Speaker 6:  run into is what is the difference between me doing
Speaker 6:  something that is good for my business and a monopoly
Speaker 6:  action And that that's actually a, a hard thing to put together, especially
Speaker 6:  for something like a free product. So like if I make my
Speaker 6:  search engine better and it hurts my competition, is that,
Speaker 6:  is that monopoly maintenance or is that good business? And it actually turns
Speaker 6:  out the line there is very fine and really not obvious to figure out. But
Speaker 6:  in this case it's like the, the basic finding of
Speaker 6:  the case was, and, and I will attempt to do this without either
Speaker 6:  being wrong or going way too deep on ad tech, both of which are very possible
Speaker 6:  to do in this case, but that basically Google owned
Speaker 6:  the part of the advertising sack that advertisers use,
Speaker 6:  the part that publishers use and the part that connects the two things. Those
Speaker 6:  are three separate products and Google owned them all. And basically the
Speaker 6:  only way to get a good experience on any of them was to use all of them.
Speaker 6:  And so everybody essentially agreed, and this was like the expert opinion
Speaker 6:  over and over and over throughout the trial that these products suck, but
Speaker 6:  you have no choice but to use them even though they're bad and
Speaker 6:  more expensive. Because without one or
Speaker 6:  without them all, you can't get one. Yeah. And that is like, that's a
Speaker 6:  monopoly like that is that just, that's just it, right? That's, that's
Speaker 6:  railroads and trains. Like It is, It is the oldest school version of how
Speaker 6:  we talk about what monopoly tying is. And it's, and
Speaker 6:  it's in such a more straightforward way than like, what does it mean that
Speaker 6:  no one cares about any search engine except yours? You know what I mean?
Speaker 5:  Well there's that. I mean, I'll just read you the conclusion from the opinion
Speaker 5:  which tracks with what you're saying. But in a, you know, a more strident
Speaker 5:  way, here It is, quote, for over a decade Google has tied its publisher ad
Speaker 5:  server and ad exchange together through contractual policies and technological
Speaker 5:  integration, which enabled the company to establish and protect its monopoly
Speaker 5:  power in these two markets. Google further entrenched its monopoly power
Speaker 5:  by imposing anti-competitive policies on its customers and eliminating desirable
Speaker 5:  product features. It it goes on it, she's not happy.
Speaker 5:  And really what, you know, it's so funny, we, I I opened the show with a
Speaker 5:  joke about like what is Facebook? So much of this comes down to like what
Speaker 5:  is the market is the market for search and competition with people searching
Speaker 5:  on TikTok And you end up in these like existential minefields.
Speaker 5:  And here again it's very simple 'cause there's only three products that do
Speaker 5:  the thing. You can't be like, well I could replace this horse with an airplane.
Speaker 5:  What is the market? It's like, nope. You, for here there's three products.
Speaker 5:  One that displays the ads, one that goes and gets the bids from the advertisers
Speaker 5:  about how much they'll pay and the systems that tie them all together. And
Speaker 5:  you can't just replace those with anything. Like those are literal software
Speaker 5:  products you have to go and buy and we know what the replacement
Speaker 5:  products would be and they don't exist because Google killed them all. Like,
Speaker 5:  It is very straightforward in a way that makes it easy to talk about. But
Speaker 5:  then it's also ad tech and like I'm confident we've already lost a bunch
Speaker 5:  of people. But the, the issue is like this is the money,
Speaker 5:  like it, it's a small part of Google's money, but it's the money that
Speaker 5:  funds the open web and the open web is Google, like
Speaker 5:  Google search without things to search for is not a good product.
Speaker 5:  Google's AI training that everyone's doing across the entire open web
Speaker 5:  doesn't work if you crush this entire ecosystem. And that is more
Speaker 5:  or less what has been happening. And one of the reasons it's been happening
Speaker 5:  is because now by this ruling Google has been
Speaker 5:  extracting more value than it's been giving back to these publishers. Disclosure.
Speaker 5:  I should know by the way that we run a publisher and like we use DFP
Speaker 5:  and our executives are very interested in the outcome of this case. We
Speaker 5:  are far, far away from that. That is literally when you look at a VERGE webpage,
Speaker 5:  there's like the stuff we make and the ads and the ads are run
Speaker 5:  by another team and they and like literally other computers that are all
Speaker 5:  tied up in Google systems. Shout
Speaker 6:  Out to Ryan Pauley though a Vox Media executive who appears in the decision
Speaker 6:  a couple
Speaker 5:  Of times. Does he really? He does. Ah, that's a great concert baby.
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna go upstairs and find, yeah, we were on a programmatic ad exchange.
Speaker 5:  It is all tied up in this, you know, the thing that really got me and I,
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna try to like make this real or
Speaker 5:  at least tangible to people. 'cause ad tech is really complicated, like
Speaker 5:  complicated and full of like pure hacks to
Speaker 5:  get around Google that Google then crushed like this cat and mouse game,
Speaker 5:  which is kind of neat, but it's also just like a bunch of ad people do an
Speaker 5:  ad stuff to extract pennies at scale and, and your eyes just glaze over.
Speaker 5:  But the way, the essential way it works is that you load up a VERGE webpage
Speaker 5:  and you know the story comes from WordPress. That's the system we use
Speaker 5:  and the advertising all comes from another set of systems,
Speaker 5:  right? Double click for publishers is the one that they're always talking
Speaker 5:  about in this decision DFP that goes out and says, I've got this ad space,
Speaker 5:  does anyone wanna buy it? I'm gonna serve it to these demographics that
Speaker 5:  I found on this website. An advertiser are supposed to bid on it
Speaker 5:  and that's an auction. And so like whoever bids the most for the space And
Speaker 5:  that scale wins or supposed to win. And what has been happening
Speaker 5:  here with Google is the, because like David said, they
Speaker 5:  own all the, the systems that interconnect, they just keep giving
Speaker 5:  themselves advantages, right? So they run the software that delivers the
Speaker 5:  ads to us. They run the bridge software in the middle and they run the
Speaker 5:  supply software that the advertisers buy into. And the two
Speaker 5:  things that jumped out to me or these policies they had, so it's an
Speaker 5:  auction, right? Like just think about you at an auction. Google
Speaker 5:  had a policy called First Look which required publishers to give
Speaker 5:  Google the first right of refusal for every impression. So you're like, I'm
Speaker 5:  gonna put this up for auction and Google like I want it. And that would just
Speaker 5:  the end of that, right? And then they had a policy called Last Look,
Speaker 5:  which gave Google the ability to see everyone else's bids in an
Speaker 5:  otherwise sealed auction before it could bid.
Speaker 5:  So you have this like sealed auction and Google can look at it and say, oh
Speaker 5:  that is worth it and pay, right? So they had a, the first look and the last
Speaker 5:  look on the auction sounds like a great business.
Speaker 5:  It printed money. Like where do you think all the GPUs came from? They got
Speaker 5:  slides in the office, man, like all of that Google, you know, like we can't
Speaker 5:  figure out pixel phones, we can just just not do that forever because this
Speaker 5:  is printing money. And every time a publisher would try to do
Speaker 5:  something to stop it, they would do hacks, right? They would run
Speaker 5:  their own auctions before opening up the auctions to Google's ad server
Speaker 5:  and then Google would find a way to shut that down. Like that's the level
Speaker 5:  of cat and mask game that was going on. Revenues just went down and
Speaker 5:  Google search traffic is down. You're like, oh, the web that Google built
Speaker 5:  is dying. It's under all of this pressure that we can see. But it was also
Speaker 5:  under this massive revenue pressure this whole time.
Speaker 7:  If Google loses control of this ad plumbing that fuels
Speaker 7:  and funds a lot of the web, like we're talking about what happens next?
Speaker 7:  Do we, do we have an idea?
Speaker 6:  I mean the, the hopeful version is you get a, a huge teaming
Speaker 6:  market of ad technology, right? That like there, there was this
Speaker 6:  big push a few years ago now I, I dunno what is
Speaker 6:  time, but there was this big push towards this thing called header bidding,
Speaker 6:  which was essentially the idea that actually instead of just Google
Speaker 6:  being able to bid in real time for ads and everybody else had to like
Speaker 6:  submit them ahead ofs like this whole thing is insane.
Speaker 5:  That was the hack I was talking about, right? I did my very best to not say
Speaker 5:  header bidding. I, and then David just said header bidding,
Speaker 6:  But header bidding. The, the whole idea was like we can use one line of code
Speaker 6:  to essentially level the field and give everybody equal access to this, which
Speaker 6:  means the advertisers are going to get the thing that they want and they're
Speaker 6:  going to pay the most money for it and everybody wins and, and the money
Speaker 6:  just keeps flowing. And in theory that's where,
Speaker 6:  that's where this goes, right? Like the, the actual technology to make this
Speaker 6:  stuff work is out there. It's just that Google has so
Speaker 6:  thoroughly like subsumed all of the supply and demand inside of its
Speaker 6:  own system that if you blow it out, in theory advertisers will get
Speaker 6:  better placements, their ads and thus better performance on their ads. Publishers
Speaker 6:  will get more money for their content. Like this is, this is the thing you
Speaker 6:  are trying to pry open is just sitting there. The question
Speaker 6:  is,
Speaker 6:  is there any actual reality in which that works? Like Google
Speaker 6:  is so far ahead, one of the things they talked about in this trial over and
Speaker 6:  over was how high the switching costs are that like even these
Speaker 6:  companies that know Google is charging them twice as much as some of its
Speaker 6:  competition, which everyone agrees is a better product. You just, it's just
Speaker 6:  not worth the hassle to leave because you're essentially just like throwing
Speaker 6:  all of your money away while you try to switch ad platforms. So
Speaker 6:  Google's bet forever has been people will stay because it's too annoying
Speaker 6:  to leave. And even with all of this, it seems like there's a real
Speaker 6:  chance that that is what happens and Google ends up being forced to spin
Speaker 6:  off either, you know, one, one part of that pipeline.
Speaker 6:  But I don't know, in in practice it seems very possible to me that not that
Speaker 6:  much actually changes. First
Speaker 5:  I wanna say that David did say header bidding and I should have just said
Speaker 5:  it first and I did my very best to not say header bidding, which is if you
Speaker 5:  ask the ad world and you say if you like go into ad world
Speaker 5:  and you say header bidding, they all just like lose their minds. Like that's
Speaker 5:  when they lost, they know it's when they lost. It's just this very weird
Speaker 5:  wonky thing. But there are quotes that really back up what David
Speaker 5:  is saying here from the opinion. I mean just straightforward,
Speaker 5:  like again this judge did not play around quote, direct
Speaker 5:  pricing evidence shows that Google could profitably price significantly
Speaker 5:  above competitive levels because enough customers would keep buying those
Speaker 5:  products and not go elsewhere, right? They were just raising the price and
Speaker 5:  the switching costs were too high.
Speaker 6:  Which by the way is like the most classic monopoly move
Speaker 6:  ever. Get everybody in and then once they can't leave, raise the prices.
Speaker 6:  It is like that's that's, that's the definition of monopoly.
Speaker 5:  Yep. Adx, which is one of the Google products here, adx, is relatively
Speaker 5:  high market share viewed in conjunction with high barriers to entry and expansion
Speaker 5:  that exists for other ad exchanges supports the conclusion that Google has
Speaker 5:  had and continues to maintain monopoly power. And then the last piece of
Speaker 5:  the puzzle, which is really interesting is that
Speaker 5:  Google also has the demand, right? And they have
Speaker 5:  the demand because of search, which they also have monopoly in per
Speaker 5:  another court. So the court says you can do all this switching
Speaker 5:  but this big volume of advertisers is already buying Google search
Speaker 5:  and Google's just like selling them this other product on the side. They're
Speaker 5:  tying them together like you're saying Alex. So here's a quote. Google has
Speaker 5:  been able to amass this unparalleled group of mostly small and
Speaker 5:  medium sized advertisers in large part due to the dominance of search,
Speaker 5:  which another district court has found to be the source of Google's monopoly
Speaker 5:  power in the markets or general search services and general search text ads.
Speaker 5:  So even if you can build a better system at returns, higher rates, Google
Speaker 5:  has tied its dominance of the ad tech market to its dominance in search
Speaker 5:  and people are buying the search ads and they said you wanna buy ads across
Speaker 5:  the web when you're on the shoe review website. People say yes and Google
Speaker 5:  extracts all of that money too. So you've reduced competition sort of across
Speaker 5:  the board and there's all this evidence because Google has to make deals
Speaker 5:  with everyone and there's all this evidence.
Speaker 6:  But also to your point Alex, that that's in in, in
Speaker 6:  that is the real threat to Google here, right? Because what you're saying
Speaker 6:  is actually all of these things are so powerful in part because they are
Speaker 6:  tied together, right? Because when you wanna buy search ads, now you're in
Speaker 6:  our system and it's actually easier and faster and more efficient for you
Speaker 6:  to buy AdWords ads on the rest of the web in the same way that you're building
Speaker 6:  ads products for search. Now we have
Speaker 6:  a big hole getting poked in the middle of search big
Speaker 6:  questions about what's gonna happen there. And you have being forced to open
Speaker 6:  up the ad tech stack like all of a sudden if I'm Google I'm looking at this
Speaker 6:  as like yes it's a threat to that small piece of our revenue
Speaker 6:  that is coming from this like open web advertising system,
Speaker 6:  but this also this rolls right back into search ads, which is that's where
Speaker 6:  the real money is. Like if, if you're Google, that's the money you're worried
Speaker 6:  about. And this is, this is not exactly that but It is right next to it.
Speaker 5:  It's also what are you gonna search?
Speaker 6:  Well there's that. Yeah. Like
Speaker 5:  What are you gonna search for real? What are you gonna search if you kill
Speaker 5:  the web in this way, if you put the SEO pressure on it, you put the
Speaker 5:  AI scraping pressure on it, the AI answers in search pressure
Speaker 5:  on it, you've put this much revenue pressure on it, profit
Speaker 5:  really making a webpage, which disclosure is the business we're
Speaker 5:  in is crazy. Yeah. Like I've asked this
Speaker 5:  question of so many different kinds of media executives
Speaker 5:  of platform executives of like the CEO of Squarespace comes on decoder.
Speaker 5:  I'm like, why would anyone make a website? And they're like, I don't know.
Speaker 5:  And that's bad. Like that is the thing that is worst for Google.
Speaker 5:  The only answer any of those people can ever really give me is to
Speaker 5:  do e-commerce. You start websites to do e-commerce 'cause you
Speaker 5:  don't wanna sell your product on the TikTok shop. So you wanna kick people
Speaker 5:  to a website so you don't have to pay a bunch of platform fees
Speaker 5:  Bad. Like that is, that is a nightmare for Google because the
Speaker 5:  new information is getting published on the platforms that are decidedly
Speaker 5:  closed to the Google search crawlers and the Google AI systems. It's bad
Speaker 5:  for all of us because the open web is just under all this pressure that
Speaker 5:  you can see every day and all the new information is on TikTok, which doesn't
Speaker 5:  talk to Instagram, which doesn't talk to X. Which it's like
Speaker 5:  there's a real thing here where it's like the future of Google's at risk
Speaker 5:  but the future of the internet's at risk because the open system has been
Speaker 5:  kind of crushed out of being, I dunno what's gonna happen next if I was,
Speaker 5:  if I was Shai, I would call Larry Page and politely ask
Speaker 5:  for permission to break up the company before the government does it first.
Speaker 5:  That's what I would do. Like straight up that's what I would do. I would
Speaker 5:  say, look, we're gonna sell YouTube and let YouTube eat something and we're
Speaker 5:  gonna try to fix this web problem so that we
Speaker 5:  don't lose to close systems because our entire
Speaker 5:  self-conception has been about openness and if
Speaker 5:  we lose openness because we crushed it out of existence, that will just be
Speaker 5:  our fault. I don't think they're ever gonna do that. I, we did learn in the
Speaker 5:  Meta trial that sometimes they think about splitting up their own companies
Speaker 5:  and I would just say to all these executives, it would be better for you
Speaker 5:  to do it on your own terms than have the government do it for you. But it's
Speaker 5:  kind of like Google might be at that point where it would be better for them
Speaker 5:  to do it themselves before letting two different district courts in
Speaker 5:  two different remedies phases come to their own conclusions. This
Speaker 7:  Feels like a make or break moment for Google in pretty much every way.
Speaker 7:  So you've got them losing their monopoly power that they've
Speaker 7:  used to build, build the best business in the history of the world
Speaker 7:  over the last 20 years. You've got OpenAI and AI
Speaker 7:  eating into search. You've got the internal cultural
Speaker 7:  problems, which I've written about a lot over the last year
Speaker 7:  and yeah, it feels like Google has to rise to this challenge or this
Speaker 7:  may be the end of Google as we know it. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I think it absolutely is the end of Google as we know it, right? It it already
Speaker 5:  is,
Speaker 7:  Right, structurally, but I'm saying in terms of relevance, in terms of power,
Speaker 7:  in terms of Google just being this on the Mount Rushmore, big tech just
Speaker 7:  always being there. It feels like they are vulnerable.
Speaker 6:  I've been wondering recently if that happened a while ago and we just
Speaker 6:  didn't notice like, 'cause I think the, the certainly in terms of like
Speaker 6:  relevance and, and sort of market power, it's still at the peak of
Speaker 6:  everything. But I think I, I just think about sort of the company that Google
Speaker 6:  was for a long time and like, I think a lot of people really rooted for Google
Speaker 6:  because Google set itself up in a way that was like, okay, as as the web
Speaker 6:  as an open accessible thing wins,
Speaker 6:  Google will win, right? And I think, I think most people saw that as like
Speaker 6:  a net good Google was like, okay, we wanna help people get online, we wanna
Speaker 6:  give people things to do on the internet. We wanna give people access to
Speaker 6:  lots of things. We're gonna make a ton of money and that's a pretty good
Speaker 6:  trade. And, and it was like that was a pretty good trade.
Speaker 7:  The mission statement was organize the world's information and make it universally
Speaker 7:  accessible. And I think that last bit is what the industry at
Speaker 7:  large loved and what right endeared a lot of goodwill to Google.
Speaker 7:  And what these monopoly cases are showing is that once the money came in,
Speaker 7:  it wasn't actually about making it universally accessible to everyone. It
Speaker 7:  was about how can we benefit our constellation of products
Speaker 7:  that we use and tie together to maintain dominance.
Speaker 6:  Right? Totally. And I think somewhere along the way Google stopped being
Speaker 6:  good for the internet and it just took us a long time to realize it.
Speaker 7:  Yikes. I
Speaker 5:  Gotta sit with that one for a while that that really does cut against
Speaker 5:  everyone's conception of Google,
Speaker 6:  Including Google's conception of Google.
Speaker 5:  I have been harsher on Google than anyone these past few years and
Speaker 5:  I, there's still the idealism within the company and
Speaker 5:  I think the thing that Alex is pointing at is the money
Speaker 5:  side of the company stopped being idealistic a long time ago, right?
Speaker 5:  That is just a bunch of sharks and like that's advertising. Like I,
Speaker 5:  have you ever met people in adv like they're sharks, like they're just trying
Speaker 5:  to sell you nail polish in in sports cars and it's great, I love those things,
Speaker 5:  but like Google's idealism to make great products
Speaker 5:  and to funnel that money into whatever wacky idea or the contact lenses
Speaker 5:  that could see like detect health problems. Like all of that started fading.
Speaker 5:  'cause none of that started working and they weren't, they didn't find anything
Speaker 5:  else to make money on except search. So they just turned the screws on search
Speaker 5:  in this very specific way and the openness became their weakness in these
Speaker 5:  antitrust cases. Like I said, I, if I, it was up to me, I would,
Speaker 5:  you know, it, this is like the time for radical reinvention of Google and
Speaker 5:  in particular to say the open web needs to be protected because
Speaker 5:  if it dies or the next new person who has an
Speaker 5:  idea to make an information will not do it on the web,
Speaker 5:  that's death. Like I I I, that's just death. I I think I even
Speaker 5:  asked Sundar Phai last year, like why would anybody start a website? And
Speaker 5:  he was kinda like, well we have YouTube and that's not great. Like that's
Speaker 5:  death. Yeah. And you gotta, you gotta do something to protect that
Speaker 5:  feedback loop so that the web persists in a way that allows search to exist
Speaker 5:  but also just allows more information to be published in open ways. I dunno
Speaker 5:  what's gonna happen. Like there's a remedies phase, there's the search remedies
Speaker 5:  phase. It's just wild that this existential problem
Speaker 5:  for Google is literally coming up the week that Meta is also facing
Speaker 5:  an antitrust trial and they seem to be in almost the
Speaker 5:  exact opposite position where the government can't even describe what
Speaker 5:  Facebook is.
Speaker 7:  It's so funny, we're talking about this, I've been looking at my notes 'cause
Speaker 7:  being in the courtroom, you know, you, you can't have a phone enough. So
Speaker 7:  I've just been writing all these notes all week and Zuckerberg
Speaker 7:  actually talked a lot about Google because he was getting asked about
Speaker 7:  basically, and I don't know if we're officially segueing now, but the FTC
Speaker 7:  was saying, do you think that Instagram and WhatsApp could have
Speaker 7:  been as successful with another company? And Google was kind of
Speaker 7:  the main example, and I don't have the exact quote but it was something along
Speaker 7:  the lines of he said, well I think ability and execution are different
Speaker 7:  things and ouch. He basically
Speaker 7:  chat on Google's organizational structure and he
Speaker 7:  was like, look, I think they're technically excellent. I think that they
Speaker 7:  often struggle. He was basically like, it perplexes me
Speaker 7:  sometimes the decisions they make because they have the ability
Speaker 7:  and I think organizationally, I think he said they're challenged.
Speaker 7:  And it's just funny in hindsight with like these two cases back to back,
Speaker 5:  We should talk about the Meta case now. I know what's gonna happen to Google.
Speaker 5:  We are gonna get the two remedies phases. Yeah. Google by the way says it's
Speaker 5:  going to appeal and in its statement said we, we've won half the case.
Speaker 5:  I hate to be a scold. There were three counts. Google
Speaker 5:  got one dismissed and lost the other two that it's technically one third
Speaker 7:  Math.
Speaker 5:  Just putting that out there, just, just noting that.
Speaker 6:  And it turns out that losing by a little and losing by a lot don't actually
Speaker 6:  matter all that much in cases like these, it's not like the
Speaker 6:  scoreboard doesn't really chart
Speaker 5:  Over time. If Google has to sell addict and DFP, they have lost by a lot
Speaker 5:  and that's the, that's what they're staring at. But the Meta case is fascinating,
Speaker 5:  right? Not only because Mark Zuckerberg is apparently doing decoder bait
Speaker 5:  live on stage in our nation's courtrooms, but because there
Speaker 5:  isn't all of this contractual evidence that they were
Speaker 5:  influencing the thing, even though everyone knows that Meta ties
Speaker 5:  its products together to make a stronger ecosystem. Yeah. Like if you breathe
Speaker 5:  at Instagram, that content ends up on five different platforms before
Speaker 5:  you even like finish pressing the button. But that's Meta
Speaker 5:  controls it all. So it's like fine. And I, I think the government has really,
Speaker 5:  it appears the government has very much struggled in this case.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I would say so. First I just wanna talk about what it was like being
Speaker 7:  there because there's something beautifully egalitarian
Speaker 7:  about being in court for something like this. 'cause he knows Zuckerberg,
Speaker 7:  he rolls like the president, right? He's, he's got a ton of bodyguards. He's
Speaker 7:  third richest man on earth and you know, it's kind of, it was cool
Speaker 7:  and, and made me have some hope for America just watching
Speaker 7:  this all play out. So this judge, chief judge
Speaker 7:  Boberg of the US district court of DC during
Speaker 7:  like one of the breaks, like 10 minute breaks, he filed, you know,
Speaker 7:  that he was possibly gonna hold the Trump administration in contempt over
Speaker 7:  the, the El Salvador de deportations and, and the illegality and
Speaker 7:  question marks around that. He, so he's got a lot going on trumpet.
Speaker 7:  Trump has called him a, a left wing lunatic. The security in the court
Speaker 7:  beyond just Zuck being there was very intense because of the fact that it
Speaker 7:  was him doing the case. So it was really interesting to see this
Speaker 7:  and you know, I expected, you know, I was there with a few other reporter
Speaker 7:  friends and the first morning we expected, you know, throngs of
Speaker 7:  cameras and lines of, of the public. 'cause you know, it's a public courtroom.
Speaker 7:  Anyone can go in. I don't know if people realize this in this country, you
Speaker 7:  can literally just walk into this courtroom.
Speaker 6:  There was a guy, fun fact this, not to derail you, but there was a guy who
Speaker 6:  sat in the courtroom every single day. I was there for the Google search
Speaker 6:  trial and read a book. I I, I cannot explain to you why this man
Speaker 6:  was there, but he just, he wore like cargo khaki pants and read what
Speaker 6:  looked like a like John Grisham novel. Awesome. Every single day in court.
Speaker 6:  Don't
Speaker 7:  Know why. Yeah. I mean the marshals are very serious. Like no electronics,
Speaker 7:  like very funny. Mike Isaac from The Times was wearing his Meta ray
Speaker 7:  bands at one point and he almost got thrown out because they
Speaker 7:  were like, is that recording?
Speaker 7:  It's great, but perfect. It was very cool just watching it play out and the,
Speaker 7:  the pomp and ceremony of it all, but also just like the, okay, this,
Speaker 7:  this part of the government at least right now seems to be working
Speaker 7:  and you know, Meta's got all these high price fancy lawyers. The
Speaker 7:  FTCs team was, I would say fairly young. I was actually surprised to see
Speaker 7:  everyone looked to be like kinda in their thirties and it, it was, it was
Speaker 7:  interesting to see the dichotomy of, of the two sides, but it's like, it's
Speaker 7:  literally me. A few other reporters like Joel Kaplan, I was
Speaker 7:  sitting right behind Ferguson, the chair of the FTC the first
Speaker 7:  day would not talk to the press, wouldn't really look at us.
Speaker 7:  And so yeah, that was just like what it was like being in the room. It's
Speaker 7:  this grand, you know, it's the chief judge's room, so it's just very grand
Speaker 7:  and to watch Zuckerberg walk in, you know, he still manages
Speaker 7:  to have like one bodyguard come into the room with him, but just to
Speaker 7:  watch him be regulated to like a common man,
Speaker 7:  you know, like he doesn't, he doesn't get to like leave first or
Speaker 7:  come in last, right? He kind of filters out with everyone like shoulder to
Speaker 7:  shoulder, you know, it was cool. But the case
Speaker 7:  itself, I left DC
Speaker 7:  really with the impression that our government does not understand how social
Speaker 7:  media works. Which is a bummer because I think there's a lot of really interesting
Speaker 7:  questions you should be asking about if you're the US about Meta power,
Speaker 7:  should one company own this much of
Speaker 7:  social media really control what fundamentally speech at this level.
Speaker 7:  And unfortunately the way they're attacking it, I think is is it just makes
Speaker 7:  no sense. It's not, it doesn't, anyone who actually uses the internet would
Speaker 7:  look at this case and say it makes no sense. So basically
Speaker 7:  the way the FTC is, you know, 'cause for an antitrust case you have to define
Speaker 7:  the market, right? And this is actually where this case has struggled and
Speaker 7:  where it got thrown out originally is the judge found that the FTC had
Speaker 7:  not kind of properly defined the market. So they narrowed it down to what
Speaker 7:  they think is the market that Meta competes in the us And do you wanna know
Speaker 7:  the only other apps that are in that market?
Speaker 6:  Wait, no, before we even get to that, I want you, I want you to explain what
Speaker 6:  they think that market is because I I I have read a lot about this now. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I couldn't explain it to you, but use that in court. Like what, what is,
Speaker 6:  how do they think about this market? They
Speaker 7:  Have narrowed it to what they call personal social networking services.
Speaker 7:  So like
Speaker 6:  The hell does that mean?
Speaker 7:  And I don't know, no one knows I've covered social media for 15 years. I've
Speaker 7:  never heard of this before.
Speaker 5:  Okay, wait, can I, and can I just add one more piece of information to that
Speaker 5:  because I think this is, It is, you just mentioned that this case got thrown
Speaker 5:  out once before. Yeah. Le Kahn's FTC got this case thrown out.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Judge Boberg threw out Lena Khan's version of this case saying the
Speaker 5:  market was ill-defined and made no sense. Yeah. Andrew Ferguson,
Speaker 5:  Trump's FTC chair Yeah. Is now in charge of this case
Speaker 5:  pursuing it even though Mark Zuckerberg is in the White House every day and
Speaker 5:  he's landed on whatever this definition is. Yeah. To cure the
Speaker 5:  already muddled definition that Lena Kahn got through.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And there's also a narrative out there that this was the Biden administration's
Speaker 7:  like lawsuit. It actually got first filed under the first Trump administration.
Speaker 7:  So this has gone through now three administrations. So
Speaker 7:  that's, that's their idea. So basically Meta competes for
Speaker 7:  sharing between friends and family. That's the market they're trying to
Speaker 7:  say they should break Meta up for. Okay. Okay. Guess guess they
Speaker 7:  own the apps that are in this market
Speaker 5:  Sharing between family and friends. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Facebook.
Speaker 7:  Facebook Besides Facebook
Speaker 6:  Like X seems like it would belong
Speaker 5:  Snapchat. Yes.
Speaker 6:  Snapchat's a good one.
Speaker 7:  There's only one more besides
Speaker 6:  Snapchat. I keep thinking of messaging apps that Meta already owns, which
Speaker 6:  is a bit of a problem I suppose.
Speaker 5:  It's not messaging, right? It's sharing
Speaker 7:  Between No, no, it's not messaging. But if
Speaker 6:  We're sharing between friends and family, that's where people
Speaker 7:  Share. No, no, no, no. Not according to our government.
Speaker 6:  Oh my God. Okay.
Speaker 7:  Snapchat and one other Tumblr. No.
Speaker 5:  Is it me we, is it the one you mentioned at the top? It's
Speaker 7:  Mei. Oh
Speaker 5:  It's what It is. Mei. I don't even know who Mei is. I just heard you say
Speaker 5:  it before.
Speaker 7:  Funny Meta's lead attorney asked Mark Zuckerberg that very question on the
Speaker 7:  stand and he said he does not know. And he said, have you ever
Speaker 7:  heard of it before this case? And he said, no, I checked my
Speaker 7:  email. I've actually gotten pitches from Mei over the last
Speaker 5:  Couple years. They, what have you been doing Alex? This
Speaker 7:  Is,
Speaker 5:  They are the greatest threat to Meta that exists.
Speaker 7:  They have some kind of blockchain angle, of course Tim Burners Lee
Speaker 7:  is involved. Frank McCort, who is also trying to put TikTok on the
Speaker 7:  blockchain is an investor. So that's me. We, they have
Speaker 7:  about 20 million I think something like that users worldwide.
Speaker 7:  I have never used it, I have never met a person who has used it.
Speaker 7:  But that is, that is the market according to the ftc. So on the, on its face,
Speaker 7:  that's, that's just ridiculous. Right. And you, you know, I was talking to
Speaker 7:  some other antitrust reporters who, who know the actual, you know, how the
Speaker 7:  mechanics of this play out better and apparently the judge can define the
Speaker 7:  market however he sees fit, you know, so it's not like the FTCs market is
Speaker 7:  definitely gonna stick or that meta's rebuttal of it will stick. The judge
Speaker 7:  may just be like, you're both wrong. And they probably are. Although I do
Speaker 7:  actually buy Meta's argument a little more, which is that no, we compete
Speaker 7:  across TikTok, iMessage, YouTube, X
Speaker 7:  Telegram signal, et cetera, et cetera. I would say
Speaker 7:  Zuckerberg spent a lot of time saying that YouTube and TikTok
Speaker 7:  especially were his main competitors. And a lot of time
Speaker 7:  I would say throwing like founder shade at Snapchat
Speaker 7:  and saying like, yeah, I wish we would've made it work. I think they'd finally
Speaker 7:  beat a billion users and they still aren't 10 years later, stuff like that.
Speaker 7:  So, ouch. 'cause he, you know, it came out in the courtroom and it's
Speaker 7:  been well covered, but that he, he tried to buy them as well so that this
Speaker 7:  is the FTCs argument. And
Speaker 7:  you know, I do think there are also looking at some interesting things around
Speaker 7:  network effects around what happens when you reach this scale and
Speaker 7:  there's so many people on a network and the switching cost is actually
Speaker 7:  your friends not coming with you. And they talked about that a little bit,
Speaker 7:  but I found their examination to
Speaker 7:  be fairly meandering. There was a lot of like, do you
Speaker 7:  remember that you wrote this Facebook blog post in 2008 about sharing on
Speaker 7:  the newsfeed? Like stuff like that
Speaker 7:  and meta's argument about the market to be much stronger.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It just feels like I just have a really hard time
Speaker 6:  looking at this in any way that says Facebook doesn't
Speaker 6:  compete with TikTok and taking that seriously.
Speaker 6:  Like, it, it just, it just does. Yeah. Like it just does.
Speaker 7:  Some of the most interesting evidence was actually in the opening arguments,
Speaker 7:  Meta displayed some internal data and we have it on the site.
Speaker 7:  We've got a, a stream that I and Lauren Finer have been contributing to.
Speaker 7:  Everyone should go check it out. There's a lot in there. Meta actually showed
Speaker 7:  data that when TikTok was briefly offline, you know, earlier
Speaker 7:  this year because of the ban traffic searched to
Speaker 7:  actually Facebook a little bit more than Instagram. And then they had like
Speaker 7:  Snapchat way at the bottom, like Snapchat got like a percent and
Speaker 7:  Snapchat actually got so mad about this that they had their lawyer in the
Speaker 7:  courtroom a couple days later also because Meta didn't properly redact the
Speaker 7:  slides for the public saying like,
Speaker 7:  you're revealing our confidential information. Staff's
Speaker 6:  Lawyer is like, don't tell anybody that nobody uses our products.
Speaker 5:  The inside baseball, by the way is that Meta tried to threaten Alex
Speaker 5:  into not publishing their unredacted slides. And I was like, that's not,
Speaker 5:  it's just not our problem. Like if you email us unredacted slides, we can
Speaker 5:  publish
Speaker 7:  Them. Yeah. It's a tale as old as time, you know, this has happened in like
Speaker 7:  every good case the Apple's lawyer was in there too, like saying we don't
Speaker 7:  have faith Meta will, you know, not disclose our confi, you know, confidential
Speaker 7:  info, which I'm sure Meta would love to, right? They they hate Apple, but
Speaker 7:  yeah. And that's, that's, that's the high level of it. And I'm curious, like,
Speaker 7:  I'm curious how much of this case is actually just naked politics because
Speaker 7:  I was watching Ferguson on Fox Business after the first day
Speaker 7:  and he point blank said, we are doing this to make sure
Speaker 7:  2020 never happens again. And he didn't say exactly what that meant,
Speaker 7:  but I think it means, you know, the Trump administration has been very
Speaker 7:  mad about how Zuckerberg funded
Speaker 7:  voting drive stuff, mail-in ballot initiatives
Speaker 7:  during the election. He actually thinks that Zuckerberg somehow played a
Speaker 7:  key role in, in him losing that race. And then you, you
Speaker 7:  have Ferguson on, you know, the president's favorite news channel saying,
Speaker 7:  you know, this case is to make sure that never happens again. So I think
Speaker 7:  that kind of shows the motivation here.
Speaker 5:  I wanna get to the, the substantive argument, but I am actually
Speaker 5:  fascinated by all of that aspect of this case in particular
Speaker 5:  because, you know, the Google case we're talking about that was argued under
Speaker 5:  the Biden administration, it was filed on their first Trump administration
Speaker 5:  argued under the Biden administration by Jonathan Cantor who has been on
Speaker 5:  our shows before. I'm trying to get him to come back and actually talk about
Speaker 5:  it,
Speaker 5:  but you know, like I've asked Cantor like you're the assistant attorney general
Speaker 5:  for antitrust, like how do you run your team? And he had like answers, you
Speaker 5:  know, like, he's like, here's how I do decisions, here's how I like prioritize.
Speaker 5:  And they were very good. Right? And that's the DOJ, which was
Speaker 5:  basically a different law firm with a different boss. This case is the FTC,
Speaker 5:  which was run by Lean Conn different law firm. Like that's the way to think
Speaker 5:  about it. Like these, the DOJ and the FTC have different legal teams. They
Speaker 5:  might have the same theories or the same goals, different lawyers, different
Speaker 5:  legal teams, different relationships to the president, right? The
Speaker 5:  DOJ is a law enforcement organization. The FTC is a law
Speaker 5:  enforcement organization like in a civil way, right? Like they're just different.
Speaker 5:  And Ferguson in particular is caught up. That new chair of the
Speaker 5:  FTC under Trump, his democratic commissioners
Speaker 5:  were fired. Like Trump fired them. They're suing him.
Speaker 5:  It will go to the Supreme Court and like a hundred year old precedent
Speaker 5:  about whether the president can just fire FTC commissioners is gonna
Speaker 5:  come up for a review. So Ferguson is in this weird box, right?
Speaker 5:  He has a boss who shouldn't be able to
Speaker 5:  fire him, but has proven that he will and like break the law and like
Speaker 5:  go fight at the Supreme Court under this
Speaker 5:  conception that the president is a chief executive of the country and makes
Speaker 5:  all the decisions, which is not true, but kind of true. It's like very
Speaker 5:  weird, right? He's just in this weird spot and he is got this case that was
Speaker 5:  argued by a bunch of his predecessors and now everyone else got
Speaker 5:  fired too because of Doge. So he is got all these baby lawyers
Speaker 5:  and he's, he, he has to play the role of like the fire breather that everyone
Speaker 5:  else has to play now. And so of course he's on Fox business
Speaker 5:  being like, the reason I'm pursuing this case is because Donald Trump
Speaker 5:  didn't get a candy bar on January 6th, 2020 or like whatever It is,
Speaker 5:  right? Right. But that's not why this case started. That's not why this case
Speaker 5:  was pursued under Le Conn Biden. That's not why they kept the
Speaker 5:  case going. That's not why they kept the case going. Even though Mark Zuckerberg
Speaker 5:  has been in the Oval Office repeatedly saying that he'll make
Speaker 5:  a deal for numbers that range from like $5 to
Speaker 5:  like $3 trillion. Like just numbers. Yeah. Like me, like just a range of
Speaker 5:  numbers. That's none of that's the real reason. But I think to
Speaker 5:  keep Trump from firing him or making a deal or undercutting this
Speaker 5:  populist antitrust movement that is pretty bipartisan,
Speaker 5:  he's got to say this is about censorship or Andrew Ferguson has
Speaker 5:  fully converted to Maga like our buddy Brennan Carr and it's about censorship.
Speaker 5:  Like I don't, I, I truly don't know, but that's just the
Speaker 5:  weird uncertainty inside all of this.
Speaker 6:  He is very much doing the thing you have to do no matter how you feel about
Speaker 6:  it. Like whe whether he is just a zealot who wants to win this case or is
Speaker 6:  just actually purely in it for the politics, you would do the same thing,
Speaker 6:  which makes it weird. Like that is the speech you give on Fox business,
Speaker 6:  no matter how you feel about actually what's going on in this
Speaker 7:  Case. Yeah. I mean he tells the world it, it's to keep, you know, J six,
Speaker 7:  you know, Trump getting kicked off from happening again. But like inside
Speaker 7:  the courtroom there was nothing about censorship, nothing. It was
Speaker 7:  not in any of the FTCs arguments because it's not, you
Speaker 7:  know, private companies can do whatever they want as it relates to speech.
Speaker 7:  That's that's the constitution. That's
Speaker 6:  How that works. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  At least for now, and like me, we censorship
Speaker 7:  never came up once in the three days Zuckerberg was on the stand.
Speaker 6:  Interesting. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  'cause the case is fundamentally about did you perceive Instagram to be a
Speaker 5:  competitor and buy it to preclude competition? Right. Did you
Speaker 5:  perceive WhatsApp to be a challenger and buy it to preclude
Speaker 5:  competition? And
Speaker 7:  They absolutely did. Yeah. I've been covering this company for a long time.
Speaker 7:  Some of the emails they were showing and internal documents, like I actually
Speaker 7:  like scooped back in the day. It was actually wild to watch like internal
Speaker 7:  documents that I remember first publishing being shown in this courtroom.
Speaker 7:  Like, and it was all about that. And It is totally true that yes, they
Speaker 7:  saw Instagram and WhatsApp as competitors. They weren't
Speaker 7:  direct competitors, but they foresaw them becoming that
Speaker 7:  to the point that, you know, there's words like neutralized that Zuckerberg
Speaker 7:  said, you know, that these famous emails that have now been out for a while,
Speaker 7:  I was expecting the FTC to show some new evidence. And,
Speaker 7:  and there were a couple things. I would say the only time inside the courtroom
Speaker 7:  where like you could feel the Meta trial team bench kind of just like
Speaker 7:  set up a little bit was when they started reading, they
Speaker 7:  started having Zuckerberg read this memo to his exec team in 2018
Speaker 7:  where he said, I think we should spin off Instagram. And literally said
Speaker 7:  that companies tend to do better after they've been spun off.
Speaker 5:  I'm telling you, man, do it before the government does it for you. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  If you think you're so much smarter than all these government flunkies,
Speaker 7:  You probably are. Yeah. Mark
Speaker 5:  Zuckerberg's a smart guy. Do it in a way that meets your interests, that
Speaker 5:  makes everybody money before the people you perceive you dumber to. You do
Speaker 5:  it to you on behalf of the American people. Yeah. Just do it first.
Speaker 5:  I I continue to believe that is the smartest answer for most of these companies.
Speaker 5:  To do it in a way that satisfies the optics of all these people but preserves
Speaker 5:  the business. Yeah. And like, I don't think, I don't think they will learn
Speaker 5:  that lesson and I think we're gonna see a bunch of weird breakups coming,
Speaker 5:  but it's just very funny that Mark saw it. Yeah. Right. He was like, oh,
Speaker 5:  I should spin this out and let it become its own thing. Yeah. 'cause it'll
Speaker 5:  go faster.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I mean, you can't deny, when you look at these lengthy
Speaker 7:  like exec memos, he writes inside the court like he's a, he's a brilliant
Speaker 7:  strategist. And in 2018 ahead of the Biden administration, he was writing
Speaker 7:  to his team. I think especially with the
Speaker 7:  Democratic administration, big tech's gonna get broken up.
Speaker 7:  We should be thinking about this seriously and planning for it. And
Speaker 7:  you know, he saw all this coming. And so at the same
Speaker 7:  time though, he's like grinning and saying, I would totally buy WhatsApp
Speaker 7:  again. It was awesome. Like, and that's the tension,
Speaker 7:  right? Is like you have him acknowledging and the
Speaker 7:  FCC presenting evidence that he knew that the company was gonna face these
Speaker 7:  calls to get broken up. Broken up. And then I'm sitting in the courtroom
Speaker 7:  and I'm watching the argument for doing it and I'm looking over at the
Speaker 7:  Meta people and they're literally like sometimes high fiving as they walk
Speaker 7:  out on breaks. Like they feel like this is a layup. Like they're just gonna
Speaker 7:  crush this case. And that's, it's a bummer.
Speaker 7:  It's a bummer for like taxpayers, it's a bummer for holding power
Speaker 7:  to account. Like there is actually power here that needs to be addressed
Speaker 7:  in some way. I think there's more interesting arguments to be made around
Speaker 7:  interoperability. Why is there so much energy around the fedi verse?
Speaker 7:  It's because people feel the actual cost of these
Speaker 7:  platforms, which is taking your speech and your network with you should a
Speaker 7:  platform as large as Meta have to allow interoperability. That's something
Speaker 7:  I would love the government to, to look at. But instead they're like,
Speaker 7:  you're competing with me. We,
Speaker 6:  It, It is very strange because I'm, I'm so torn between like my
Speaker 6:  principles and how I feel about technology and the internet and
Speaker 6:  like, I, I would like using WhatsApp more if it weren't
Speaker 6:  owned by Meta. Like that's just, I it's just how I feel a
Speaker 7:  Lot of people feel that way. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I, and yet every single thing I have seen
Speaker 6:  and read about this trial makes me agree with Meta.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And, and there's just so many moments, like, so much of this
Speaker 6:  discussion seems to have been basically the
Speaker 6:  FTC saying to Zuckerberg and the other witnesses, like, you bought
Speaker 6:  these companies because they were threats and, and they're sort of like,
Speaker 6:  well sure. Like we, we thought that they might be, but also they are only
Speaker 6:  as successful as they are because they are part of this company. And I, I
Speaker 6:  like, again, I hate how compelling I find that argument.
Speaker 7:  The evidence is, it's irrefutable. It
Speaker 6:  Is. And and I think the, the WhatsApp piece of It is, is my absolute favorite
Speaker 6:  because there, there was a bunch of evidence presented that basically
Speaker 6:  the, the WhatsApp guys were just happy. They were just like, they, they remind
Speaker 6:  me of like, when Microsoft tried to buy Nintendo and Nintendo was like, what
Speaker 6:  do we want with your money? Like, leave us alone. We're having a great time
Speaker 6:  over here. But the, the basically, like, you, you heard this more than I
Speaker 6:  did Alex, but my, my impression was basically like Zuckerberg goes to talk
Speaker 6:  to the WhatsApp co-founders and he's like, he's like, don't you wanna have
Speaker 6:  lots of features and sell ads and take over the world and you're gonna be
Speaker 6:  huge? And they were just like, not really. No.
Speaker 7:  No. They said they wanted to be Craigslist and Zuckerberg.
Speaker 6:  Like
Speaker 7:  Hell yeah. And Zuckerberg was like, one
Speaker 6:  Of us should wanna be Craigslist.
Speaker 7:  So, and then the judge is like, how does Craigslist work? And then Zuck is
Speaker 7:  like, well Boberg feels like a Craigslist guy. I have to say if I had to
Speaker 7:  pick
Speaker 6:  One platform for Judge Boberg,
Speaker 7:  It would be Craigslist. Yeah. And, and Mark was like, or next door and Mark
Speaker 7:  was like, I, I didn't want them to be Craigslist. Like I saw this being a
Speaker 7:  billion plus user platform. And he literally called Y kmb the CO of
Speaker 7:  WhatsApp unambitious after he met with him the first time. And
Speaker 7:  that really cuts at the FTCs argument because intent alone
Speaker 7:  does not prove you did something to become a monopoly. You act as,
Speaker 7:  as far as I understand it, the government has to show that Meta degraded
Speaker 7:  the marketplace by, you know, buying competition. That
Speaker 7:  basically these apps, these services got worse. Prices went up. They
Speaker 7:  can't argue that 'cause it's free. Right. Although they're trying to make
Speaker 7:  some ad load argument that's not really even sticking as they're saying it
Speaker 7:  in court.
Speaker 7:  And then Zuckerberg can just say no, like we, and they're showing the board
Speaker 7:  decks where like they projected to get to X user milestone. They way surpassed
Speaker 7:  it way faster. Nearly 3 billion people use
Speaker 7:  WhatsApp now, which is the first time I've heard of WhatsApp user stat in
Speaker 7:  years, something Zuckerberg said on the stand,
Speaker 7:  Instagram, he was like, Kevin's sister and I, we thought we could get to
Speaker 7:  a hundred million users and if we did that, that would be a success. And
Speaker 7:  it got to a billion within a few years. And so
Speaker 7:  it's hard to argue that Instagram and WhatsApp became
Speaker 7:  meaningfully worse. Now I know everyone is listening and going, I come on,
Speaker 7:  what are you saying? Like, I hate Instagram. I love it, but I hate it. Right?
Speaker 7:  And that's the tension of the case is that people do feel strongly that
Speaker 7:  these apps could be better if, if Meta and its incentives weren't, weren't
Speaker 7:  behind them. But if you look at the marketplace, it's like there was a
Speaker 7:  lot of times spent on path. Right. Which, like, I had not thought about
Speaker 7:  Path in so long.
Speaker 6:  I was just gonna mention Path. Path caught so many strays in this trial.
Speaker 6:  It was so
Speaker 7:  Brutal. My, and it was because Zuckerberg also looked at buying Path
Speaker 7:  and Path is an example of a startup that he didn't buy and it
Speaker 7:  died and it's been lost to the, you know, to to
Speaker 7:  tech history. And he
Speaker 6:  Talked about it in exactly the same way, which is I think why Meta kept bringing
Speaker 6:  this up, that it was like it was the same. Like this is growing. People really
Speaker 6:  love it. Maybe it's a threat. Like he talked about it in the same terms he
Speaker 6:  talked about Instagram and it's like, look at the one that they bought and
Speaker 6:  look at the one that they didn't. And It is, I I'm not saying those two things
Speaker 6:  are like predictive, right? Like correlation causation. But
Speaker 6:  one is Instagram and one is not.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Well, okay, so I will, I'm I'm gonna try to use Zuckerberg's own argument
Speaker 5:  against him. Okay. Because It is true that Zucks strategy
Speaker 5:  memos and even It is like dashed off emails where he like emails a random
Speaker 5:  engineer and It is like I had this idea and the engineer's like
Speaker 5:  help. You know, like the ideas are always really good 'cause he's smart
Speaker 5:  and he is ruthless and he, there's an email, it's one of the emails
Speaker 5:  you scooped back in the day, Alex, where he's like, my insight is that
Speaker 5:  every generation comes up with a new sharing mechanic and I need to buy the
Speaker 5:  sharing mechanic. Yeah. So we had friends and family updates on Facebook,
Speaker 5:  Instagram is photo sharing. And then he clearly saw that messaging was the
Speaker 5:  next one with WhatsApp, right? Yeah. And this tracks everything Facebook
Speaker 5:  and Instagram say about themselves. Yeah. All the action is in the dms.
Speaker 5:  They say this all the time. So you just see Mark was like, okay, I had
Speaker 5:  this mechanic. I see the next one is gonna be photo sharing. I'm gonna buy
Speaker 5:  that mechanic. What's the hottest thing there? Okay, the next one is obviously
Speaker 5:  private messaging. I'm gonna buy that mechanic. What's the hottest thing
Speaker 5:  I can buy there? And he just did it. And I could not
Speaker 5:  tell you what that thing is as it relates to path check, checking
Speaker 5:  into play. Like what? What, I don't even remember what it was, but it wasn't
Speaker 5:  something where I'm like, oh, there's some core mechanic here that will
Speaker 5:  undercut the entire promise of Facebook. I think
Speaker 7:  It was their idea that the graph would be artificially limited. 'cause path
Speaker 7:  was like you could only add so many people. They based it on that. There
Speaker 7:  was like a theory,
Speaker 5:  But that's not a sharing dynamic. Right, right. That was past theory. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And even by Zuckerberg's own like framework, it would never be a
Speaker 5:  thing. The
Speaker 6:  Location based check-in thing was was real.
Speaker 5:  That was Foursquare. I
Speaker 6:  Know. But it was like it was all sitting right there. Right. This like sort
Speaker 6:  of real life geographic thing was like, was almost
Speaker 6:  that.
Speaker 5:  Sure. I like bring back Path David, let's do,
Speaker 6:  You could check in on Facebook Fe
Speaker 5:  Federated Path. It's the, it's the future. You can have six friends and all
Speaker 5:  of them are like, why am I here? But the next turn,
Speaker 5:  the one that they almost missed was, what if we show you videos
Speaker 5:  from people? You dunno. Truly. That was the next one. That was TikTok.
Speaker 5:  Was TikTok. And they immediately, they could not buy TikTok and And they
Speaker 5:  even said there was all these like Chinese issues. Yeah. Chinese ownership
Speaker 5:  issues with why we couldn't buy music.
Speaker 7:  Again, he looked at it before anyone else. He met the founder before it was
Speaker 7:  even in the US 'cause he knew this was coming and it was like I couldn't
Speaker 7:  do it 'cause of the China
Speaker 5:  Stuff. And they had to hard pivot Instagram and they had to compete.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Whatever you think of Instagram reels, It is a better competitor to
Speaker 5:  TikTok than YouTube shorts, right? Yep. Because they absolutely had to compete
Speaker 5:  and they are worthless and they're very good at, and they'll just do it.
Speaker 5:  And that's the market distortion that the government hasn't been able to
Speaker 5:  articulate. Like if Facebook had actually had to compete with an
Speaker 5:  Instagram that actually had this new dynamic that Mark Zuckerberg had identified,
Speaker 5:  things would be different. Both of those companies would be competing with
Speaker 5:  each other. Yeah. But that's, it's, it's still
Speaker 5:  illusory to David's point. You, you will never know. And Matt's argument
Speaker 5:  on the other side is pretty good. Which is, well I don't know. It's Instagram,
Speaker 5:  here It is.
Speaker 7:  I am not an expert on the edge cases of antitrust law enforcement and maybe
Speaker 7:  the FTC will finally get something through throughout this trial. That makes
Speaker 7:  sense. I have looked at an absurd amount of internal
Speaker 7:  Facebook documents over the years and their data
Speaker 7:  analysis, how they view the market and not stuff that like it's been PR
Speaker 7:  sanctioned, like stuff leaked to me. I feel like I actually have a under
Speaker 7:  the hood real assessment of how they view the world. They
Speaker 7:  think maniacally about time spent, about,
Speaker 7:  they talk like they're the un it's like population density. It's
Speaker 7:  like we are at X density in X country. They're thinking so much
Speaker 7:  broader than the ftc. They're thinking like, how can I suck time
Speaker 7:  away from Netflix, et cetera. Right? It's like the Reed Hastings quote. It
Speaker 7:  is like, I'm competing with sleep who was on the board of Facebook for like
Speaker 7:  15 years. That's how these companies operate because that's
Speaker 7:  the business model. And I don't think the FTC understands how the business
Speaker 7:  model informs the strategy, which is that if you're an advertising business
Speaker 7:  model, really all that matters is eyeballs and getting as much
Speaker 7:  of those eyeballs for as long as possible. And the only real monopoly
Speaker 7:  Meta has is its network, is its network effects. And the thing Zuck is
Speaker 7:  constantly trying to fight is a new thing coming in and eating into those
Speaker 7:  network effects, whether it was Google Plus back in the day, which got an
Speaker 7:  insane amount of airtime in this trial was very fun. I really felt like I
Speaker 7:  was getting like a, like a Stanford business cl like seminar,
Speaker 7:  like Silicon Valley tech history class. It was really fun. Google
Speaker 7:  Plus path, like OpenAI, which we'll talk about in a little bit,
Speaker 7:  snap these things that come in and like potentially siphon people away from
Speaker 7:  the network, which leads to a thing called network collapse, which they did
Speaker 7:  talk about in the courtroom that he just, like you said, he
Speaker 7:  recognized these formats and goes, I can graph this onto my bigger network,
Speaker 7:  I'll scale it faster. And that will make sure that the startup that invented
Speaker 7:  that form, whether it's stories or whatever, can't reach a billion
Speaker 7:  users. He kept saying over and over, he is like, once you get to a billion
Speaker 7:  users, like the world is your oyster. Like he's like, he's like, I really
Speaker 7:  like, there's very few companies that do that. Very few do it on their own.
Speaker 7:  He's like, he actually made the case that none have done it on their own.
Speaker 7:  That they all have big parent companies. YouTube, TikTok with Bite
Speaker 7:  Dance Snap is close to a billion. Yeah. I
Speaker 5:  Feel like, is this more Evan Spiegel shade? Like he, he, he can't get to
Speaker 5:  the magic number.
Speaker 7:  It was around the SNAP acquisition questions Yeah. Is when he said this.
Speaker 7:  And that's, he knows that's his competitive moat and that's, it's,
Speaker 7:  it's strong and it's durable and there are monopoly questions there, but
Speaker 7:  it's not like tying, it's not like what Google does with its products where
Speaker 7:  it, it's, it's just like he recognizes if he can get to something and strap
Speaker 7:  it onto his scale, he'll kill it. And he is done that very well
Speaker 7:  over the last 20 years.
Speaker 5:  We'll see what happens with this one. I, and again, I don't want to overdo
Speaker 5:  it on the, on the like legal inside baseball piece of
Speaker 5:  it, but you got like a dozed up FTC that fired everybody,
Speaker 5:  run by a guy who has to be a fire breather on Fox News to please
Speaker 5:  his boss who is absolutely shown that he will come
Speaker 5:  right up to the edge of the law and asked the Supreme Court to overturn a
Speaker 5:  hundred year old precedent and fire people that he's not supposed to fire.
Speaker 5:  Like that's not a recipe for great lawyering. Right.
Speaker 5:  And like I think the DOJ under Biden can't turn specifically like
Speaker 5:  having talked to him about how he ran what was effectively a law firm.
Speaker 5:  I was like, oh, they're doing good lawyering. I think they had a, they had
Speaker 5:  better cases to deal with because Google does have all these deals.
Speaker 5:  I am very curious. The DOJ has the Apple case, which has the same
Speaker 5:  dynamics as Meta here in big ways, right? It's just Apple. They're just
Speaker 5:  like, well we have the iPhone, we can just do whatever we want. iMessage,
Speaker 5:  here It is, blah, it's done. We'll see. Right. A lot
Speaker 5:  of this is once you have, once you own a platform, how dirty can you be and
Speaker 5:  is that illegal? Right? And some of the stuff with, with Apple is like,
Speaker 5:  we all know it App developers, like they, they call me and yell at me to
Speaker 5:  start in-app subscriptions because that's where they make the money from.
Speaker 5:  Is that, I don't know. But that was started under one
Speaker 5:  administration and now it's come to this one and
Speaker 5:  Pam Bondi is gonna pursue Apple. Like
Speaker 5:  there's just an element of that which is like, is it the government's case?
Speaker 5:  Is it the law that's bad? Is it that META'S Legal or Apple's legal or is
Speaker 5:  it just a bunch of Doge kids? Dunno what they're doing. There's and they're,
Speaker 5:  and they're up against Meta's lawyers. Right? Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And I, well I think there's also an element, you know, leaving DC and talking
Speaker 7:  to a lot of the Met execs, you know, 'cause they're all there and you know,
Speaker 7:  it was off the record, but just the vibe I got is like, I think there's a
Speaker 7:  consensus that Trump is going to be harder on all these companies than they
Speaker 7:  thought. And that Yeah, if they, they thought if they could just kiss up
Speaker 7:  that things would be easy. And I think Trump is a
Speaker 7:  little smarter than they maybe gave him credit for in terms of leverage.
Speaker 7:  And I, I, I think Meta would've very much liked to settle this case. Not
Speaker 7:  necessarily because they were worried about losing it, but because it's a,
Speaker 7:  it's a massive pain and it's a, it's a, you know, bad headlines. It's
Speaker 7:  Zuckerberg's time, a ton of money, et cetera.
Speaker 7:  The discovery process, which is very embarrassing. But
Speaker 7:  yeah, I, I would hope, I would think that, and you know, the journal had
Speaker 7:  a great story about this, that Hal Zuckerberg pushed to, to, you know, settle
Speaker 7:  this. I think he probably thought that he would,
Speaker 7:  might be able to, because of the, the January stuff that we talked about,
Speaker 7:  all the mago changes that they made. And Apple's gonna go to DOJ and
Speaker 7:  like I, I think all these CEOs are in for a kind of a leopard face moment
Speaker 7:  in the next year or so.
Speaker 6:  That photo that everybody has of all the CEOs standing on
Speaker 6:  the day is behind Trump at the inauguration, is going to end up being iconic
Speaker 6:  for reasons that none of those CEOs like. Exactly. Is my ongoing thesis
Speaker 5:  Actually, can I respond to that in a, like, just a slightly different I agree.
Speaker 5:  That photo will be very embarrassing. Yeah. For all of them because the leopards
Speaker 5:  are reading all their faces. It's happening. Trump wants these wins, then
Speaker 5:  he wants to settle, like he wants to win the trial so that he can negotiate
Speaker 5:  the settlement that ends the appeals. Right? That's, that's what you do.
Speaker 5:  The tariffs on China are 5000000000% and then we're gonna make a deal Trump,
Speaker 5:  the thing that kills me at that is the expectation they had
Speaker 5:  going into that photo was corruption, right? Tim
Speaker 5:  Cook is gonna personally donate a million dollars to Trump's library and
Speaker 5:  that'll take the DOJ case away from Apple naked
Speaker 5:  corruption. That is a nakedly corrupt thought. There's, there's nothing about,
Speaker 5:  and that's fine in the sense that like a lot of people believe the
Speaker 5:  government is corrupt and so like, Trump being even more corrupt
Speaker 5:  does not offend them. But it's
Speaker 5:  not fine in the sense that like, even when we were covering
Speaker 5:  the Google case today, people on Blue Sky were replying to me being like,
Speaker 5:  they'll just buy him off.
Speaker 3:  Yep.
Speaker 5:  What? Like that, that means that the system is collapsed. Like you
Speaker 5:  don't believe in it anymore and maybe you didn't before, but
Speaker 5:  like the level to Which we have accepted that
Speaker 5:  just naked corruption is how this works is a little more dangerous
Speaker 5:  than I think people are are giving it credit for. Like, if you believe
Speaker 5:  that Google can be like, oh, screw it, write 'em a check and it'll go away.
Speaker 5:  And that is, maybe you don't think that's right, but you think that is possible.
Speaker 5:  You've are it, it's gone. You have to not believe that's possible. You have
Speaker 5:  to actually hold everybody to account and say, actually that's corruption.
Speaker 5:  So I'm not saying call your senator and tell 'em to break up Google. Just
Speaker 5:  an idea that you could do.
Speaker 5:  I'm saying, I'm saying you can't, if you give into nihilism
Speaker 5:  that the corruption is already won, you've already, you've just given in
Speaker 5:  like, you should not feel helpless. You should feel outraged that the
Speaker 5:  expectation of that photograph was corruption. And there's t that there's
Speaker 5:  a little glimmer of hope that it ha it hasn't been just overt corruption
Speaker 5:  from the jump. Like they at least have to go to trial.
Speaker 5:  I dunno what's gonna happen after that. But they at least have had to go
Speaker 5:  to trial. I
Speaker 7:  Think Trump is more savvy about power and leverage than the CEOs thought
Speaker 7:  and knows that. Yeah. The moment he just starts
Speaker 5:  Taking checks or most of his checks tapers as we will come to.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah. And the moment you just start taking any check to kill anything,
Speaker 7:  you've lost power. And I think Trump cares about power.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. All right, we gotta take a break. We're gonna come back. We're gonna
Speaker 5:  talk about OpenAI, which is also making some moves to scare Mark Zuckerberg.
Speaker 5:  We'll be right back.
Speaker 5:  understand what's happening here. But yeah,
Speaker 5:  OpenAI has been for the last several weeks,
Speaker 7:  Showing off this internal prototype that is a kind of x like
Speaker 7:  social feed with a bunch of AI stuff in it. Apparently they're calling the
Speaker 7:  post yts, which for early Blue Sky users was the,
Speaker 7:  the name for posting on Blue Sky affectionately before Jake Grabber killed
Speaker 7:  that. Well, no, they were
Speaker 6:  Skeets on Blue Sky.
Speaker 7:  Oh wait, there were Skeet, which is worse. Not Eets
Speaker 6:  Somehow slightly worse on Blue Sky. No,
Speaker 5:  It's not slightly worse. It's horrible. It's a, it's a joke that is fully
Speaker 5:  out of control. Oh my God. And people still call them skeets, even though
Speaker 5:  I, I believe Blue Sky I prefer you didn't No.
Speaker 6:  Liz Lipato calls them skeets. No one else calls them Skeets. Don't
Speaker 5:  More people than than you want. Call them skeet. Does
Speaker 7:  Yeee Yeet come from something else though
Speaker 5:  That Ye's. Like a gamer term. It means like throw a thing into the ocean.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah, yeah. Okay. Yeah, so they're Ying and oh,
Speaker 6:  The Yeee myself off this podcast. That's
Speaker 5:  Right. See, that's, you understand what,
Speaker 7:  No, so they're, Sam Alman has been going around to conferences and
Speaker 7:  in private dinners, et cetera, and talking about how he wants to compete
Speaker 7:  with Elon and X and they have a prototype and we skipped
Speaker 7:  some of the details. It's very early. It's like, it's early, but o the way
Speaker 7:  OpenAI works is like something that's very early, could actually ship within
Speaker 7:  like a few weeks. So especially after I think
Speaker 7:  the reaction to this and all the headlines, and I think the story got
Speaker 7:  a lot more attention than maybe we even expected. So maybe that pushes them
Speaker 7:  to, to ship faster. I saw Kevin Wheel, their
Speaker 7:  CPO, who was the former head of product at Instagram,
Speaker 7:  gave an interview to Bloomberg shortly after the story saying like, we need
Speaker 7:  to find a way to let people share stuff that they do with Chad
Speaker 7:  GPT more easily. So they're already starting to hint at it. This puts
Speaker 7:  them on like a direct, you know, collision course with Elon obviously, but
Speaker 7:  also Zuckerberg who is adding a feed like
Speaker 7:  AI social network to its assistance. Later this year, they're
Speaker 7:  actually gonna turn the Meta RayBan app, the companion app into the Meta
Speaker 7:  AI app. So you'll still have to have it to pair with the glasses and
Speaker 7:  they're gonna ship new glasses later this year, but they're gonna have a
Speaker 7:  feed as well in there. So this is like a Grok and X merged
Speaker 7:  right through the same company. If you're on X, you'll see Grok, you
Speaker 7:  know, suggesting things in the responses. It's everywhere in the app. And
Speaker 7:  now the product teams are, are merged. So this trend is happening across
Speaker 7:  the industry. So it kind of makes sense for OpenAI to go here, you know,
Speaker 7:  chat, BT has been a, a, you know, a single player experience
Speaker 7:  and I think Open Eye recognizes that to, you
Speaker 7:  know, they're probably not thinking about this it this way, but really to
Speaker 7:  justify this in, in, you know, incredible valuation they have and all
Speaker 7:  this money that they've raised. They, they need to make money beyond
Speaker 7:  just selling chat GT subscriptions, though, I don't think they're gonna do
Speaker 7:  advertising anytime soon. I think this would be a natural, this is why I
Speaker 7:  said we may still talk about Ad tech.
Speaker 5:  Wait, what's the money if they don't do advertising, they start a social
Speaker 5:  network and there's an advertising. What's the money?
Speaker 7:  What's the money? Yeah, just running ads in the feed.
Speaker 7:  So It is, It is
Speaker 6:  Advertising, but it's not advertising in chat GPT, it's advertising in
Speaker 6:  social GPT or whatever
Speaker 7:  In the feed. That will probably it, they may do a standalone app, the prototype
Speaker 7:  is standalone, but they may just merge it with chat. GPT their
Speaker 7:  CFO. Sarah Friar was the CO of Nextdoor, which sold ads in a feed. Like they
Speaker 7:  have a lot, I mean, they could do this, it would make sense. And it
Speaker 7:  begins to explain to me why Zuckerberg has been so
Speaker 7:  focused on them beyond just the model competition, I think. And he was, it
Speaker 7:  was kind of interesting like publishing this story when I was in the courtroom,
Speaker 7:  like the same day I am like watching him on the stand saying like, look,
Speaker 7:  once you get to a billion users, you know,
Speaker 7:  really, like, it's, it's very hard to compete and you can
Speaker 7:  fan out and spread out, I think was his words and do a lot of different things.
Speaker 7:  And I think he probably saw this coming. So OpenAI is,
Speaker 7:  is approaching a billion users, they'll probably hit it this year
Speaker 7:  and they're just in this huge expansion product mode, right?
Speaker 7:  So they're going in a bunch of different directions. But I think the social
Speaker 7:  piece really makes the idea of
Speaker 7:  chatt PT being more than just a Google killer potentially.
Speaker 7:  Now they also want to be a Meta killer. So this is like the kind of
Speaker 7:  ever expanding ambition of Sam Altman. I think
Speaker 6:  This runs into one of the big trends
Speaker 6:  right now that I find like completely befuddling, which is that everyone
Speaker 6:  is now convinced that lots of people really want endless
Speaker 6:  feeds of AI generated content. And
Speaker 6:  maybe they do, maybe, maybe I'm the one who's wrong here, but like,
Speaker 6:  you know, listening to Mark Zuckerberg sit on stage and say people really
Speaker 6:  love ads. People love ads so much that we've actually considered at one point
Speaker 6:  having a feed of just ads because people like the ads as much as they like
Speaker 6:  the content, which to me reads not as we have great ads, but
Speaker 6:  we have shit content is like that's, you should take that as an insult, not
Speaker 6:  a compliment, but anyway. And then like everybody's building these creative
Speaker 6:  tools so that It is easier and easier to make stuff with AI and share it
Speaker 6:  on your feeds. And we're, we're like running headlong into all of
Speaker 6:  my social feeds are going to just be absolutely overrun by
Speaker 6:  AI content. They already are. And it seems to me what's happening is
Speaker 6:  OpenAI looked at like the, the Studio Ghibli thing, right? That like took
Speaker 6:  over the internet for two days and everybody was sharing the stuff they made
Speaker 6:  in chat GPT somewhere else. Yep. And they look at that and they're like,
Speaker 6:  okay, no, we need to own this whole cycle. And to me I'm like, no,
Speaker 6:  it's just AI all the way down and this is a disaster. And so I'm like,
Speaker 6:  I'm, I'm so, I don't know, I'm just lost between these two different things
Speaker 6:  that both seem to be happening and it doesn't not seem like a thing anyone
Speaker 6:  should want.
Speaker 7:  I mean, Eli, what you said on Blue Sky's, right? Everyone wants their own
Speaker 7:  distribution. I don't think they've want Yeah. These images
Speaker 7:  and the value and attention around them being just monetized
Speaker 7:  by Elon Musk who is actively suing them and trying to
Speaker 7:  literally keep them from existing. Dude, why won't Sam
Speaker 5:  Altman quit X and join Blue Sky? Like you
Speaker 5:  wanna compete with Elon, you've got this big problem. He's still on his platform
Speaker 5:  every day. Yeah. Like just do it. Stand up your own mast on server. I don't
Speaker 5:  do something other than that. Right.
Speaker 7:  The open eye people are constantly Yeah. Complaining about Elon. I'm like,
Speaker 7:  you're just giving him training data. Like your entire company is posting
Speaker 7:  nonstop on X all day long. And as a result the AI
Speaker 7:  industry is very active on X. Like X has lost a lot of
Speaker 7:  audience. But I would say the AI industry remains one of its core
Speaker 7:  audiences. Yeah. And I do think OpenAI would have a pretty
Speaker 7:  compelling pitch to take that audience with them on a,
Speaker 7:  on a different surface and it could end up being like
Speaker 7:  even more split, right? Where you just have like people who like Elon's version
Speaker 7:  of AI on X and, and the audience is fracture
Speaker 7:  even more. I think we're just gonna continue to see this constant fracturing.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's just like, it's, it's funny to me, like you can stand up your
Speaker 5:  own social network. You can, you can do all this stuff or you could just
Speaker 5:  stop using the one owned by the guy who hates you, who's your competitor,
Speaker 5:  but you
Speaker 7:  Still gotta eat. Where are you gonna eat
Speaker 5:  Threads? Like anything like find some obscure
Speaker 5:  European Mastodon server and be like, I live here now and like a bunch of
Speaker 5:  people will come with you 'cause you're Sam Altman, here's where the news
Speaker 5:  is gonna be. Yeah. Right. Like, here's where I'm gonna lowercase sad boy
Speaker 5:  tweet about no one liking. Like, you can do it anywhere you want,
Speaker 5:  but like he chooses to do it on X for some reason. And I'm assuming that
Speaker 5:  reason is the absolutely bizarre relationship between those two men.
Speaker 7:  I think it's also network effects. It's what we're talking about with Meta.
Speaker 7:  It's just the AI industry is there. It's where companies still announce news
Speaker 7:  tech, tech companies especially. And
Speaker 7:  I, I think OpenAI sees an opening because they're the hottest tech company
Speaker 7:  in the world right now to take that audience.
Speaker 6:  And I think the idea that if you're Sam Altman people will follow you to
Speaker 6:  your obscure ma on server. I'm not sure that's true. And I'm, and I'm, I
Speaker 6:  know for sure that if you're Sam Altman, you're not sure you wanna find out
Speaker 5:  If you have the confidence to just like roll up to, to roll up to the richest
Speaker 5:  people in the world and be like, here's what I need, a trillion dollars.
Speaker 5:  Like you should find out if people will follow you to a masteron server.
Speaker 6:  Like,
Speaker 5:  Like there's one person who has this, the sheer audacity to be
Speaker 5:  like, I need a billion, I need a trillion dollars to buy every GPU in the
Speaker 5:  world.
Speaker 6:  I mean, Elon Musk spent $44 billion to make himself cool on Twitter.
Speaker 6:  Like you, it's, it's, it's a harder thing to do than you think
Speaker 7:  Stargate is just to fund the biggest mast on server in the world.
Speaker 5:  There's this quote in your piece, Alex, it's by somebody who runs a different
Speaker 5:  AI company. Yeah. They're anonymous. The grok integration with X has made
Speaker 5:  everyone jealous, especially how people create viral tweets by getting to
Speaker 5:  say something stupid. Neil,
Speaker 6:  The next thing I said was about to be this quote. Very good. This is the
Speaker 6:  funniest I've ever read.
Speaker 5:  Very, it's, it's an incredible quote and it has just made me think about
Speaker 5:  AI art and how people react to it and the feeds being full of art and like
Speaker 5:  why people are into it. And the, and we've written a lot
Speaker 5:  about this, like Addie and I have like spent a lot of time being like, ai,
Speaker 5:  it's like, why are we, it's very much like someone telling you about their
Speaker 5:  dream. Like that's how I always feel. Like, has someone ever
Speaker 5:  excitedly told you about a dream they had and you're like, cool. And it's
Speaker 5:  like the most important thing that's ever happened to that person and just
Speaker 5:  the disparity and experience is just too vast to be overcome.
Speaker 5:  Like you were you riding a dolphin? Great. Like, that's like how I feel
Speaker 5:  every time CAIR. It's like very good. And I think the
Speaker 5:  Studio Ghibli stuff hit because of the incredible juxtaposition of
Speaker 5:  the art style and the creator hating it. And then you're making Guantanamo
Speaker 5:  Bay memes with it, right? Like there's something in there that was wrong,
Speaker 5:  like on a fundamental level, the thing itself
Speaker 5:  portrayed the great conflict of our time. And then you turn
Speaker 5:  to the next one and you're like, oh, you made an action figure of yourself.
Speaker 5:  Is that, oh my God, is that your MacBook? Like, who gives a shit? Like,
Speaker 5:  like who cares? And I think the AI industry is really misconstrued
Speaker 5:  what the interest was. It's not people talking about their dreams,
Speaker 5:  it's people stealing artistic expression And that driving
Speaker 5:  a wave of conflict. And then people being able to participate on
Speaker 5:  either side of that conflict in ways that like drive the conflict
Speaker 5:  forward or, or amplify it. Like no one was outraged when people
Speaker 5:  made their weird action vickers. Like no one felt bad about it.
Speaker 6:  No, it's just boring. It
Speaker 5:  Was just like, here's some stuff.
Speaker 6:  There's even diminishing returns on the outrage, right? Like you can't run
Speaker 6:  the studio Ghibli playbook over and over and over again. And I think,
Speaker 6:  like, I'll be honest that the, the novelty factor of
Speaker 6:  I asked Chad GBT to do something and look at this wacky thing it came back
Speaker 6:  with has lasted a lot longer than I expected. It's still very much
Speaker 6:  there. This is the thing that a lot of these companies are trading on, is
Speaker 6:  like, people think grok is silly and they they like that.
Speaker 6:  And maybe that'll last forever.
Speaker 5:  No, but the, even even the grok one, the conflict of the grok is really obvious,
Speaker 5:  right? Grok is often like, yeah, yeah, Elon's pretty racist
Speaker 5:  and that's hilarious, right? Like it's
Speaker 5:  subversive,
Speaker 6:  But it's, but it's not like I too can type Elon as racist
Speaker 6:  into a text box and then screenshot it. But you're
Speaker 5:  Not a robot controlled by Elon. Like there's nothing subversive about us
Speaker 5:  doing, we just do it all the time. Right?
Speaker 6:  But, but is that, is that gonna be funny forever? Like, this is my point,
Speaker 6:  I just, I don't know how many versions of that thing we're gonna
Speaker 6:  get before this just stops being interesting.
Speaker 7:  I mean, open AI's user base doubled after it launched that
Speaker 7:  chat, the upgraded image generation. So you can, right, because
Speaker 7:  it's
Speaker 5:  A new
Speaker 6:  Capability. Can we say that differently? A lot of people went to a website
Speaker 6:  after that happened. That's what happened. A lot of people went to a
Speaker 6:  website. It's not the same, it's just not the same thing. Like
Speaker 6:  there are a lot of people and the numbers are crazy. I I absolutely agree
Speaker 6:  with that. But like a lot of people went to a website.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, yeah. I just, I just, I I too have a problem with
Speaker 7:  like the Studio Ghibli thing in particular. Like the fact
Speaker 7:  that they picked the style of the guy who called, what did he call ai? He
Speaker 7:  said it was like a, a the, the Studio Ghibli founder. Didn't he say something
Speaker 7:  about how it's like a Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's like a crime against
Speaker 7:  Humanity. Crime against humanity. The fact that that was the style that went
Speaker 7:  viral feels, feels wrong. Yeah. But
Speaker 7:  I don't think we can discount the interests people have at scale with this
Speaker 7:  stuff and open, I sees it in their numbers. Sure.
Speaker 7:  Maybe it's like fleeting or maybe it's a, a
Speaker 7:  gimmick that can only be replicated so many times, like you're saying. But
Speaker 7:  I think, look, I think we're professional riders and we,
Speaker 5:  I'm sorry, insult to life itself.
Speaker 7:  Just insult to life itself. Yeah. We're, we're professional riders we like,
Speaker 7:  or it's our jobs, like, say say things on the internet. I think most people
Speaker 7:  look at x or threads or blue sky or whatever and they don't really know what
Speaker 7:  to say. And I think the, the tech product view
Speaker 7:  of this, just talking to the people inside these labs is that like
Speaker 7:  we see a, a demand for people who wanna engage and don't
Speaker 7:  necessarily know how to or are scared to, and AI will help them. AI will
Speaker 7:  give them ways to express themselves that they could not before. And it's
Speaker 7:  reflected in the metrics of how people are gravitating towards these products.
Speaker 7:  So yeah, like the, I think the culture class is gonna continue to have,
Speaker 7:  you know, a lot of like hand ringing and like rightful criticism of
Speaker 7:  how these companies approach things like ip. But I also think we can't deny
Speaker 7:  that this is a trend that is here to stay. I, I, I at least think so
Speaker 6:  I do buy that. But I think, I think that's a, that's a actually a really
Speaker 6:  great definition of AI as a tool in a, in a way that
Speaker 6:  I really like. Frank AI is an enabling tool for lots of things, I think is
Speaker 6:  actually really exciting. Yeah. But what I see so much of the
Speaker 6:  bet here being is that AI is going to keep being
Speaker 6:  sort of the main character. Hmm. And it, and, and again, it has been for
Speaker 6:  much longer than I expected, so maybe I'm just wrong and maybe this thing
Speaker 6:  is so funny and silly and weird and unexpected that people will keep wanting
Speaker 6:  to interact with it forever.
Speaker 6:  But it just, that just does not feel right to me. I don't know,
Speaker 7:  I don't think the open eye social network's gonna be just like an endless
Speaker 7:  feed of only people's like Ghibli photos. I think like
Speaker 7:  it's a jumping point to build a AI native social network
Speaker 7:  that uses AI throughout the entire posting and editing and, and
Speaker 7:  publishing and recommendation process that like every other
Speaker 7:  established company is now trying to retrofit. And OpenAI has this insane,
Speaker 7:  highly engaged user base that they, I think they think they can fan out and
Speaker 7:  take this opportunity. Especially with what Google's going through, like
Speaker 7:  we were talking about and the fact that these other companies seem to just
Speaker 7:  not get product in this way. So yeah, I I think,
Speaker 7:  I think it's gonna be a disaster, but it's also the future which is like
Speaker 7:  kind of AI
Speaker 5:  Nutshell, The Verge everybody Yeah.
Speaker 5:  There's other stuff going on in AI world. Open eye debuted
Speaker 5:  GP 4.1 and then Sam was like, I promise I'm gonna
Speaker 5:  clear up these names. God, they're so bad. What is going on here? Like
Speaker 5:  it's, it's better, right? It's the newest
Speaker 6:  Better one. I personally so vindicated by this because I've been complaining
Speaker 6:  about the names on this show and elsewhere for forever, that when you go,
Speaker 6:  it's like a dropdown of nonsensical numbers where
Speaker 6:  they don't even go up in order in the way that you think that they should.
Speaker 6:  And so to have Sam be like, yeah, we know the numbers are ridiculous, please
Speaker 6:  make fun of so we're gonna fix it. Made me, made me feel a lot better.
Speaker 7:  Something else. OpenAI and Google share besides their bitter AI rivalry is
Speaker 7:  a horrible naming convention for their models. But
Speaker 6:  Alex, am I crazy? Is OpenAI on like a pretty wild product
Speaker 6:  run here? Like it's it's really the, there was deepsea. Yeah. And then they
Speaker 6:  were like, oh, we're gonna launch some stuff and like, boy have they, it
Speaker 7:  Seems unprecedented to a degree where it's like hard to
Speaker 7:  even keep up as someone covering it. My understanding is this model
Speaker 7:  architecture is their first, and I, I still feel like I'm trying to
Speaker 7:  understand really what this means practically, but like agentic model that
Speaker 7:  has now, it's the first one that does the deep thinking stuff,
Speaker 7:  but also can hook into all of the chat GPT products. So it can pull in web
Speaker 7:  results, do multimodal, it can like
Speaker 7:  apparently like do really interesting weird things with images and like edit
Speaker 7:  them and turn them around and like people are dropping an image like have
Speaker 7:  it reverse engineer where it was taken. So like the YouTube, like Google
Speaker 7:  Earth guy, like viral stuff, but like with ai.
Speaker 7:  So it's just a, it's a smarter model that now hooks
Speaker 7:  into all of the product. Whereas the models have so far been fairly sequestered
Speaker 7:  to certain aspects of chat GPT and what it can do. That's
Speaker 7:  my understanding of it. But they're, they're on such a tear, it's really
Speaker 7:  hard to keep track. I mean it's
Speaker 5:  Interesting 'cause the tear seems to be more related to
Speaker 5:  making better products out of all the products.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Or like attaching capabilities between products to each other to
Speaker 5:  get to the next step as opposed to here's the next new
Speaker 5:  model which is smarter than the last model by Yeah. However many percentage.
Speaker 5:  I do wonder if that's because Kevin Miles there, he's the product guy and
Speaker 5:  he is like, make the products good, but there's also a part where it feels
Speaker 5:  like the frontier model is not gonna get so much better. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That it drives usage. You actually have to like make products.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I've been writing about this for a while. The, the competitive nature
Speaker 7:  now is at the product layer, not the model layer. The models are commodifying.
Speaker 7:  Yes. Like they still feel different like when you use a new one. But I think
Speaker 7:  chat GBT, they're trying to make it like an operating system for your life.
Speaker 7:  I think they want to be Google Meta,
Speaker 7:  you know, product all productivity software. It's this,
Speaker 7:  it's, it's one of the grandest visions I've ever seen in like consumer tech
Speaker 7:  in terms of like, we are gonna use AI to try to do everything and,
Speaker 7:  and then he is working with Johnny Ive on hardware, right? That like you,
Speaker 7:  you tie that into your own hardware over time. What
Speaker 5:  If humane but good.
Speaker 7:  What if human made the good?
Speaker 6:  I mean, and to be clear, this is the story you have to tell in order to raise
Speaker 6:  the amount of money that they have raised. It
Speaker 7:  Is, but, but, but you look at what they're doing to chat GBT And that is
Speaker 7:  clearly the goal is like to Oh yeah. Encompass more of your everyday life.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean there was the, was it this week that they announced the thing
Speaker 6:  where it'll remember all your past conversations, which is think Yeah. The
Speaker 6:  memory stuff. I feel like that didn't get talked about enough that that's
Speaker 6:  like all of a sudden if you, if you can have this thing be sort of accumulating
Speaker 6:  over time as you use it, the, the possibilities of stuff it can start
Speaker 6:  to do for you. It is really powerful.
Speaker 7:  It's lockin too. 'cause it knows more about you and it's way easier to, it's
Speaker 7:  way harder to wanna switch to another product because Chachi pet knows everything
Speaker 7:  about you.
Speaker 6:  Totally.
Speaker 5:  I realize I'm saying this is a guy who's on a been on a podcast for 15 years,
Speaker 5:  like has made a lot of YouTube videos and I just don't wanna be perceived
Speaker 5:  in this way. Like I, I don't want the computer to know me.
Speaker 7:  It already
Speaker 5:  Does. No, thank you. It's
Speaker 7:  Already showing you ads for like random car stuff. Like,
Speaker 5:  Oh man already knows you, my computer so believes that I'm gonna buy a Volvo
Speaker 5:  ex 90, like whatever, whatever's going on in here, it knows one
Speaker 5:  thing and it's gonna sell me a goddamn Volvo EX 19.
Speaker 6:  I feel like your computer's wrong about that.
Speaker 5:  It's so wrong about, about that. It's not correct. Also a Range Rover,
Speaker 5:  it really believes that what I'm gonna do is probably a Range Rover sport
Speaker 5:  And that
Speaker 6:  That feels closer.
Speaker 5:  It's not, I I I've looked at the reliability records of that vehicle. I
Speaker 7:  Just wanna like, I real thing, do you guys use the voice mode on Chachi pt?
Speaker 5:  All the timely, I was actually just looking at my history to be like, what
Speaker 5:  would this thing think about me? And it will think that I'm a 6-year-old
Speaker 5:  girl who occasionally asks for pickled red onion recipes. And that's,
Speaker 5:  that's like, those are the two things that happen
Speaker 7:  When I was in DC Yeah, we
Speaker 5:  Use it all the time. Like Max and I use it all the time.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. When I was in DC I was like, before I was the first day of court, I
Speaker 7:  was like laying in bed and I was like, I'm going to court tomorrow this court.
Speaker 7:  Like I'm not exactly sure how it's gonna work. Like what do I need to know
Speaker 7:  about going in? Like what can I not bring? And like it was, it was
Speaker 7:  amazing. Like it was like this is, I I can't believe it just, it works.
Speaker 7:  Was it
Speaker 5:  Correct?
Speaker 7:  Yes, it was correct. Yeah. And that, that's like I, I don't
Speaker 7:  know if they're doing better grounding with like real data that they're stealing
Speaker 7:  or what, but it's, I'm, excuse me, buying
Speaker 7:  licensing
Speaker 5:  Now I have to disclose it,
Speaker 5:  licensing deal with our company somewhere on the back end. It's, it's there.
Speaker 5:  I yeah, it it has nothing to do with us.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. But no, I I think like the combo of like the, the, the desktop product
Speaker 7:  really starting to encompass like all the productivity, the voice being very
Speaker 7:  good and then them doing hardware with Johnny I think is like this
Speaker 7:  insane play for everything.
Speaker 6:  The vision is really big. And I, and I think you're right that It is the,
Speaker 6:  the shift has really happened away from like, we, I think
Speaker 6:  pretty quickly we're gonna start to have conversations internally at The
Speaker 6:  Verge about whether we cover new models because it's, it's rapidly
Speaker 6:  getting to the point that it doesn't matter that much. It's like, it's like
Speaker 6:  covering new versions of AWS software. Like it's just, it's just not
Speaker 6:  meaningful to most people in these specific ways. I don't
Speaker 6:  think we're there yet.
Speaker 7:  We could just do a story stream where it's like new model came out.
Speaker 6:  Like yeah, like new model came out, it's 4% better.
Speaker 5:  Well, I mean you, you gotta cover the new models because they're all cheating
Speaker 5:  on the benchmarks and that's actually the story. Well yeah,
Speaker 6:  Agreed, agreed on that front. But yeah, we are, we are very much
Speaker 6:  moving toward like what can you build to have people
Speaker 6:  do with these things? And that's gonna be the only thing that matters.
Speaker 5:  I continue to believe, I mean the whole industry has been chasing what is
Speaker 5:  the new input paradigm that overtakes
Speaker 5:  multitouch forever. Like even Apple has been chasing, we,
Speaker 5:  I'm constantly joking about Apple, introducing the Apple watch to the digital
Speaker 5:  Crown. 'cause they, in their head, they have like a system,
Speaker 5:  like an equation that makes good products and they just learned it from
Speaker 5:  watching old Steve Jobs keynotes. Like they reversed engineer to Steve Jobs
Speaker 5:  keynote and he is like, well he did a click wheel, he did U2
Speaker 5:  was there and he said it was small. And then they got to the Apple
Speaker 5:  watch and they're like, okay, it's got a wheel. U2 is here and it's small.
Speaker 5:  Like,
Speaker 6:  It's
Speaker 5:  Like that's just how their brains work. You know,
Speaker 5:  everyone has been trying to move on to say, okay, this is the new input,
Speaker 5:  this is the new user interface paradigm that's gonna drive the next form
Speaker 5:  factor that's gonna drive the next wave of apps, whatever It is. And It is
Speaker 5:  true that with AI in particular, what you have is natural
Speaker 5:  language voice. So you can just talk to the computer, it'll talk back to
Speaker 5:  you. It's a very compelling and then we still
Speaker 5:  dunno how any of that's gonna make money. And then at the same time, right,
Speaker 5:  there's the big cursor deal, which seems like a really big deal. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  then OpenAI is going to potentially buy this company called Windsurf for
Speaker 5:  $3 billion. Yeah. There's this whole enterprise set of applications that
Speaker 5:  has kind of nothing to do with, is this a new input paradigm? It's much more,
Speaker 5:  oh, we're gonna make everybody vastly more productive in this specific way.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And that's where all the money is.
Speaker 5:  And that's, that does feel like where all the money is. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But I, the part where Johnny Ive is like, I can take the new input paradigm
Speaker 5:  and make the next great product. It, it's, even if it's Johnny,
Speaker 5:  ive, even if it's Sam Altman, even if they have direct access to the next
Speaker 5:  model from open, like it's still uncertain because it,
Speaker 5:  it hasn't been proven that that's what you wanna do all the time.
Speaker 6:  I'm actually very excited about this next moment because I, I wrote a feature
Speaker 6:  for Wired like 10 years ago now. Basically
Speaker 6:  proclaiming the beginning of the voice era.
Speaker 5:  You were a
Speaker 7:  Little early.
Speaker 6:  I was, I was rough. Right. And I was wrong. Right. Like it was, it it happened.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Everybody started doing voice, but in much more limited ways than I
Speaker 6:  think I was expecting. Yeah. But we're now at the point where the tech works.
Speaker 6:  Like, it's, it's not perfect, but it works. The, the basic
Speaker 6:  can I speak and be spoken to with a computer in a useful way?
Speaker 6:  It works. And now the open question is,
Speaker 6:  so what, what do we do with that? And that no one has good answers to that
Speaker 6:  yet. Right. Like it's, it's fun and interesting. Yeah. But we're sitting
Speaker 6:  on more and if there's gonna be more, it's coming.
Speaker 7:  I think we're gonna be talking about the Johnny thing with Sam Altman in
Speaker 7:  the coming year to two years. I really do. I think Johnny's
Speaker 7:  biggest funder for his new company is Lre Pal Jobs. Like it's, and he's
Speaker 7:  hired all of the original Apple team design team. If you're
Speaker 7:  gonna bet on anyone coming in as like a wild horse and, and doing
Speaker 7:  something interesting, I would be paying attention to that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And meanwhile Apple is going under whatever series shuffles it's
Speaker 5:  undergoing. Right? Like who knows, who knows that they can, they can pull
Speaker 5:  it off. But you know, apple, we started by talking about opening, starting
Speaker 5:  a social network. Apple still has the most important distribution of all.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Right. It's just like in your pocket, like Oprah at the Apple TV launch
Speaker 5:  being like a billion pockets, you know, like
Speaker 5:  if they can get it together, like maybe they'll get there. But it's interesting
Speaker 5:  that they're wavering and Google is wavering and then Sam Altman's
Speaker 5:  like, I need a trillion dollars. Yeah. And I just dunno how that plays out.
Speaker 5:  All right. We gotta take a break. We're gonna come back with a lightning
Speaker 5:  round. We'll be right back.
Speaker 5:  So Brenda loves to threaten or even file what he
Speaker 5:  calls news distortion cases or the FCC, which licenses the nation's
Speaker 5:  airwaves to broadcasters can say to various news
Speaker 5:  organizations, the broadcast news organizations,
Speaker 5:  N-B-C-C-B-S, Fox, Hey, you're distorting news. You're taking the
Speaker 5:  spectrum, we're giving you and doing something misleading with the news on
Speaker 5:  it. They're not supposed to do this in most cases. Right? The First
Speaker 5:  Amendment protects those broadcasters and you can air what you want to air
Speaker 5:  as long as you're not being willfully misleading in particular ways.
Speaker 5:  And It is true that Fox owns a bunch of broadcast stations. Sinclair
Speaker 5:  Broadcasting very conservative, owns a bunch of broadcast stations. And yes,
Speaker 5:  NBC and CBS and a BC also own a bunch of podcast stations.
Speaker 5:  So you can see already Americans have choices. But this
Speaker 5:  week the Trump administration is under tremendous amounts of criticism
Speaker 5:  and controversy because it mistakenly deported a man to
Speaker 5:  El Salvador, Kmar Abrego Garcia. It did this with
Speaker 5:  basically no evidence. It has admitted to the court that it had
Speaker 5:  no real evidence And that this was a mistake. I call it administrative error.
Speaker 5:  And instead of bringing a man back, which the Supreme Court ordered,
Speaker 5:  it had to facilitate. It is doubled down now on calling him a
Speaker 5:  terrorist and a gang member. The evidence, by the way, this may be a gang
Speaker 5:  member, is that he was wearing a Chicago Bulls hat and a t-shirt
Speaker 5:  with dollar bills on it, or a sweatshirt with dollar bills on it, where the
Speaker 5:  presidents on the bills had their eyes covered, ears covered and, and mouth
Speaker 5:  covered. And somehow that indicated that they, they were in a gang. I don't
Speaker 5:  know, man. That's the evidence the government has proffered this week for
Speaker 5:  evidence that he's being in a gang. It's not great.
Speaker 6:  It's nothing is what It is. It's nothing.
Speaker 5:  It's it's nothing. I mean, this is a, he was in the country legally, but
Speaker 5:  he had a, a, a court order saying he couldn't be deported because he,
Speaker 5:  his, he was in danger if he went to El Salvador from other gangs there. So
Speaker 5:  the court, the Trump administration has mistakenly deported him. They've
Speaker 5:  gone up to the Supreme Court, which has ruled that has to facilitate his
Speaker 5:  return. They've gone to the court again, the court is very angry with him,
Speaker 5:  with the Trump administration. Now, I don't know how this is gonna play out,
Speaker 5:  but news organizations around the country have been covering it and
Speaker 5:  covering in particular fact that there's no evidence that this man was actually
Speaker 5:  an MSN 13. Like, not like none at all outside
Speaker 5:  of a hat and one confidential informant that nobody has ever. No, you, you
Speaker 5:  were good at, none at all. That was, you were, you were set there. That's
Speaker 5:  not at all. Yeah. So Brendan this week has decided to threaten
Speaker 5:  Comcast disclosure. Comcast is an investor in Vox Media, but truly
Speaker 5:  they dislike me. He decided to threaten Comcast this week.
Speaker 5:  He said Comcast outlets have spent days misleading the American public, implying
Speaker 5:  that a Braigo Garcia was merely a law abiding citizen, just a regular Maryland
Speaker 5:  man. When the truth comes out, what is the truth, Brendan? They ignore
Speaker 5:  it. Comcast knows that federal law requires its licensed operations to
Speaker 5:  serve the public interest. News distortion doesn't cut it.
Speaker 5:  Abrego Garcia came to America legally from El Salvador, was validated as
Speaker 5:  a member of the violent MS 13 gang, a transnational
Speaker 5:  criminal organization and denied bond by immigration court for failure
Speaker 5:  to show he cannot pose a danger to others. Why does Comcast ignore these
Speaker 5:  facts? Because they're not facts, Brendan. They're just not facts.
Speaker 5:  And actually the job of news organizations we run, one is to
Speaker 5:  question the government, is to take the political figures of our
Speaker 5:  government, to take the Attorney general, to take JD Vance
Speaker 5:  and say, is that true? Is it true what you're saying? We've
Speaker 5:  given you the power to jail people. The state has a monopoly
Speaker 5:  on violence in this country. You have that power. Are you using it well?
Speaker 5:  Are you using it with justification? Are you using it in the name of justice?
Speaker 5:  They're not like, whatever you think about this case, whatever you think
Speaker 5:  about deportations in this case, they have not given this mandu process.
Speaker 5:  They shipped him off to El Salvador and the only evidence they have
Speaker 5:  actually profited is It is wearing a bulls hat.
Speaker 5:  Like, great. That is a controversy. You can cover it the way they're covering
Speaker 5:  it on a Fox. You can cover it the way they're covering it on newsmax. You
Speaker 5:  can cover it the way they're covering it on MSN bbc. But the government doesn't
Speaker 5:  get to go threaten the news organizations covering it. Brendan
Speaker 5:  Carr doesn't get to show up and say News Distortion doesn't cut it.
Speaker 5:  And the only reason he's saying It is because NBC owns some broadcast licenses
Speaker 5:  and he has the authority to say it. He can't say it to us, we're on the internet.
Speaker 5:  He can't say it to M-S-N-B-C or Fox, which are cable stations
Speaker 5:  that he doesn't have control over. This is just naked political
Speaker 5:  posturing because some of these stations run over the
Speaker 5:  broadcast airwaves. And even in his mentions, I'll point out, even in his
Speaker 5:  mentions, people are calling him an idiot. Like, this is just wrong.
Speaker 5:  It's wrong for the person who runs the nation's communications infrastructure
Speaker 5:  to say that not supporting the administration's lies
Speaker 5:  is news distortion. Actually, what he'll be saying is, I support
Speaker 5:  our vibrant broadcast networks, which reach most Americans. Pushing hard
Speaker 5:  on the truth whether or not you agree with mass deportations,
Speaker 5:  whether or not you agree with the Trump administration coming down
Speaker 5:  really hard on everybody who was illegally in this country. Fine,
Speaker 5:  you can think what you want, but in this case the lie is obvious.
Speaker 5:  In this case, the evidence has not been produced and It is not news distortion
Speaker 5:  to say the government has not produced this evidence. I just,
Speaker 5:  I, he's such a flunky. It drives me bananas. It
Speaker 5:  is nice that people are starting to call him out on it. I will say that,
Speaker 5:  but It is just obvious that just like Andrew Ferguson, there are things he
Speaker 5:  has to say and there are are lines he has to accept
Speaker 5:  from the rest of the administration in order to preserve his job. And Brendan
Speaker 5:  does it with such glee that you have to just accept that he
Speaker 5:  wants to,
Speaker 6:  I think that gives him too much of an out to say these are things that he
Speaker 6:  has to say. I think all evidence about Brendan Carr suggests that he is so,
Speaker 6:  so, so happy to be saying and doing all the stuff that he is saying and
Speaker 6:  doing. He's like, Mr. I'm out here having the time of my life. Guy like
Speaker 5:  Wearing the head of Donald Trump on the
Speaker 6:  Game. Yeah, no, none of this is making him sad on his insides.
Speaker 5:  So then here's the loop closing, which I think is even more dangerous as
Speaker 5:  he does. President Trump was watching television late at night. The thing
Speaker 5:  he does.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Presidents, they're just like us.
Speaker 5:  He watches 60 minutes a lot. Donald Trump, it appears. So this week he's
Speaker 5:  watching 60 minutes and he gets real mad and he posts this long rant on truth
Speaker 5:  social about how they're talking to Kamala Harris. Again, they
Speaker 5:  mentioned the word Trump and they're not nice to me. And at the end of this
Speaker 5:  long rant he says they should lose their license. Hopefully the
Speaker 5:  FCC is headed by a s highly respected chairman. Brendan Carr will impose
Speaker 5:  the maximum fines and punishment for their unlawful and illegal behavior.
Speaker 5:  CBS is out of control and they should pay a big price for this. When you
Speaker 5:  become the flunky, the president of the United States can say,
Speaker 5:  I want to punish the speech of this company and my guy's gonna do
Speaker 5:  it for me. That is just a violation of the First Amendment
Speaker 5:  straightforwardly. No matter how you think about the legal mechanics of who
Speaker 5:  owns the broadcast licenses, the president watching tv, getting mad at the
Speaker 5:  coverage and then directing his flunky to punish the company is not how it's
Speaker 5:  supposed to work. Like at all. They work for us.
Speaker 5:  Like when I watch these press conferences, the thing that I want some reporter
Speaker 5:  to say sometime is, do you realize that you work for me?
Speaker 5:  Because they've all forgotten it. Brendan has forgotten it. He works for
Speaker 5:  us. And I think it's probably times someone reminded him of that.
Speaker 5:  And Brendan, I would happy to do that. If you just want to come onto Coder
Speaker 5:  or The Vergecast as always, the door's open. I don't think you can do it.
Speaker 5:  'cause I don't think you can take the heat. I know people are starting to
Speaker 5:  tweet these segments at you. It's pretty good. So if you think you can do
Speaker 5:  it, if you think of the intellectual rigor to show up in the show and justify
Speaker 5:  your actions, you're welcome. That's been Brennan Carr is dummy America's
Speaker 5:  favorite podcast. Within a podcast
Speaker 6:  Jingle tk.
Speaker 5:  It's funny, like I'm just becoming like an angry talk radio show host, you
Speaker 5:  know, but that's, you gotta fight firefighter. It's
Speaker 6:  Okay. I like to think we just need to get it outta your system once a week.
Speaker 6:  It makes you like a happier person afterwards.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The the number, it's like what you want most
Speaker 5:  of all is just feedback from the audience. You know, like anybody who makes
Speaker 5:  something that's like as desperate, you know, like, read my novel and now
Speaker 5:  we get a lot of the feedback, but the feedback only enrages me. 'cause it's
Speaker 5:  just stuff Brendan has done that other people
Speaker 6:  Notice.
Speaker 5:  I,
Speaker 7:  The the feeling of like, you work for me. I had in the Meta trial earlier
Speaker 7:  this week when like Ferguson was like looking down at all of us, like who
Speaker 7:  were there with the press and like would not make eye contact with us. And
Speaker 7:  then his like comms lead who used to I think work for the Washington examiner
Speaker 7:  was also like, just pretending we didn't exist when we were standing
Speaker 7:  right in front of him and trying to like, ask basic
Speaker 5:  Things. It's like really bad for the comms people, right? It's like, you
Speaker 5:  know, like that's why you're here. But like, I mean that like the highest
Speaker 5:  level. Yeah. Donald Trump works for you whether you love him or you hate
Speaker 5:  him. That that's the whole point. He works for us.
Speaker 5:  We, we get to fire him at the end, right? Like
Speaker 5:  I, this whole administration has completely forgotten this like, very important
Speaker 5:  piece of the puzzle. But that said,
Speaker 5:  Brendan isn't smart enough to make it through the whole four years. So we'll
Speaker 5:  see what happens. All right. Pallet cleanser, David.
Speaker 6:  Okay, we're gonna skip right over tariffs because that that doesn't count.
Speaker 5:  That's a
Speaker 6:  And also nothing has changed. Tariffs happen. They don't
Speaker 5:  Happen. Well the numbers, the numbers have changed, but it doesn't matter.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  But who cares? They'll change again by the time this podcast goes up. Like
Speaker 6:  the, the numbers have changed. There you go. That's the news.
Speaker 6:  We figured out the G seven X story. Eli Alison Johnson went
Speaker 6:  and answered our question about, there's
Speaker 5:  Like two answers to this question and one of them is so
Speaker 5:  confusing and the other one is like also confusing in
Speaker 5:  a very different way.
Speaker 6:  So, okay, so I, I want, I want you to explain this story because actually
Speaker 6:  this story originates with you. Fun fact. I, I did the, the final
Speaker 6:  edit on this story and I made Alison take out the line where she says, I'm
Speaker 6:  writing this story because Neil, I made me do it.
Speaker 5:  We definitely put up a Liz story today that it contains like a very similar
Speaker 5:  line. It's great. That's, that's what being an energy chief is about. It
Speaker 5:  is true. However, that other people on our staff also saw the story.
Speaker 5:  Okay, so the Canon G seven X three
Speaker 5:  a camera from 2018 has gone totally virally, cannot get this camera anywhere.
Speaker 5:  If you can get it, it's even like a used one is selling for like
Speaker 5:  $300 over MSRP. This is not normal. Like
Speaker 5:  there's lots of pocket cameras with one inch sensors that do a good job of
Speaker 5:  just taking photos, but it's gone viral on TikTok and so it's sold out
Speaker 5:  everywhere and there are tiktoks now about how to get one,
Speaker 5:  like when in the middle of the night to wake up and like power refresh the
Speaker 5:  target website. So I see all this, Allison and the crew and I
Speaker 5:  talk about it and we had the first idea, which is we should buy one and see
Speaker 5:  if this camera's any good. And then Allison is like, it's been three weeks
Speaker 5:  and I can't buy one. Like I've been trying to buy one. Yeah. Like
Speaker 5:  many people have been like setting up weird bots for her
Speaker 5:  to buy like Antonio de Beno. And our team was like, I'm really good at buying
Speaker 5:  stuff. Like I'll help you so we we could not get one
Speaker 5:  crazy if you have one, let us know if you like it. But then she talked to
Speaker 5:  all the creators who are using it and it turns out one, it's just
Speaker 5:  an answer. Which is fascinating, right? There's still enough choice
Speaker 5:  in that market that just an answer is
Speaker 5:  useful. Right? So it, yes, you could just buy an RX 100. Yes.
Speaker 5:  There's like various Fuji cameras that like do the job, but this is just
Speaker 5:  the answer. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like it takes, it takes pretty good video, it takes pretty good pictures.
Speaker 6:  It's a reasonable size that you can carry around with you like and
Speaker 5:  It looks cool, which is important.
Speaker 6:  Sold. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  Then so that part is like confusing in, in the sense that like, who
Speaker 5:  knows how things become the answer. Do you know what I mean? Like, and it's
Speaker 5:  not a cannon that stepped up production, it's just here's this thing
Speaker 5:  everyone wants and cannon's like it's a five old camera, buy her new camera
Speaker 5:  instead. Like very much canon's like, would you like to buy the new camera?
Speaker 5:  And people are like no old camera.
Speaker 6:  One of the things Allison found is that there, there is like a newer camera
Speaker 6:  in that line, I think it's called the Power Shot V one that like
Speaker 6:  just relatively recently came out. You can buy it so easily. It's just right
Speaker 6:  there. Yeah. Wants that one. You can just have it, but no one wants it. They
Speaker 6:  want the five-year-old one.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Because it's just the answer. So that's confusing in the sense that
Speaker 5:  like, why do things become popular? You know, it's like some art
Speaker 5:  and science confusing. The more confusing thing is the reason people like
Speaker 5:  It is because apparently it shoots great flash photos. So all the tips for
Speaker 5:  using it are like open the flash even in like broad daylight, just like fire
Speaker 5:  that flash out.
Speaker 6:  It's, it's 1999 again Nili. It's
Speaker 5:  Great. We're doing it. I kind of love it. I haven't, I I've started popping
Speaker 5:  the flash on my RX 100 to be like baby rave, you
Speaker 5:  know, like it's like a good time. Wait till these kids figure out how to
Speaker 5:  shoot with slow shutter. So you get the nice background and the flash.
Speaker 5:  It's so funny. Yeah. Flash was just like you, it was, it was embarrassing
Speaker 5:  to need flash for so
Speaker 6:  Long. Oh yeah. And,
Speaker 5:  But it was cool before that And that now it's the trend And that it's cool
Speaker 5:  that, and this one camera, like literally the, the
Speaker 5:  conversation, the discourse is you need to buy this camera because
Speaker 5:  of its flash.
Speaker 6:  And that means all these kids are like looking at their parents' photos from
Speaker 6:  college being like, oh that's so vintage. And those are the pictures they
Speaker 6:  want to take. And I'm realizing those are the pictures that I have from college
Speaker 6:  because I'm 100,000 years old.
Speaker 5:  So when we were like early two thousands
Speaker 5:  moved out to Chicago, we were in the bar every night and my friends and I
Speaker 5:  had those like Cannon Power shot elfs and they only worked
Speaker 5:  with flash in the bar. Oh yeah. Like they unusable they did not have low
Speaker 5:  light capabilities. Yeah. And those flashes are really harsh and really direct
Speaker 5:  and really cold. And we would always hold our Miller Light bottles in front
Speaker 5:  of the flash and shoot through those. 'cause they would both diffuse the
Speaker 5:  flash and then t tint them like Miller Lights brown, you know, that's pretty
Speaker 5:  good. And then people would, we were like, oh my God, what if we use a Heineken
Speaker 5:  bottle? Like what? And they're like, we're like, we should sell filters for
Speaker 5:  flat. And this idea died like the iPhone came out the next day and we're
Speaker 5:  like, well that's over. But that's how we solved the problem back in the
Speaker 5:  day. We just held the beer bottles in front of the camera flashes. I have
Speaker 5:  a lot of very weird photos taken that way from about like 2004
Speaker 5:  to 2007.
Speaker 6:  I love this for you.
Speaker 5:  It was great. Anyway, the the, the mystery is solved and the mystery is,
Speaker 5:  it's just the one, like, it just became the one. It's just the thing that's
Speaker 5:  popular and the thing specifically popular about It is the flesh,
Speaker 5:  right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It is like the, the virality has fully taken hold on that
Speaker 6:  thing. And it's like, it can happen with anything. It can happen with a weird
Speaker 6:  Fleetwood Mac song with a guy drinking cranberry juice and it can happen
Speaker 6:  with 5-year-old cameras like no one knows. And it,
Speaker 6:  it can literally happen to anything at any time.
Speaker 5:  Do not turn on the flash on your smartphone. No, it's not as good.
Speaker 5:  I just, I need to tell you this. Do
Speaker 6:  You think we can make the phrase, it's not as good eating the flash happen
Speaker 6:  when you pop up the flash, you're heating the flash? No. Do you think we
Speaker 5:  Can do that? Unless you ripped the flash off the camera and like threw it
Speaker 5:  into another room. Like no, that's not, that's not what that word means,
Speaker 6:  Bro. I'm gonna get a picture. Just let me y the flash real quick. I feel
Speaker 6:  like we can make this happen. Is
Speaker 5:  Yeee gonna be gonna make this happen? Is ye gonna be in the title of this
Speaker 5:  episode? Can't do this. We, we can't do this. We, it's going to be, I'm,
Speaker 5:  we can't keep saying Y is already old science. It's like 5-year-old saying
Speaker 5:  already and now we're just talking about like a bunch of old dudes like eat
Speaker 5:  this is what I'm saying. How about Yee the monopoly?
Speaker 5:  That's the new title of the verse Cats. Alright, we'll accept ye the monopoly.
Speaker 5:  Do you have one more pallet cleanser David?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Should we talk just for a second about Phil Spencer saying Microsoft
Speaker 6:  really wants to support the switch to Yeah. Which a bunch of gamers
Speaker 6:  that I know and talked to found a mix of very exciting and sort of
Speaker 6:  odd. Like basically what he said is, you know, Microsoft's whole
Speaker 6:  plan is they wanna have Xbox stuff everywhere including on the Switch
Speaker 6:  too, right? And they've like, they've, they're launching these games for
Speaker 6:  the, the PS five. I think Indiana Jones comes out like today
Speaker 6:  as you're hearing this on the PS five, which would be very exciting for some
Speaker 6:  people. But he said, he was like, we want to have our franchises, our
Speaker 6:  games on the switch to also seems
Speaker 6:  like great news, lots of gamers are like sick. This is that one of the reasons
Speaker 6:  people don't get things like the switch to is 'cause it can't play some of
Speaker 6:  those games. So the idea that it might, it's very exciting but then there
Speaker 6:  was an interesting backlash to it of people being like, Microsoft is
Speaker 6:  just going, you know, squeeze Nintendo and ruin this beautiful console for
Speaker 6:  capitalism. And I just think it's kind of funny like the, the way
Speaker 6:  everybody talks about all of the gaming industry that isn't Nintendo
Speaker 6:  is increasingly sort of ruthless and brutal and
Speaker 6:  not beautiful and artistic. And then Nintendo is this just like beautiful
Speaker 6:  flower child over here. Yeah. That we cannot allow to be ruined by
Speaker 6:  these other companies.
Speaker 5:  Well I mean Nintendo is the only company that can look at something like
Speaker 5:  Zelda and be like, yeah, it's done.
Speaker 5:  We're done. The story's over, we have no more story here. We're gonna start
Speaker 5:  a new story over here. Like very few companies can look at
Speaker 5:  Breath of the Wild and be like, yep, this version of this has come to its
Speaker 5:  conclusion. Most companies are like, have you heard of DLC? There's more
Speaker 5:  of it. Right? And then I think for Microsoft in particular,
Speaker 5:  they're, they lost this console generation, I dunno what they're gonna do
Speaker 5:  with the next one.
Speaker 5:  They bought all these studios, we're gonna monetize the games of the advertising.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So we're gonna put the games everywhere so we can get multiplayer.
Speaker 5:  It's kinda like network effects. So if you want a big multiplayer games full
Speaker 5:  of advertising Yeah. You just need a lot of players. Yeah. So of course you're
Speaker 5:  gonna be on the switch. And I think that's the thing gamers in particular
Speaker 5:  are responding to is like every game is becoming some like open world
Speaker 5:  advertising paradise full of things to buy. Yep. And
Speaker 5:  Nintendo games are like, would you like to have fun? Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  that's the end of that. Like Yes, yes.
Speaker 6:  I would, I I will play tennis with Bowser for five hours. Yes, thank
Speaker 5:  You. I think that's why people, we've been playing a lot of Astro Bot
Speaker 6:  Nice.
Speaker 5:  Like that game's great. I don't feel like someone's gonna a ask us for
Speaker 5:  money while we're playing. Like there's very few of
Speaker 5:  those games left and when they come out people love them. But I think, I
Speaker 5:  think Microsoft has to put advertising on the Nintendo Switch. I think that's
Speaker 5:  what people reacted
Speaker 6:  To. Yeah. The other funny switch thing that happened this week was Switch.
Speaker 6:  Nintendo had another event just to show off more of the new Mario Kart game,
Speaker 6:  which looks sick. Like I'm so excited about that game. And
Speaker 6:  the whole chat in the whole thing was just about the price.
Speaker 6:  A bunch of people were like a like, tell us what the actual
Speaker 6:  price is. Why won't you let us buy this? Lower the price. How dare you? And
Speaker 6:  then a bunch of people being like, ah, games are expensive and it just,
Speaker 6:  all anyone cares about at this point is like, what is this thing actually
Speaker 6:  gonna cost and when are you gonna let me buy it? And anytime Nintendo does
Speaker 6:  anything else, that's the only question left. And that is also the question
Speaker 6:  I have because the pre-order date has come and gone. They have not even announced
Speaker 6:  when it's going to happen. I would like to throw my money at a switch to
Speaker 6:  please,
Speaker 7:  It's gonna end up costing like $1,500 to buy this much too.
Speaker 5:  So honestly,
Speaker 6:  Like you can either wait a year and get it at normal price or buy it now
Speaker 6:  for a thousand dollars. Like it, it could happen.
Speaker 5:  I mean there's all the, you know, high-minded like Trump really
Speaker 5:  began with Gamergate and to have it come full circle to you can't buy an
Speaker 5:  Nintendo is very funny. I'm just gonna, I'm, I just needed to say it on
Speaker 5:  our show one time. I, I think Nintendo will, will figure out a
Speaker 5:  way to get this thing on sale. I I, I actually really,
Speaker 5:  I talked to the CEO of a very large company that makes a
Speaker 5:  lot of stuff this week and he was like, I don't think anyone understands
Speaker 5:  we're all gonna solve it with smuggling. He was like dead serious.
Speaker 7:  Just like Tim Cook, like flying planes like out of like Vietnam.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like we're gonna, all the parts will, we'll like all the parts will
Speaker 5:  go to Mexico for final assembly And that final assembly is like
Speaker 5:  a sticker that says made in Mexico and then that will come in through that
Speaker 5:  tariff regime, like the amount of that that is going to start happening.
Speaker 5:  The thing specifically that was described to me is you have
Speaker 5:  all these export controls in these various countries that like you have to
Speaker 5:  check the list and he is like, yeah we just set up 15
Speaker 5:  shell companies so that it completely obscures where things are going.
Speaker 5:  All those people get to make money but that money is less than the tariffs.
Speaker 5:  And I was like, is it smuggling? And he was like, yeah, it's smuggling. Like
Speaker 5:  it was just very direct. So
Speaker 16:  Do we pay tariffs or do we pay bribes? Like it Yeah, he
Speaker 5:  Was like, he was very straightforward. It was like, yeah, we're justing smuggling.
Speaker 5:  So I'm excited for Nintendo to figure out smuggling. Basically it's the next
Speaker 5:  great switch. Two game Smuggle A switch, two Yeet the switch
Speaker 5:  two. I would play that game. We're done. That's it. That's the B test. Everybody
Speaker 3:  Rock
Speaker 5:  And roll.
Speaker 3:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 3:  you. Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one.
Speaker 3:  The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media podcast network.
Speaker 3:  Our show is produced by Will Por, Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer. And
Speaker 3:  that's it. We'll see you next week.