# Transcript
ID: cbc4b3a7-8127-44f7-adc4-7fed9f3c7996
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/63082181100986374/-1299986884874682318/s93290-US-4518s-1750756699.mp3
Description: Tesla is famous for throwing caution to the wind in the name of rolling out cool technology, so it was somewhat surprising to see its robotaxi service launch over the weekend in somewhat muted fashion. The Verge's Andy Hawkins joins the show to explain what, exactly, Elon Musk and co. launched, and what it says about the state of the self-driving revolution. After that, The Verge's Allison Johnson takes us through the history of MVNOs, and why they might just be the best deal in wireless carriers. We talk about Trump Mobile, Ryan Reynolds, e-SIMs, and what it would mean to make it easier to switch service. Finally, we answer a question from the Vergecast Hotline about how to free up storage on your iPhone. It's harder than it should be, but hopefully easier than you think.
Speaker 1:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of being unsupervised.
Speaker 1:  I'm m your friend David Pierce. And I'm doing, I think I've talked about
Speaker 1:  this on the show before, my annual ish
Speaker 1:  full on backup of everything. So over the years, I've, I've basically developed
Speaker 1:  a rule about how I think about files and folders and stuff. I
Speaker 1:  want to have them in three places. And anything that doesn't allow this,
Speaker 1:  I try not to use, I want to have all my stuff, like in whatever app I'm using,
Speaker 1:  whether it's notes or photos or to-dos or bookmarks or
Speaker 1:  whatever. I want to have it all somewhere. And then I want to have it all
Speaker 1:  in a, some other sort of cloud storage thing, Google Drive,
Speaker 1:  Dropbox, Microsoft, pick your poison. And then I wanna have it all
Speaker 1:  somewhere on a physical drive. And that usually means things like
Speaker 1:  text backups and a lot of like HDML and PDF
Speaker 1:  downloads. And this is the time of year when I try to make sure that all
Speaker 1:  of that is intact. In theory, I should do this a lot more often. I should
Speaker 1:  do this like once a month or once a week. There was a time where I did it
Speaker 1:  once a week and was like very diligent and proud of myself, not so much
Speaker 1:  recently. So now what I'm doing is I'm downloading all of my photos, I'm
Speaker 1:  downloading all of my notes as text and markdown files. I'm downloading all
Speaker 1:  of the bookmarks and stuff. I have, I'm downloading like browser history,
Speaker 1:  which I'm confident is not a thing I'm ever gonna need. But basically anything
Speaker 1:  I can turn into some kind of searchable archivable file
Speaker 1:  gets downloaded, gets put on a drive like this one, I have a couple of them
Speaker 1:  lying around. And I try to just make sure it all lives
Speaker 1:  there. And this is a way of like backing everything up without
Speaker 1:  making my life more complicated, which I like. Right? This is just like a
Speaker 1:  permanent archive that in theory I never have to touch. I think very
Speaker 1:  rarely have I ever actually had to go onto this drive and find something.
Speaker 1:  It's just a fail safe and it works for me. I got inspired to do this, by
Speaker 1:  the way, by today's hotline question, which we will come to at the end of
Speaker 1:  the show. It's a fun one and an annoying one, and we'll get
Speaker 1:  to that. But anyway, before we get to all that, today is not just about storage
Speaker 1:  and file backup, though. I could talk about that for hours. We're gonna do
Speaker 1:  two things on the show today. First, we're gonna talk to Andy Hawkins about
Speaker 1:  the slightly complicated Tesla taxii
Speaker 1:  announcement over the weekend. And we're also gonna just catch up on the
Speaker 1:  state of Robotaxis in general because this market continues to be very
Speaker 1:  confusing and is moving both slower and faster somehow
Speaker 1:  than you might think. I'm also gonna talk to Alison Johnson about MVNOs this
Speaker 1:  new type of wireless carrier that suddenly seems to be everywhere
Speaker 1:  And I think might be more important than we realize. There's Trump Mobile,
Speaker 1:  there's Mint Mobile, there's like Boost, but there's something bigger
Speaker 1:  happening here. And Allison And I are gonna try to figure out what it's all
Speaker 1:  that is coming up in just a second plus more stuff on storage.
Speaker 1:  But first we have to take a break and I have to go and download, let's see,
Speaker 1:  11,000 photos for MyCloud Drive.
Speaker 1:  Pray for me. This is The Vergecast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Andy Hawkins is here. Hi Andy. Hi.
Speaker 5:  How's it going?
Speaker 1:  You know, I once again have to talk about robo taxis that both do and
Speaker 1:  don't exist. So this is that, that question fills me with a lot of
Speaker 1:  confusing feelings.
Speaker 1:  There was a launch this weekend, we would say, is that, is that a fair
Speaker 1:  assessment of what happened? Something
Speaker 5:  Happened, a a thing happened. Okay. It was, I
Speaker 5:  don't know if you could call it a launch. It still feels very beta to me.
Speaker 5:  Okay. In many ways, but we can get into that. But yes, I, I guess one could
Speaker 5:  argue a thing was launched.
Speaker 1:  Okay, so what, what did happen this weekend? Like what there was a, there
Speaker 1:  was a small, I'm, I was very confused by this because Tesla is
Speaker 1:  a company that like does big splashy things
Speaker 1:  at the, at headquarters all the time and is like constantly making noise
Speaker 1:  about these huge announcements. And then this, what you would think would
Speaker 1:  be a big moment in Tesla's history, just kind of sneakily came and
Speaker 1:  went on a Sunday. What, what happened here?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it it was very muted. You're you're absolutely
Speaker 5:  right in that assessment, which is, which is not normal for Tesla,
Speaker 5:  but then again we're, this is Tesla and, and so few things are normal for
Speaker 5:  this company. But yes, what happened was on Sunday,
Speaker 5:  June 22nd for several hours, a handful
Speaker 5:  of Tesla vehicles were operating in the city of Boston,
Speaker 5:  Texas with no one in the driver's seat. And they picked up and dropped off
Speaker 5:  a bunch of passengers. Many of those people were Tesla
Speaker 5:  fans, extremely so
Speaker 1:  Sure
Speaker 5:  The most vocal of, of Tesla fans one could say.
Speaker 5:  And that is why they were allowed to ride in the cars. They were,
Speaker 5:  it was an invite only situation. So these invites went
Speaker 5:  out to all of Elon Musk's best friends, and
Speaker 5:  they got to ride in these driverless Tesla vehicles. And
Speaker 5:  I'm saying driverless because there was no one behind the steering wheel,
Speaker 5:  but they were not the unsupervised robotaxis that Musk
Speaker 5:  promised at the beginning of this year because there were Tesla
Speaker 5:  employees sitting as safety monitors in the passenger seat.
Speaker 5:  They didn't have steering wheels or pedals on their side, but they could
Speaker 5:  effectively hit a kill switch and stop the vehicle from operating if
Speaker 5:  they wanted to. As far as I could tell, I watched a lot of live streams
Speaker 5:  that that is one thing that Tesla fans online love to do is live stream
Speaker 5:  their cars using full self-driving. True. And so when the Robotaxis
Speaker 5:  came up, they were ready to live stream. So I watched many, many,
Speaker 5:  several hours long videos of these live streams.
Speaker 5:  So
Speaker 1:  What, what is the rider experience? As best you can tell? You have, you didn't
Speaker 1:  get to ride in one, you weren't in Austin, but like you said, you, you've
Speaker 1:  seen these, so like walk me through a, a ride in a Tesla
Speaker 1:  RoboTaxi is far as we know.
Speaker 5:  So from what I could tell, there is a, a separate app that is not the Tesla
Speaker 5:  app. It is a standalone robax app. You download that app, it ports over
Speaker 5:  your profile from the Tesla app, including all of your
Speaker 5:  preferences and all those things. And then you can hail a vehicle using this
Speaker 5:  app much in the same way that Uber, Uber works. Yeah. Okay. It's basically
Speaker 5:  Uber. Okay. And that was something that a lot of these folks were saying
Speaker 5:  that this is a very similar experience to Uber. The vehicles
Speaker 5:  only operated in a very small part of South Austin. It's
Speaker 5:  not clear to me how large a size of a geofence this is, but it is
Speaker 5:  very small, much smaller than Waymo's geofence in Austin.
Speaker 5:  Waymo right now has over a hundred vehicles operating
Speaker 5:  across Austin. I think the, the, the, their geofence is around 65 square
Speaker 5:  miles. Teslas was much smaller, so you had to initiate a
Speaker 5:  ride in the geofence. And, and also the, the destination needed to be
Speaker 5:  also within this same geofence. So you were seeing a lot of people
Speaker 5:  call rides to their hotels or they would drive into the geofence to
Speaker 5:  use, to use the, the roboto taxii service, hail a vehicle and then take
Speaker 5:  a ride to like a fried chicken place or something like that. Sure. And a
Speaker 5:  lot of these people, folks were, would take a ride, they would get out at
Speaker 5:  their destination and then they would immediately hail another ride. They
Speaker 5:  were sort of just like in a, a, a, a, a revolving cycle.
Speaker 5:  Right?
Speaker 1:  So you use the app, you get this car, it comes, you, you
Speaker 1:  get in it and there's no one, there's not like a person to drive
Speaker 1:  away, but there is a person in the front seat. Yes.
Speaker 1:  This is like the, the dynamics of the, like, how do I get in and start the
Speaker 1:  ride? Strike me as potentially deeply hilarious in this, in this moment.
Speaker 1:  Like, you have a driver, but they're not driving. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And I think it is, we should also just be really clear here. Like the idea
Speaker 5:  of a safety driver or a safety monitor, extremely common in the autonomous
Speaker 5:  vehicle space. Waymo Cruz, everyone basically has
Speaker 5:  used a safety driver at some point, either behind the steering wheel
Speaker 5:  in the passenger, sometimes both. I've been in self-driving cars where there
Speaker 5:  was two people in the front seat. Their hands were, you know, sort of off
Speaker 5:  off all the controls, but they were there to, to take control if something
Speaker 5:  happened. Those were during test phases, I think is is the real
Speaker 5:  important thing to, to, to make clear here. And what
Speaker 5:  Tesla is doing is, is pretty unique in, in the, in the field. And so far
Speaker 5:  as they're using these safety monitors as part of a commercial service.
Speaker 5:  Again, not open to the public yet. It'll be interesting to see if they
Speaker 5:  do open it to the public, whether they keep the safety monitors in or whether
Speaker 5:  they pull those folks out. But at this stage of the game, these are
Speaker 5:  paid rides. Elon Musk has said he's charging a flat rate of $4
Speaker 5:  and 20 cents entirely coincidental. I'm sure that price, of course.
Speaker 5:  $4 and 20 cents. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I'm sure the accountants went over that one rigorously to figure out
Speaker 5:  The exact correct number has no meaning. I'm sure that I could tell. But
Speaker 5:  you know, these are paid rides. Got that safety monitor in, in the, in the
Speaker 5:  the passenger seat. I saw a few videos where the rider were,
Speaker 5:  would try to interact and ask questions of the safety monitor.
Speaker 5:  That person was not having it. They were, I think it's pretty clear that
Speaker 5:  their instructions were Don't talk to the passengers. Sure. Don't touch the
Speaker 5:  controls unless you absolutely have to. And we can get to this,
Speaker 5:  but there was one incident that I saw where one of the vehicles
Speaker 5:  drove briefly in the opposite lane of traffic on the wrong side of the road.
Speaker 5:  Oh dear. And I thought it was super interesting, first of all that it did
Speaker 5:  that. Second of all, that the safety monitor made no attempt to grab
Speaker 5:  the steering wheel or do anything, even though the vehicle was
Speaker 5:  briefly on the wrong side of the road. Wow. Operating
Speaker 5:  dangerously. So that's kind of an interesting thing about this whole Tesla
Speaker 5:  experience that is unique, I would say across the industry.
Speaker 1:  Unique in what sense? Like, I think part of the reason this this moment is
Speaker 1:  so interesting to me is it is both the launch of a
Speaker 1:  commercial product that real people can use for sure. But it is also very
Speaker 1:  much a testing phase, right? Like they're not making money on
Speaker 1:  $4 and 20 cents a ride. They're not doing this
Speaker 1:  in any kind of sort of meaningful volume for people that's gonna make
Speaker 1:  this make sense as an app to open when I just want to get somewhere. And
Speaker 1:  like this is very clearly a beta test. Right? And I think part of the
Speaker 1:  reason it's so interesting to me is that this is a moment
Speaker 1:  that Tesla, which has been talking a big game about
Speaker 1:  its autonomous abilities for a very long time, has
Speaker 1:  to actually show what it can do. Right? Like a thing you And I have talked
Speaker 1:  about before is like, don't listen to what Elon Musk tweets like listen to
Speaker 1:  what he says to investors because that's where you have to, you have to tell
Speaker 1:  the truth. And like when you put the car on the road is when you at some
Speaker 1:  point have to tell the truth. And this, especially compared to what we've
Speaker 1:  seen from Waymo recently, which is just on this like relentless massive
Speaker 1:  expansion plan. Like Waymo feels like it's close. And this to me
Speaker 1:  did not look like Tesla feels like it's close. This felt very small
Speaker 1:  from Tesla to me. And I think that's not a bad thing, it's just a recognition
Speaker 1:  of where Tesla is at this moment. Yeah. And I just found that, yeah, that
Speaker 1:  disparity in dichotomy sort of fascinating. Oh
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's super fascinating And I think it's a reflection of a, a few
Speaker 5:  things. I think you're spot on in your analysis so far. I think it, it's
Speaker 5:  a, it's, it's absolutely a reflection of where Tesla is at this moment, right?
Speaker 5:  Like they were on a tear for a few years, especially
Speaker 5:  during those post pandemic years where they were just,
Speaker 5:  their, their stock price was, you know, on the upward trajectory. They were
Speaker 5:  selling ton of vehicles super profitable. And then
Speaker 5:  you saw 2024 happen, the
Speaker 5:  Trump endorsement Elon Musk going full tilt on on
Speaker 5:  maga, dark maga, sorry. And then things start to to change pretty
Speaker 5:  drastically for the company sales started to drop, they ended
Speaker 5:  2024 having sold fewer vehicles than they did in 2023.
Speaker 5:  That was the first time in many years that that had happened. And, and then
Speaker 5:  as we've seen in the, in the, the, the first months of 2025,
Speaker 5:  that's gotten worse and worse as Musk has gotten more and more political
Speaker 5:  with Doge and his involvement in the Trump administration. So I think that
Speaker 5:  there was a sense at the company that needed to do something to recapture
Speaker 5:  the narrative, to justify this enormous valuation that the company's been
Speaker 5:  enjoying for such a long time where they are valued exponentially more than
Speaker 5:  your average car company. And that was all about robotics. Bus has been
Speaker 5:  talking about AI and robotics for such a long time without having
Speaker 5:  delivered a product to anybody. And it was just coasting on vibes, right?
Speaker 5:  Tesla was your prototypical meme stock. It was just chugging
Speaker 5:  along on the vibe train. And So I think as soon as
Speaker 5:  sales started to go down and you started to see sort of chips in the facade,
Speaker 5:  I I think that that's when the company decided, okay, we need to actually
Speaker 5:  start delivering on what we've been promising on what Musk has been promising
Speaker 5:  for such a long time. I mean, it's been almost a decade that it, since he
Speaker 5:  said millions of roboto taxis on the road within the next two
Speaker 5:  years and every year was su successively another two years. We just need
Speaker 5:  two more years to make this happen. And now they finally have to deliver
Speaker 5:  in order to reverse this trend as it's been going on in their financials.
Speaker 5:  And I think that's why this seems so small, so contained,
Speaker 5:  so rushed in many ways. I mean, it was just sort of like they needed to meet
Speaker 5:  this June deadline that he put in place at the beginning of this year and,
Speaker 5:  and it's just drastically different than what he's been selling to people
Speaker 5:  for such a long time. I mean the, the the, the vision of Tesla for, for forever
Speaker 5:  was you buy a Tesla vehicle, that vehicle is gonna be the one that is
Speaker 5:  fully driverless, right? We're gonna sell you this, this technology, you're
Speaker 5:  gonna be able to add your car to the Tesla network and make money off
Speaker 5:  of it. Right? Cars typically lose value as soon as they leave the
Speaker 5:  dealership. That's just the, the state of the game Tesla was, was saying.
Speaker 5:  It doesn't have to be that way. You could actually earn money off your vehicle.
Speaker 5:  It will become more valuable over time. That is not what is being
Speaker 5:  rolled out this week in Austin. This is a fleet service. It is more
Speaker 5:  akin to Uber and Waymo than it is to anything that Musk has been selling.
Speaker 5:  And I think that is is sort of why we're, what we're seeing today is, is
Speaker 5:  so different than what has been promised for such a long time.
Speaker 1:  Do you think anything that we've seen in this launch
Speaker 1:  either, either makes you feel more or less confident about some of those
Speaker 1:  bigger visions? I mean, obviously we, we should talk about the cyber cab,
Speaker 1:  which is notably not these cars, but that's fine.
Speaker 1:  And, and there have, there like, there is this big grand kind of
Speaker 1:  Galaxy brand, Tesla vision around Robotaxis. It's like you're talking
Speaker 1:  about, right? And I think none of this points to
Speaker 1:  that, but also none of this makes me feel like it's out of the question.
Speaker 1:  Does that make sense? Like, do you, do you feel like we're closer or further
Speaker 1:  away after seeing all this launch?
Speaker 5:  I mean, it's only been one day. Sure. And And I think that that's like
Speaker 5:  the thing that kind of makes me concerned. We, we can't, we can't really
Speaker 5:  evaluate any service after just the day we haven't tested it ourselves.
Speaker 5:  And the fact that it's being filtered through these extremely biased protest
Speaker 5:  accounts, I think should give everyone a lot of pause about what we're seeing
Speaker 5:  on the ground in Austin that said, you know, I think it's a good idea that
Speaker 5:  they have safety monitors in the front seat. You know, I think a lot of folks
Speaker 5:  are are trying to drag Tesla for doing that. But at the same time, I would
Speaker 5:  prefer there to be more, more safety, safety nets,
Speaker 5:  backups, fallbacks, all these kind of things that you need to have in place.
Speaker 5:  Because I think when you look at Tesla's technology versus Waymo or someone
Speaker 5:  else, you can see why there is this concern about
Speaker 5:  how this company has been rolling these things out over the years. The fact
Speaker 5:  that it's computer vision only system without relying on things like radar
Speaker 5:  and lidar as secondary sensor inputs. And
Speaker 5:  the fact that, you know, full self-driving as a product has been shown many
Speaker 5:  times. A lot of people like it, a lot of people use it. But there have been
Speaker 5:  numerous cases of, of crashes that have taken places, injuries
Speaker 5:  with Tesla's driver assist products, even deaths there. And the
Speaker 5:  government has been investigating Tesla for a number of years now based on
Speaker 5:  how they market their products, but also the technology itself and whether
Speaker 5:  or not it is actually safe as they market it
Speaker 5:  to be. And we don't know because Tesla as a company is a black box. We have
Speaker 5:  no visibility into the safety of their products. They give us safety
Speaker 5:  statistics that are extremely selective and are designed to make the company
Speaker 5:  look good and are not actually verifiable in any way or
Speaker 5:  peer reviewed in the ways that Waymo has done with their safety data. They
Speaker 5:  have published numerous articles in scientific journals, peer reviewed
Speaker 5:  scientific journals that they say show that their vehicles cause fewer
Speaker 5:  crashes. Cause fewer injuries. Cause fewer deaths. Tesla has not
Speaker 5:  done that. And yet they're now on the road in a city without
Speaker 5:  drivers behind the wheel. It's been one day I think we need
Speaker 5:  to take a deep breath and, and, and cross our fingers and hope that nothing
Speaker 5:  goes wrong.
Speaker 1:  That's fair. Yeah. I think, I think that's right And I think it, it seems
Speaker 1:  to me that we're in a position of
Speaker 1:  sort of uncharted territory with Tesla, which is that actually reading about
Speaker 1:  a lot of this, this is much more careful than I've come to
Speaker 1:  expect from Tesla. Oh yeah, actually, yeah. This is, this is the sort of
Speaker 1:  thing that I think 12 months ago Tesla even would've just been like, it's
Speaker 1:  out there, pools go see what happens. And this is like, this is
Speaker 1:  the kind of like very thought through very small, very cautious
Speaker 1:  thing that we actually don't expect from Tesla. And a,
Speaker 1:  I think that's terrific, right? Like that is clearly the correct outcome
Speaker 1:  given where we are. But it's so unlike Tesla that it, it it almost feels
Speaker 1:  scarier as a result. And,
Speaker 5:  And yet it's still risky. I mean, you're right. Totally. And you're also
Speaker 5:  like, it's 'cause it looked, because like yes, we, I think we could very
Speaker 5:  well have assumed that Tesla was just gonna go full tilt and you know,
Speaker 5:  a thousand driverless vehicles on the road. They did not do that. Right?
Speaker 5:  It's a small group. It's like, I
Speaker 1:  Honestly thought at some point they would just turn it on for every Tesla
Speaker 1:  that exists and then the government would be like, what? And Elon Musk would
Speaker 1:  be like, whatcha gonna do about it?
Speaker 5:  That's honestly what
Speaker 1:  I knows
Speaker 5:  Gonna happen. Did I do that? Yeah. Right. But no, it, it does, it does
Speaker 5:  outwardly it looks cautious and they, And I don't want to
Speaker 5:  detract from that And I, I do wanna give the company some credit for, for,
Speaker 5:  for exhibiting some a modicum amount of caution.
Speaker 5:  Sure. That said, it is still lacking in some
Speaker 5:  serious safety safeguards that, that I think we've seen a lot of other
Speaker 5:  companies do. Waymo, for example, will drive six months with safety drivers
Speaker 5:  behind the wheel co wheel, no passengers. Then they'll allow passengers in,
Speaker 5:  then they'll take safety drivers out and it'll be for invite only for
Speaker 5:  employees only. And they'll test it that way for another six months.
Speaker 5:  There's a, there's a, there's a process here that they go through. They don't
Speaker 5:  drive on highways, they don't go to airports. Tesla also no highways, no
Speaker 5:  airports at the moment, but they decided to go out there and
Speaker 5:  start inviting customers with safety monitors in the passenger seat.
Speaker 5:  They didn't go through this sort of process of testing for over
Speaker 5:  a year, which is what they do because they, their argument is we have 3
Speaker 5:  billion miles of customer driven data on full self-driving. We
Speaker 5:  have end-to-end neural nets that are powering these
Speaker 5:  vehicles. We have everything that we need. And yet they haven't sort of been
Speaker 5:  transparent about how they're testing the vehicles. They're not releasing
Speaker 5:  the statistics that we're seeing. They don't have these additional sensors
Speaker 5:  that other companies use because Musk has long argued that they're too expensive
Speaker 5:  and it just doesn't make sense. Even though the costs on those sensors have
Speaker 5:  been, has been dropping at pretty steeply over the years. So totally. Again,
Speaker 5:  you have to give them some credit, but not entirely too much credit
Speaker 5:  because there are still a lot of risks that the company is taking here.
Speaker 5:  And as we've seen in the past with full self-driving, when things go wrong,
Speaker 5:  Tesla's defenders will come out and say, oh, this, this and this, and this
Speaker 5:  is why this happened. You know, they'll make any excuse that they can as
Speaker 5:  to why mistakes have happened. We saw it yesterday when this car drove on
Speaker 5:  the wrong side of the road. You saw a lot of people rush into the comments
Speaker 5:  and say, oh, my own car on full self-driving will do that. Sometimes it's
Speaker 5:  so annoying. That's a big problem. It shouldn't
Speaker 1:  Do that, that
Speaker 5:  Your car should not just decide to drive on the wrong side of the road, you
Speaker 5:  know? And So I know I I wanna give them some credit, but I I don't
Speaker 5:  wanna give them too much credit.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I mean, to be, to be very clear, I think for a long time there are
Speaker 1:  going to be better ways to get to the fried chicken restaurant than getting
Speaker 1:  in a Tesla robax. You know what I mean? But, So I think it just
Speaker 1:  let, let's sort of zoom out a little bit because I think the way I have been
Speaker 1:  thinking about the Robax world for a while is that there is,
Speaker 1:  there is Waymo kind of in a, in a tear of its own and then there's sort of
Speaker 1:  everybody else. But Tesla was this wild card that was like,
Speaker 1:  who knows what it's gonna do, who knows how well it's gonna work. Like we
Speaker 1:  just don't know. And we're, we're still, like you said, very early in this,
Speaker 1:  but it does seem like we can at least slot Tesla
Speaker 1:  in somewhere in terms of where the company thinks it is in self-driving.
Speaker 1:  Is it still
Speaker 1:  Waymo and then everybody else?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I I think in a lot of ways, And I think you also have to talk about
Speaker 5:  Uber in some respects too, because Uber has sort of made this move now to
Speaker 5:  partner with, you know, dozens of, of self-driving car companies
Speaker 5:  in, in North America, but also in Europe and, and in Asia and they're sort
Speaker 5:  of tried to become kind of like the platform for any company to come and,
Speaker 5:  and deploy vehicles on, which
Speaker 1:  Seems smart, right? Like the, the yeah, doing the Uber thing strikes me as
Speaker 1:  a much safer bet than trying to do the Tesla thing where it's like we're,
Speaker 1:  we're gonna try to own everything, but that requires doing everything at
Speaker 1:  giant impossible scale. Yeah. Uber is just like, whoever wins we win, which
Speaker 1:  actually at this moment strikes me as a pretty good call.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think it is, it is pretty smart. They're working with Waymo, they're
Speaker 5:  working with a number of other pretty legit operators. So I
Speaker 5:  I do think that there is, and they're also doing it on the, on the delivery
Speaker 5:  side, on the Uber Eats side as well, right? With, with the sidewalk robots.
Speaker 5:  So that's a really interesting approach to it. But yes, I, I do think that,
Speaker 5:  like you do have to say that Tesla is part of the conversation. They are
Speaker 5:  operating driverless vehicles on the road in a commercial capacity and they
Speaker 5:  have said, you know, Musk has said 10 20 vehicles at launch,
Speaker 5:  perhaps a thousand vehicles within a few months, and then we're gonna be
Speaker 5:  in California, he wants to start operating in Los Angeles, he wants to do
Speaker 5:  it in San Francisco. These are Waymo markets as well. And I think
Speaker 5:  that that's a fascinating thing. And then obviously they've said that in
Speaker 5:  2026 they're gonna start production on the cyber cab and then we're, we will
Speaker 5:  eventually start, you know, then the ball will really be rolling and, and
Speaker 5:  there'll be no turning back at, at that point. Sure. But I, I do think that,
Speaker 5:  you know, it will entirely depend on which markets that Tesla
Speaker 5:  has operated in and what sort of obstacles they may come across Texas. Zero
Speaker 5:  obstacles, right? There's just no, all you have to do is basically show proof
Speaker 5:  of insurance and you can do whatever you want. Yeah. And obviously you're
Speaker 5:  dealing with an extremely musk and Tesla friendly government that
Speaker 5:  exists in that state that said they had just passed some regulation that
Speaker 5:  says that you need to apply for a permit, perhaps Tesla, you'd like to wait
Speaker 5:  until September 1st when these regulations kick in and then apply for a permit.
Speaker 5:  That's what a lot of lawmakers in Austin were trying to pressure the company
Speaker 5:  into doing. Didn't happen. Tesla just went ahead and, and did the thing anyways.
Speaker 5:  California, entirely different situation. There's in a, a very rigid
Speaker 5:  permitting process, you need to do, have several months of testing. You need
Speaker 5:  to submit, you know, documents to the government to show that their, your
Speaker 5:  technology is up to snuff. You know, you have to apply for a driverless
Speaker 5:  permit, you have to apply for a commercial roboto taxi permit. You know,
Speaker 5:  there's all these sort of a successive number of permits, but that's the
Speaker 5:  market, right? California is the big market that, that Tesla wants to get.
Speaker 5:  If they want to compete with the Ubers and the Waymo's and everyone else,
Speaker 5:  they're gonna need to be in those markets competing with them as well.
Speaker 5:  And I, they, they may run into some problems as the sort of regulatory
Speaker 5:  requirements get more and more difficult as they look to spread out.
Speaker 1:  Right. Is is the sense in the industry that this stuff is gonna be
Speaker 1:  kind of a, a let a thousand flowers bloom market where it'll be sort of like
Speaker 1:  the car market where there's lots of different companies and you can choose
Speaker 1:  your, your own provider and everybody can kind of peacefully coexist on the
Speaker 1:  roads? Or are we running towards some kind of like
Speaker 1:  winner take all, or at least winner take most version of
Speaker 1:  the, the robo taxii future here? Because if that's where we're going, I
Speaker 1:  kind of have a hard time figuring out how anybody catches Waymo at this point,
Speaker 1:  at least quickly. But maybe it doesn't matter. Maybe maybe
Speaker 1:  Waymo can continue to be Waymo and Tesla or some other company can figure
Speaker 1:  out how to be just as successful in just as many places and everybody can
Speaker 1:  coexist together. What is the sense of how it shakes out there?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think it's gonna be entirely dependent on safety.
Speaker 5:  Okay. I I, I don't wanna mean to sound like a broken record, but really it,
Speaker 5:  it it's the kind of situation where as soon as something bad
Speaker 5:  happens, someone gets hit, a crash occurs, the whole
Speaker 5:  industry almost needs to reset at that point. And that's when you start to
Speaker 5:  see who's a winner and who's a loser in that situation. Because as we've
Speaker 5:  seen in the past when there's some sort of injury or death that
Speaker 5:  that can ruin companies, it happened to Uber, it happened to cruise
Speaker 5:  under, under GM's ownership and it could very well
Speaker 5:  happen to Tesla, right? Sure. As soon as there have been already injuries
Speaker 5:  and crashes, right. But there have been people behind the wheels of those
Speaker 5:  vehicles and so Tesla can say, we're not liable. We told you to pay attention
Speaker 5:  and you didn't. This is a different situation and Tesla is taking on a lot
Speaker 5:  more risk now than they ever have in the past and a lot more liability.
Speaker 5:  That said, I do think Uber's model is really interesting and could be the
Speaker 5:  one that we see as the most successful. You get you
Speaker 5:  sort of like smaller AV operators, maybe
Speaker 5:  more locally based, you know, who are able to deploy their vehicles to a
Speaker 5:  small number of, of customers on Uber's platform. And then you have sort
Speaker 5:  of like your big operators like your Waymo's and others who
Speaker 5:  have more runway, more capital, more financial support and
Speaker 5:  therefore are able to grow, acquire more VE vehicles
Speaker 5:  and then sort of spread across the country. But, you know, it, it
Speaker 5:  will be a very safety guided, I think
Speaker 5:  development and it and it should be, right? Yeah. If you can't prove
Speaker 5:  that you can operate these vehicles And I think the liability thing is the
Speaker 5:  one that is the biggest hurdle for most of these companies. If you cannot
Speaker 5:  put a driverless vehicle on the road and be confident in the fact that that's
Speaker 5:  not gonna come back and bite you in the ass and cost you hundreds of millions
Speaker 5:  of dollars it liability costs, then you, you should
Speaker 5:  feel confident in doing that. But otherwise that's gonna be the thing that
Speaker 5:  I think that weeds out sort of the, the major players with the, with the
Speaker 5:  confidence and, and those that maybe are a little bit operating with a little
Speaker 5:  bit more risk.
Speaker 1:  Okay, but you think, I mean it's an interesting way of thinking about it
Speaker 1:  'cause there's so much potential for like
Speaker 1:  problem and change there that maybe I'm wrong to think that Waymo is in
Speaker 1:  any way sort of insurmountable at this point. Like there are still so much
Speaker 1:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  Big
Speaker 1:  Huge, massive stuff left to do.
Speaker 5:  I mean, Waymo has been able to circumnavigate the
Speaker 5:  problems in the past with when, when someone has deployed a vehicle that
Speaker 5:  was not ready and someone got hurt or injured, there's been sort of the
Speaker 5:  under, there's an understanding that like that hurts the whole industry,
Speaker 5:  right? People don't tend to separate Waymo from, from Tesla
Speaker 5:  or, or what have you. They just,
Speaker 1:  They're just self-driving cars.
Speaker 5:  They're just self-driving cars and it's a technology that is not ready for
Speaker 5:  prime time because of this, this incident that happened. I feel like Waymo
Speaker 5:  has been able to skirt around that a a few times in ways that other companies
Speaker 5:  have not. But that said, you know, I, I do think that if something
Speaker 5:  happens in the future and if it's a Tesla vehicle that is responsible for
Speaker 5:  something that happens, some sort of incident, it'll, it will be tough because
Speaker 5:  it is also a perception game. And if you can't convince
Speaker 5:  people at scale to trust this technology, they're
Speaker 5:  just not gonna use it. They're gonna rely on human driven, you know, Uber
Speaker 5:  vehicles, which is why Uber hedging its bets now saying, oh we got,
Speaker 5:  we got human drivers and we got robot cars. You know, that's a way to sort
Speaker 5:  of say both can coexist and that's a company that could potentially be well
Speaker 5:  positioned for more success in the future. But yeah, I
Speaker 5:  I do think that like if it once and, and something will, something will go
Speaker 5:  wrong. I, I don't want to be doom and gloom, but there will be eventually
Speaker 5:  an incident that happens, someone will get injured, especially as more of
Speaker 5:  these vehicles hit the road and you just reach a certain level of scale where
Speaker 5:  it's unavoidable, these types of incidents. Sure. It'll be really interesting
Speaker 5:  to see who's responsible and how the rest of the industry responds to that
Speaker 5:  incident. And then if the public decides to reject it and say,
Speaker 5:  okay, this, that's enough. We've had enough of this, which we saw in
Speaker 5:  LA recently with these Waymo's getting completely incinerated during these,
Speaker 5:  these anti-ice protests, you know, that's a bad look for
Speaker 5:  Waymo. It's a bad look for the, for the whole industry too. And I think it's,
Speaker 5:  it's, it goes to show that there's still a bit of a hill to climb in terms
Speaker 5:  of public acceptance and trust.
Speaker 1:  Totally. Well, speaking of things that have fully climbed that hill, at least
Speaker 1:  in my brain, can we talk about the Nissan Leaf just for one second before
Speaker 5:  We go? Oh yes. Oh well happy to.
Speaker 1:  The last time you were on, I told you I was irrationally excited about this
Speaker 1:  car and then Nissan sort of fully unveiled
Speaker 1:  the, the 2026 leaf And I feel so incredibly vindicated
Speaker 1:  'cause this car seems awesome. It's great. I'm very into it. Tell
Speaker 1:  me, tell me why I should or should not be excited about the, the New Leaf.
Speaker 5:  Okay, so you should be excited for it because the specs look great. It's
Speaker 5:  like over 300 miles on certain trims. They haven't said what the price
Speaker 5:  is, but I'm sure it's gonna be like in the $40,000 range, which is
Speaker 5:  where most EVs are these days. I if it's under 40, I I will
Speaker 5:  be impressed. But I I'm sure if that's gonna be reliant on some
Speaker 5:  incentives that probably won't exist by the time this, this car comes out
Speaker 5:  fair. It's got dual ports on it for both CCS charging,
Speaker 5:  fast charging and Tesla Max fast charging.
Speaker 5:  I have not seen that before in a, in a production vehicle. Typically
Speaker 5:  you'll, you'll, they'll come out with one or the other and they'll give you
Speaker 5:  an adapter for the rest. This 1D Son's just saying, why not just put
Speaker 5:  two ports on this, on this bad boy Love it. So that, that's pretty sick.
Speaker 5:  And just the look of it, it's just looks so much better. Right? It's like,
Speaker 5:  it's kind of reminded me in some ways of like when the new Prius came out
Speaker 5:  a couple years ago Totally. And how much a glow up that was, it just like
Speaker 5:  looked sleeker and sexier than the, than the old Prius.
Speaker 5:  The same is is with the leap. It just, it it's sort of like cast off its
Speaker 5:  frumpiness and it's now a fully grown up crossover. SUV it, it
Speaker 5:  just, it just looked great. The downside, it's Nissan, right?
Speaker 5:  Nissan not in a, not in a great place right now. Yeah. Struggling
Speaker 5:  a lot. They had a huge round of layoffs a few months ago. Tried to
Speaker 5:  merge with Honda, didn't work out, had to, had to break that up.
Speaker 5:  But clear that the company is still going through a lot of financial
Speaker 5:  difficulties. I don't think that's gonna affect the Leaf at all. I think
Speaker 5:  that they're really gung-ho about the leaf and, and are, And I, I
Speaker 5:  don't doubt that Nissan, it's not gonna be like a Fisker situation. Nissan's
Speaker 5:  not gonna cease to exist or what have you. But I do think that that, that
Speaker 5:  might give some folks pause, but yeah, otherwise I, I do think that the Leaf
Speaker 5:  looks awesome And I can't wait to test that out.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It just seems like we're we're still so desperate
Speaker 1:  for like compelling mainstream EVs And I think
Speaker 1:  the, the Leaf tried and failed to be that so many times that
Speaker 1:  it was like, it just, it just kept whiffing on like really basic stuff. It
Speaker 1:  was like, what if we made a car that was ugly and didn't go very far? And
Speaker 1:  I was like, well I don't think that's it Nissan,
Speaker 5:  But it was like, but it was the first, it was the thing, right? Like everyone
Speaker 5:  gives Tesla the credit for, you know, inventing the EV market, but it was
Speaker 5:  really Nissan that took the risk, right? Yeah. They were the ones who put
Speaker 5:  the, the leaf came out first. That was the first, it wasn't long
Speaker 5:  range by any stretch of the imagination, but it was way more than a lot
Speaker 5:  of like the very early compliance vehicles that we saw. And it was
Speaker 5:  cheap. It was so cheap. It was, you know, 112 miles of
Speaker 5:  range, like 30 grand, maybe even like 25 grand. That was
Speaker 5:  what this was all supposed to be before like the EV market got kind of hooked
Speaker 5:  on luxury goods and Right. You know, fine leather goods and all that kind
Speaker 5:  of stuff that you see with like the rivian and the pole stars and whatnot.
Speaker 5:  Things just got too fancy and we kind of lost, lost sight of like,
Speaker 5:  what was the point of all of this is to, if you really wanna drive adoption,
Speaker 5:  you got to meet people where they are and you especially gotta meet them
Speaker 5:  where their finances are and, and so many EVs today. And I think
Speaker 5:  that, you know, you could say that Tesla was really responsible for that
Speaker 5:  with the model S and then that sort of like, kind of was the model that everyone
Speaker 5:  wanted to follow because they were so successful. So Right. Had the Leaf
Speaker 5:  been the one that was the success and not the model S It
Speaker 5:  could have been a different story. You could have seen Ford and GM and BMW
Speaker 5:  and everyone else like rushing to put $20,000 EVs on the road. Hmm.
Speaker 5:  But instead it was Tesla that was the breakout star and thus that's why we
Speaker 5:  got 70, 80, $90,000 EVs before we got
Speaker 5:  any, any hint of a 20,001.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I am, I'm rooting for this car for exactly that reason. It feels like
Speaker 1:  the thing the Leaf has always wanted to be is a, is a thing we
Speaker 1:  need in in the car market right now. And at least from the, the look
Speaker 1:  of the thing it feels, it feels like it might have actually gotten there,
Speaker 1:  but I agree with you. I think price will end up being everything And I would
Speaker 1:  not say I'm terribly optimistic given Yeah. You know, gestures broadly,
Speaker 1:  all everything.
Speaker 5:  But that's it. You know, we're, we're, we're supposed to be getting cheap
Speaker 5:  EVs from Ford, from Volkswagen supposed to be coming out some really cheap
Speaker 5:  ones. Next year we're gonna get the R two from Rivian. That's supposed to
Speaker 5:  be their, their $40,000 ev. I, I do feel
Speaker 5:  despite all of these headwinds and, and political machinations that are going
Speaker 5:  on, it does seem that the industry is still committed to putting out a, a
Speaker 5:  affordable EV that people can actually buy and hopefully the leaf will
Speaker 5:  will be sort of like that precursor to a lot of great things to come.
Speaker 1:  I'm, I'm you and me both.
Speaker 1:  the sort of thing that I feel like in the course of my day-to-day life, I
Speaker 1:  have spent almost no time thinking about this. This sort of like
Speaker 1:  weird world of network usage and
Speaker 1:  carriers and who you buy your service from. I've just, like, I signed up
Speaker 1:  for a Verizon account in 2004 and
Speaker 1:  basically have not thought about it since then. And then with all this Trump
Speaker 1:  mobile stuff, we, we got to like actually sort of have a bunch of
Speaker 1:  conversations about how self service works that I have just not really had
Speaker 1:  before And I have found myself deeper down this rabbit hole than I ever expected.
Speaker 1:  And it, it is sort of fascinating And I feel like you've had kind of the
Speaker 1:  same journey over the last like seven days.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, and I've, I I go into the rabbit hole sometimes when I am
Speaker 7:  writing about, you know, wireless services and Boost Mobile and all that
Speaker 7:  and it goes deep. Like there are some people out there
Speaker 7:  who are like so plugged into their network and like
Speaker 7:  what spectrum they're using and what, you know, like all of the
Speaker 7:  kind of things that go on under the hood. There's a lot, but I've,
Speaker 7:  I have skimmed the surface and it is fascinating stuff
Speaker 1:  I think. Yeah, I agree. So let, let's just start at sort of the very base
Speaker 1:  floor here and then build up what is an MVNL?
Speaker 7:  So an MVNL is a mobile virtual network
Speaker 7:  operator and it is basically like
Speaker 7:  a storefront for wireless service. They don't
Speaker 7:  own the network in the US we have three wireless
Speaker 7:  networks. So they buy the service from one of those three
Speaker 7:  providers and they resell it and that it's like
Speaker 7:  basically as simple as that. So the MVNO is a little bit
Speaker 7:  more of like a, a marketing exercise
Speaker 7:  and they feel like they can tap into a different
Speaker 7:  market that the big providers are not like addressing
Speaker 7:  directly is kind of fascinating. I talked to a
Speaker 7:  friend analyst, Avi Greengart, and he was like, they've been around
Speaker 7:  for decades actually. Like I feel like I've heard about them
Speaker 7:  so much in the last, you know, two or three years. But
Speaker 7:  as, as long as there's been like an audience to
Speaker 7:  address, there's been like an MVNO for that group
Speaker 7:  of people.
Speaker 1:  So why would the big three carriers in the US
Speaker 1:  at and t T-Mobile Verizon allow this to happen?
Speaker 1:  Like you're, you're basically saying they're, they're
Speaker 1:  taking their network, which these companies spend an enormous amount
Speaker 1:  of money on like building and maintaining the infrastructure to have wireless
Speaker 1:  coverage all over the United
Speaker 1:  States and sell it to a sensibly your competitor. Why would these companies
Speaker 1:  do that?
Speaker 7:  So they get like a guaranteed return on
Speaker 7:  that bit of, you know, their capacity and they might have
Speaker 7:  more capacity than they're always using.
Speaker 7:  So it's a little bit of like a guaranteed payday for them when
Speaker 7:  they sell it to the MBNO. You know, they make
Speaker 7:  their money. The MBNO then has to go like make their money back by
Speaker 7:  reselling it. So it, it helps them in that way. And
Speaker 7:  there are just market segments that like a Verizon or an
Speaker 7:  at and t is maybe too big to go after or
Speaker 7:  wants to uphold a perception of like it's the best
Speaker 7:  fanciest wireless network in the world. So there
Speaker 7:  are, there are audiences of like people with poor credit
Speaker 7:  or people who don't speak English that like Verizon
Speaker 7:  is not going to like, hire a whole team to translate
Speaker 7:  all their marketing materials into like a particular language.
Speaker 7:  So it's, it's beneficial to them in like a number of
Speaker 7:  ways.
Speaker 1:  Okay. And my understanding of the the capacity thing is that that
Speaker 1:  has gotten more and more possible over
Speaker 1:  time. And I think this is where I start to make very clear how little
Speaker 1:  I understand how wireless networks actually work. But my, my sense of it
Speaker 1:  is that as these networks have gotten faster as we've, you know, gone up
Speaker 1:  the gs, they've also gotten more efficient. So like however,
Speaker 1:  whatever a hundred million people on Verizon actually use less of this sort
Speaker 1:  of overall capacity than before. So maybe even as it's getting better, Verizon
Speaker 1:  and at t and and T-Mobile have actually more empty space
Speaker 1:  to offer. Do I have that basically right.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And someone else I spoke to was pointed
Speaker 7:  out that 5G really like
Speaker 7:  the genuine 5G like we're in the era of
Speaker 7:  all the networks have actual 5G networks now they're not trying to
Speaker 7:  rebrand 4G as 5G and that technology
Speaker 7:  does allow for more capacity. So
Speaker 7:  that might be partially why we're hearing a little bit more
Speaker 7:  over the last like year or two in particular,
Speaker 7:  especially T-Mobile, which has had kind of the headstart with all the
Speaker 7:  sprint spectrum. So they had just like extra
Speaker 7:  capacity lying around, you wanna sell it and definitely get some money
Speaker 7:  back for it.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So when I think of MVNOs, I think the first one
Speaker 1:  I think of is Boost Mobile. And I feel like Boost Mobile's been around
Speaker 1:  forever, since like the, the early aughts and has basically
Speaker 1:  been on every imaginable network over time. It's been bought and sold like
Speaker 1:  a half dozen times. It, the company has a crazy story but is like
Speaker 1:  pretty successful and has been for a long time,
Speaker 1:  mostly without ever operating its own network. I think that's like a little
Speaker 1:  murkier now in a 5G world, but it doesn't matter. Mostly it has been an M-M-V-N-O
Speaker 1:  for most people for a very long time. The thing I think of when I think of
Speaker 1:  Boost and by extension most other MVNOs is just
Speaker 1:  that it's cheaper, right? Like it is, it is, there are fewer,
Speaker 1:  you know, perks that come with the account. There aren't as many retail stores
Speaker 1:  that you go to to get your phone serviced. You're not gonna get maybe as
Speaker 1:  good a deal on a phone, but the price per month is cheaper. And that I feel
Speaker 1:  like is pretty consistently the story with MVNOs. Is it usually
Speaker 1:  just kind of that simple? Like you you trade a few things but you get a cheaper
Speaker 1:  price every month?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, basically. I think that's, and there's a few
Speaker 7:  other things you could be playing in there. Like
Speaker 7:  they may not require a credit check and Verizon will,
Speaker 7:  you know, needs a credit check for you to get on one of their plans.
Speaker 7:  So they make that a little bit easier. Yeah, they may be
Speaker 7:  okay with, you know, lower credit scores too, or, and
Speaker 7:  a lot of MVNOs, I don't know if it's exclusively
Speaker 7:  all of them, but they tend to be prepaid.
Speaker 7:  So you pay for your service and then you have your month of service and Right.
Speaker 7:  The big unlimited plans from all the bigger carriers
Speaker 7:  are postpaid and you kind of sign a contract,
Speaker 7:  you know, quote unquote you, they can cut your service off if
Speaker 7:  you stop paying them kind of deal.
Speaker 1:  Right? Yeah. So what, what's your sense of the
Speaker 1:  downsides of these? Like if you, you get a cheaper price is it
Speaker 1:  should like roughly the same service that these things promise, like this
Speaker 1:  has always been my open question is like, yes, you are. You,
Speaker 1:  you are, I understand taking T-Mobile network capacity and giving it
Speaker 1:  to me for less money than T-Mobile. And I'm like, would I trade
Speaker 1:  retail store access for that? Absolutely. Unequivocally yes. Like maybe
Speaker 1:  not everybody would, but I happily would. I will fix my own damn phone. Thank
Speaker 1:  you. Yeah. But then there, there's always, I feel like you, you look at the
Speaker 1:  fine print and it's always like weird bandwidth priority
Speaker 1:  stuff going on that I've never been able to, I don't know. And it, it's just
Speaker 1:  always like that's the stuff that makes me squirrely is like in ways I don't
Speaker 1:  understand is this actually sneakily less good than T-Mobile, even though
Speaker 1:  it's technically T-Mobile?
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I, I think it yes and
Speaker 7:  no. Okay. There's deprioritization, which
Speaker 7:  is something that, you know, you can buy a plan from Verizon and
Speaker 7:  still experience deprioritization. That's where you have an allotment
Speaker 7:  of a certain amount of premium data and once you hit
Speaker 7:  that threshold, it's usually pretty high. And the other thing that comes
Speaker 7:  into play with the MVM knows is that the networks have these
Speaker 7:  kind of quality of service tiers for
Speaker 7:  their, the way they split up traffic. So
Speaker 7:  they put things that are really like sensitive to
Speaker 7:  latency on the highest priority, like
Speaker 7:  voice calls, first responders, that kind of thing. And then
Speaker 7:  like down the ranks is, you know, your
Speaker 7:  mobile gaming, your internet of things, all that stuff. And I
Speaker 7:  think MVNOs tend to sit like just
Speaker 7:  one tier or so below, like the main
Speaker 7:  wireless brand's own traffic. I see, I see. Does that mean
Speaker 7:  you'll experience that difference in, in a meaningful way?
Speaker 7:  Like it's really hard to say. I, I know a
Speaker 7:  bunch of people on MVNOs now who are like thrilled
Speaker 7:  with their service And I don't think it's ever bothered them
Speaker 7:  if that's a factor.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I will say the, the one that I have heard about this is Pure
Speaker 1:  anecdotal, but I, I know a surprising number of people who switched to Mint
Speaker 1:  Mobile over the years and had really good experiences and meant mobile's
Speaker 1:  thing was like, it's, it's T-Mobile, but it's 15 bucks a month. And
Speaker 1:  also like Ryan Reynolds is here And I think
Speaker 7:  Like right,
Speaker 1:  That was very meaningful for people. But also the idea that you are getting,
Speaker 1:  I think even, even 90% as good T-Mobile's coverage
Speaker 1:  for $15 a month, I think is a trade most people are perfectly happy
Speaker 1:  to make. And I remember a lot of this happening, especially during
Speaker 1:  COVID when people were at home a lot, and you're on wifi a lot And I
Speaker 1:  was thinking about this, researching all this stuff. Like the amount of time
Speaker 1:  that I spend off of a wifi network at this point
Speaker 1:  is pretty small.
Speaker 7:  Can I tell a story real quick? I had my,
Speaker 7:  my Verizon account completely shut down while I was traveling home from
Speaker 7:  ww DC Oh no, it was a whole technical weird
Speaker 7:  thing with how I am, I kind of did it to myself, like switching around
Speaker 7:  from EIM to physical sim, we got it sorted out,
Speaker 7:  but I got off the plane And I was like, oh no, I'm dead. Like I have died.
Speaker 7:  I don't have cell service. Like I just live here at the airport now. And
Speaker 7:  it was actually like, I was like, no, there's wifi and
Speaker 7:  there was like wifi in the parking garage And I could text on wi, I could
Speaker 7:  call on wifi. I'm like, oh actually, like this is
Speaker 7:  fine. Yeah. And I like got my Uber on wifi And
Speaker 7:  I survived. But it's a, it's an interesting thing that some of the, so like
Speaker 7:  the cable companies also run MVNOs,
Speaker 7:  which is such a weird thing of like, you know,
Speaker 7:  you can have Xfinity mobile service and then
Speaker 7:  Verizon wants to sell you home internet And I don't know what to make of
Speaker 7:  that. But yeah, I think one thing that cable companies are doing is
Speaker 7:  like tapping into that that like, hey, you're on wifi a lot.
Speaker 7:  Like we'll just kind of facilitate that when you're out and about if
Speaker 7:  there's an Xfinity wifi network, like you can use that and,
Speaker 7:  and it saves us on the data that we're paying for.
Speaker 7:  It's a whole like, weird world out there.
Speaker 1:  It it is a strange thing. And I think, I mean that, that goes back to your
Speaker 1:  point about this kind of rise in MVNOs over the last few years that I think
Speaker 1:  is real. Like, I went back and was like, okay, is this just a thing that
Speaker 1:  we've been hearing about recently? And there have been tons of these before.
Speaker 1:  The, the answer is no. Like the, there has been a boom the last several years
Speaker 1:  in MVNOs and I've been trying to figure out why
Speaker 1:  and, And I have a couple of theories, but I'm, I'm curious if you, if you
Speaker 1:  have a sort of leading theory about the, the boom in MVNOs recently.
Speaker 7:  So I talked to my friend Avi and he made the good point that like Ryan
Speaker 7:  Reynolds really did like start a lot of this. Wait,
Speaker 1:  Really? I've been making that joke all week. I thought I was just kidding.
Speaker 7:  No, I thought it was funny too, but he was like, no. Okay. Ryan Reynolds
Speaker 7:  is actually to blame here, but it having
Speaker 7:  like a friendly face to an MVNO and like the branding of
Speaker 7:  Mint Mobile is so cute and it's a little fox and it's just kind of like
Speaker 7:  friendly and kind of appealing, I think
Speaker 7:  attracted a lot of people and sort of helped like
Speaker 7:  shake off the stigma of, you know, a prepaid service or an
Speaker 7:  MVNO as like, oh that's just cheap and
Speaker 7:  you know, you, you gotta buy from the main carriers
Speaker 7:  if you want actual good service. It's kind of like a Costco effect
Speaker 7:  where you're like, oh yeah, actually it's kind of cool to
Speaker 7:  shop at Costco and like save a bunch of money on like
Speaker 7:  nice stuff I would've bought somewhere else.
Speaker 1:  But So I, I I think that makes sense. And then I mean, you consider the fact
Speaker 1:  that Ryan Reynolds like didn't start but like bought into an MVNO, made a
Speaker 1:  bunch of fun ads and then sold that MVNO Mint to T-Mobile,
Speaker 1:  which provided the service for Mint already.
Speaker 1:  So it essentially sold T-Mobile back to T-Mobile. Yeah. For
Speaker 1:  $1.35 billion bananas. Like
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Genuine congratulations to everybody involved. And I think to
Speaker 1:  me what that says is like, okay, there, there was a real understanding at
Speaker 1:  the end of that, that the brand matters a lot, right? That like you can
Speaker 1:  have, and this is what you're talking about, you can have network capacity,
Speaker 1:  you can have whatever, but like people want to deal with a company that
Speaker 1:  they like and that that's a really meaningful thing. And So I get that from
Speaker 1:  the perspective of like, I get why you would start up an MVNO, like I that
Speaker 1:  this is why Trump mobile makes sense to me, right? You're like, okay, any
Speaker 1:  sort of affinity based thing, it's pretty easy to start a
Speaker 1:  wireless carrier. It's a thing people pay money for, it's a relationship
Speaker 1:  they have. It's like, I get it, I get why the smart list guys did it. It's,
Speaker 1:  there's gonna be more and more of this over time. The part of it that I struggle
Speaker 1:  with is like, I don't know a lot of people with a ton of like Comcast brand
Speaker 1:  affinity. I guess this is where we should disclose that Comcast through NBC
Speaker 1:  Universal Investor and V Media, I don't know a lot of people who are like
Speaker 1:  psyched about their relationship with Comcast. And so the idea of like, oh
Speaker 1:  sure, I'll sign up for wireless services just seems tricky. But then I guess
Speaker 1:  the other thing this has made me think a lot about is, And I'm sure you and
Speaker 1:  I have heard this speech from many different people, many times that like
Speaker 1:  people want to have fewer accounts and fewer bills and just the
Speaker 1:  idea of like, okay, I can take your wireless service away from being another
Speaker 1:  account and another bill and another customer service line and just wrap
Speaker 1:  it into this thing you already have. And I think if I'm getting like galaxy
Speaker 1:  brained about it, I think that's the theory for like the bank, right? Which
Speaker 1:  is a, a very sticky account that you're probably gonna keep for a very long
Speaker 1:  time. It's like you're used to dealing with your bank.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I think so. And there's, there's a little bit of like,
Speaker 7:  we are more used to like dealing with things online
Speaker 7:  And I think like five or so years
Speaker 7:  ago if I thought about switching wireless service, I'm like, well I gotta
Speaker 7:  walk into a store And I gotta talk to a T-Mobile person
Speaker 7:  and get a SIM card and do the thing
Speaker 1:  And they're gonna spend an hour trying to convince me not to quit. And yeah,
Speaker 1:  that's the thing I hate the most about it is when you call and you're like,
Speaker 1:  I would like to cancel. And they're like, would you like a deal? And you're
Speaker 1:  like, I would like to cancel. And they're like, you would you like a better
Speaker 1:  deal? And you're like, I would like to cancel,
Speaker 7:  Right? And
Speaker 1:  They're like, okay, I can offer you a year of service for 99 cents. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And I like, just let me go. Yeah, I quit. Please let,
Speaker 7:  Let me leave. Where, where were you six months ago with this deal? Yeah,
Speaker 7:  no, So I, I know I am not in a hurry to
Speaker 7:  add more accounts to my life, but I think yeah, it,
Speaker 7:  having EIM as an option makes it
Speaker 7:  easier And I think a little bit of the,
Speaker 7:  of the momentum is there with your, I talked to
Speaker 7:  my hairstylist and she switched to Mint mobile and she is
Speaker 7:  not a tech person and was a little bit terrified about doing all of
Speaker 7:  this, but she's like, yeah, it's, you know, they talk you through it. There's
Speaker 7:  cute little graphical interfaces to help you like
Speaker 7:  switch your plan and you do it. I, I think having
Speaker 7:  those things there for people kind of help
Speaker 7:  spread the word of like, oh, this isn't as terrifying as it sounds like
Speaker 7:  and you don't actually have to go spend half a day at a wireless
Speaker 7:  carrier retail store, right?
Speaker 1:  My sort of Galaxy brain theory about why this could be a very exciting
Speaker 1:  trend and I'm curious if you agree with this theory. I talked a little bit
Speaker 1:  about this with Jake on Friday, but I've been thinking about it ever since
Speaker 1:  that what we get now is we get like at and
Speaker 1:  t T-Mobile, Verizon have spent tons of money building
Speaker 1:  very impressive infrastructure all over the United States. This stuff is
Speaker 1:  gonna get bigger, they're gonna keep working on this and they're going to
Speaker 1:  be increasingly happy to like recoup that investment by selling it to MVNOs,
Speaker 1:  right? So we're gonna get this giant proliferation of ways to
Speaker 1:  get more or less identical wireless service,
Speaker 1:  like sort of within a, within a small range of quality, pretty good wireless
Speaker 1:  service. What that means now is there are going to be a million
Speaker 1:  ways to compete on everything else, right? Like the, the, they're gonna
Speaker 1:  compete on billing, they're gonna compete on like how good the app is for
Speaker 1:  managing your account. They're gonna compete on different kinds of features
Speaker 1:  and different stuff you can do and different perks that you get or they're
Speaker 1:  just gonna compete on price. And all of a sudden that like we've been on
Speaker 1:  this constant rise in the cost of wireless service.
Speaker 1:  Like a thing we talk about on the show all the time is that we get pretty
Speaker 1:  bad service for a lot more money than almost anywhere else. And it's largely
Speaker 1:  because there are three companies that matter and nothing else. And
Speaker 1:  it's not the same as having like truly competitive networks
Speaker 1:  everywhere, but it's, it's, it's the closest to that that we're gonna get
Speaker 1:  I think. And, and so maybe what we're gonna get is this
Speaker 1:  gigantic boom and like if not the network competition then
Speaker 1:  like interface competition on top of that network. Yeah. And that might be
Speaker 1:  very exciting. So like I've, I've been reading about Disney Mobile a bunch.
Speaker 1:  Do you know about Disney Mobile at all?
Speaker 7:  No.
Speaker 1:  Disney has an MVNO. No. Amazing really,
Speaker 1:  to be honest with you, I could not confirm whether it still exists. Okay.
Speaker 1:  I don't think it's popular, I'll tell you that. Alright. But it launched
Speaker 1:  in 2006. Like to your point, this stuff has been around for a long time.
Speaker 1:  It was originally on the Sprint network and this was the thing that really
Speaker 1:  was, I was like, oh, this is why MVNOs could be awesome. So
Speaker 1:  it was basically, it was a like Disney based
Speaker 1:  experience. They were like, we we wanna do for, for families and kids
Speaker 1:  and parents what we think they would want in a
Speaker 1:  phone service. So here's just a list. I'm reading their press release from
Speaker 1:  2006 and they have a bunch of new features that they were
Speaker 1:  launching. One was set spending allowances and track usage for, for
Speaker 1:  voice minutes and all this stuff back when minutes were a thing. Oh yeah.
Speaker 1:  And you would get alerts when the allowances had been reached so parents
Speaker 1:  could be like, you know, you get this many text messages and this many minutes
Speaker 1:  and then it'll, it'll let us know when you get to the end of it. That was
Speaker 1:  a big deal back then back when everyone was paying a ton for minutes over.
Speaker 1:  It determine the hours of the day and days of the week when kids can use
Speaker 1:  their phone. Good idea. Program restricted and always on phone numbers to
Speaker 1:  manage with whom kids may communicate super smart, prioritize
Speaker 1:  important family messages and locate kids' phones with GPS capabilities.
Speaker 1:  So they took this thing right and they're like, okay this is sprint service,
Speaker 1:  but we can actually like change the features you get with your plan
Speaker 1:  and how you use it and how you access it and how we bill it in a way that
Speaker 1:  makes more sense for this group of people. And that to me
Speaker 1:  is like, I'm like, oh you could, there are an infinite number of versions
Speaker 1:  of that thing that you could do And I think that is like
Speaker 1:  way more so than just like one fewer bill. That idea I find super,
Speaker 1:  super, super compelling. Am I just totally piped dreaming here? Like is this
Speaker 1:  not where we're headed? Could, could I have this world or am I just insane?
Speaker 7:  I hope you're right And I think like some of that will happen,
Speaker 7:  but the thing that makes me a little pessimistic is that it all starts with
Speaker 7:  their relationship with the main three carriers and
Speaker 7:  they, I don't know what level they're dictating, like what
Speaker 7:  you can and can't do, you know, with the service
Speaker 7:  it certainly in their interest to make sure that like
Speaker 7:  their offering is the shiniest best, you know, coolest.
Speaker 7:  I think it has already happened a little bit with like with
Speaker 7:  MIT mobile and T-Mobile buying MIT mobile
Speaker 7:  kind of speaks a lot I think about how
Speaker 7:  that is an important piece of business that they wanna bring
Speaker 7:  back in-house. So I, I don't know, I'm just a
Speaker 7:  little pessimistic from the like capitalism, doing
Speaker 7:  capitalism kind of side of it. But I hope it would
Speaker 7:  be cool if there were like actual better ways to
Speaker 7:  interact with a wireless company. I definitely we're gonna see
Speaker 7:  like I think some of the MVNOs are sort of bundling
Speaker 7:  services in that way to kind of like differentiate
Speaker 7:  and the Liberty mobile, which is the network that
Speaker 7:  the MVNO that Trump mobile is just kind of glomming onto.
Speaker 7:  They had a whole bunch of thing that was like, it was like telehealth and
Speaker 7:  device protection. It would be cool to see
Speaker 7:  a company do that and do it in a
Speaker 7:  good way that doesn't feel like upselling. You know,
Speaker 7:  I don know why this just pops into my head, but I was like, Headspace should
Speaker 7:  do an MVNO. What if Headspace did? Oh that's
Speaker 7:  interesting. I don't know like built in soothing
Speaker 7:  activities that you could do when you're dealing with
Speaker 7:  your wireless carrier.
Speaker 1:  No. See, okay, here's, here's my idea for Headspace. It
Speaker 1:  Headspace dynamically replaces all hold music with
Speaker 1:  meditations. Yeah, yeah, yeah. So when you're waiting it just, it just replaces
Speaker 1:  it and it gives you just like a five minute meditation. Yeah. While you're
Speaker 1:  waiting on hold to talk to, you know, your bank or whoever.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It's like we noticed you're on hold with Walgreens for 30 minutes.
Speaker 7:  Would you like, would
Speaker 1:  You like to meditate?
Speaker 7:  Do you wanna hear the sound of whales? Yeah,
Speaker 1:  I do. Thank you. Headspace. I would love to hear whale sounds
Speaker 7:  Free idea. I will sign up for Headspace Mobile.
Speaker 1:  Headspace, get at us. You, you can have this, but we do have free service.
Speaker 1:  That's how this works.
Speaker 1:  One other question on this and, and then I'm gonna let you go. The, the other
Speaker 1:  piece of this to me seems like phone unlocking becomes
Speaker 1:  an important part of the equation here, right? Like E SIMs make it easy to
Speaker 1:  switch your phone, but we're still in this kind of nebulous,
Speaker 1:  is my phone locked to my carrier world here in the United
Speaker 1:  States? Again, I should point out that so much of this is gonna seem like
Speaker 1:  esoteric and ridiculous to people anywhere else who have long had better,
Speaker 1:  more competitive mobile phone universes that
Speaker 1:  don't require all of the shenanigans that we're talking about here. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  But here in America it does feel like if we can get eims and we can get
Speaker 1:  unlocked phones and we can get big vast carrier choice, we are
Speaker 1:  like somewhere cool and exciting. Are we on a good path
Speaker 1:  to unlocked phones?
Speaker 7:  I think we're on a like very slow good path. Okay. There's
Speaker 7:  some legislation I think they were trying to tell the
Speaker 7:  carriers like, you cannot lock someone's phone to a network.
Speaker 7:  Like you have to unlock it after a certain amount is it was like six months,
Speaker 7:  I think it was
Speaker 1:  60 days was the the thing they were
Speaker 7:  Going for 60 days. Okay, yeah. That's even better whether or not
Speaker 7:  like I've paid off my device to Verizon, that's between me and
Speaker 7:  Verizon. But like they can't just be like, you may only
Speaker 7:  use this phone on a network. That's good. That's progress
Speaker 7:  I think. But I think there is a little bit of just a habit
Speaker 7:  with, especially in the US of like, it's time for a new phone.
Speaker 7:  Go to Verizon, right? Or go to their website and, and
Speaker 7:  undoing that a little bit. I don't know exactly how that starts,
Speaker 7:  but like you can just go to Apple's website and
Speaker 7:  you can get a device like payment plan. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  It doesn't have to come from the wireless carrier but somehow the,
Speaker 7:  the good deal always seems to be tied into like, well
Speaker 7:  you know, if you connect to your Verizon account we'll just help pay for
Speaker 7:  this phone for you.
Speaker 1:  All right, for now, go back to your day off. Thank you for doing this. I
Speaker 1:  appreciate it. We are gonna take a break and then we're gonna come back and
Speaker 1:  do a question from the hotline. Thank you Allison.
Speaker 7:  Thank you.
Speaker 1:  Be right back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Let's go to a question from the first cast hotline
Speaker 1:  as always. Number is 8 6 6 VERGE one one. The
Speaker 1:  email is vergecast at The Verge dot com. You can hit me up directly like
Speaker 1:  we're not hard to find. If you have questions, get at us. We love hearing
Speaker 1:  all of your questions. Today's question is something we've talked about on
Speaker 1:  the show before but we get a lot and So I want to just tackle
Speaker 1:  it again in as aggressive and straightforward way as we
Speaker 1:  possibly can. It's about storage here. It's
Speaker 10:  Hey Vergecast, this is Anthony from Denver.
Speaker 10:  I have a question about the best way to free up space on
Speaker 10:  iPhones. Last week while my mom was visiting with me,
Speaker 10:  she had shared that she had just bought new iPhone 16
Speaker 10:  but it was already kind of running outta space and was very slow. So
Speaker 10:  she wanted to know what she could do to free up space on her phone and,
Speaker 10:  and hopefully speed it up. And specifically she wanted to know if there's
Speaker 10:  anything that she could do to remove photos from her phone and, and back
Speaker 10:  them up and and store them elsewhere. Now my, my wife And I we're both
Speaker 10:  Pixel users so we were both kind of flabbergasted
Speaker 10:  to learn that Apple doesn't have a photo backup solution.
Speaker 10:  It has iCloud, which is ti far, far as you know, we could tell
Speaker 10:  is like a syncing service, but Apple doesn't really have any solution for
Speaker 10:  both backing up photos while also removing them
Speaker 10:  from the device. And so after researching for a few
Speaker 10:  hours the, the solution that we ended up like coming to
Speaker 10:  is you could use a service like Google Photos or Amazon photos
Speaker 10:  or you could try downloading them to a computer and moving them to
Speaker 10:  an external hard drive. My wife And I, we ended up deciding to solve this
Speaker 10:  problem with Google Photos and after about two hours or so of backing up
Speaker 10:  most of the photos and deleting some of them, we ended up saving her about
Speaker 10:  50 gigabytes of space on our iPhone. But we
Speaker 10:  were both kind of left wondering like how has Apple not made
Speaker 10:  a well designed like photo backup solution?
Speaker 10:  Like why would anyone want to use 50 gigabytes of
Speaker 10:  space on their device for photos when they don't
Speaker 10:  have to, when they probably don't even want those photos to be
Speaker 10:  on their device at all? And is there really, like is there
Speaker 10:  anything else that iPhone users can do?
Speaker 1:  You, you can see why they sent me down a rabbit hole of thinking about where
Speaker 1:  all of my stuff is, right? And I have a few
Speaker 1:  thoughts for our, our friend here and for everyone who is thinking about
Speaker 1:  this switch as far as I can tell is everyone I think like I'm running out
Speaker 1:  of storage on my phone is as universal a problem
Speaker 1:  as anybody has on technology, right? Like it's, it's everywhere. So
Speaker 1:  here's what I would say. If you use an iPhone, this is all going to be Apple
Speaker 1:  specific because frankly Apple does this in the worst possible way and Google
Speaker 1:  is at least a lot more straightforward. You just dump stuff into Google Photos
Speaker 1:  and there it's, the thing that I would say is that a, even if
Speaker 1:  you're on iOS, Google Photos is great and you should use it if you, there's
Speaker 1:  a good chance you have lots of storage over there. That's a thing I pay for
Speaker 1:  separately anyway just because I wanted the drive storage and the more Gmail
Speaker 1:  and so like there's a solid chance you're already paying for more
Speaker 1:  Google storage. So use that, use Google Photos, turn on the auto backup,
Speaker 1:  it'll send everything up there. I think Google Photos is a vastly better
Speaker 1:  photo experience than anything Apple is doing. So that's what I tend to use
Speaker 1:  anyway. I also will say, And I, And I hate so much
Speaker 1:  that I'm saying this, Apple's 2 99 a month,
Speaker 1:  200 gigabyte iCloud deal is a pretty good deal. It
Speaker 1:  is absurd that you don't get that for free. That that's not the base tier,
Speaker 1:  that Apple, the richest company in the world is going to nickel and dime
Speaker 1:  you $3 a month just to have like an appropriate amount of storage for your
Speaker 1:  photos. But it's, it's three bucks a month to largely not
Speaker 1:  have to think about this most of the time and frankly that's worth it.
Speaker 1:  A couple of other things, the the first thing most people should do is go
Speaker 1:  to settings on their phone and turn on the
Speaker 1:  optimized storage thing in photos. Lemme just do this right now So I have
Speaker 1:  it right. You go, you go to settings and then you tap
Speaker 1:  on your name at the very top and then you go to iCloud and then you tap
Speaker 1:  on photos. So this is telling me I have
Speaker 1:  10,745 photos and 687 videos
Speaker 1:  taking up 102.29 gigabytes of space. That's a lot.
Speaker 1:  I suspect there are a lot of you who have much more than that and you wanna
Speaker 1:  turn on the thing that says optimize iPhone storage. So basically
Speaker 1:  what that does is instead of leaving the whole kind of
Speaker 1:  increasingly large file with every new rev of Apple's camera system
Speaker 1:  on your device, it keeps all of it in iCloud and downloads a smaller
Speaker 1:  one to your device. What I have found is this is just
Speaker 1:  rubbish at actually working. Sometimes it loads things way too
Speaker 1:  slowly. Some it seems to leave things on your device for too long. It is
Speaker 1:  not actually optimizing space nearly as successfully
Speaker 1:  as it ought to. Again this is where Google photos does it much better. It
Speaker 1:  just leaves all this stuff in the cloud and then you tap it and it pulls
Speaker 1:  it down when you need it. Like much better system but that
Speaker 1:  should at least save you a little bit of space. There is also
Speaker 1:  a bunch of tools in here for just deleting things, which I think is
Speaker 1:  what I would tell most people to do. So again, you go, you go into settings
Speaker 1:  and you go to your face and you go to iCloud and you go to photos and
Speaker 1:  then you hit manage storage and it loads this thing for you that
Speaker 1:  basically then gives you actual information about
Speaker 1:  all of this stuff on your phone, right? It, it takes a long time
Speaker 1:  in my case because it has to look through 10,000 things but it pops up a
Speaker 1:  thing that says review your photos and videos. Mine is telling me I can get
Speaker 1:  50 gigabytes of space back by deleting duplicates, screenshots and videos.
Speaker 1:  In my case almost all of that is videos. And the thing I
Speaker 1:  like about this is there's this one screen all the way deep down here
Speaker 1:  in settings that will actually show you in order your largest
Speaker 1:  videos. And I would bet, and I have confirmed this both on my phone and
Speaker 1:  on some others just as sort of basic, you know, research purposes
Speaker 1:  that almost everybody has a few like sneakily humongous
Speaker 1:  videos on your device. You accidentally took a seven minute long
Speaker 1:  video in your pocket without noticing it. You have one that's like six minutes
Speaker 1:  of ProRes that is taking up half the storage on your phone. Like there's
Speaker 1:  just a bunch of little things here. So for me, like if I delete the nine
Speaker 1:  biggest videos on my phone, I'm looking at eight
Speaker 1:  gigabytes worth of space just to free up like that. So that's
Speaker 1:  one thing to do. You can delete all your screenshots, you can delete all
Speaker 1:  of your complicated overly
Speaker 1:  done edited photos. You can delete your duplicates, you can delete all the
Speaker 1:  stuff that you don't need and it's much easier to do here in settings than
Speaker 1:  it is almost anywhere else on your phone. So delete the stuff,
Speaker 1:  put it in iCloud. And then the thing that I would do if
Speaker 1:  you like really want to invest in this is go to the iCloud photos
Speaker 1:  website, which is a better way to like mass move
Speaker 1:  stuff around, open it up, make the use the little
Speaker 1:  slider at the top to make the photos as small as possible. Scroll all the
Speaker 1:  way to the top to the very first photos you took, which o
Speaker 1:  overwhelmingly I suspect are ones you might wanna keep but don't need like
Speaker 1:  ready access to download all those photos and put them somewhere else,
Speaker 1:  like delete some of them, download some of them it, it is easy
Speaker 1:  and quick to do from a web browser in a way that on your phone or an iPad
Speaker 1:  or even in the Photos app on a Mac is just kind of messy. This is like a
Speaker 1:  good mass tool for just getting
Speaker 1:  everything out. And what I'm trying to do in this go round is basically
Speaker 1:  only keep the last couple of years of photos actually in my iCloud. Everything
Speaker 1:  else goes into this like permanent storage of some kind. And
Speaker 1:  so the idea is that I have a place to get those and someday when I want to
Speaker 1:  go look at them, I will know where they are but they're not sitting in the
Speaker 1:  cloud storage accessible to me all the time and taking up space because they
Speaker 1:  don't need to be And I don't need them all the time. So those are all my
Speaker 1:  recommendations. You probably have lots of storage space also by the way
Speaker 1:  in places like Amazon and Microsoft and everybody I think has like a
Speaker 1:  Dropbox account lingering that they're not using. There are places you can
Speaker 1:  put things other than iCloud And I would encourage you for almost everything
Speaker 1:  that isn't something you think you're gonna like actively need and use,
Speaker 1:  put it somewhere else because Apple does not do a good job of managing your
Speaker 1:  storage and desperately wants you to overpay for it. So just don't play
Speaker 1:  Apple's games, delete all your biggest stuff, put it all
Speaker 1:  somewhere else. And I think life will be okay. And in theory, this is a thing
Speaker 1:  you should do, I don't know, once a year that'll take you 20 minutes. It's
Speaker 1:  like not a hard project, but it is a thing you shouldn't have to do. That
Speaker 1:  is not to excuse Apple. It's annoying that this is the case, but that's what
Speaker 1:  I do. So I hope any of that helps. And if you have a better tip
Speaker 1:  for how to manage all of this stuff so that you don't have to go in at the
Speaker 1:  last minute, every once in a while and just mass delete a bunch of stuff,
Speaker 1:  I would love to hear it. Tell me all of your tips. Alright, that is
Speaker 1:  it for the show today. Thank you to everybody who's on the show with me.
Speaker 1:  And thank you as always for listening as ever, if you have questions, thoughts,
Speaker 1:  feelings, storage ideas, weird things that you're as obsessive as
Speaker 1:  I am about with markdown files, get at us. The
Speaker 1:  hotline is 8 6 6 VERGE one one. The email is Vergecast at The Verge
Speaker 1:  dot com. We absolutely love hearing from you. This podcast is produced by
Speaker 1:  Will for Eric Gomez and Brandon Kiefer. The Vergecast is VERGE production
Speaker 1:  and part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neli and I'll be back on
Speaker 1:  Friday to talk potentially more about Tesla. He's gonna have some FCC thoughts.
Speaker 1:  We got a lot of stuff to catch up on before we all head out on parental
Speaker 1:  leave. We'll see you then. Rock and roll