# Transcript
ID: f24a0c55-8c86-4c37-89fb-461f36c27aa8
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-5864802473182750791/-6009757246145900744/s93290-US-4643s-1736726140.mp3
Description: In this special live episode of The Vergecast, from the Brooklyn Bowl in Las Vegas, it's time to talk CES. Nilay and David run through some of the show's biggest stories, plus the Meta news that dominated the conversations all week in Vegas. Then Allison Johnson, Jennifer Pattison Tuohy, and Victoria Song join the show to talk about all the newest, best, weirdest, and worst gadgets they've seen this year. AI is everywhere, everyone's making smart glasses, the smart home might be turning a corner, and we've seen it all this week.
Thanks to everyone who came out to the live show! And if you couldn't make it, stay tuned — this won't be the last time we all get to hang out.
Speaker 3:  Hello and welcome to Vergecast the flagship podcast of Bowling.
Speaker 4:  Can we pivot to that? This feels good.
Speaker 3:  It does feel good. I'm your friend. Neli David Pierce is here.
Speaker 4:  Hello. Do you spin the ball when you bowl? Like does it go? Does it do the
Speaker 4:  great,
Speaker 3:  I don't wanna tell you my moves. We are live at CES. We're at Brooklyn Bowl.
Speaker 3:  We have a live audience. Say hello to the live audience. Live audience. Say
Speaker 3:  hello to the listeners.
Speaker 3:  It's crazy in here. Delta has taken
Speaker 3:  over Brooklyn Bowl on our behalf. There's Vir has logos at the bar on
Speaker 3:  all the screens. This is a super cool room. Thank you all so much for being
Speaker 3:  here with us. If you're listening, we're gonna try to keep this on the rails
Speaker 3:  as much as we ever keep a VERGE cast on the rails. But I, I
Speaker 3:  have to be honest with you, just the presence of this crowd has me knowing
Speaker 3:  that things are gonna get super weird on this episode of VERGE Cast, it's
Speaker 3:  gonna be great. Jen, Allison and Vie are gonna join us. We're gonna talk
Speaker 3:  about everything that's happening in cs, across their beats, across other
Speaker 3:  beats. There's a helicopter that lands in a van that I really, really want
Speaker 3:  to talk about.
Speaker 4:  You've brought this up so many times now and you've like, you keep bringing
Speaker 4:  it up in such a way where you're like, you don't think it's cool, but you've
Speaker 4:  now said it so many times that I'm like, NELI actually thinks this is very
Speaker 4:  cool and
Speaker 3:  It's lot we're gonna get into, I don't wanna, I don't wanna waste that we're
Speaker 3:  gonna get into it,
Speaker 3:  but there's, and we're gonna have lightning rounds obviously Search cast
Speaker 4:  Sponsored by all these people, sponsored
Speaker 3:  By all these people. David, tell me like, what's your vibe on CS this year?
Speaker 4:  It's, it's been a weird CES.
Speaker 4:  There hasn't been like the thing, like, I feel like last
Speaker 4:  year the rabbit R one, which sucks, was the thing
Speaker 4:  at CES. It was like, it was the gadget that a lot of people were talking
Speaker 4:  about and interested in. And this year it's like, it's, it's almost like
Speaker 4:  two practical, like all the stuff I'm excited about and that we're gonna
Speaker 4:  talk about is like real things that real people are gonna use, which is not
Speaker 4:  what CES is about. Yeah. CES is about like deranged ideas about technology
Speaker 4:  and there are lots of those and we will get to many of them. Yeah. Including
Speaker 4:  helicopters that come out of the back of cars. But it, it just doesn't feel
Speaker 4:  like there has been like the, the one sort of breakout thing
Speaker 4:  yet, which in terms of like stuff that regular people will actually buy.
Speaker 4:  It's probably a good CES on that front, but it doesn't feel
Speaker 4:  quite csy that way. Yeah. Does that make
Speaker 3:  Sense? So I have another theory about what's going on, CS and I, it's like
Speaker 3:  my face hugger theory of technology. Okay. Or
Speaker 3:  like what, you know, an aliens like brush outta the chest. There's cs
Speaker 3:  the, the show that we all think we're coming to with the gadgets and the
Speaker 3:  TVs and whatever. And then at the aria there's the
Speaker 3:  marketing people. Yes. There's some marketing people
Speaker 3:  here. Be careful they're gonna latch onto your face and then
Speaker 4:  On you can like it's literally, it's like much better dressed people walking
Speaker 4:  much more intentionally at the Aria. Yes. Than at the Venetian.
Speaker 3:  Well I'll get that one second. There are definitely better dressed intentionally
Speaker 3:  seems maybe. So If you
Speaker 3:  just think about what's going on in technology broadly, right? We all have
Speaker 3:  screens. The screens have apps. They show you video, they show you ai, slop,
Speaker 3:  whatever they're showing you. And in the middle all that's funded by advertising.
Speaker 3:  And sometime over the past decade the advertising industry realized that
Speaker 3:  they should be here. Where everyone's gonna talk about next year's screens
Speaker 3:  and then they have the money and like
Speaker 3:  the the car helicopter car guys like I'm here too.
Speaker 3:  And so it's just like this other parallel CES is here
Speaker 3:  where If you want to meet 300 Meta executives, they're at the
Speaker 3:  Aria. Yeah. They're not on the show floor. If you want to see the entire
Speaker 3:  Amazon's ads team or all the TikTok people, they're here. Like
Speaker 3:  a lot of the major company executives are here. They're just deal making
Speaker 3:  about ads somewhere else. And the show floor is like, it's
Speaker 3:  not what it used to be. And So I think that's where you get the like there's
Speaker 3:  not one big thing that everyone's talking about. 'cause the one big thing
Speaker 3:  everyone's talking about is like programmatic advertising.
Speaker 4:  Well and the other one is is ai, which
Speaker 4:  I was talking to one of 'em gonna steal our thunder from one of our guests
Speaker 4:  here who was saying basically like the strange thing about AI is you can't
Speaker 4:  demo it to anybody. Yeah. Like it's just, it's, it's just like a thing that
Speaker 4:  happens but it actually just looks like a television. So you're like, this
Speaker 4:  television has a chat bot and it's like well A, what does that mean And B,
Speaker 4:  how do you show that on a show floor? So it's like Samsung just had a ship
Speaker 4:  because that's the only thing there is to show is look, it's
Speaker 3:  The Samsung booth has a sign in it and If you have been to the show floor,
Speaker 3:  the Samsung booth has a sign in, it says smart things for ships. This is
Speaker 3:  real. Which seems dangerous to me as a person who runs smart things in
Speaker 3:  his home. We'll have Jen on later I'll, we can ask her if she thinks smart
Speaker 3:  things is
Speaker 4:  Appropriate. I would just say
Speaker 3:  For sea bound navigation you
Speaker 4:  Spend a tremendous amount of time talking about how your goal is boat money.
Speaker 4:  And I feel like smart things for ships boat money, like there's a straight
Speaker 4:  line in there for
Speaker 3:  You some. Well, so right next to smart Things for Ship is a sign that says
Speaker 3:  society. It's not even like connected society, it's just the
Speaker 3:  word society. And it's like Samsung is announcing society
Speaker 3:  and next to society, their vision for it is that your ship will have
Speaker 3:  smart home technology on it. And you're like, I think,
Speaker 3:  I think this is a dangerous approach to what we're doing, but it's really
Speaker 3:  weird. Like Samsung is showing all these like solutions. There's no products
Speaker 3:  in their booth, which is really weird. There's a model of a ship in the word
Speaker 3:  society and then we're gonna talk about the Frame tv, I promise you we're
Speaker 3:  gonna talk about Frame tv. Those are the two wolves inside beach shows. And
Speaker 3:  the Frame TV is not even being demoed in that booth. The art gallery, the
Speaker 3:  Frame TV is being demoed in that booth. So it's just very odd
Speaker 3:  moment for I think a lot of these companies where they're over the hardware
Speaker 3:  race. Yeah. And then a bunch of the younger companies, the TCLs are like
Speaker 3:  still super in the hardware race.
Speaker 3:  I will say, and we should talk about this quickly, we're gonna talk about
Speaker 3:  this a lot I suspect for the next four years because there are so many marketers
Speaker 3:  here and because there are so many major technology company executives here.
Speaker 3:  Meta announced yesterday that they're getting rid of fact checking. They're
Speaker 3:  going, they're changing their community standards. And we've been able to
Speaker 3:  do a bunch of reporting about that 'cause everyone's here. And then sort
Speaker 3:  of like what does it mean to advertise on Meta when their community
Speaker 3:  guidelines are changing is a thing that I've just had conversations about
Speaker 3:  because all of those folks are here and I, that's not
Speaker 3:  usually what you expect from cs. I'm assuming you came here to
Speaker 3:  hear me rant about the Frame TV and not about Meta community guidelines,
Speaker 3:  although it's The Vergecast. So you, I'm hoping that you all understand both
Speaker 3:  things will always happen at the same time.
Speaker 3:  But that to me has been the story of the show just
Speaker 3:  because of the rooms I have happened to be in. Yeah. Everyone is talking
Speaker 3:  about it. Oh for sure. 'cause it feels like the whole tech industry is now
Speaker 3:  in a much more transactional place. Cynically transactional.
Speaker 3:  And that announcement coming on the first day of cs I think is no
Speaker 3:  accident of timing because all of Meta's marketers are here with their clients
Speaker 3:  explaining what they mean when they say you can now refer to women
Speaker 3:  as household objects on Meta. Which is a rule that they have changed. Yep.
Speaker 3:  That's a rule that you can do. And the reason they announced it here is 'cause
Speaker 3:  their salespeople are sitting with their biggest clients being like, here's
Speaker 3:  how this is actually gonna play out. And I think that has gotten a little
Speaker 3:  bit lost, right? Like yes, the timing is weird. Yes. It,
Speaker 3:  mark Stocker made what appears to be like a hostage video.
Speaker 3:  Is anyone here good at makeup? Can someone help him? So he is not always
Speaker 3:  blown out in the T-zone. Like I'm only, I look great an eyeliner and that's
Speaker 3:  all I know how to do. But my goth phase did not. He always
Speaker 3:  looks like he just needs to get evened out.
Speaker 3:  That's just facts. But this is also
Speaker 4:  Just what he does every four years now is make one of those videos where
Speaker 4:  he takes the opposite position of the one that he took four years ago.
Speaker 3:  Right. And it's super cynical. I I think he's gotten a little bit radicalized,
Speaker 3:  right? He gets yelled at a lot. I think none of the big tech companies liked
Speaker 3:  working with the Biden administration because the Biden administration's
Speaker 3:  approach the big tech companies or what was effectively what If you didn't
Speaker 3:  exist, right? It's true. They all hated
Speaker 3:  Lena Khan. They all hated this Department of Justice. Google has two
Speaker 3:  antitrust cases. Brewing Meta has a big one coming up in April.
Speaker 3:  That's I think the FTC is running about Instagram and WhatsApp and potentially
Speaker 3:  breaking that apart. So I think they all just made their deal with the devil
Speaker 3:  to be like, we give Trump money, maybe these problems will go away.
Speaker 3:  And I think part of that is Mark literally using a lot of,
Speaker 3:  like he says, the the legacy media is lying to you. Like in that
Speaker 3:  video he says transgenderism and he says that you can, the
Speaker 3:  rule is now you can refer to being gay or transgender as a mental
Speaker 3:  illness. These are explicit, these are dog whistles to a community that
Speaker 3:  is very, very receptive to them. And all of that is transactional. Right?
Speaker 3:  Whether or not he believes that, I don't know. There's a lot of gay and trans
Speaker 3:  people who work at Meta, like he has to support his own team in some way.
Speaker 3:  And I think he's gonna have to explain that.
Speaker 4:  It also doesn't matter. Like I think, I think the, the lesson we're learning
Speaker 4:  here really quickly is that what Mark Zuckerberg believes, or what Tim Cook
Speaker 4:  believes or what any of these folks believe actually doesn't matter. Like
Speaker 4:  they, they will run their companies as business people. And I think the,
Speaker 4:  the thing that is happening is we, we either have to decide
Speaker 4:  to stop being surprised or like dedicate ourselves to continuing to
Speaker 4:  be angry that this happens. But this is just, everyone has just said what
Speaker 4:  it is now.
Speaker 3:  I I was with another big tech company executive yesterday and they were just
Speaker 3:  like, we're treating the this this time it's business.
Speaker 3:  I was, I was just the point of view that they had and I, it's
Speaker 4:  Just been business the whole time. But I think that there was, there was
Speaker 4:  a long period of time where there was a sense that like, okay, maybe
Speaker 4:  we are going to buy into this new world where like young people care about
Speaker 4:  values and each other and we're gonna save the world and you know, ESG is
Speaker 4:  gonna be a part. And then everybody has decided, oh nevermind. That's actually
Speaker 4:  not what it is. We're just going to win at capitalism. And that is, that
Speaker 4:  is the game.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So we're gonna cover this a lot. I think over the next four years
Speaker 3:  we already have some further coverage scheduled for next week on both the
Speaker 3:  site and the podcast. But I just, I wanted to call it out being one because
Speaker 3:  we're like, what's the story of CES? For me, part of the story of
Speaker 3:  CS is the marketing industry is here, like in force it
Speaker 3:  is driving the show in a way that is basically invisible even on
Speaker 3:  our site. Like our site is basically like, look at this laptop, it folds
Speaker 3:  in half. And that's really fun and I love it. But the money here is all
Speaker 3:  is all in the aria. It's all, a lot of people talking about how to command
Speaker 3:  attention and the story of the show over there
Speaker 3:  has been the biggest advertising platform around has made this big
Speaker 3:  capitulation, this very transactional, very cynical capitulation. And
Speaker 3:  I think that's gonna have repercussions across the tech industry. Yeah. Because
Speaker 3:  If you don't have to spend $270 million in Pennsylvania,
Speaker 3:  like you don't, you won't. And I think they're all gonna learn that lesson
Speaker 3:  from Mark. And I think the question is like, does anybody, does anybody here
Speaker 3:  think Mark Zuckerberg is not like a ruthless transactional businessman
Speaker 3:  bowling? Yeah. He gave one of these. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Like a half and half. Does anyone think Tim Cook is not a ruthlessly
Speaker 3:  transactional businessman Like Tim Cook famously the why are you
Speaker 3:  still here story. You guys know the story where like they were talking about
Speaker 3:  some problem with the supplier in China and his lieutenant was here and he
Speaker 3:  looked at him and he said, why are you still here? And the guy got up, left
Speaker 3:  the room and flew to China. Yeah. That guy, he's gonna be able to handle
Speaker 3:  it, right? He handled Trump excellently the first time. Bezos
Speaker 3:  ruthlessly transactional businessman. Yep. And then you've got like Sundar,
Speaker 3:  like can he do it? Like, can Evan Spiegel roll up to Mar-a-Lago and
Speaker 3:  be like, I've redesigned the Snapchat interface again.
Speaker 3:  Like I think all like this is gonna have huge repercussions across the tech
Speaker 3:  industry. 'cause you need to be all kind of personality. And so we're gonna
Speaker 3:  cover it I think for the next four years. But,
Speaker 4:  But
Speaker 3:  That's it. Now we should cover gadgets. Can we
Speaker 4:  Talk about the biggest question of CES? This is the, the the all that stuff
Speaker 4:  is, you know, more important. Whatever the question I have about CES is,
Speaker 4:  is the Frame Pro actually a good television? Oh my
Speaker 3:  God. All right. Have you,
Speaker 4:  I mean this question sincerely. So Chris Welch on our team wrote about the,
Speaker 4:  the saying Samsung, the frame. I've learned that it's not called the Frame
Speaker 4:  television, it's called The Frame, which is ridiculous and I hate it. But
Speaker 4:  The Frame Pro is a new tv and he started by being like, oh,
Speaker 4:  this thing might kick ass. It's very cool. Lots of new stuff. And over the
Speaker 4:  course of like 72 hours has come to basically I have been lied to. This
Speaker 4:  thing might be awful. And So I wanna know, I wanna know how you feel.
Speaker 3:  I want one, I want to point out as America's, I have not spent any time with
Speaker 3:  Chris. He came to that conclusion independently as America's
Speaker 4:  Foremost frame owner. Which is a thing.
Speaker 4:  You just have to, you have to wear it. I I
Speaker 3:  Do own one. How many people do you have A Frame tv. All right.
Speaker 3:  Bowlers,
Speaker 4:  NELI owes all of you money. Yeah, I just want
Speaker 3:  That that was just a fist in the air. You're just like, yeah, frame tv, lots
Speaker 3:  of frame TVs. I have a Frame tv, everybody knows A Frame tv. The Frame TV
Speaker 3:  represents the death of Hollywood. I want you to, every time you turn on
Speaker 3:  this tv, I want you to be like, what I'm doing is killing Hollywood. And
Speaker 3:  I mean that, I mean that in a very real sense. It is also Samsung's biggest
Speaker 3:  success. It is a cultural product, not a tech product.
Speaker 3:  You buy this thing 'cause it looks good when it's off. You buy this thing
Speaker 3:  'cause it has an art store. How many people are paying the 50 bucks a month
Speaker 3:  for the art store? How many people are that? One person will admit
Speaker 3:  it. How many of you're paying for it and you just don't wanna admit it in
Speaker 3:  this room with me right now, I I pay the money too. All right.
Speaker 3:  It is a cultural product. It is not a technology product. And that is the
Speaker 3:  thing everybody wants. The iPhone is a cultural product. It's not a technology
Speaker 3:  product. It's a very high end technology product. But inherently it's a cultural
Speaker 3:  product. So Samsung can have influencers and HT TV and interior
Speaker 3:  designers sell the frame TV as like a statement piece that you put in your
Speaker 3:  living room. I have a Frame tv. My, I have a new neighbor and they redid
Speaker 3:  their living room and they were like, we bought the Frame tv. And they're
Speaker 3:  like, it's not a Real Frame tv. And I was like, why are you bidding this
Speaker 3:  to me? No one like shows me any other product. And it's like, it's not the
Speaker 3:  real one that doesn't happen. But the Frame TV has achieved the status
Speaker 3:  and the fact that it is a bad TV is like
Speaker 3:  totally secondary to its status. It is a shit tv.
Speaker 3:  I'm sorry. You don't, you don't have, you don't have, you can just, it's
Speaker 3:  fine that I know it and you know it, you don't have to tell anyone else.
Speaker 3:  But it is a 7-year-old Edge lit panel that Samsung
Speaker 3:  has long since made its margin on. And now they're selling them
Speaker 3:  for like three bills. Like a lot of you paid thousands of dollars for your
Speaker 3:  Frame TV when the core component of it is like a $200 Samsung panel
Speaker 3:  from seven years ago. But it's all the stuff they've layered onto it. Right?
Speaker 3:  The Matt display, they break out the box, they make it flat, you can buy
Speaker 3:  the frames. I have a lot to say about the Frames and they art store.
Speaker 3:  So they're, they're making all of this margin based on the lifestyle value
Speaker 3:  of the product on the product itself. And so the Frame Pro,
Speaker 4:  This is such a long way of explaining why you bought a terrible television
Speaker 4:  that has not yet answered my question. So Samsung, the thing this time was
Speaker 4:  they were like, what if we made it a good tv? And it sounds like they didn't
Speaker 4:  do that.
Speaker 3:  They didn't do that. So they, they got to use some words.
Speaker 3:  So the ba so you know Edge Lit TV has the lights around the edge
Speaker 3:  of the screen that light up the, the LCD panel. The new hot tech
Speaker 3:  is mini LED back lights. I have lots and lots of small back lights you can
Speaker 3:  turn on off the zones, you get true blacks. And then you know I have eds
Speaker 3:  which are the, that's what I have. That's actually what I have. Our Frame
Speaker 3:  TV is in our bedroom and my daughter watches Moana. I don't want, she's sick.
Speaker 3:  That's why we own that tv.
Speaker 3:  So Samsung is saying we've made it mini LED which everyone you're supposed
Speaker 3:  to think they're on the cutting edge of the technology 'cause they can't
Speaker 3:  use oled. 'cause If you put art on an OLED picture for days at a time,
Speaker 3:  you'll burn out the oled. So they can't use the best technology. So they
Speaker 3:  say they're using this up and coming disruptive technology called mini where
Speaker 3:  every other mini LED TV has thousands if not tens of thousands of
Speaker 3:  dimming zones that let them simulate an OLED black level. But Samsung isn't
Speaker 3:  doing that. They just put them around the fucking edge of the TV so they
Speaker 3:  can crank 'em really bright so the TV can get brighter. So they still have
Speaker 3:  an edge lit panel, like they haven't done
Speaker 3:  anything. Well
Speaker 4:  They did something. What
Speaker 3:  Did they do? But they
Speaker 4:  Didn't do the thing that they should have done. Which is make it a better
Speaker 4:  television.
Speaker 3:  I don't think it matters when I say it's the death of Hollywood. What I mean
Speaker 3:  is you all bought this to, I keep pointing it all you this like Jacques,
Speaker 3:  how dare you all
Speaker 4:  Of these, these monsters bought this television. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  This every Hollywood celebrity, you know, is mad at you. Tom Cruise is gonna
Speaker 3:  come in here and turn off motion smoothing one by one.
Speaker 3:  But you bought a TV that is better when it's off.
Speaker 3:  Like substantially better in its off state than it's on
Speaker 3:  state. Like the picture quality when the frame TV is off is better than when
Speaker 3:  it's on. And that's cool like that. That's why we have one in our bedroom.
Speaker 3:  'cause it's mostly off. It's such a small step from there
Speaker 3:  to just hanging a real picture on your wall.
Speaker 3:  It's such a small step from there to what's the, there's an e ink, like
Speaker 3:  color e ink frame that they're selling here.
Speaker 4:  It's a poster. You have to charge it once a
Speaker 3:  Year that has an art store. It's such a small step to that. It's such a small
Speaker 3:  step to not having a TV because your,
Speaker 3:  your TV is off showing you $50 a year content from
Speaker 3:  the MoMA while you're on TikTok.
Speaker 4:  Can I offer you a different idea? Which is the new LG stand by Me too. Which
Speaker 4:  is just a thing you carry with a strap. This is a why a television when you
Speaker 4:  can have a television with you all the time.
Speaker 3:  Have you guys seen this Stand by Me too. It has a strap, but then it also
Speaker 3:  has a, so it's just a TV with a battery and it, a battery lasts for like
Speaker 3:  four hours. It's very funny. The, you know, the first one was a suitcase.
Speaker 3:  It came in like a, like a James Bond style suitcase
Speaker 3:  with a, he would play solitaire on it. So he'd be like, I'm James Bond. And
Speaker 3:  he'd be like, we're playing solitaire. But it ha the now it
Speaker 3:  has a strap, it has a giant surface style kickstand attachment.
Speaker 3:  So you can just make it a giant tablet computer, which is very cool. Everyone
Speaker 3:  I saw encounter this thing in the LGB earth was captivated by it.
Speaker 4:  It's literally just a huge iPad without a touchscreen, which is both.
Speaker 4:  Yeah, it's ridiculous and kind of great.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  And they're, they're showing it. There's like the, the big ideas, like you'll
Speaker 4:  you'll hang it up at your coffee shop to show the menu or whatever and that's
Speaker 4:  all fine and good. But I, I want this thing to just like wander around my
Speaker 4:  house with me and just, I just sit it next to me as I watch shows.
Speaker 4:  Like that's what I do with my phone all the time now. I'm like,
Speaker 3:  It's a pop to not having a tv. What you are describing is a person
Speaker 3:  without a television. And every now and again, you're gonna bring out your
Speaker 3:  little shoulder strap TV and you're gonna like watch a show and you're gonna
Speaker 3:  put it away. And once that hap like the culture
Speaker 3:  of the world changes once, the default is we don't have TVs.
Speaker 3:  And I, I promise you the Samsung Frame TV is the leading indicator of
Speaker 3:  eventually not having TVs. I mean, and the frame Pro is a con
Speaker 3:  and I just wanna be very careful about this. Like who, what professional
Speaker 3:  needs this tele, like what are we doing? But we are
Speaker 3:  fully into lightning round by the way. I just wanna be clear. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  So can can I just burn you through some more news? Yeah. Before we bring
Speaker 4:  out our, our friends to talk about more interesting stuff than your weird
Speaker 4:  ideas about television. Can we talk about Dell just for like a, just for
Speaker 4:  like a minute. I just need to be very mad at Dell out loud on this podcast.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. So Dell,
Speaker 3:  That's a CS tradition
Speaker 4:  Dell, which had a million names of products for its
Speaker 4:  laptops that no one could ever make sense of. Now has fewer names for its
Speaker 4:  products that make somehow even less sense. So Dell has completely renamed
Speaker 4:  its whole,
Speaker 3:  They got rid of XPS.
Speaker 4:  Right? Which
Speaker 3:  Was this, which was a good brand.
Speaker 4:  It was like the best Windows computer. And they're like, ah, nevermind. So
Speaker 4:  now there is the, there is the Dell.
Speaker 3:  Just
Speaker 4:  Dell. Just Dell. So you, you just like, I'll have a Dell please. It's like
Speaker 4:  a thing you can do now there's also the Dell Pro and there's the Dell Max.
Speaker 4:  And if you're like David, that doesn't make sense. I have more for you. Within
Speaker 4:  each of those tiers there is a Premium a plus and a base tier.
Speaker 4:  So there is, there is now a Dell base. I'd like a Dell
Speaker 4:  base please. That's sure.
Speaker 3:  That's like a rental car
Speaker 4:  All the way up to a Dell Max Premium.
Speaker 3:  Which Dell Max Premium,
Speaker 4:  I assume it costs $16 million.
Speaker 3:  Are they, are they different products?
Speaker 4:  I honestly couldn't tell you. I don't think Dell knows. I really don't. I
Speaker 4:  think they just like had a bunch of laptops and they were like, we don't
Speaker 4:  know what any of these are anymore because we just have infinite skews of
Speaker 4:  things and just put a bunch of them in buckets and we're like,
Speaker 3:  There
Speaker 4:  You go. Shipped these to Best Buy.
Speaker 3:  And the middle one is plus
Speaker 4:  The middle one is plus,
Speaker 3:  So you can get a Dell Max plus
Speaker 4:  You can't. That's correct. Or a Dell Pro plus.
Speaker 4:  I hate this so much.
Speaker 3:  You're so mad.
Speaker 4:  I have always said that my future is to just start a consultancy where I
Speaker 4:  will walk into your boardroom say that name is the stupidest thing I've ever
Speaker 4:  heard leave. And you, you owe me $50,000. Like I'll be the one to say to
Speaker 4:  your CEO. That's the stupidest idea you've ever had.
Speaker 3:  That's why people hire consultants. This is what
Speaker 4:  I'm saying. I will do that for so cheap. Right. If it saves us
Speaker 4:  from stupid names like this. But anyway, so that sucks. The computers I'm
Speaker 4:  sure will be fine. Dell has made fine computers for a very long time. Can
Speaker 4:  we talk about the Sony ELA car for just a hot second? Do we think this
Speaker 4:  exists now we have a price. This thing has been at CES in various forms of
Speaker 4:  prototype for three years now.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, four years. They, they over, have you guys seen the Eila? It's
Speaker 3:  just a sedan like, I dunno, it looks like
Speaker 3:  a Lucid air, but Sony did it, you know, it's a
Speaker 3:  $89,000. I was with some people today like walking around the show floor
Speaker 3:  and I was like, this is Sony's car, it's a sedan that costs
Speaker 3:  $89,000. And they like just a group of people.
Speaker 3:  Gfa like I'm, I feel very bad for Sony Honda. They announced this
Speaker 3:  thing five years ago at the height of infinite demand
Speaker 3:  for Tesla. Like where Tesla was like, we can't make model wise fast enough.
Speaker 3:  And every car company was like, well what if we announced a car that
Speaker 3:  we're gonna ship five years from now to fill some of that model wide demand.
Speaker 3:  And our
Speaker 4:  Only idea about it is that it has PlayStation in it somehow.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. So I mean, so Sony's giant worry is that the cars will drive themselves
Speaker 3:  and then people you'll the, you'll have more free time. 'cause in you're
Speaker 3:  like living room on wheels, going to wherever you're going and your autonomous
Speaker 3:  car. And Sony should program the content and advertising
Speaker 3:  that you consume during that time. And I've heard this idea from
Speaker 3:  multiple entertainment companies, multiple car companies, that once we have
Speaker 3:  autonomous cars, you drive around living room on wheels, whoever wins that
Speaker 3:  fight to program, that screen is the next winner. And I'm just like, you
Speaker 3:  know, the people still have phones. You have to beat my iPhone
Speaker 3:  still. Like I get in an Uber all the time. The Uber drives around just
Speaker 3:  fine. I'm not like, I hope somebody like I turn off the screen in the back
Speaker 3:  of the taxi. I wanna look at my
Speaker 4:  Phone. I do play the trivia games back there every once in a while. Oh no,
Speaker 4:  they're so fun. You're
Speaker 3:  Being so ruthlessly tracked.
Speaker 4:  Oh, I'm, yeah, it's fine. They know how good I am at trivia. Like it's, it's
Speaker 3:  Not a run. But I, but so they have announced the price and then I think a
Speaker 3:  really funny thing is, you know, the IFA is the Sony Honda Mobility joint
Speaker 3:  venture where Honda's doing a car and then Sony's programming. The experience
Speaker 3:  isn't on the car. And you can like, you can in fact play PlayStation in the
Speaker 3:  back of the ifa. Great. But at the same time, at this very show,
Speaker 3:  Honda is showing off its own cooler cars and you're just like,
Speaker 3:  hey, it's an $89,000 sedan that you don't like. Like this thing is doomed.
Speaker 3:  I hope none of you have pre-ordered ela. If, If you, If you, you know,
Speaker 3:  have fun, you know, life is a series of experiences that you're allowed to
Speaker 3:  have. But the actual Honda cars look way cooler, like
Speaker 3:  much more futuristic. There's a, they they keep calling it a saloon, which
Speaker 3:  is just what British people say instead of station Wagon. And it's like just
Speaker 3:  a long,
Speaker 4:  I just learned that this week by the way. It's awesome. That's such a better
Speaker 4:  name than Station Wagon. Yeah. Like a saloon car is cool,
Speaker 3:  But it does imply that there'll be like swinging doors and the British have
Speaker 3:  once again lied to us,
Speaker 3:  but it's like just such a cool looking car. It makes a lot of sense. Like
Speaker 3:  you can see Honda's really thought about repackaging a car around a battery
Speaker 3:  instead of what most car makers are doing, which is like putting a battery
Speaker 3:  in existing design and playing it safe but no price, no
Speaker 3:  ship date. We're like ages away. We're still in vaporware carland. And then
Speaker 3:  the other thing that's really interesting is none of the other car makers
Speaker 3:  are here. And so for years, you know, Mercedes would be here and be like,
Speaker 3:  this car has OLEDs on the outside and then BM bmw, like our car has e ink
Speaker 3:  on the outside. And she'd be like, what about the inside of a car?
Speaker 3:  And then they would show you crazy ideas for, you know, interactive cockpits
Speaker 3:  and they would talk about EVs endlessly and autonomy endlessly. And none
Speaker 3:  of them are here this year.
Speaker 4:  We've seen such a trend like in the last 12 months of all of
Speaker 4:  these companies walking back from these wild ideas. Yeah. Because there was
Speaker 4:  a minute where it was like, this is, this is the future and it is coming
Speaker 4:  right now. And now everybody's like, this is potentially the future and it's
Speaker 4:  coming in a very long time because we can't figure out how to charge these
Speaker 4:  things.
Speaker 3:  Right. They were counting paradigms, they're counting on widespread electrification,
Speaker 3:  which they have largely achieved in China, but they can't talk about that
Speaker 3:  here. And they are counting on autonomy and
Speaker 3:  those things are just not happening at the rate that Yeah. Anyone wants em
Speaker 3:  to. Yeah. Waymo is here and they,
Speaker 4:  Alison Johnson's over here. Alison, come hang out with us. Let's talk about
Speaker 4:  CES. Yeah, welcome Alison. Everybody.
Speaker 4:  Alison has been talking about a phone toaster nonstop for several
Speaker 4:  days,
Speaker 4:  which I feel like you bring, bring your mic over. Okay. There's a bunch
Speaker 4:  of stuff we should talk about, but can we just talk about the phone toaster?
Speaker 4:  We're sorry. I feel like you've like really oversold. We're
Speaker 7:  Gonna get right the phone toaster. Okay. Phone toaster. So the story is
Speaker 7:  I got a press release in my inbox and I was so annoyed
Speaker 7:  immediately with phone toaster. I was like, I don't wanna
Speaker 7:  hear about this. And then we got here and I was like, well, I I
Speaker 7:  should go see the phone toaster.
Speaker 3:  Is it actually called the Phone Toaster?
Speaker 7:  No. Okay. That's, I told, I called it that once in my head and then it was
Speaker 7:  just phone toaster after that.
Speaker 7:  It's what it is, is the whole thing is called sw. It, it's
Speaker 7:  a, it's called
Speaker 3:  Sw It
Speaker 7:  Sw it like sw it.
Speaker 3:  They had phone toaster in their back pocket and they went with whip it.
Speaker 7:  I know. I, you know. All right. They went with Whip It.
Speaker 7:  It's a, it's like a charging system for your phone
Speaker 7:  where you have the phone case, there's a battery
Speaker 7:  pack in it and you use it like you would
Speaker 7:  a phone with a case and a battery and when it's time to charge you
Speaker 7:  stick it in the phone toaster and it goes and it swaps
Speaker 7:  out the battery and you take it out, you're good to go two seconds.
Speaker 7:  And I was like, I'm still kind of like not understanding this.
Speaker 7:  And they're like, well you just, you never charge your phone again. You just
Speaker 4:  Sweep it. The truth is you perfectly understand it.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. Don't you need, how much does it cost?
Speaker 7:  Okay. So that's the thing.
Speaker 3:  I don't, that's not a good, okay.
Speaker 7:  The phone toaster itself, the hub is for the
Speaker 7:  Hub. Hub. It's the hub. Okay. The phone cases are the link.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Phone toaster is $450. Sure.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah. And the phone case is $120.
Speaker 3:  It doesn't come with a case.
Speaker 7:  Do you have to buy because you have to buy the one for, can you
Speaker 4:  Get the case without getting the toaster? You could, but why would you,
Speaker 4:  why would you?
Speaker 7:  Okay. That's fair. You need the toaster
Speaker 3:  And you need multiple Does how many batteries are in each toaster?
Speaker 7:  There's five batteries in the toaster.
Speaker 4:  Do you ever say sentences and be like, how did we get here? I
Speaker 7:  I'm like, this is what I'm paid to do
Speaker 3:  And just correct me. So you would need like two, you need like one at home
Speaker 3:  and one in your office or something. That's right. So you're like a thousand
Speaker 3:  dollars deep into felt
Speaker 7:  Toaster. Yeah. You gotta invest a thousand dollars in your toasters and,
Speaker 7:  and then you never have to charge your phone again.
Speaker 3:  I feel like I can never charge my phone again for a thousand dollars in a
Speaker 3:  variety of different ways.
Speaker 7:  I know you could have chargers like in every corner of your house. I just
Speaker 7:  think like, there's something I appreciate where I
Speaker 3:  Feel like we have two phones.
Speaker 7:  You could have a lot of phones.
Speaker 4:  Just, I'm sorry. Are you, are you telling me you don't find the idea of being
Speaker 4:  able to just like walk into your like
Speaker 4:  living room when you get home and just go like, and your phone is magically
Speaker 4:  charged again? Yeah. That kicks ass. That's it. You know what it's, it makes
Speaker 4:  me think of like in in action movies when the guy can do like a
Speaker 4:  really cool like hot swap of of magazines of ammo
Speaker 4:  and it's like they like flip their guns around. That's us. That's what we
Speaker 4:  get now. Yeah. With the phone toaster
Speaker 7:  For $450.
Speaker 4:  This is a
Speaker 3:  For one homie. It's called the sw. It
Speaker 4:  Just again, hand by consult. I will tell you it should have been the phone
Speaker 4:  toaster.
Speaker 7:  It's a phone toaster. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  I'm saying
Speaker 3:  This says, remind me that when I got my first Sony, it had the little flip
Speaker 3:  down microphone. I did practice trying to make that a cool move
Speaker 3:  was not successful and remained single throughout high school. Carry on.
Speaker 4:  What else have you seen? That's cool. You've been, you've been running around.
Speaker 4:  I have seeing all kinds of stuff. So I feel like you've had less of a like
Speaker 4:  focused goal at CES and you're more just like, what weird things can I
Speaker 4:  encounter? Yeah. I, which is the correct way to do CES?
Speaker 7:  I have the best job and it's, I've never had this job at CES before.
Speaker 7:  This is my sixth CES. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  because
Speaker 4:  You spent a lot of your time not at CES with phones and there are just no
Speaker 4:  phones here. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 7:  No phones. Just not a
Speaker 4:  Phone show. I
Speaker 7:  Reviewed the one plus 13. It's awesome. And then I just left it
Speaker 7:  in my hotel room and I went into the show floor. No it, it rules
Speaker 7:  'cause like I've had the CS experience where you run from meeting to
Speaker 7:  meeting and you're like sweating and you're talking to people and you don't
Speaker 7:  get to see anything. So this year I got to see things
Speaker 7:  and I wandered through the west hall. I was like,
Speaker 7:  I'm just going to like see what's here and get out real quick. Like an hour
Speaker 7:  and a half later I was like taking pictures of myself with every like massive
Speaker 7:  tractor I could find. I was like, this is the coolest thing. There's like
Speaker 7:  massive, you know, electric vehicles and
Speaker 7:  I was like, oh I got, I gotta move on. Like I can't spend
Speaker 3:  My, can you do the demo? I think it's, caterpillar has a great demo where
Speaker 3:  you can sit in a cockpit and remote operate a digger that's like hundreds
Speaker 3:  of miles away. Oh no. What? And there's just a line I got and it's like they
Speaker 3:  have a drone. Is it over five? Looking at the digger. You do the digger
Speaker 7:  On a or
Speaker 3:  5G. Yes. It's all 5G. Finally the promise of 5G is been
Speaker 3:  realized and it's three guys standing in line to operate a digger 500 miles
Speaker 3:  away. I knew
Speaker 7:  It.
Speaker 3:  It all happened. We've run the race, we did
Speaker 4:  It
Speaker 3:  F China
Speaker 7:  Remote
Speaker 3:  Control digger. There's a long line of people who just like sat in this
Speaker 3:  thing and they like scooped up some dirt and they put the dirt away and it's
Speaker 3:  like they're watching it on a TV and it's like, oh man, this isn't actually
Speaker 3:  cool.
Speaker 7:  That's what I'm gonna do tomorrow.
Speaker 3:  You should go back tomorrow. Yeah. But it was very fun. One guy ran into
Speaker 3:  like, he couldn't do it and the guy's like, let me find you some looser soil.
Speaker 3:  And I was like, that is the harshest
Speaker 4:  Term
Speaker 7:  I've ever, alright, well now I'm nervous.
Speaker 4:  Let me find interesting looser soil as a motivational poster that I would
Speaker 4:  like to exist. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  People, no,
Speaker 3:  It's
Speaker 4:  Rough. When life gets hard fund looser soil, it like that leaves something
Speaker 4:  to me that's
Speaker 7:  Like, that's
Speaker 4:  Powerful.
Speaker 3:  Have you seen in Central Hall next to the Samsung
Speaker 3:  booth, there's a little booth for just an LED manufacturer.
Speaker 3:  Like they don't make the displays really? They make the LED componentry
Speaker 3:  and they're very proud of, apparently they've invented a million things first.
Speaker 3:  Like the first wire free LED circuitry that can do a thing like all
Speaker 3:  this stuff, the first heat resistant whatever. But their tagline,
Speaker 3:  I swear to you, this is the tagline of this company, birth is not fair,
Speaker 3:  but opportunity must be fair. And it's like in
Speaker 3:  huge letters. And then right below it, it's like the future of
Speaker 3:  ole signage. And I'm like,
Speaker 7:  Wow.
Speaker 3:  Like stick to your guns. Like I go for it. Like shout it from the
Speaker 3:  rooftops opportunity. Must be fair. It's like right next to
Speaker 3:  the Samsung booth. So all these people are walking by it and like taking
Speaker 3:  selfies with it. 'cause it's so weird. And I think it's working, like, I
Speaker 3:  think a lot of people are being radicalized into like an inherently progressive
Speaker 3:  agenda, but it's ole manufacturer,
Speaker 7:  They wanted to see the frame pro. That's what they,
Speaker 4:  Yeah. I feel like that's where your opportunity is to go over and be like,
Speaker 4:  actually Ed isn't really massively available yet. It's it's still too expensive
Speaker 4:  if you couldn just work on OLED becoming
Speaker 3:  Commercial. Not fair. Find looser soil,
Speaker 7:  Find
Speaker 3:  Looser. What else have you seen that's scrap?
Speaker 7:  So I, I got to wander around the central hall. I, So
Speaker 7:  I used to cover cameras fulltime, I stopped by Nikon
Speaker 7:  and you might be bummed to hear that there are like zero cameras.
Speaker 7:  Oh man. At the Nikon booth. I was scandalized. There's like
Speaker 7:  airplanes and then someone like doing a fake weather forecast for some reason.
Speaker 7:  But I I found Nikon. Yeah. I was like, sure,
Speaker 7:  but there's a camera they're gonna take to the moon and it has a little jacket
Speaker 7:  on. I thought that was so sweet. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  You got really excited about the jacket. I
Speaker 7:  Did. Yeah. I came back like three times and I was like, I wanna make sure
Speaker 7:  I get all the facts right about the, the moon camera. Now I got
Speaker 7:  to just like see the show from the perspective of
Speaker 7:  someone who's just like, wants to go see cool shit. The
Speaker 7:  LG booth is awesome. They do the, there's a whole thing with the
Speaker 7:  translucent TV panels where like, you know, you
Speaker 7:  stand around, you watch it and it's like jellyfish and then it morphs into
Speaker 7:  other stuff and then they, all the panels kind of come out and
Speaker 7:  it's stained glass and it looks like Jesus is about
Speaker 7:  to like emerge from the TVs. Right. I was like, this
Speaker 7:  is a spiritual experience right here for some people.
Speaker 7:  But yeah, like I just, I got to check out Eureka Park. I got to,
Speaker 7:  I went to the Spear.
Speaker 3:  Oh, for the Delta
Speaker 7:  Two? Yeah. Yeah. I went for that. I was never been there before.
Speaker 7:  I wasn't prepared for the Smellovision like portion of
Speaker 7:  it. They did a thing with Uber Eats where it was like
Speaker 7:  a bit, there was a guy on like a moped like delivering
Speaker 7:  Uber Eats and then they like pump in this smell of
Speaker 7:  like hazelnut and everybody's kinda like, do you smell that?
Speaker 7:  It's kind of sweet. And then they were like, oh, a hazelnut
Speaker 7:  coffee. Just how I like, I was like,
Speaker 4:  That's a lot.
Speaker 7:  It, it was
Speaker 3:  A lot. One thing that I've been dying to ask you about is the TCL l Next
Speaker 3:  paper phone. Yeah. I dunno if you've seen it. As you
Speaker 3:  know, David is the number one retail agent for the books Palmer here in America.
Speaker 3:  Which by the way, it currently is in some sort of weird Chinese AI
Speaker 3:  data privacy scandal. So well done. David, thank
Speaker 4:  You
Speaker 3:  For way to do an op on the people of America with your weird ePaper phone.
Speaker 4:  I believe I advocated for mostly using that thing in airplane mode. So I'm
Speaker 4:  good. I feel fine about this.
Speaker 3:  So we, we, we've just seen a lot of interest in these like
Speaker 3:  minimal phones and it is a secondary device, right? Like, I don't, it
Speaker 3:  doesn't make any sense to me to have a e ink phone as your primary device.
Speaker 3:  And so TCL this is like their second or third next paper phone
Speaker 3:  and they're, they, they have Matt displays and then you can switch 'em to
Speaker 3:  black and white mode. But this year they look almost like E Inc.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah. They've been doing this next paper thing and it like was in
Speaker 7:  the tablets first and then they brought it to the phones. And the
Speaker 7:  the thing that I'm most excited about, and I think you are too,
Speaker 7:  is the next paper key, which is just a little slider button on
Speaker 7:  the side of the phone that puts it into Max Ink
Speaker 7:  mode. And that just, that's
Speaker 3:  Where it looks the most like
Speaker 7:  Ink mode. Yeah. Yeah. That's the like ein mode and it's like Mono
Speaker 7:  David
Speaker 4:  Consultancy approves of that. Yeah. On
Speaker 7:  Max you just like, pretend your phone is an ein phone for a minute and it's
Speaker 7:  like, does it
Speaker 4:  Work? Like I feel like we, we've seen a lot of companies do this thing where
Speaker 4:  they're like, it's an LCD but it's a, it's a better one to look at. What
Speaker 3:  Netflix, what was the little startup just now?
Speaker 4:  The daylight.
Speaker 3:  The daylight. And they were all in. They were like, this will save you.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And it it, it was one of those, like, it had some interesting ideas,
Speaker 4:  but it is a little bit like the, a sort of jack of all trades and master
Speaker 4:  of None thing where it's like, it, it almost accomplishes all of its goals
Speaker 4:  but it actually accomplishes none of them. And I feel like this has been
Speaker 4:  true with a lot of these things, which is why I end up going back to E Inc.
Speaker 4:  Because it's like Sure. It's slow refresh rate and it's, it doesn't work
Speaker 4:  super well in certain conditions, but like it does the thing it's supposed
Speaker 4:  to do. Which is not blare light in your eyes all the time. This does next
Speaker 4:  paper. Like can it do the middle thing
Speaker 7:  Kind of. Okay. I mean there's like, they have a matte kind of
Speaker 7:  finish on the screen and they, they say all this stuff about,
Speaker 7:  it's like, you know, rated to be really easy on your eyes and the
Speaker 7:  blue light and the, all that. But like, really it's just,
Speaker 3:  But really the thing that happens is you flip the switch on the side of the
Speaker 3:  screen and like smoke comes out from the middle of the screen. Like
Speaker 3:  there's an animation that's like ein is eating your display from the inside
Speaker 3:  out. It's very sci-fi and then it like takes over,
Speaker 3:  it shuts down the screen and comes back as an e ink screen also for some
Speaker 3:  extremely convoluted reason it quits all of your apps. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  So it's not great in that
Speaker 4:  Sense. I I literally believed you when you said smoke comes out. Like I was
Speaker 4:  honestly like That makes sense. Yeah. TCO made a phone, you hit
Speaker 3:  Explodes and you're left with a Kindle. Yeah. Pre prestige. When when you
Speaker 3:  flip it back like a, like a purpley smoke emerges from the middle
Speaker 3:  of the screen.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It's like a ripple. It's,
Speaker 3:  And there's a middle one, which is like a desaturated color e ink. And it's
Speaker 3:  just like the thing, like I watched people cruise by all kinds of dumb AI
Speaker 3:  ideas all day today and everyone stopped at the next paper booth.
Speaker 3:  'cause the idea that you have a phone where you're reading it looks more
Speaker 3:  like paper is inherently very compelling. And to me it's like,
Speaker 3:  oh, maybe that's like the most interesting phone we're gonna see for a while.
Speaker 3:  'cause it's, it's not like AI is gonna do any
Speaker 7:  I know. Yeah.
Speaker 4:  All right Allison, before we ruthlessly kick you off the stage. Okay. We
Speaker 4:  have to talk about the thing that you and I both got. Yeah. I would say unnecessarily
Speaker 4:  excited about at CES unveiled. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  I scooped you.
Speaker 4:  You did. It was honestly, we have a slack room where we were talking about
Speaker 4:  the stuff we were gonna write about and I was like, I'm doing this now. Alison
Speaker 4:  was like, I did it already. It is the meanest thing that's ever happened
Speaker 4:  to me. It's a a top fear water bottle. What's the whole thing? Explain
Speaker 4:  this to the people. It is, who should all buy this thing immediately?
Speaker 7:  Soda Stream. But for Hydro flask, like, that's it. It's
Speaker 7:  a little top. You screw onto the top of your water bottle.
Speaker 7:  You put the CO2 canister in and there there's like a little plastic lid
Speaker 7:  you put on top and it does the put carbonation thing. And then
Speaker 7:  you have sparkling water and you can be free and walk with it.
Speaker 7:  I,
Speaker 4:  It's honestly, it's all I've ever wanted. I don't know why I got so excited
Speaker 4:  about this. But the idea of like, and they make a like specific water bottle.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And they're like, you can have your still water bottle and your sparkling
Speaker 4:  water bottle. Yeah. Which is like drop the little capsule in and it's, oh,
Speaker 7:  I want,
Speaker 3:  How many uses do you get outta each capsule? This
Speaker 7:  Is who can,
Speaker 4:  Don't don't ask questions. Don't worry about it. You can
Speaker 7:  Feel it's good.
Speaker 3:  $5,000
Speaker 4:  Water bottle. You never charge your
Speaker 3:  Phone a subscription. It's tracking
Speaker 7:  You. Yes. And you have sparkling water for the rest of
Speaker 3:  Your life. It's important. You know, sparkling water is freely available.
Speaker 3:  Okay. Point that out.
Speaker 4:  And we don't all have that LaCroix money. Be like, yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah.
Speaker 4:  All right Allison, thank you. You're gonna come back when we do some q and
Speaker 4:  a stuff, but for now go away. Okay. Yeah. We have to move on.
Speaker 4:  Thank you. Yeah. Allison,
Speaker 4:  Jen Tuy, come hang out with us. Let's talk smart home things.
Speaker 4:  Jen Tuy. Everybody should know this. All of our team is wonderful, but no
Speaker 4:  one at CES is a celebrity. Quite like Gen Tuy is a
Speaker 4:  celebrity. Yeah. Anyone who makes a smart home, anything which
Speaker 4:  is everyone at CES is like largely obsessed with Gen
Speaker 4:  Tuy. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Welcome.
Speaker 4:  We're very
Speaker 8:  Excited you're here. I, I was with Owen our a geographer today and I
Speaker 8:  had quite a few people. In fact, I see some in the audience who are Yeah.
Speaker 8:  Come up to me and was like, said how wonderful they love The Verge, but that
Speaker 8:  I'm their favorite. So yeah. A few also said they
Speaker 8:  were gonna subscribe.
Speaker 3:  Hey, there you go. That's what we have a subscription fee, but
Speaker 3:  you get sparkling water.
Speaker 4:  Can we talk about robot vacuums? All I want to talk about in the whole world
Speaker 4:  is robot vacuums. I I have become
Speaker 4:  completely sold on all weird robot vacuums
Speaker 4:  ideas this week. That's
Speaker 8:  Good. 'cause there are a lot of them.
Speaker 4:  There's so many of them. I just wanna, I I want you to explain
Speaker 4:  the ones that you've seen and liked the best. But the one that I got to see
Speaker 4:  that is my favorite was there's a robo rock one
Speaker 4:  that is just, it's, it's just a roomba looking thing, but it has
Speaker 4:  a robotic arm that comes out. I mean, so slowly,
Speaker 4:  so slowly it just, it slowly comes out and it kind of goes like
Speaker 4:  this. And then if it like sees a sock next to it, it just sort of gently
Speaker 4:  reaches over and picks up the sock and then just moves with it somewhere
Speaker 4:  and then just puts the sock down in a different place. Correct. And there
Speaker 4:  was a person at the Robo Rocks booth whose job was to
Speaker 4:  reach over and put the sock back in the vacuum's way.
Speaker 8:  And
Speaker 4:  It was the be i, I stood there for like much too long watching this person
Speaker 4:  just slowly fight with the vacuum about where the sock should go. And I enjoyed
Speaker 8:  It very much. Did you see them doing their dance?
Speaker 4:  No. There's a dance they had, they
Speaker 8:  Had a whole row of them stacked right the front of the booth and
Speaker 8:  they had them dancing and sink the arms. Incredible. I know. It was, it was
Speaker 8:  pretty good.
Speaker 3:  Can I just say, I'm, and everyone wants to talk about humanoid robots. I'm
Speaker 3:  afraid of the vacuums that have limbs.
Speaker 8:  They're,
Speaker 3:  But before we got on stage, Jen was like, one of them has legs. That's just
Speaker 3:  a thing. She casually said, I I'm gonna find out more
Speaker 8:  Soon. Legs and arm. That was, that was the, you know, we, it, they
Speaker 8:  elevated throughout the week. So it started and we actually got to see the
Speaker 8:  robo rock a sneak peak last month. So we were, we were
Speaker 8:  all prepped for the arms. And in fact when we were all prepped for the arm,
Speaker 8:  the uprising, the robot uprising was coming. And then
Speaker 8:  the other Rob, so there are lots of competitors in the robo rock, robo
Speaker 8:  vac space and Robo Rock came out with the arm and then
Speaker 8:  dreamy came out with the legs. And then that was
Speaker 8:  their debut. And these are, these are robots that are coming, you're gonna
Speaker 8:  be able to buy. And they're like, the next couple of months, these aren't
Speaker 8:  concept vacuums. And then I went to the dreamy booth and they're like, oh,
Speaker 8:  but now we have one that has legs and an arm.
Speaker 8:  So this is, and that they said, actually that'll be out by the end of the
Speaker 8:  year.
Speaker 3:  How fast can it run?
Speaker 8:  So this is, it's, the legs are a little, I mean it's,
Speaker 8:  they just basically raise the robot up far enough so that it can
Speaker 8:  kind of get over and transition. Like if you've ever had a robot vacuum that
Speaker 8:  can't get into your bathroom, 'cause you've got like a high ledge and then
Speaker 8:  it kind of, the legs kind of collapse from under it and it goes forward.
Speaker 8:  So it's not like it's gonna climb up your staircase to the second floor.
Speaker 8:  You
Speaker 4:  Can almost like hear it go every time. It's
Speaker 8:  Just
Speaker 4:  Like lunging over.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. Well and when I was watching the one with the legs and the arm,
Speaker 8:  he said, well, we kind of modeled it after a horse.
Speaker 8:  And you can see the legs go up and then the arm goes up and it's like,
Speaker 3:  And this is, I wanna be clear, this is a vacuum cleaner.
Speaker 8:  So the idea is if anyone's ever used a robot vacuum, they often get stuck.
Speaker 8:  Or if you've left your socks out, they'll suck up your socks. And then there's
Speaker 8:  AI powered obstacle avoidance, which is supposed to help them get around
Speaker 8:  the sock. But then, then they haven't cleaned the floor where the sock was.
Speaker 8:  So this idea is it's gonna pick up your sock. You can tell it where to put
Speaker 8:  it. And so it'll go put it in a basket or it,
Speaker 8:  the dreamy one can pick up shoes so it can go put shoes.
Speaker 3:  It's strong enough to pick up a shoe.
Speaker 4:  500 pounds. Yeah, we we're done for it. It's over now.
Speaker 3:  It can hop like a horse and pick up shoes.
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  I
Speaker 8:  Don't like this. And this one actually the dream, the new dreamy one can,
Speaker 8:  can use tools. So
Speaker 4:  Yeah, I actually don't like that. I changed my mind.
Speaker 3:  I'm out. So they've all seen the movies, right?
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 8:  But the ultimate idea is they'll clean everywhere. 'cause right now they
Speaker 8:  are kind of spotty. Yeah. But it'll, and it, it can, it has this
Speaker 8:  little arm kind of goes into a toolbox and takes a tool out. But yes, I could
Speaker 8:  de I mean right now it's a soft brush. But you know, when it's like little
Speaker 8:  chains,
Speaker 4:  There's a full like battle bot situation you're describing. Well,
Speaker 8:  I kept saying, you know, could we put you're across the way from each other?
Speaker 8:  Can we just get the two robots together? Yeah. And go for it. But
Speaker 8:  no, they weren't having any of them. Like,
Speaker 3:  Are are, is there a list of acceptable tools?
Speaker 8:  It's just little brushes. It's
Speaker 3:  Like they're mostly brushes. Brushes because like you give this robot a hammer,
Speaker 3:  like all kinds of weird shit just checking. All right.
Speaker 8:  But they're everywhere. Robots with arms, legs, all sorts of things.
Speaker 3:  It does seem like in terms of just like household
Speaker 3:  robots, it's the vacuums that people are like, these are the ones people
Speaker 3:  actually buy and then everything else is kind of, and so there's just a tremendous
Speaker 3:  amount of weird vacuum ideas.
Speaker 8:  It's where the innovation is definitely in the robot space because, and
Speaker 8:  I've talked about this before, you know the whole kind of dream is the rosy
Speaker 8:  the robot, the human eye. But that's, you know what if and when that ever
Speaker 8:  comes is gonna be, no one's be able to afford it
Speaker 8:  and it's gonna be kind of scary. So for me the idea of like
Speaker 8:  modular single purpose robots or
Speaker 8:  robots that can do one or two tasks rather than
Speaker 8:  like a big powerful humanoid robot roaming around
Speaker 8:  your house makes a lot more sense. And in fact, switch bot who's kind of
Speaker 8:  known for quite innovative, slightly janky products,
Speaker 8:  came out with a modular robot platform. So the little,
Speaker 8:  it has a little robot with something that's called an fusion platform that
Speaker 8:  goes on top. And then you can put different accessories and it will drive
Speaker 8:  around your house and like bring you things. It has,
Speaker 8:  you can put a fan on it so you can have it like come and keep you cool.
Speaker 8:  Purify the air. So this is like, you know it's,
Speaker 4:  Wait, you forgot the one where it'll do a Teles robot. Oh it's just a big,
Speaker 4:  big ass selfie stick that you can stick big selfie stick, stick your phone
Speaker 4:  and then it'll just wander around your house. Yes.
Speaker 8:  That one sold. That would be
Speaker 3:  All the way back to an iPad on
Speaker 8:  A's what it is.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. It also cleans your floors at the
Speaker 8:  Same time.
Speaker 3:  Like 10 years ago I walked around CS and people were like, the future of
Speaker 3:  work is an iPad. On a segue, we actually, we have a
Speaker 3:  great video from ageism. James Vincent just came to our
Speaker 3:  office from his home in London as an iPod on
Speaker 3:  a stick or an iPad on a stick. And his conclusion was like, no one respects
Speaker 3:  me.
Speaker 3:  You can see it's like it's hard. All right. I'm saying good luck to everyone.
Speaker 8:  I know the robots
Speaker 4:  Have the idea of them though. Like the idea that you have this little tiny
Speaker 4:  thing that a does a thing, it cleans your floors, but it also
Speaker 4:  increasingly like understands and has mapped your house, knows how to move
Speaker 4:  around. The idea that there's more stuff you can do with
Speaker 3:  That back. Can you tools and throw shoes?
Speaker 4:  Yeah, that I'm less excited about
Speaker 3:  The can.
Speaker 4:  You can open a box and use tools could go sideways but
Speaker 4:  air purifiers and selfie sticks, I mean yeah this
Speaker 3:  Works. It's gonna roll up in like a puff of smoke is gonna come out and you're
Speaker 3:  gonna fall to the ground. Yeah,
Speaker 4:  Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Wake up without a kidney. What is going on? Use tools.
Speaker 3:  Yeah, think about it. I'm just saying
Speaker 4:  I'm fine with this. It doesn't look like a person so it's less creepy.
Speaker 8:  Well actually the switch bot is, they are working on an the switch bot just
Speaker 8:  on a little face.
Speaker 3:  Alright, speaking of horror, so let's talk about matter. There's a
Speaker 3:  lot of matter stuff here. There is an entire door
Speaker 3:  lock camera, biometric handle.
Speaker 8:  It's the year of the door lock I called it. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  Your most, the product you listed here is most likely to buy is the
Speaker 3:  new schlag lock that has ultra wideband. Yes.
Speaker 3:  And I believe I was reading Jen's right up and it's like it calculates your
Speaker 3:  velocity as you approach the door, which is just not a thing that you
Speaker 3:  think a door lock needs to do.
Speaker 8:  Well so the idea is actually got a demo of it this evening. It they're not
Speaker 8:  shown on the show floor. They did, that was all they released. But they did
Speaker 8:  give me a little sneak peek just before I came here. And the idea of the
Speaker 8:  velocity is If you are, so UWB is like what we, what's in
Speaker 8:  use in cars now for automatic unlocking. So it,
Speaker 8:  it's precise positioning so it knows how you're approaching. So this way
Speaker 8:  If you are walking sideways across your front lawn, your
Speaker 8:  door's not gonna unlock right? It knows that your, your trajectory towards
Speaker 8:  the lock. So as you're walking towards the lock, If you are running it
Speaker 8:  will unlock faster. Like say you wanna get in your house quick,
Speaker 4:  Does it like whip open the door If you really want to surprise somebody,
Speaker 3:  It's like the vacuum is coming, unlock the door.
Speaker 8:  But it's a great, I think the UWB technology is really what's gonna push
Speaker 8:  smart locks into the mainstream because to date
Speaker 8:  access control has been kind of fiddly. The fingerprint I
Speaker 8:  is my favorite option. But for a lot of people it's not a great option.
Speaker 8:  Fingerprints can be, you know, don't always get recognized. It's
Speaker 8:  fiddly to set up and then the keypad obviously that's, that's
Speaker 8:  almost takes as long time as getting your key out if you're putting there.
Speaker 8:  And then they've had this idea of automatic unlocking for a while but it's
Speaker 8:  never been very good 'cause it uses wifi and
Speaker 8:  geofencing and a few different radios. So like there's so many failure points.
Speaker 8:  Whereas this is just point to point radio to radio as you
Speaker 8:  approach the door will unlock and it unlocks before you get there. So you're
Speaker 8:  not standing there like a lemon for like 30 seconds waiting for your daughter
Speaker 8:  to unlock. Which has happened to me regularly. So quick
Speaker 3:  Question, how do lemons stand?
Speaker 8:  It's an English term
Speaker 8:  backing up in,
Speaker 3:  I'm like I'm super fascinated this 'cause there's also a new, there's standards
Speaker 3:  on top of standards, right? Yes. There's,
Speaker 8:  So this is allero,
Speaker 3:  It's called Aero.
Speaker 8:  So this isn't, so ALLERO is coming this year
Speaker 3:  The classic Swar home story.
Speaker 8:  Yes. And it's been known like, so aero's like
Speaker 8:  Matter LiRo is been, is like an industry collaboration between
Speaker 8:  Apple, Google, Samsung and then all the lock makers and it's an access
Speaker 8:  control standard to basically make it so that any
Speaker 8:  smartphone can unlock any door lock obviously authorized not
Speaker 8:  just, so rather than having to have a specific platform to use
Speaker 8:  your smart lock or a specific smartphone, any UWDB
Speaker 8:  device or NFC. So it's bringing Apple Home key, the
Speaker 8:  idea of home key to all phones. So right now if you've ever used Apple
Speaker 8:  Home Key, it's very convenient. Put tap your watch to your lock,
Speaker 8:  tap your phone to your lock unlocks it. But you can't use that If you have
Speaker 8:  an Android phone. But now that's with ly we're gonna get
Speaker 8:  NFC unlocking for all phones and UWB unlocking for all
Speaker 8:  compatible phones, obviously you have to have UWB and NFC in your phone.
Speaker 8:  But that's, that's been coming for a while. There's a lot of
Speaker 8:  phones and watches that now have that. So I think, I mean it's gonna take
Speaker 8:  a while. The Allero standard is gonna be announced like what it is
Speaker 8:  the spec this year. But I think the lock manufacturers are already
Speaker 8:  starting to make the locks to work with it. And Apple
Speaker 8:  announced at ww DC last year. Yes last year
Speaker 8:  that that they are supporting the UWB hands free unlocking. So
Speaker 8:  it, there's a lot of momentum there and it is, it's a really seamless
Speaker 8:  experience compared to most of the other ways that you use Smart Lock. So
Speaker 8:  I think we're gonna see a real uptick in Do you have a smart lock? Yeah,
Speaker 3:  I've got the encode plus. Okay. Which is home key. Yeah. And then I have
Speaker 3:  the cheap Aqura one, which is also home key and that one you
Speaker 3:  get what you pay for. It's just like sort of straightforwardly get
Speaker 3:  what you pay for. Yeah. But it's great 'cause we just tap the phone on the
Speaker 3:  door and it unlocks And the problem is sometimes I have an Android
Speaker 3:  phone and then I can't do that. Right. And like it seems like all this is
Speaker 3:  just one turn too late. I know you're calling it the year of the smart lock,
Speaker 3:  but it, and there's a rumor that Apple will make a lock this year, which
Speaker 3:  is very funny. Like of all the products
Speaker 8:  That we make with the video built in and that's the other thing we saw video
Speaker 8:  doorbells built into smart locks everywhere and Palm unlocking. I'm not so
Speaker 8:  sure about the palm unlocking. You
Speaker 3:  Just like wave your palm at it.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, I did it a few times. I think Phillips, not Phillips Hu what
Speaker 3:  Does it like your palm?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, they say it's a lot more secure than a fingerprint.
Speaker 8:  Apparently your Palm has more sure things going on.
Speaker 3:  I don't know
Speaker 4:  What we're beating is like a, like a key and a lock. Like I think a fingerprint's
Speaker 4:  probably fine. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  We're we're we're still moving in the right
Speaker 8:  Direction. But then it's the hands free element. You know, you just, no
Speaker 3:  This is not hands free, but
Speaker 8:  It is because you actually touching this hands that's just not touching.
Speaker 8:  You're,
Speaker 3:  This is the most hands actually there's no, there's no hand contact.
Speaker 3:  Hand hand. Very much hand. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  It's, it's in I'd say it's in between. Sure.
Speaker 3:  This is why I want it to just whip open the door when I walk up.
Speaker 8:  See that it doesn't do yet. Can
Speaker 3:  You set the velocity? Can you be like, this is how fast I can run.
Speaker 8:  No, it it, so that's what I, I hadn't Schlag Schlag was the first
Speaker 8:  company I'd heard talk about velocity. So it, but I think that's neat because
Speaker 8:  If you are in a hurry rather than it, you suddenly
Speaker 8:  have to stop. Yeah. It's gonna, it it can anticipate it's reacting
Speaker 8:  to you and that's really where the smart home's going. I think it's like
Speaker 8:  it anticipates your needs rather than you needing to tell it what you
Speaker 8:  want to do or program it or put buttons in, you know, push buttons,
Speaker 8:  put your fingerprint and the smart your home is starting to react to you.
Speaker 8:  And that's kind of where we're moving I think.
Speaker 3:  So what's really interesting is, so you know Apple, this is kinda the second
Speaker 3:  time they've pulled this move, right? They did Home Kit and then they
Speaker 3:  gave a lot of home kit away to become Matter. Then they did Home Keys and
Speaker 3:  they gave a lot of home key away to be Aly and we'll see if that comes to
Speaker 3:  anything right? But like you can see like they're moving more things into
Speaker 3:  the industry ecosystem because they, they just need the ecosystem
Speaker 3:  to exist, right? And very, very few companies wanna make stuff for just one
Speaker 3:  platform, especially at the scale most of these companies operate at. But
Speaker 3:  then the rumors are like Apple will just make a lock with a face
Speaker 3:  like face ID built into it. And that makes no sense to me. And then the
Speaker 3:  rumor is this year Apple will do like a smart home
Speaker 3:  iPad situation that
Speaker 8:  Will get,
Speaker 3:  But then I'm just like looking at the other news here, which is Aqura has
Speaker 3:  announced Ooh like a wall mountable smart home controller. Yes. And
Speaker 3:  you're like oh they're just gonna kill their, this ecosystem of products
Speaker 3:  they need to make this work that they keep giving the standards away to.
Speaker 3:  They're just going to eat them. Like the equator thing is
Speaker 3:  wild. So has anybody ever pause is here, I know he has
Speaker 3:  the CEO of home assistance here. I know this person has done it,
Speaker 3:  but has anybody ever been like, I'm gonna put an iPad on my wall to control
Speaker 3:  my smart home stuff? It's this yes, it's our audience. I know
Speaker 3:  more of you than subscribe to the art store on the frame TV is, that's what
Speaker 3:  I wanna say. And it's like hard. It's just like a fundamentally complicated
Speaker 3:  idea. 'cause you gotta get power to the iPad, you gotta keep the iPad in
Speaker 3:  kiosk mode or you gotta run an Android tablet. You end up with a bunch of
Speaker 3:  weird matter I can you tell how much therapy I do with Jen on like a
Speaker 3:  day-to-day basis about pharma stuff. And so
Speaker 3:  Aqura has these new ones, I I think you've actually seen them where they
Speaker 3:  just replaced your light switches in the way that,
Speaker 3:  has anybody ever seen the new like aftermarket screens you can put in
Speaker 3:  cars where you just like take out the old radio and they're just like, fuck
Speaker 3:  it tablet. Which like covers up all the vents and now it's
Speaker 3:  like, what if we do that in your house? It's like we're gonna take out your
Speaker 3:  light switches and we're just gonna mount a seven inch display where your
Speaker 3:  light switch was and guess where the power comes from? The power to your
Speaker 3:  light switch and then this will be the panel. Yeah. And this feels like the
Speaker 3:  new thing to me.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, this is this smart home control interfaces, which is something I go
Speaker 8:  on about a lot on the site. It's like because you voice
Speaker 8:  and phone control are just not compatible in a household
Speaker 8:  where there's more than one person. Like you need ways to control your smart
Speaker 8:  home. And Brilliant was the first sort of air company in this
Speaker 8:  space that did replacing the light switch with a touchscreen panel. But
Speaker 8:  what's happened now is that with matter, you've now got, you're
Speaker 8:  not locking yourself into an ecosystem. And the problem had been, even though
Speaker 8:  brilliant tried with integrations is that there just weren't enough things.
Speaker 8:  If you're gonna wire something to your house, it needs to control everything.
Speaker 8:  And a carer right now it is not quite there but
Speaker 8:  with matter they're saying they're gonna be able to, you'll basically eventually
Speaker 8:  be able to control any matter compatible device straight
Speaker 8:  from the touch screen. It's wired to lights so you're solving the problem
Speaker 8:  of your lights. You can, you know, dim change
Speaker 8:  colors, set scenes using the touch panel for the
Speaker 8:  light that it's wired to. And then any other lights in your home
Speaker 8:  or maybe your door door lock. It's also a video intercom. So If you
Speaker 8:  have video doorbell, it'll pull up when someone rings you can talk
Speaker 8:  to them. It has a little microphone. It's big and chunky though.
Speaker 8:  And then there's a spousal approval factor when it comes to light switches.
Speaker 8:  So my actual favorite, one of the AKA they showed off three
Speaker 8:  touchscreen panels and one has a little dial, it
Speaker 8:  has a tiny little screen in it that you can swipe the screen to choose
Speaker 8:  what you want to select. So say I want to turn on the living room lights
Speaker 8:  or dim them and then it has this lovely tactile dial that you can just turn
Speaker 8:  And that's
Speaker 4:  U us is like cool and tactile as light switches. They're like, they good.
Speaker 4:  This
Speaker 3:  Looks like, like a thermostat
Speaker 4:  Spousal approval through the roof on
Speaker 8:  Light switches. Philistine. Yeah, but
Speaker 8:  you can't, the light switch turns your light on and off or maybe dims it.
Speaker 8:  This I can swipe and touch one button
Speaker 8:  and like all the lights in my house or in my living room will set to a
Speaker 8:  mood. You know, the mood, the movie time dim to a
Speaker 8:  certain light, maybe throw in a little funky
Speaker 8:  color just for some, you know, fun. No you, I'm not selling. How many
Speaker 4:  People in your household know successfully how to operate this thing? Well
Speaker 8:  That's the thing. These,
Speaker 4:  V's. Job this week was to wear all of the smart glasses
Speaker 4:  and also all of the wearables, which I think means like touching gross things
Speaker 4:  more than most people who go to CES. You've had a lot of like
Speaker 4:  close encounters with gadgets that we don't recommend at this show.
Speaker 9:  Thanks for reminding me David. I actually hadn't
Speaker 9:  thought about that.
Speaker 3:  So your job is putting stuff that's been on other people's face and your
Speaker 3:  face. Yeah. How are you feeling?
Speaker 4:  I, you know, which violates every rule of C.
Speaker 4:  Can we talk about smart glasses for me? Yeah, let's talk about smart glasses.
Speaker 4:  If there is like a device category that everybody was excited
Speaker 4:  about this week, I feel like it's smart glasses.
Speaker 3:  Can I just read you the names of these companies that be typed into the list
Speaker 9:  And these are the ones that I was like, okay, in my inbox there's like at
Speaker 9:  least 500,000 smart glass pitches. These are the ones that I selected
Speaker 9:  as worthy of talking about.
Speaker 3:  Okay, rocket that's spelled R-O-K-I-D
Speaker 3:  nuance X reel. Everyone knows Nuance Music,
Speaker 3:  Camilio,
Speaker 9:  Camelo,
Speaker 3:  Camelo, even Realities and then Halladay. Yeah
Speaker 3:  this, these are just, people are just coming. I'm pretty sure holidays are
Speaker 3:  referenced to Ready Player one, right? Because holiday and Ready player one
Speaker 3:  seems
Speaker 4:  Right,
Speaker 3:  But it's just like we're, we're entering a new zone of companies
Speaker 3:  like, we're like reality Hacker Labs. Like it's like that's what
Speaker 4:  We're gonna do. Well it just makes me think like this stuff must have gotten
Speaker 4:  a lot easier to make in the relatively recent
Speaker 9:  Mess. Phenomenally easier to make. This is a thing that, so I've been a
Speaker 9:  smart glasses skeptic for a really long, long time because
Speaker 9:  there were just, I mean we all know what happened with Google Glass, right?
Speaker 9:  Glass holes like eh, that's not really a thing.
Speaker 9:  But I think in the last two to three years the technology has
Speaker 9:  miniaturized and basically expanded to a point where it's like, oh
Speaker 9:  crap, this could actually happen. And
Speaker 9:  that's kind of what we're seeing on the floor. So I think we've gotten to
Speaker 9:  a point where everyone has agreed, oh smart glasses, they're a
Speaker 9:  thing. This is happening. Wait,
Speaker 3:  Can we just put a little definition around smart glasses? 'cause
Speaker 3:  it's pretty wide open right now. So the Meta ray
Speaker 3:  bands, I think Meta will call smart glasses. Yes. But they have no
Speaker 3:  display component. Yes. Right. That's a camera and
Speaker 9:  There's like categories
Speaker 3:  Voice assistant and I think Meta is dramatically
Speaker 3:  overselling. Does anybody here have them? Alright.
Speaker 9:  No you can. You see, you see, you see Yeah. Yeah. A lot of people hop them
Speaker 3:  Substantially more people than pay for the art store. I just wanna be clear
Speaker 3:  about that too. You're, is there you, do you have them because
Speaker 3:  they're a camera or because you're talking to Meta AI all the time. How many
Speaker 3:  of you're talking to Meta AI all the time on your redbands? No, I
Speaker 3:  we would point out either everyone's embarrassed or no hands have gone up.
Speaker 3:  How many of you're too embarrassed to admit that you're talking to weird
Speaker 3:  Meta ai right. Bands all the time. How many of you're using the camera all
Speaker 3:  the time? 'cause it's really convenient to Yeah, that's a lot of hands. Yeah.
Speaker 3:  Yeah. And So I think Meta is dramatically overselling the smart glass,
Speaker 3:  the smartness of its smart glasses. 'cause it's not a display. Yeah
Speaker 3:  it's just a camera on some glasses that look okay, sure. But all the
Speaker 3:  ones that we're talking about Cs are displays. Yes. Right. That's the new
Speaker 3:  category.
Speaker 4:  Well that everybody including Meta agrees that's the next thing.
Speaker 3:  So yeah. But like Meta is like this is a surprise hit like smart glasses
Speaker 3:  are the future. I'm like weird little cameras are the future for you.
Speaker 9:  Well it's, it's kind of both. Yeah, it's kind of both. I just think
Speaker 9:  Meta rolled out the AI in such a way that people just don't
Speaker 9:  know how to use it properly. And if they say multimodal one more time, I'm
Speaker 9:  going to lose it. That's just like where I'm at. But
Speaker 9:  you know the interesting thing was like, let's talk about Rocket, right?
Speaker 9:  So Rocket it does everything that the Meta glasses do.
Speaker 9:  They have a camera in it but there is a display and it's a pretty
Speaker 9:  cool display but it's a, I think what they call this type of display is a
Speaker 9:  monocular monochrome display. And so
Speaker 4:  Monocular monochrome display, I like
Speaker 9:  That monocular monochrome display with micro etched displays in
Speaker 9:  the lenses. So like you look at them, they look like a normal pair of glasses.
Speaker 9:  They are much lighter than the Meta ray advance 'cause weight. We've talked
Speaker 9:  about this a lot. The weight is kind of a deal breaker sometimes. Yeah. When
Speaker 9:  you're wearing them. So they're quiet light, you can't actually see
Speaker 9:  the display unless you like the light hits you in a certain way it's etched
Speaker 9:  into the actual glass. But when you look into it, you can see
Speaker 9:  kind of like a, like if you're thinking of a military fighter jet and that
Speaker 9:  type of green laser looking display in there, you can see it okay it's an
Speaker 9:  actual display. And then the demo, I got
Speaker 9:  the, the person was speaking to me in Chinese and I could see the translation
Speaker 9:  happening in real time really. And then I could say something to her and
Speaker 9:  she would answer me in Chinese and there
Speaker 3:  Was no external commute. Was this going out to a cloud? Was this happening
Speaker 3:  locally?
Speaker 9:  Well that, that was a hard question because again she's speaking to me in
Speaker 9:  Chinese.
Speaker 3:  Well I'm just wondering like yeah If you can do that locally on a
Speaker 3:  pair of glasses with a reasonable battery life, that's,
Speaker 9:  I mean it is attached to your phone, right? Sure. Okay. Yeah. So that that's,
Speaker 9:  that's basically, we are still at the point where your phone is powering
Speaker 9:  all of this and it's over Bluetooth. It's not like computing everything locally
Speaker 9:  on that particular thing, but it's pretty wild. And as like journalists you
Speaker 9:  can have a teleprompter on there, you're wearing a pair of glasses, it does
Speaker 9:  not look like you're seeing anything. And this kind
Speaker 9:  of subsect of the monocular green laser thing that I
Speaker 9:  saw three of them, which I was like, oh that's a mini trend within a big
Speaker 9:  trend. Cool, cool stuff.
Speaker 3:  Right? There's a component here that everyone has decided they can use and
Speaker 3:  like,
Speaker 9:  And the reason why is because they have solved in a certain
Speaker 9:  aspect the ambient light problem. Oh. So the ambient light problem with smart
Speaker 9:  glasses is that you walk out into the sun and you can't see shit because
Speaker 9:  it's the sun, it like blinds everything out. So there's no point in a smart
Speaker 9:  glass If you can't see the display that you paid a lot of money for. But
Speaker 9:  with the green it's easier on your eyeballs. So like green
Speaker 9:  light is apparently the healthiest for your eye. It's the easiest to see
Speaker 9:  and it borrows from military technology because the contrast is
Speaker 4:  Really great. I will say what you just said is alarmingly similar to how
Speaker 4:  humane described the projector on the pin. And that didn't go super great.
Speaker 4:  No
Speaker 9:  It didn't. But it's
Speaker 3:  Like, it's little different. Did you ever say they borrowed from military?
Speaker 4:  No, but they were big on green lasers and how they were gonna be useful in
Speaker 4:  sunlight. That is. And then you go outside and it's
Speaker 9:  What if it work? But that's it's but that it's outside in the sunlight. Like
Speaker 9:  that's the, that so like holiday's solution to that. And I found Holliday
Speaker 9:  to be the most finicky of the three with the smallest amount. 'cause it's
Speaker 9:  like this tiny little dot it's held in like the bar
Speaker 9:  of it. So like when you think about wearing smart glasses and where the
Speaker 9:  display appears, it's actually like in the bar itself. So when you're talking
Speaker 9:  to someone, they're just basically doing this the entire time looking
Speaker 9:  up into the corner. And so it looks, looks like they're rolling your eyes
Speaker 9:  at you the entire time.
Speaker 3:  Well So I, I'm curious about this 'cause you got to see them. Yeah but you
Speaker 3:  know, earlier we were talking about like is there a product at CS that everyone
Speaker 3:  was talking about and like the holiday glasses are the closest to it And
Speaker 3:  then I think a lot of people got the demo and had that experience and it
Speaker 3:  stopped being the thing that everyone was talking about it.
Speaker 4:  It's, yeah, it seemed much more exciting at the beginning of the week than
Speaker 4:  I think it turned out to be once people started trying it. So
Speaker 9:  Like here's the thing, smart glasses. Yeah but you, the most annoying thing
Speaker 9:  about XR smart glasses, any of these things is that you have to see it to
Speaker 9:  believe it. And you know, when we're thinking about making
Speaker 9:  videos for these things and trying to like convey to people like, oh this
Speaker 9:  is actually cool. Literally you're taking these glasses, you're taking your
Speaker 9:  phone and you're like, if I angle the thing in the right way, I can get a
Speaker 9:  really blurry half portion of the green laser that you're gonna see.
Speaker 9:  So it's really hard to convey to people that, and like the holiday thing,
Speaker 9:  I think they got in early at the show, which was like good for them. But
Speaker 9:  like you're literally like, I don't know and it's not
Speaker 9:  as discreet because when you talk to someone you can see a green.in their
Speaker 9:  eye, like just a green.in their eye and you're like,
Speaker 9:  that's weird.
Speaker 3:  That's my targeting laser for the robot
Speaker 9:  Robot. That's my target. I'm an Android robot with a green dot.
Speaker 3:  So always. So you talk about the demo of the translation, like we've always
Speaker 3:  talked about, there's a lot of problems between here and the dream of AR
Speaker 3:  glasses, right? So you need a display,
Speaker 3:  which it seems like some people are getting closer to one display
Speaker 3:  solution that you can put on reasonably lightweight glasses. You need compute.
Speaker 3:  And it sounds like we're offloading that to the phone. I now, yeah,
Speaker 3:  then you need a bat, you need a battery that is not heavy but Verizon, enough
Speaker 9:  Battery life, you need a battery the more advanced it is for sure.
Speaker 3:  And then you, you like need stuff to do. Yeah,
Speaker 3:  right? Like you need to like augment reality. Like the, the goal is like,
Speaker 3:  I, I say this all the time, If you can just make me a pair of glasses
Speaker 3:  where you can just tell me your name, like I'll buy 'em in a heartbeat. The
Speaker 3:  problem is you need to build like a worldwide facial recognition database.
Speaker 3:  Just gimme surveillance state and everything will be fine and it's, you know,
Speaker 3:  we're headed there anyway. Okay. So like when we talk, just gimme the glasses
Speaker 3:  but you need to like build all this other stuff. Yeah. And it seems like
Speaker 3:  the ones here, they're really focused on like display.
Speaker 9:  So like what, what it is now and what I've seen on the floor is that we have
Speaker 9:  all agreed that smart glasses, we've agreed on smart glasses with all these
Speaker 9:  companies. What we've not agreed on is how to do them. So
Speaker 9:  what you have at CES is a bunch of people going smart glasses and now we're
Speaker 9:  gonna throw so much spaghetti on the wall and see what sticks. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  So they're trying to figure out, and like Google told me this
Speaker 9:  when I went to see the Android XR demos of their smart glasses prototype
Speaker 9:  is that you cannot approach it from one way. You have to approach it from
Speaker 9:  all other ways. So the, the thing about META'S glasses that
Speaker 9:  kind of really kicked the door open is it got normal people thinking
Speaker 9:  like, oh I have a use for this. I'm gonna take a, like for me, I'm gonna
Speaker 9:  take so many videos of my cats and they're not gonna be freaked out because
Speaker 9:  I have a phone in their face. And it sounds really stupid, but that actually
Speaker 9:  is a thing that gets people going toward it. And then for some of these people
Speaker 9:  they're like, oh you know what teleprompters, how many people would,
Speaker 9:  If you have to speak on anything, how many of you would love to have a little
Speaker 9:  teleprompter in front of your eyes that you can read that no one knows that
Speaker 9:  you're reading? Like it's great, you could have notes in something. Like
Speaker 9:  you can travel to a different country and yeah, your phone's in your pocket,
Speaker 9:  but you can talk to someone and understand what they're saying. Like that's
Speaker 9:  pretty cool If you think about that. Yeah. So those are like
Speaker 9:  real life use cases. So you have people approaching from the style first,
Speaker 9:  like the Essilor Luxottica people, they're just like, you know, I saw them
Speaker 9:  today, they were very Italian, very stylish. I felt like a schlub next to
Speaker 9:  them. But they were like, we want things that people use. So the nuance audio
Speaker 9:  ones, they are over the counter hearing aids in a glasses format because
Speaker 9:  it reduces stigma. It can still like noise cancel to a
Speaker 9:  certain, it is really cool. 'cause if I look at David and he's talking, it'll
Speaker 9:  amplify his voice, but then if I turn away from him, it'll cancel him out.
Speaker 9:  So like that's just,
Speaker 3:  That's the goal. That's that's a great idea.
Speaker 9:  You want idea? Yeah. So it's pretty cool. Yeah. And it supports all prescriptions
Speaker 9:  and it's like kind of geared towards the elderly who need glasses to
Speaker 9:  see and can't hear. That's so that's like a real use case that they have.
Speaker 9:  And then you have people on like the other end of the spectrum, like the
Speaker 9:  music is and the X reel and they're like, we are the future. You will
Speaker 9:  be watching movies on your glasses and like everything will be seen and
Speaker 9:  there'll be a little, so they had me like AI prompted
Speaker 9:  Fat Cat with unicorn wings that I could just like pinch to
Speaker 9:  be large. And I'm like, sure, that's a thing that's smart.
Speaker 3:  But like that's a display. Like what they're saying is like a display. You
Speaker 3:  can put a display in front of your eyes, but Nuance has display. We don't
Speaker 3:  know what's gonna be on
Speaker 9:  There. Display Nuance has no display, right? That's just audio only. So like,
Speaker 9:  I think in the transition, like BS kind of kicked it off with the glasses
Speaker 9:  with just making them audio. That's cool. Carmelo has
Speaker 9:  no display. The cool thing about Culo, and this is the only cool
Speaker 9:  thing is that you, you slide, you press a button and it changes the color
Speaker 9:  of the lens. And I'm
Speaker 3:  Like, that's why I thought it was called camilio. I just wanna be very honest.
Speaker 3:  Oh yeah, probably should be.
Speaker 9:  But you hear that on paper and you're like, that's stupid. Then you go into
Speaker 9:  the thing and you're like, Ooh, it changes colors. I'm so cool. Or
Speaker 9:  like you have, you change the tint. So it's like, oh it's really bright out.
Speaker 9:  I need the tint to be full, full of the way. Or if you're like me and you're
Speaker 9:  shady, you're like, oh I don't like this person. I'm gonna pull it all the
Speaker 9:  way to dark So I can make eyes at them. And So
Speaker 3:  I love the idea that you're wearing your glasses and just ruthlessly like
Speaker 3:  subtweeting people. Oh for sure. Like you're like, goodbye, goodbye. And
Speaker 3:  then you like turn your head, you're like, I can't hear you anymore. I
Speaker 9:  Can't. It's like, ooh,
Speaker 3:  Yay. It. It does seem like all of this
Speaker 3:  right there, there's some part of it's like, I think really fun, right? There's
Speaker 3:  all very innovative, we're all gonna try a bunch of stuff, but it also feels
Speaker 3:  like, well we can't make a watch, right?
Speaker 3:  Like no one's gonna buy a smart watch that isn't an Apple or a Google or
Speaker 3:  a Samsung ecosystem device. So we're gonna mount a computer
Speaker 3:  to your face. Here's a bunch of face stuff.
Speaker 9:  I mean the number one problem with the face stuff is that we are
Speaker 9:  so vain as a species. Like kids cry when they find out they have to
Speaker 9:  wear glasses because oh my god, they have to wear glasses. If you're David
Speaker 9:  who routinely tells me has 2020 vision, thanks
Speaker 4:  David. People say I have the best vision.
Speaker 9:  Okay. People, people say, say that. Say that. David has the best, many
Speaker 3:  People have, lot of people say
Speaker 9:  That say like, why would you wear glasses? Right. Unless there's a function
Speaker 9:  for it. You're just, I would
Speaker 3:  Like people to know that
Speaker 4:  I don't need glasses. Yeah. Like I want the opposite of glasses.
Speaker 9:  Right? But if you're like me and you're basically a blind bat, and If you
Speaker 9:  look at my phone, the text is so large, you know,
Speaker 9:  you're used to wearing glasses and so then it becomes more functional because
Speaker 9:  it's something you're already wearing. But that's, that's a huge problem.
Speaker 9:  Prescriptions are a huge problem if you're blind like me, negative nine.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, negative eight, huge astigmatism. Some of these glasses can't support
Speaker 9:  my actual thing. So then it's like, eh, you know, and
Speaker 9:  everyone's face is different. Everyone is aesthetic existent at different
Speaker 9:  mass producing these things. There's so many different challenges towards
Speaker 9:  smart glasses. So it's not like we're all gonna be wearing these tomorrow.
Speaker 9:  But I do think they've decided for whatever reason, yes, this is
Speaker 9:  possible. Throw everything at the wall, see what sticks, see what,
Speaker 9:  what is the way forward. And they all believe that it will converge
Speaker 9:  at this point where we have computers on our faces if we can.
Speaker 4:  I mean that's the CES story right there. That's the CES story. Like just
Speaker 4:  pick a thing that maybe will happen in a decade and let's try some weird
Speaker 4:  stuff about it. Yeah, yeah. Basically.
Speaker 9:  I love
Speaker 4:  That. That's,
Speaker 3:  That's, I'll remind you of course of my chart of whale bullshit. Do you know
Speaker 3:  about the chart? Two axes. One is utility and one is fids. And
Speaker 3:  you need to have vastly more utility than fids or your failure and
Speaker 3:  face is like a minus 500. I I propose If you put
Speaker 3:  something on your face, it has to be so useful.
Speaker 9:  It does, but I also propose that we actually visualize this graph and every
Speaker 9:  single time I do a wearable review, we have the graph in here.
Speaker 3:  We can do this, AI can do this for
Speaker 9:  Us, and AI can do this for us. And so, so
Speaker 3:  It will be lies, it will not
Speaker 9:  Be accurate. When, when I take briefings, I can go, okay, here's here's The
Speaker 9:  Verge approved graph. Please point to where on this graph your product is.
Speaker 9:  That would, that would make my life so much easier. I'm just saying
Speaker 3:  I'm correct about this. I think Joanna stole this in the journal recently,
Speaker 3:  so now we have to take it back. Let's putting out, okay, last thing I wanna
Speaker 3:  talk to you about V and we should we, we
Speaker 4:  Have to quit. We've gone way over. We, we don't need to let these poor people
Speaker 4:  go.
Speaker 3:  Okay.
Speaker 4:  Yeah. And we can, we'll, we'll hang out after, but we gotta, let's end the
Speaker 4:  podcast and go hang out with these nice people.
Speaker 3:  I just wanted her to talk about Mariami for one second.
Speaker 4:  No, you can't. It's not
Speaker 3:  Allowed. There's a weird robots that just hugs you. It's like a hugging robot.
Speaker 3:  Go, go find the hugging robot.
Speaker 4:  It's cute. Go find the hooky robot. All right, here's the title of
Speaker 3:  The episode. Thank you all for joining us. We have gone way over. It's wonderful
Speaker 3:  to be here with you. Thank you to Delta for bringing us Brooklyn Bull, which
Speaker 3:  is amazing. We just like looking at my giant face next to our logos on bowling
Speaker 3:  alley screens. This whole time has been delightful for me. My ego is very
Speaker 3:  healthy. I appreciate all of you frame TV owners. We can get a drink in
Speaker 3:  a corner and really work through it. That's it. That's for cast rock and
Speaker 3:  roll.
Speaker 11:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. Hey, we'd love to hear from you.
Speaker 11:  Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one. The Vergecast is a
Speaker 11:  production of The Verge and Vox Media podcast network. Our show is produced
Speaker 11:  by Liam James will pour an Air Gomez and that's it.
Speaker 11:  We'll see you next week.
Speaker 1:  I.