# Transcript
ID: fbcbca8e-ac95-462b-a6c5-94b488ef7151
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7315509064411450621/-4455092330454953186/s93290-US-5542s-1760089714.mp3
Description: Say this for OpenAI: it's very good at raising money, and it's very good at getting attention. David and Jake are joined by The Verge's Hayden Field to talk about OpenAI's demo day, the company's app store plans, why it's trying to build every possible ChatGPT feature all at the same time, and more. After that, the hosts talk about the ongoing popularity of the Sora app, and whether OpenAI has truly built a new kind of social network. Then Hayden has to leave, so David and Jake take on the lightning round to discuss Intel chips, Alex Cooper's Google deal, Starry internet, and more.
Speaker 2:  Welcome
Speaker 7:  To the Vergecast, the flagship podcast of being accessible
Speaker 7:  but not intrusive. We'll get back to that Johnny Iif.
Speaker 7:  Everybody accessible but not intrusive. This is what we're doing here. I'm
Speaker 7:  your friend David Pierce. Jake Kakis is here. Hi Jake. Hey, good to be here.
Speaker 7:  Hayden Field is here. Hi Hayden.
Speaker 8:  Hey, excited
Speaker 7:  Hayden from some very generic hotel room somewhere in the Bay area.
Speaker 7:  Is, is that, is that correct? Exactly.
Speaker 8:  You guys are the first people I'm talking to today. Amazing. About to head
Speaker 8:  to some more AI lab offices. It's an honor for me too.
Speaker 7:  So you, you're out there, there's a bunch of AI stuff going on this week,
Speaker 7:  but the, the big event of the week was open AI's dev day
Speaker 7:  and we have a lot of news to talk about this week. There's a bunch of AI
Speaker 7:  stuff, but we're, we're gonna, I should just level with all of you. We're
Speaker 7:  gonna spend most of the show talking about open AI 'cause it's been a really
Speaker 7:  fascinating and bizarre week for OpenAI. We're gonna talk about soa. We have
Speaker 7:  a bunch of stuff to do in the lightning round, but Hayden, we have you for
Speaker 7:  a little while before you have to get outta here. So let's, let's talk dev
Speaker 7:  day first, just like what is, what is a dev day like?
Speaker 7:  Jake went to his first Apple event recently. I've been to lots of things,
Speaker 7:  but never an OpenAI dev day. Like what's, what is a dev day at OpenAI?
Speaker 8:  Great question because it's kind of a confusing name. I've been to everyone
Speaker 8:  they've ever done besides the one where they didn't allow press last year.
Speaker 8:  It's basically an annual event where they announce a bunch of stuff. It's
Speaker 8:  technically four developers. They invite 1500,
Speaker 8:  2000 developers to come and listen to all their new
Speaker 8:  announcements, features, tools. So some of it's a little bit niche,
Speaker 8:  you know, it's things that only developers would wanna know so they can build
Speaker 8:  within the platform. But a lot of it is also pretty consumer facing.
Speaker 8:  They use it kind of as a, just a catchall for everything they're gonna
Speaker 8:  do that year to build, you know, investor interest to get
Speaker 8:  a lot of headlines. So some of it's a little bit niche and hard to understand
Speaker 8:  for the average person and some of it is just pretty wide. Like
Speaker 8:  they always have a keynote by Sam. And then, yeah, a bunch
Speaker 8:  of like small workshops, things like that, that are a little bit
Speaker 8:  more, you know, only focused on developers.
Speaker 7:  So if the spectrum is like highly produced video
Speaker 7:  on the ww DC side all the way to like,
Speaker 7:  I don't know, Microsoft build where it's just a bunch of like VPs writing
Speaker 7:  code on stage. Where, where does OpenAI fall on the spectrum?
Speaker 8:  I feel like it's an exact middle ground. Okay. Because we literally had
Speaker 8:  people writing code on stage as demos and then on the other
Speaker 8:  side of the coin we have, you know, like a live stream keynote by
Speaker 8:  Sam and a very controlled media room with a
Speaker 8:  q and a with all the execs. So yeah, it's definitely a combo and it's a strange
Speaker 8:  combination of both those vibes for sure.
Speaker 7:  Okay. I just, I I have come to appreciate Jake, I don't know how you feel
Speaker 7:  about this, but like we make fun of the people who just like write coat on
Speaker 7:  stage during keynotes, but I, I have come to kind of love it. Like I, I respect
Speaker 7:  the hustle of just getting real nerdy with it. Oh
Speaker 9:  It's a sport. I love that. Like it it is the weirdest live demo because
Speaker 9:  it is the most boring live demo, but like Oh yeah, the stakes are there.
Speaker 9:  They're high.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it always reminds me of like I went to the Excel World Championships
Speaker 7:  a couple of years ago and like the vibes are exactly the same where it's
Speaker 7:  like I don't understand any part of what these people are doing and it's
Speaker 7:  completely inscrutable to anyone who is not like six inches away from the
Speaker 7:  screen watching it. But like I respect you anyway. Like game
Speaker 7:  recognized game.
Speaker 8:  I have to say, I did interview one of the people that did a demo
Speaker 8:  yesterday, like after the fact and she was pretty
Speaker 8:  compelling. Like she narrated what she was doing the whole time. She knew
Speaker 8:  her audience and you know, they projected a
Speaker 8:  a ton of fun stuff on the screen behind her so they knew how to hold your
Speaker 8:  attention even if you didn't know what the hell was going on, which is great.
Speaker 7:  Love that. So the, the big news, like you said of all of the
Speaker 7:  sort of, there's like developer news and sort of infrastructural news, but
Speaker 7:  it seems like the big consumer news was
Speaker 7:  apps inside of chat GBT. Is that, was that the big story do you think?
Speaker 8:  Yeah, to me that was okay. You know, allowing companies
Speaker 8:  to you know, integrate their apps directly into chat
Speaker 8:  EBT so that you can say, Hey I'm looking for a house in the Bay
Speaker 8:  area, don't worry I'm not on Zillow. Give me, you know, the
Speaker 8:  houses within this price range. And then you can ask follow-up questions
Speaker 8:  on whatever the app delivers you. Not just Zillow but any of these apps ostensibly.
Speaker 8:  So you know, let's use the Zillow example. It gives me a bunch of
Speaker 8:  houses and then I say okay, narrow this down to only ones with a yard or
Speaker 8:  narrow this down with to only ones with two bathrooms 'cause I'm tired
Speaker 8:  of sharing a bathroom. You know, you say all that and then it can like really
Speaker 8:  deliver follow ups and you know, narrow the list and kind of work with
Speaker 8:  you. Nick Turley, the head of Chacha BT, who I interviewed yesterday
Speaker 8:  said to think of it as apps you can talk to. So yeah that was
Speaker 8:  definitely the big news to me. There's also the agent toolkit they
Speaker 8:  announced agent kit where you know, companies,
Speaker 8:  enterprises can build their own AI agents and it's just kind of another
Speaker 8:  push for open AI and to both the consumer and the enterprise world. They're
Speaker 8:  trying to tackle both and corner of the market on both, which is tall order.
Speaker 8:  And then the very last thing that I thought was pretty notable was
Speaker 8:  allowing companies to use so a's technology via
Speaker 8:  the API. So we're gonna see a lot more AI generated video out there. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  So we're gonna come back to SOA in a little bit 'cause I think this has been
Speaker 7:  sort of the week of SOA and I wanna talk a lot about
Speaker 7:  what is going on and what we've seen. But the, the apps and the
Speaker 7:  agent thing i I is just so bizarre and
Speaker 7:  fascinating to me because I think like you and I have spent a lot of time
Speaker 7:  talking on this show and elsewhere over the last couple of months about
Speaker 7:  AI agents. It's all anybody wants to talk about everybody is like agentic
Speaker 7:  AI is the future of everything. You're just gonna instruct a system to go
Speaker 7:  do something for you and it's gonna go do it. And then open AI
Speaker 7:  is like, well what if we just let Spotify integrate
Speaker 7:  so that you could just make a Spotify playlist with Spotify and we didn't
Speaker 7:  have to magically train some AI system to
Speaker 7:  do it because Spotify can do it. It's just like watching
Speaker 7:  that announcement, I'm like, this is so clearly and obviously the
Speaker 7:  right idea if what you want is for your tool to actually work
Speaker 7:  and it like, it's so different from the way that open AI and everybody else
Speaker 7:  has talked about it where it's like it's not, we're not doing app stores,
Speaker 7:  we're not having platform wars. What we're gonna do is we're gonna train
Speaker 7:  this thing so that it can do everything all by itself and that if
Speaker 7:  it's ever going to work, it's not gonna work anytime soon. But this thing
Speaker 7:  where Zillow can just pipe in its database and let chat GPT basically
Speaker 7:  be like fuzzy search for Zillow will work.
Speaker 7:  That is a doable, plausible thing. And it is like a complete
Speaker 7:  strategy shift in how everybody has been talking about AI for the last like
Speaker 7:  12 months.
Speaker 8:  Definitely. And it's interesting because something they were
Speaker 8:  emphasizing a bunch when we interviewed these execs was chat GPT
Speaker 8:  becoming an operating system instead of just one tool. So they're really
Speaker 8:  making the push to, you know, integrate all these apps, make it like
Speaker 8:  an everything app. You wake up in the morning, you use chat GPT Pulse,
Speaker 8:  you go about your day, you're ordering food, you're looking for a house,
Speaker 8:  you're coding for work and you're using chat GPT. They're basically
Speaker 8:  trying to make it a everything destination. And when I asked
Speaker 8:  Nick Turley yesterday about whether they were going for,
Speaker 8:  you know, an Apple app store, he was a little bit cagey he
Speaker 8:  said, said, oh there's no metaphor for what we're doing, but
Speaker 7:  No, no, no, no. Hold on, hold on, hold on. That's bullshit. That's the perfect
Speaker 7:  metaphor for what they're doing. That is like, that is the metaphor that
Speaker 7:  Apple figured out how to basically turn a
Speaker 7:  successful platform into an unstoppable money funnel.
Speaker 7:  And the reason all of these companies are out here saying we're moving
Speaker 7:  past the app store model, we wanna do the other things, is because Google
Speaker 7:  and Apple won and all of these companies have spent a generation
Speaker 7:  living under that, right? Giving up 30% not being able to do certain things
Speaker 7:  because they don't follow the platform's rules. And they've been saying,
Speaker 7:  okay, what we need to do is actually build something that is outside of that
Speaker 7:  and bigger than that. And that's what the Metaverse was supposed to be. That's
Speaker 7:  what AI is supposed to be. And now OpenAI looks around and realizes, oh
Speaker 7:  we're huge. We have critical mass, we have the thing that is hard to
Speaker 7:  get, which is scale. And now that we have scale, what we should build is
Speaker 7:  the unstoppable money funnel where other people do all the work and give
Speaker 7:  us money for it because we built the thing with scale. Like it's the
Speaker 7:  same exact playbook and and anybody who says it's not is
Speaker 7:  just trying to hide something from you. It is the exact same thing.
Speaker 8:  Exactly. He didn't deny it, he was just a little cagey, but it was clear
Speaker 8:  to everyone in the room. I think that that is what they're doing. Okay, good.
Speaker 8:  And it's also like, you know, yeah, the level of
Speaker 8:  control seems pretty similar. You know, right now they're only launching
Speaker 8:  with eight or so apps. I asked him a lot about what the
Speaker 8:  process is going to look like for developers who want to submit their apps
Speaker 8:  to be
Speaker 8:  rolled out within chat GBT and he said, anyone can build
Speaker 8:  right now, but you know, there's gonna be a tall order for
Speaker 8:  getting distributed and then there's gonna be another kind of
Speaker 8:  design aspect that you have to meet in order to be widely distributed.
Speaker 8:  So it reminds me a lot of Apple to be honest. Yeah, that's
Speaker 7:  The stuff that Apple tries not to say out loud is that it has
Speaker 7:  that kind of control over what's going on. Jake, am I,
Speaker 7:  am I overstating this? You and I have been fighting about app stores for
Speaker 7:  forever. This
Speaker 9:  Is giving me nightmare flashbacks to Alexa
Speaker 9:  skills and basically every other app store on earth, right?
Speaker 9:  I I feel like we keep having this thing where a new platform comes out.
Speaker 9:  Maybe it's the Apple Watch, maybe it's, you know, VR
Speaker 9:  headsets, maybe it's a smart assistant and we're
Speaker 9:  just like, we'll make it good by making apps on it. Great. Okay, so now there's
Speaker 9:  a million apps within chat GBT, so I can use the apps that I can already
Speaker 9:  use on the same platforms in a different way. It,
Speaker 9:  I don't know the, every time that happens it feels like
Speaker 9:  they, they're just throwing stuff at the, at a wall and it feels like a dead
Speaker 9:  end to me and interesting. I'm not saying that it's not gonna work here,
Speaker 9:  but the, the promise of AI was that they
Speaker 9:  didn't need to do all this. That they're just like, we can use these things,
Speaker 9:  we can use these apps, it's fine, we're just gonna go use them. And instead
Speaker 9:  they're like, you know, know what if we actually
Speaker 9:  made other companies do all the work and hard code everything and
Speaker 9:  put specific rules around everything so that our product works and
Speaker 9:  what if they don't?
Speaker 7:  But the difference is, it, it, it might and the first thing you just
Speaker 7:  described doesn't work and might never work like
Speaker 7:  it, the the whole like we're gonna teach our AI model
Speaker 7:  how to use the internet the way that you do thing. Like the all the computer
Speaker 7:  use stuff. Like all of that is somewhere between vaporware and just bullshit.
Speaker 7:  And I would, I would put it closer to bullshit than vaporware,
Speaker 7:  but like none of that exists in any kind of meaningful way. And I
Speaker 7:  keep talking to people who are like, we went down that road, we tried it,
Speaker 7:  we have pushed, we have tried the thing and there is absolutely no evidence
Speaker 7:  that like truly useful ag agentic AI is anywhere close to being
Speaker 7:  anywhere close to being useful. Whereas you can
Speaker 7:  plug your API into my front end and we can do stuff together that works.
Speaker 7:  That's, that's technology. That's how everything already works. And
Speaker 7:  we're, we're starting to see the companies with scale figure that out,
Speaker 7:  right? Like Amazon is running this exact same playbook with Alexa
Speaker 7:  plus, which is like, you know, no one should really want to be compared to
Speaker 7:  Alexa plus right now, but like the idea is the right one where they're like,
Speaker 7:  instead of trying to convince our model to like learn how to click
Speaker 7:  around the DoorDash website, we're just gonna plug into DoorDash because
Speaker 7:  we have a relationship with DoorDash and they'll do that. This comes
Speaker 7:  to a certain problem that like Mila always calls this the DoorDash problem,
Speaker 7:  which is why would DoorDash say yes to that? Why would I let myself be completely
Speaker 7:  disintermediated by this other product? But
Speaker 7:  the, the difference between a lot of the stuff you were talking about Jake,
Speaker 7:  and where I think we are now is chat t is already that front
Speaker 7:  end of stuff for lots and lots of people. Like people are
Speaker 7:  increasingly used to the idea of no matter what I want, I'm gonna go
Speaker 7:  to chat GPT for it. And that is powerful. And if you have that,
Speaker 7:  and I think there is some evidence that chat GPT has that or is at least
Speaker 7:  getting that very quickly for like millions and millions of people, you become
Speaker 7:  the the home screen for people, right? Like that's the closest thing to like
Speaker 7:  the the iPhone equivalent. And so if I'm open ai, I completely understand
Speaker 7:  why I would be chasing this as hard and fast as I possibly could.
Speaker 9:  I I think that's completely fair and I think you're right like this, this,
Speaker 9:  this is what they need to make it actually work because the thing that they're
Speaker 9:  promising does not actually work in that way yet.
Speaker 7:  They haven't made God yet it turns out. And until they make God, APIs are
Speaker 7:  pretty good, you know what I mean? They're so
Speaker 9:  Close. I think that's what Sam Altman said. This is the thing I,
Speaker 9:  my fear, my great fear is that all of these other platforms, they go apps,
Speaker 9:  apps, apps and then they don't do anything else. And I think if
Speaker 9:  chat GBT goes too far down this road, they lose
Speaker 9:  track of whatever else they're trying to build, maybe they never build it,
Speaker 9:  then the platform becomes less useful. Right?
Speaker 9:  I'm, I am worried about where this ends up at at this moment. I
Speaker 9:  tried it, it made some Spotify playlist for me. Pretty cool. Alright,
Speaker 7:  Wait, did you actually try it? How did, like what? Tell me about your Spotify.
Speaker 7:  Yeah,
Speaker 9:  Yeah I tried, I was like make a Spotify playlist for me. It made a Spotify
Speaker 9:  playlist. Cool. I, I was, I said hey can you actually remove a song from
Speaker 9:  that Spotify playlist? I said nope, I can't do that but here's instructions
Speaker 9:  on how you can do it. So you know, it's a start it it's like, but
Speaker 9:  this is the thing, it needs to get way, way, way more powerful and I
Speaker 9:  think the thing they're promising, right, if it can do computer use then
Speaker 9:  it would just go and it would click the buttons and it would remove the,
Speaker 9:  the song for me in this case it was like, oh that one wasn't
Speaker 9:  hardcoded and then you just run into the same set of problems you had originally
Speaker 9:  with Alexa apps where if you didn't say the exact same,
Speaker 9:  you know, prompt to order a Domino's pizza, how you're supposed to order
Speaker 9:  a Domino's pizza, you just end up with nothing.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. One example I saw on X the other day was
Speaker 8:  that someone was like, oh this would actually be really useful if you could
Speaker 8:  say, hey DoorDash, order me a meal that you know,
Speaker 8:  I'll like tonight that's like under this number of calories and is like,
Speaker 8:  you know, not pizza, which is what I've been eating all week. You know, and
Speaker 8:  then it would be really useful. But as we know, AI is not good at common
Speaker 8:  sense. So we'll see when they're able to offer that. If ever. The
Speaker 8:  Zillow example I liked because it was a follow-up question on the data
Speaker 8:  you were presented, which is great, but like you just said, Jake, the follow
Speaker 8:  up question you asked it was not able to deliver. So I think, you know, something
Speaker 8:  they kept emphasizing yesterday was that they're in the early stages of this,
Speaker 8:  they just wanted to roll it out but you know, people are gonna be underwhelmed
Speaker 8:  if they don't work. So we'll have to see because I wanna test all the apps
Speaker 8:  they have out there right now, you know, the Canva one for
Speaker 8:  posters. Does it really work? You know, if you're saying, hey make me a
Speaker 8:  slide. Luckily I've never had to make a slide deck in my life but I, I hear
Speaker 8:  that's a common thing that you need a lot of people need in their jobs, you
Speaker 8:  know, stuff like that. I wanna see which of them actually work well and which
Speaker 8:  of them can handle the follow up questions or is it just the only one
Speaker 8:  that they presented on stage that can handle the follow-up questions?
Speaker 7:  It is very telling what they choose to do in some of these demos, but I think
Speaker 7:  like the, the DoorDash example is a really interesting one. 'cause that is
Speaker 7:  the sort of thing that seems like an obviously good idea and you sort of
Speaker 7:  look at the technological piece of it and you're like, well all the steps
Speaker 7:  to do this kind of sorta exists. Yeah. So like
Speaker 7:  it can't be that out of the question that I should be able to ask that question
Speaker 7:  and get a return. And I think where I land is that
Speaker 7:  the it, I a hundred percent agree that that thing you just described is impossible
Speaker 7:  and, and it won't work and you shouldn't try it. The shortest path
Speaker 7:  to get there for me seems pretty clearly like some
Speaker 7:  kind of functional AI input system, right?
Speaker 7:  Where like that is better than going
Speaker 7:  in and clicking a million filters on a website, right? Like there's a reason
Speaker 7:  travel keeps doing this too, where it's like now if you wanna find a flight,
Speaker 7:  you have to go to 35 dropdowns. Yep. Pick a thing
Speaker 7:  and do the flight. But if I could just type in what I, where I want to go
Speaker 7:  and when and it have it do it for me that that's a better way.
Speaker 7:  And that's the kind of thing that these AI bots are very good at. Then
Speaker 7:  the other side is, okay, either chat GPT or Claude or
Speaker 7:  whoever else has to go and successfully click around the internet in order
Speaker 7:  to select all those filters for me or it needs to plug into
Speaker 7:  somebody's database and API to inform it what those
Speaker 7:  things are and pull the data out of the database. And to me that seems
Speaker 7:  a lot more plausible than chat GPT is going to learn how to click around
Speaker 7:  door Dash's website. And so I like, again, none of this works, but it seems
Speaker 7:  like if, if you want that thing to work, these companies working together
Speaker 7:  and making apps makes a lot more sense to me than any kind of like
Speaker 7:  agentic future.
Speaker 8:  I agree. That's actually what I thought when I was watching this demo for
Speaker 8:  the first time because the way I always think about this stuff is I
Speaker 8:  think it's easy to get in the weeds and when you're really in the AI industry
Speaker 8:  or when you're really into just covering the AI industry or you're just consuming
Speaker 8:  it a lot, you get really into the the
Speaker 8:  small stuff and the small incremental steps forward. But for me,
Speaker 8:  I always think about like who is really gonna use this? Are my friends that
Speaker 8:  are like pretty offline gonna use this? Are, is my mom gonna be interested
Speaker 8:  in using this? Is anyone I know really gonna use this? And this
Speaker 8:  was the first thing I've seen in a long time where I could say yes. Like
Speaker 8:  right now a lot of my friends use Chacha PT all the time. A lot of them
Speaker 8:  don't even have an account. This is something I could see getting the people
Speaker 8:  that don't use it to use it and because our lives are
Speaker 8:  really annoying in some ways and this is a way to kind of fix
Speaker 8:  that if it works the right way. Like what you were saying, David, with travel,
Speaker 8:  the reason I haven't booked my Thanksgiving flights yet, it's annoying.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. And I don't wanna deal with it. If I could just plug that in. And by
Speaker 8:  the way, when I was interviewing some of the OpenAI
Speaker 8:  folks yesterday, one-on-one they mentioned travel again and
Speaker 8:  again as an example of something they were trying to, you know, help fix
Speaker 8:  here in terms of the booking process. So we'll see how it all plays out.
Speaker 7:  Jake, you look skeptical.
Speaker 9:  I, my fear is that I think you are correct David, right? Like
Speaker 9:  this is the way to get things done. My fear is that
Speaker 9:  if it stops here, then what they have done is spent $500 billion
Speaker 9:  to event invent Alexa. Right?
Speaker 8:  I I agree.
Speaker 9:  Yes. Is is an option. It's just a lot of
Speaker 9:  people wasted a lot of money in that case. Yeah.
Speaker 8:  I mean they need to, they need to make it good and keep building
Speaker 8:  both the things they're building if they want it to not just die a slow death,
Speaker 8:  like all the other things we've seen.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, Alexa, but you can talk to it in actual sentences is a
Speaker 7:  very plausible outcome for all of this that is going to cost a lot of people
Speaker 7:  a lot of money and maybe burn down the US economy in the process. But like
Speaker 7:  I agree that feels like a, a totally possible endpoint because I think like
Speaker 7:  I, I don't know if, if this has been y'all's experience, but in my AI use,
Speaker 7:  the thing that works most consistently is the input. Like I can, I
Speaker 7:  can say complicated rambly things
Speaker 7:  and these systems more or less understand what I'm talking about far more
Speaker 7:  successfully than anything we've had before. You don't have to say, you know,
Speaker 7:  instructions in a very specific cadence. You don't have to like remember
Speaker 7:  the exact words to say in the exact right order. You can just sort of talk
Speaker 7:  and its ability to figure out what you're talking about works. It doesn't
Speaker 7:  always work, but it's, it's very good. Those are the things that I'm like
Speaker 7:  consistently impressed by with these AI systems.
Speaker 7:  Everything after that, which it turns out is where all of the work is beyond
Speaker 7:  playing music and setting timers
Speaker 7:  still undone. And, and again, I think to, to open AI and, and back to
Speaker 7:  what you were saying a few minutes ago, Hayden, the thing that is so interesting
Speaker 7:  to me about open AI is it is running at every
Speaker 7:  possible version of the answer as fast as it can at all
Speaker 7:  times. And even Sam Alman seems very clear about like, we have no idea what
Speaker 7:  any of the answers are. I'm very good at raising money and we seem to be
Speaker 7:  winning, so I am going to chase as many things as fast as I possibly can.
Speaker 7:  Like he's basically said those words in that order
Speaker 7:  to anyone who will listen and he's, he's
Speaker 7:  probably right, but like opening eyes rolling out the thing where you can
Speaker 7:  do all of that kind of like Spotify make a playlist,
Speaker 7:  you know, find a flight, whatever sort of search in chat GPT, it's also offering
Speaker 7:  that technology to those app makers who wanna build it into their own stuff.
Speaker 7:  It's also doing the agent stuff that they're just like, we have no idea,
Speaker 7:  but we have all the money in all the users and so we're gonna chase everything
Speaker 7:  at the same time and see what happens. And that is the open AI story.
Speaker 8:  Except during the exec q and a I was at, they seemed a little,
Speaker 8:  a little more nervous than usual about making money, you know, really
Speaker 8:  they, they kept saying it wasn't in their top 10
Speaker 8:  concerns, but then they would go on to say, but
Speaker 8:  eventually we're going to have to be very profitable. But then they would
Speaker 8:  say, but we're patient and confident that that will happen.
Speaker 8:  But I've never seen them act more nervous about it. You know,
Speaker 8:  they, they usually are very calm and just mention it maybe
Speaker 8:  once, but they mentioned it multiple times. They're really cagey about the
Speaker 8:  amount of compute they need, which is of course all the compute. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 8:  It was interesting to see them squirm a little bit
Speaker 8:  about the need to make money and how they were going to do it. So
Speaker 8:  yeah, I think this is them, you know, going into a bunch of different ventures
Speaker 8:  trying to make that happen.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I think there, there was a lot of really interesting reporting and
Speaker 7:  just sort of puzzle piecing this week of all of
Speaker 7:  open AI's money stuff. Like they, they announced this big deal with a
Speaker 7:  MD to get more compute. They have this big deal with Nvidia,
Speaker 7:  they have a big deal with Microsoft. Like there is just this gigantic
Speaker 7:  pool of money flowing in and out of open AI at all times. And it's like,
Speaker 7:  as long as OpenAI continues to be the
Speaker 7:  big leading thing and everybody believes in it, it's, it's,
Speaker 7:  this'll keep working. But like one of one of my
Speaker 7:  hottest takes coming outta the summer was that OpenAI is a house of cards.
Speaker 7:  It it still very much feels like that to me. And it's like, the question
Speaker 7:  is, is OpenAI so big and so propped up that it's gonna get to
Speaker 7:  chase all of these things until one of them becomes the answer.
Speaker 7:  Or at some point, like the minute anybody loses confidence and pulls out
Speaker 7:  like one of the Jenga blocks here, the whole thing is gonna come falling
Speaker 7:  down. And I I I think if, if you're Sam Altman, you have to know that,
Speaker 7:  right? That like he's on this treadmill and he has to keep running this fast
Speaker 7:  or else things are gonna start to get really ugly really fast because the
Speaker 7:  minute somebody looks at him and goes, can I have my money please? He
Speaker 7:  he's gonna, no, they don't have any to give you. They lit it all on fire
Speaker 7:  at a data center somewhere.
Speaker 8:  We'll see
Speaker 7:  That's the open AI story. So the other thing that happened at the dev day
Speaker 7:  this week was we got somewhere between a little information
Speaker 7:  and no information about what open AI and Johnny I were up to. You went to
Speaker 7:  this like fireside chat, right? What was it, what was it like? What did we
Speaker 7:  learn?
Speaker 8:  Nothing. We learned nothing.
Speaker 8:  It was stunned to hear this. It was very high level, it was very naval
Speaker 8:  gazy, you know, beautiful words, essay
Speaker 8:  vibes. We didn't get any concrete info. I didn't expect a lot
Speaker 8:  of concrete info, but I expected like, you know, maybe one
Speaker 8:  specific or a, a semi specific anything, just give us anything. And
Speaker 8:  it was very go girl give us nothing. Like, you know, we didn't really see
Speaker 8:  all the reporters I was sitting with, we were had high hopes and
Speaker 8:  we all turned off our recordings like, you know, we knew nothing was gonna
Speaker 8:  happen and we ended up just, you know, sitting and writing some of our stories
Speaker 8:  that we needed to write. I saw a couple people get up and leave
Speaker 8:  the media knew very quickly that nothing was really gonna come out of it.
Speaker 8:  I had an open AI person ask me afterward how it went. I said, you know,
Speaker 8:  it was something, it, it, it didn't, I think it was
Speaker 8:  probably pretty inspiring to the developers listening, you know, but
Speaker 8:  they didn't say anything. It was, it was a lot more about like, you know,
Speaker 8:  what advice would you give to someone who's building for the first time?
Speaker 8:  You know, it was very like inspirational quote naval
Speaker 8:  gey, nothing that people really who wanted
Speaker 8:  specifics from something would be excited about. So I think it was a
Speaker 8:  little tough because I mean it was a fireside chat led by an AI
Speaker 8:  CEO so you know, we didn't really expect a lot more, but everyone
Speaker 8:  knows they're building this mysterious buzzy hot device
Speaker 8:  of some sort. There's been a lot of headlines about that even this week.
Speaker 8:  So, you know, people wanted to to advance the storyline a tiny
Speaker 8:  bit and that did not happen.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, there was an interesting financial time story this week with
Speaker 7:  I would say more details than Johnny I was willing to give
Speaker 7:  up in that chat. And one of the things that, that story I talked about, and
Speaker 7:  this is the reason I ring it up now, is that, that they're having real
Speaker 7:  compute issues trying to figure this thing out because evidently the device
Speaker 7:  they wanna build is, is basically like an always on, always
Speaker 7:  listening assistant type of thing, which makes sense. Like if that seems
Speaker 7:  like if you're open AI and Johnny Ive, that's the thing you would wanna build,
Speaker 7:  but they're trying to figure out how to a, navigate the unbelievable privacy
Speaker 7:  challenges that that creates. Which yes, of course good idea,
Speaker 7:  but also trying to figure out how to manage the
Speaker 7:  incredible compute requirements of that. And this is like, OpenAI is
Speaker 7:  already pretty honest about the fact that it can't get enough
Speaker 7:  compute to do what it's trying to do and that stuff is very expensive and
Speaker 7:  cost a ton of money and they want to, they want to make
Speaker 7:  a thing that is listening to you and processing everything that you do and
Speaker 7:  hear and say all the time. Like that just presents a completely
Speaker 7:  different set of problems that I think it's
Speaker 7:  gonna, like you can see why Sam Altman spends all of his time talking about
Speaker 7:  and raising money for data centers because none of this works if it
Speaker 7:  can't get that kind of like nearly infinite,
Speaker 7:  very cheap compute, those are the jangle blocks that
Speaker 7:  go away the most quickly and all of this falls apart. Yeah,
Speaker 9:  There's also a really important element for an at-home device.
Speaker 9:  Gen TUI was just writing about this for the site with, you know, the new
Speaker 9:  Google Home speakers, the new Alexa plus stuff.
Speaker 9:  These things take longer than they used to because they have to go up
Speaker 9:  to the cloud and do the fancy AI processing and then come back down. That's
Speaker 9:  not a good experience. It's not clear if they're going to be able to right
Speaker 9:  chat GBT is fine, but it's, it's completely different when you were in your
Speaker 9:  home asking it to do something that is immediately right in front of you,
Speaker 9:  if it takes time to turn on the lights or get you something useful, you're
Speaker 9:  not going to use this product. It's not clear to me which direction they're
Speaker 9:  gonna go here or if they're gonna be able to solve that problem. Right. They,
Speaker 9:  they fundamentally have just have not had to deal with the problem of a
Speaker 9:  local chat GPT in the past. So this is like very much
Speaker 9:  a new space for them.
Speaker 7:  Totally. I think it's, it's, it's gonna be interesting to see
Speaker 7:  where any of that lands or like one fun Johnny I problem will be
Speaker 7:  how do you interface away the slowness of it, right? Because like we've even
Speaker 7:  seen all of these tools get, one of the reasons they like
Speaker 7:  talk to you more as they're thinking is to make the process feel faster
Speaker 7:  even while it's slow. So it feels like something is happening.
Speaker 7:  It's, it's not fun to talk to a thing and then
Speaker 7:  just sort of stand there and watch it think silently for 30 seconds before
Speaker 7:  it gives you an answer. And when it's just a little pendant around your neck,
Speaker 7:  I, I don't know how you solve that problem from an interface perspective,
Speaker 7:  but I'm very curious to see what they come up with.
Speaker 8:  I'm also interested because you know, one thing I've seen with the Johnny
Speaker 8:  Ive and opening eye device is that it's supposed to be the same
Speaker 8:  type of, you know, concept. You know, you put it in your
Speaker 8:  pocket, you have it in your bag, but it's something easily accessible.
Speaker 8:  You know, kind of like a small device that
Speaker 8:  you're not gonna wear but it's gonna be there listening and you put it on
Speaker 8:  it on the table and you ask a thing. So I mean I just can't see right now
Speaker 8:  how it people have a different experience than they had with friend, you
Speaker 8:  know, because you know, yeah our own B song wrote about
Speaker 8:  her horrible experience with friend asking her, oh I didn't
Speaker 8:  hear that. Or
Speaker 7:  All right, we're back. Let's talk about SOA because I think SOA, the app
Speaker 7:  launched last week but has been like sort of the thing everybody's talking
Speaker 7:  about this week. Have you guys used soa, the new OpenAI?
Speaker 7:  It's TikTok but everything is AI generated, I would say is essentially how
Speaker 7:  the app works. Have you guys used it?
Speaker 8:  Yes, I wrote a few stories on it. I like tested it so much and
Speaker 8:  I was screen recording, so many copyright violations,
Speaker 8:  so many interesting videos of Sam Altman committing crimes,
Speaker 8:  crying, talking to people and a lot of other
Speaker 8:  weird animal videos. So yeah, right now I think it's a combination of
Speaker 8:  open AI employees, Sam Altman and animal videos.
Speaker 8:  That's my current read.
Speaker 9:  I used it for a few minutes and honestly I thought it was way more compelling
Speaker 9:  than I expected it to be, just compared to like the usual, I
Speaker 9:  don't know, feed of other people's AI is usually
Speaker 9:  wildly uninteresting and the Sora feed felt to me
Speaker 9:  like just a kind of a weird meme feed which
Speaker 9:  you know, take it or leave it but it there, there was something there.
Speaker 9:  It felt lively. Well
Speaker 7:  So, okay, let's, let's poke at that because I think, yeah, part of what's
Speaker 7:  been so interesting to me has been, that has been a more consistent reaction
Speaker 7:  than I expected to SOA and I think
Speaker 7:  Katie nais writes a business insider posted on threads, a thing that
Speaker 7:  I think perfectly encapsulates this whole thing. And there's nothing more
Speaker 7:  fun than reading somebody's jokes on a podcast, but I'm gonna do it. She
Speaker 7:  said, me looking at Vibes Feed, this is Meta's Vibes app, which is just the
Speaker 7:  same thing but worse. Me looking at vibes feed, this is screensaver so boring,
Speaker 7:  why would anyone want it? Me looking at videos I made of my own face in Sora.
Speaker 7:  He, he, he, I love this. It's funny it's me. I'd like, I
Speaker 7:  have seen versions of that reaction so many times and there's so many
Speaker 7:  people who are like, I went into this not expecting to be compelled by this.
Speaker 7:  I thought it was just gonna be a feed full of AI slap I hate feeds full of
Speaker 7:  ai slap this one feels different. So Jake, why do you think it feels different?
Speaker 9:  So I, number one, their algorithm is better, right? Or
Speaker 9:  their AI is better, they can make better videos, right?
Speaker 9:  Meta's vibes, feed screensaver is the perfect way to put it. It like
Speaker 9:  it, it is just like glazed over generic nonsense. There
Speaker 9:  is nothing to see there. Sora, it, it feels
Speaker 9:  like memes, right? Like you can write a joke and the video
Speaker 9:  can land the joke. And I'm not gonna say that
Speaker 9:  they're all amazing, but the app is like very much intentionally
Speaker 9:  set up to kind of get to the joke and make it land. One thing that they did
Speaker 9:  that I think is very clever is when you go to a video,
Speaker 9:  you can swipe up or down to go to the next video, but you can also swipe
Speaker 9:  left or right to see different variants of the same video. 'cause people
Speaker 9:  keep remixing them 'cause it's AI and it's fake and you can turn it into
Speaker 9:  whatever you want. And so that puts this really fascinating riff on
Speaker 9:  the sort of, you know, TikTok remix of everything
Speaker 9:  where, okay, maybe the first person didn't quite get it, but by the 10th
Speaker 9:  iteration maybe somebody has actually landed a joke that's pretty funny here.
Speaker 9:  And so that's the one that gets served to you and the feed ends up feeling
Speaker 9:  pretty lively and you can see a lot of people kind of collaborating around
Speaker 9:  the same idea. So I, I do think there's something a little more social
Speaker 9:  and a little more natural there. And it starts with the fact that they're
Speaker 9:  able to make better, more specific videos that have some intent behind them.
Speaker 9:  And I think it follows through with the fact that they actually put some
Speaker 9:  smart social features in here to feel like there's liveliness and activity
Speaker 9:  to it.
Speaker 8:  One of those features is the fact that when you double tap on a video,
Speaker 8:  the AI like picks an emoji that captures the vibe of the video. So like,
Speaker 8:  you know, if you're like walking by a cornfield talking about something totally
Speaker 8:  different, maybe the emoji that it picks is a farmer. And so that's another
Speaker 8:  aspect of the joke. Like it seems like that part is also kind of in
Speaker 8:  on the joke. But I felt the same way, Jake, it was interesting because
Speaker 8:  yeah, vibes to me was like Facebook
Speaker 8:  slop, you know, I saw like cor keys on Hampstead Heath, I
Speaker 8:  saw like, you know, just random
Speaker 8:  blobs, blobbing is kind of the, the great like explanation
Speaker 8:  of what I saw. But so with Sora, I think, you know, yeah,
Speaker 8:  I think people underestimate how much people just wanna like meme their friends,
Speaker 8:  you know? And that's what it allows you to do. And it's also
Speaker 8:  strangely accurate. I was like terrified when I saw the demo because
Speaker 8:  it, I couldn't tell what was real, especially when it was
Speaker 8:  not like a fantastical setting. You know, if it's someone just talking in
Speaker 8:  front of a white wall or flipping a light switch, I couldn't tell
Speaker 8:  even if I had met someone in real life, you know? So I think that was what
Speaker 8:  was both scary and compelling. It's like, you know,
Speaker 8:  a potential misinformation nightmare, but also people can make
Speaker 8:  realistic funny videos of their friends and their pets. So that's something
Speaker 8:  that I've seen a lot of people do this week and people have been been like
Speaker 8:  begging me for SOA codes just so they can try it out because of that.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, the, the thing that I have thought was really interesting, and I think
Speaker 7:  Sam Altman mentioned this in the, they like released their first update to
Speaker 7:  SOA with a bunch of sort of new policy things, but one of the things he said
Speaker 7:  was that an unexpected use case has been people using the app to make
Speaker 7:  something and then share it with small groups of people outside the app.
Speaker 7:  That it is like, and this has certainly been the case for me, like SOA videos
Speaker 7:  are suddenly everywhere in my group chats, which I find like mostly sort
Speaker 7:  of cringey. And it's like if, if you're the person who is just like constantly
Speaker 7:  making AI videos you think are funny and sending to me your friends, like
Speaker 7:  please reconsider some of those decisions is, is what I would say.
Speaker 7:  But they're everywhere and this is like, this is clearly like a behavior
Speaker 7:  people are, are engaging in. And so I think even if they
Speaker 7:  haven't nailed something in the sort of social network
Speaker 7:  experience of it, there is something about this creation tool
Speaker 7:  that works. And I think, and and to the, to the TikTok point, like TikTok
Speaker 7:  is as much a creation app as a consumption app. And so it's like the idea
Speaker 7:  is we wanna make it easy for you to make something. And I think, like Jake,
Speaker 7:  to your point, this is the easiest app ever to make something.
Speaker 7:  And that's powerful, especially when that something involves you, which just
Speaker 7:  inherently means something to people. Like everything is more fun
Speaker 7:  when it involves you as the user and that
Speaker 7:  that push in that direction just seems like it's working.
Speaker 9:  I completely agree and I think that the part of this is that they are, you
Speaker 9:  know, maybe trying to turn the notch past
Speaker 9:  AI slop, right? The problem with most of these AI generators is you
Speaker 9:  actually just don't have that nuanced control over what they're creating.
Speaker 9:  And here you're, you're able to get a little bit closer, you're able to
Speaker 9:  put text and it does the text that you want, you're able to put dialogue
Speaker 9:  and it does the dialogue that you want. And I have not tested
Speaker 9:  extensively. I'm not saying it's perfect, but I think there are clearly
Speaker 9:  people who are writing jokes and landing those jokes here. Will this
Speaker 9:  maintain itself as an entertaining thing for more than the five minutes I
Speaker 9:  spent on it? I I, I think there's a big open question there,
Speaker 9:  but it does feel like you're getting more intentional content. It is stuff
Speaker 9:  that people are actually creating and it kind of just has the liveliness
Speaker 9:  of a weird Twitter feed, which is very different than,
Speaker 9:  you know, the Facebook AI slot feed, which still just looks like, I don't
Speaker 9:  know what this is, you couldn't make anything better than like, this is,
Speaker 9:  this is nonsense just glistening puppies.
Speaker 8:  And it does remind me of TikTok in a way because
Speaker 8:  on TikTok, a lot of people are just lurkers and they're like, you know,
Speaker 8:  sending tiktoks to their friends, they're talking about tiktoks they saw
Speaker 8:  in the group chat, but they're not actually making anything. And some people
Speaker 8:  do make things and everyone knows their face. So this is kind of a similar
Speaker 8:  vibe in that I've seen a bunch of open AI employees, for example,
Speaker 8:  as you would expect, make a ton of videos. And then I've seen a lot of other
Speaker 8:  people I know personally in regular life just consume them and send them
Speaker 8:  to each other. Or like you said, Jake make them and then
Speaker 8:  send them to just the group chat, but never post them publicly. And that's
Speaker 8:  something Sam said on dev day. He said he didn't expect,
Speaker 8:  you know, all the group chat fodder. And he also didn't expect that people
Speaker 8:  would want maybe a in-between of their cameo being public.
Speaker 8:  You know, he thought it was either they would be all in or all out, but he
Speaker 8:  didn't expect, he said that some people would wanna have their cameo public,
Speaker 8:  but only for certain scenarios and not being allowed to say certain things
Speaker 8:  or appear in certain videos or maybe only be visible to some people. So
Speaker 8:  I think he didn't, or he said he didn't expect the, you know,
Speaker 8:  continuum that people of comfort that people might feel with their own face
Speaker 8:  being used in a, in an AI slot machine or just an AI
Speaker 8:  generated TikTok social media app.
Speaker 7:  Okay. I'm glad you brought this up because you, you, you were
Speaker 7:  there and you, you wrote a really good story about sort of OpenAI being
Speaker 7:  surprised by what has happened with SOA A, that it was as popular as
Speaker 7:  it was. The, the number we saw was 627,000
Speaker 7:  downloads of the app in the first week, which is a a lot, and b not
Speaker 7:  that many. Like, just in the scheme of things, like that's a lot and
Speaker 7:  also not a lot at the same time, so we should just do what that number, what
Speaker 7:  we will, but he kind of went through over and over and was like,
Speaker 7:  yeah, we had no idea this many people would use it and have feelings about
Speaker 7:  what AI is doing. And I'm just like, buddy, like, either you're lying
Speaker 7:  or you're not paying attention. And I, I don't know which one of those things
Speaker 7:  it is. And to me, this thing OpenAI
Speaker 7:  continues to be happy doing, which is just releasing things and
Speaker 7:  then figuring it out later is dangerous. And, and
Speaker 7:  this is like we, we've been through this with, with Facebook for so many
Speaker 7:  years, right? Where it was like, okay, Facebook kept doing things
Speaker 7:  without thinking about the like second and third and fourth order effects
Speaker 7:  of those things. And I was like, you, you do that long enough and all of
Speaker 7:  a sudden, like really, truly horrible things are happening around the world
Speaker 7:  enabled by your technology and that you didn't think about them or
Speaker 7:  expect them does not absolve you of responsibility for those
Speaker 7:  things. But OpenAI and Sam Altman in particular
Speaker 7:  has been very happy to just be like, here's the thing, we don't know how
Speaker 7:  you're gonna use it so we we will all figure it out together. And he even
Speaker 7:  said, I pulled this quote from your story. He says, we've gotta have this
Speaker 7:  sort of technological and societal co-evolution. I believe that works. And
Speaker 7:  I actually don't know anything else that works. There are clearly going to
Speaker 7:  be challenges for society contending with this quality and what will get
Speaker 7:  much better with the video generation, but the only way that we know of to
Speaker 7:  help mitigate it is to get the world to experience it and figure out how
Speaker 7:  that's going to go. That sucks. And I don't like that at all.
Speaker 7:  And for Sam Altman to be like, oh, people might have complicated feelings
Speaker 7:  about how their video is being used. I don't believe him for a second, but
Speaker 7:  I, I like, I just, I think they can't, they are happy to not have
Speaker 7:  guardrails and put them in later when companies with
Speaker 7:  copyright lawyers demand it. And short of that, I think this company
Speaker 7:  is just very happy to just unleash everything upon the world and see what
Speaker 7:  happens. And that worries me a lot. I don't know, Hayden, am I being too
Speaker 7:  mean to Sam Altman here?
Speaker 8:  No, to me, yes. It's a really controversial
Speaker 8:  thing to just say, oh, we're gonna roll out this technology, just see how
Speaker 8:  people use it, and then that's how the world's gonna contend with it. We've
Speaker 8:  gotta put it out there and then just see how it works and go from there.
Speaker 8:  To me that's a move fast and break things approach, which is
Speaker 8:  obviously so controversial and we've all seen how that plays
Speaker 8:  out.
Speaker 7:  You, you end up breaking things, like to be clear, that's, that's you, you've
Speaker 7:  said the quiet part loud, which is that it, you will break things
Speaker 8:  And it's one of those things that, like we've seen this happen over and
Speaker 8:  over again where it's disproportionately affecting minorities, vulnerable
Speaker 8:  populations. We've seen like facial recognition go wrong when it's just
Speaker 8:  rolled out AI generated revenge porn. You know, this has
Speaker 8:  already allegedly already been used to like, you know, generate kind of
Speaker 8:  threatening stalker-ish videos of someone. So it's interesting because,
Speaker 8:  you know, the few people in power and AI
Speaker 8:  don't always, I think, think about the downstream use cases of how this could
Speaker 8:  be used for the people that are most vulnerable here. However,
Speaker 8:  I know what Sam Altman would say to this, which is that they didn't do a
Speaker 8:  move fast and break things approach because they
Speaker 8:  introduced this with more safeguards than people wanted. He
Speaker 8:  said that everything he's hearing from critics is that it's way
Speaker 8:  too restrictive, that it's censorship, that, you know,
Speaker 8:  it's not even a fun app because there's so many controls and safeguards on
Speaker 8:  it. So that's kind of the weird continuum here. Does
Speaker 7:  That track at all with what you're hearing in the world? 'cause that does
Speaker 7:  not track at all with what I'm hearing in the world. What I'm hearing in
Speaker 7:  the world is I can make SpongeBob do meth. Like that's cool.
Speaker 8:  Yeah, and also the fact that, you know, they started out with this
Speaker 8:  opt out copyright policy and then they changed it to opt in
Speaker 8:  after stakeholders protested. Now for me, I've only seen
Speaker 8:  power users complain about the restrictions and the safeguards. I
Speaker 8:  haven't seen any like just kind of general consumers complain
Speaker 8:  about it. That's just me. Anecdotally, maybe everyone's
Speaker 8:  really up in arms about the fact that they can't, you know, generate certain
Speaker 8:  things because of the safeguards. But for me, you know, anecdotally people
Speaker 8:  have either been happy that they can make videos of their friends and their
Speaker 8:  dog or they just don't use it at all. I've seen
Speaker 8:  on Twitter, of course, a lot of power users complain about how restrictive
Speaker 8:  the safeguards are, but to me they're not that restrictive. So
Speaker 9:  The optout copyright id, what are you talking about?
Speaker 9:  You can't just like grab cash from a register and be like, whoa,
Speaker 9:  whoa, whoa. Sorry guys. It's opt out for me. Like I, if
Speaker 9:  you needed to tell me in advance, if you didn't want me to steal that, like
Speaker 9:  that's not how it works. These companies have a very
Speaker 9:  expensive lawyers like, you know, you know that Disney
Speaker 9:  doesn't want you generating these things. Like it, you can't
Speaker 9:  just tell them, oh, you you, we didn't know, you didn't tell us that.
Speaker 9:  Like, that's just the law. It's just there. It, it's not a
Speaker 9:  conversation. I, so yeah, I, I don't know.
Speaker 9:  It is very funny that Sam Altman is out there being like, we, we didn't
Speaker 9:  expect any of this, this, who could have known how people would use this?
Speaker 9:  And it's like everyone Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Like have have one meeting. Have one meeting. Do
Speaker 9:  You know why they, they made it opt out because they knew
Speaker 9:  it would be more entertaining that way because they wanted to see how long
Speaker 9:  they could go before they got into trouble. And the answer is like 30
Speaker 9:  minutes. But like, obviously, because that is the first thing you're gonna
Speaker 9:  try to do because it's a lot more fun. You can generate weird things with
Speaker 9:  Pikachu. But yeah, I
Speaker 9:  it is true. He, he is correct. The way that we contend with this as a
Speaker 9:  society is that we unleash it into society and reckon with the
Speaker 9:  whatever horrible outcome there is. I, but
Speaker 9:  yeah, that's not like very comforting to hear that said aloud by
Speaker 9:  the guy who is unleashing it into society. It
Speaker 7:  Also doesn't have to be the idea that like, society
Speaker 7:  is the Guinea pig for new technology is like not how it has to
Speaker 7:  be. It's it, it is. If what you need is infinite amount of money
Speaker 7:  to keep doing what you're doing, but it doesn't have to be like that. And
Speaker 7:  I like the idea that there is no other way to roll out interesting new
Speaker 7:  technology other than to just like drop it on the world and watch and see
Speaker 7:  what happens is not great.
Speaker 8:  I agree. And another thing that I thought was interesting was like, what
Speaker 8:  in this app was like maybe overly safeguarded would compared to
Speaker 8:  what wasn't? So, you know, I saw Brick and Morty videos. I was
Speaker 8:  able to generate like a ton of stuff that I shouldn't have been able to.
Speaker 8:  But then when I tried to make a video of myself running through a field,
Speaker 8:  it was like, woo, too racy. Like that could be too sensual. I changed
Speaker 8:  the word. Yeah. I changed the word to frolicking instead of running. It
Speaker 8:  was fine. So like, that's
Speaker 7:  Been sexy about a frolic. That's that's what I always say.
Speaker 8:  That's what I thought was hilarious. It's like, it was overly, maybe this
Speaker 8:  is what some people were complaining about. It was overly safeguarded on
Speaker 8:  some things and then the dial was turned way down on the,
Speaker 8:  some of the stuff that it should have been against. So yeah, I, I
Speaker 8:  don't know. I mean, like, why are we able to see, you know, SpongeBob cooking
Speaker 8:  meth, but not me running through a field? I don't know.
Speaker 7:  That is very funny. I like that very much. So, Hayden, you need to go here
Speaker 7:  in a couple minutes, but I do wanna talk about how you guys are thinking
Speaker 7:  about the staying power of this thing. 'cause Jake, you mentioned it too.
Speaker 7:  And what we've seen with a bunch of these tools, particularly with the image
Speaker 7:  and video generators in the past, is they have this like huge
Speaker 7:  flash in the pan because everybody's like, oh my God, look at this amazing
Speaker 7:  thing. Look what I can do. I can make SpongeBob do meth. And then they all
Speaker 7:  kind of die, right? Like we, we had the, everybody made the studio Gibble
Speaker 7:  versions of themselves and then kind of stopped using those tools at the
Speaker 7:  same level. Hayden, you first, do you think Sora has a
Speaker 7:  different kind of staying power, or is this just like the next
Speaker 7:  meme along the path of like, flash in the pan memes?
Speaker 8:  I mean, it's hard for me to say because there
Speaker 8:  have been things I've been wrong about in the past, but that's not true.
Speaker 8:  I think this is gonna be one of those things that some people really, really
Speaker 8:  love and use all the time. But I don't think it's going to,
Speaker 8:  you know, replace TikTok or be,
Speaker 8:  you know, a mainstay for most people. I think it'll have
Speaker 8:  like a cult following and pe some people will use it every once in a while
Speaker 8:  and a lot of people will use it a lot. But I don't think it's going to
Speaker 8:  have the same staying power as say, TikTok or
Speaker 8:  any of the other social media apps that people lose time on for hours and
Speaker 8:  hours every day. Just because by nature I think it's like
Speaker 8:  full of memes, full of jokes. It's not something that
Speaker 8:  you are gonna spend a ton of hours on if you're just the average person.
Speaker 8:  One example is, I saw some research the other day that's showed that the
Speaker 8:  more you use TikTok, the more it funnels you into like, longer
Speaker 8:  form content, story times, things that are high drama that you're gonna get
Speaker 8:  invested in. Maybe multi-part stories. You know, I don't, SOA
Speaker 8:  doesn't have anything like that right now, so it's like, you know, you're
Speaker 8:  gonna pop on, you're gonna make a funny video, maybe you're gonna send it
Speaker 8:  to your group chat. I don't see you spending a lot of hours on it. So that's
Speaker 8:  just my take.
Speaker 7:  Jake, what do you think?
Speaker 9:  I think it all comes back to the intent, right? Are you
Speaker 9:  creating something that has purpose and meaning behind it? And right
Speaker 9:  now all this feels very novel and you go on there, you're
Speaker 9:  seeing stuff that you've never seen before. There's lots of funny jokes.
Speaker 9:  At some point I'm going to see my 500th AI
Speaker 9:  Obama and it's going to not be funny and novel anymore. And at
Speaker 9:  that point, I, I don't know why I'm going on this app. So do I think that
Speaker 9:  this kind of medium has a future? Like Yeah, probably.
Speaker 9:  I think if you built this into TikTok and you allow people to create these
Speaker 9:  every once in a while for specific purposes, yeah, absolutely,
Speaker 9:  there's a future there. But they fundamentally have a
Speaker 9:  novelty gap to overcome because on TikTok,
Speaker 9:  there's always gonna be something new and different and real that actually
Speaker 9:  matters. And fundamentally on soa, there's nothing that really
Speaker 9:  matters. And so I I I'm not sure it will be able to
Speaker 9:  sustain itself in that
Speaker 7:  Way. The TikTok example is really fun. 'cause I, I was thinking about this
Speaker 7:  like, is is the success of Sora
Speaker 7:  dependent on the idea that me typing into a prompt,
Speaker 7:  you know, make a video of me doing x, y, z dance challenge
Speaker 7:  as compelling as a video of me doing that dance challenge?
Speaker 7:  And I, I think the, the AI bet is that if it's not, it's very close
Speaker 7:  and much easier. And so that will win. But I don't think
Speaker 7:  I buy that. And I think that that gap of like
Speaker 7:  ultimately the, the me doing the thing is just going to
Speaker 7:  be unbeatable by some AI system of me doing the thing,
Speaker 7:  keeps it from making that final turn that you need to be that kind of
Speaker 7:  mainstream success.
Speaker 8:  It's about whether it's just as compelling, like you said, David, to see
Speaker 8:  someone, a facsimile of someone doing something or
Speaker 8:  seeing a real person doing a real thing in a real way. And
Speaker 8:  I don't know, I think this is comes back to the same question of like AI
Speaker 8:  generated music, AI generated film. Sometimes people
Speaker 8:  just wanna connect with a real person doing a real thing in a real way.
Speaker 8:  And I think that's like, it comes down to human nature. And so, you
Speaker 8:  know, people think this is fun, it's cool, it's like a novelty, but
Speaker 8:  I don't know that it has, yeah, the same staying power as an app
Speaker 8:  full of videos of people doing real things in real ways and real people that
Speaker 8:  you can really meet.
Speaker 9:  long now, nobody even remembers the thunder round, which is a distant, no
Speaker 9:  distant memory at best. I get tweets
Speaker 9:  from one to two people a week telling
Speaker 9:  me how, how appalled they are at what has
Speaker 9:  happened here. I will say more people miss the sound effects than I expected.
Speaker 9:  We have a lot of sound effects fans in the Vergecast audience, and I want
Speaker 9:  you to know I hear you and I love you. I don't wanna upset anyone here.
Speaker 9:  I never really liked the sound effects. I thought we could have gotten some
Speaker 9:  cooler thunder sounds. They they were, they were a little weak for my
Speaker 9:  taste, but all right, if can, maybe that's why the thunder round didn't make
Speaker 9:  it. If you can figure out how to like 10 x this idea and we, we have like
Speaker 9:  video effects and set, like if you can terrify me with the sound of this
Speaker 9:  thunder, we can talk about it. I want some cool like electronica
Speaker 9:  thunder, like, like that's what I want. Okay.
Speaker 9:  For the, the revival or if we can somehow get the budget to license
Speaker 9:  thunderstruck by AC CDC Yes. Then we can talk about it. Okay.
Speaker 9:  Deal. Okay. But for now, it is the lightning round. The lightning since it's
Speaker 9:  just you and me. Hayden had to go, like we said, we picked three things
Speaker 9:  each and we're just gonna blast through them. Why don't you go first?
Speaker 9:  What's your first one? Alright, my first one, so Alex Cooper of the
Speaker 9:  podcast call her daddy announced this week that she's
Speaker 9:  has, it's like an ad agency thing. She's has some big
Speaker 9:  inaugural deal with Google to make pixel ads.
Speaker 9:  This starts with an initial ad, which as far as I can tell only appeared
Speaker 9:  on Instagram. Maybe it was on TikTok. I don't know. It's like a, it's a,
Speaker 9:  a vertical video that is, I don't know,
Speaker 9:  kind of nonsensical. It has some pixels in it. This does not matter. This
Speaker 9:  is another thing I wanna talk about. Really what I wanna talk about is that,
Speaker 9:  so Alex Cooper was at the pixel announcement event over the
Speaker 9:  summer. She like did a weird little demo in that weird Jimmy Fallon hosted
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Event. It was on her Instagram. And in the time since
Speaker 9:  then, she's posted a handful of photos where, you know, the
Speaker 9:  very first photo on the grid is her with a pixel.
Speaker 9:  And you can see that pixel real clear. And I have
Speaker 9:  traditionally been very skeptical of the like,
Speaker 9:  celebrity endorsement deals, but I,
Speaker 9:  I'm starting to come around to the idea that perhaps these
Speaker 9:  actually matter quite a bit. And I think that a few years of
Speaker 9:  Alex Cooper posting Instagram photos with a Pixel would
Speaker 9:  probably do more for Android and the Pixel brand than if the Pixel
Speaker 9:  12 could perform brain surgery. Like, I, I do not think there
Speaker 9:  is a feature that is going to convince people to move over from
Speaker 9:  the iPhone. I think that it is a cultural battle at this
Speaker 9:  point between iPhones and not iPhones, and
Speaker 9:  you actually need that permission slip. And I, it's
Speaker 9:  silly, I don't know how much people notice, but I do think
Speaker 9:  that Google paying Alex Cooper to post photos with the pixel
Speaker 9:  is, is maybe the best thing they have done for the Pixel.
Speaker 7:  Okay, I completely agree with this. This is not where I thought you were
Speaker 7:  gonna go with this, which like this whole thing that
Speaker 7:  Alex Cooper and Google sort of co announced where they're like, they're gonna
Speaker 7:  make a bunch of content with these devices and they're they's they're gonna
Speaker 7:  use it in their production process. All of that is always
Speaker 7:  nonsense. Like, I don't, I don't know how be clear about that. All of that
Speaker 7:  is always nonsense. And the, the only thing I think when
Speaker 7:  I see those announcements is like, I can't wait for her to get caught
Speaker 7:  in the same way that like, gal Gado got caught years ago doing like posting,
Speaker 7:  I think it was Huawei sponsored content with an iPhone like via Twitter
Speaker 7:  for iPhone and like Marque Brownley made a, made a habit out of calling these
Speaker 7:  people out. And like, I loved all of that stuff. I th I think you're
Speaker 7:  absolutely right that Google should have done this and is going to get way
Speaker 7:  more than it paid for with whatever it is paying Alex Cooper, Alex Cooper
Speaker 7:  is like wildly famous and beloved and important,
Speaker 7:  like, like hugely culturally relevant in a way that
Speaker 7:  I think even like the, the professional athletes that Google
Speaker 7:  has paid before to do this are not like Alex Cooper carries a different
Speaker 7:  kind of weight specifically with women than than anybody else I've ever seen
Speaker 7:  holding a pixel before. And I'm, I'm like looking at her Instagram grid now,
Speaker 7:  and you're right, the Pixel is everywhere in a way that is like
Speaker 7:  sort of obvious and gross, but also is going to work. Like, I I think
Speaker 7:  you're right and it, it's, it's sort of
Speaker 7:  nice to see Google actually try and do this because Google,
Speaker 7:  we're, we're gonna talk a bunch about this on Tuesday with V and Allison
Speaker 7:  who reviewed all of Google's stuff. But like Google's gadgets are
Speaker 7:  very good. And the reason for years now that more people have not bought
Speaker 7:  Google's gadgets is that Google doesn't market
Speaker 7:  well, Google seems unable to successfully
Speaker 7:  spend and do what it takes to market. Its very good products.
Speaker 7:  And so the fact that it's actually leading into this stuff, I find like very
Speaker 7:  encouraging as somebody who wants to see the phone wars be more interesting.
Speaker 9:  It's really interesting because I do think to your point that
Speaker 9:  there's a difference between Alex Cooper and a lot of the sports figures
Speaker 9:  who usually get these deals. There's, there's much more of a parasocial relationship
Speaker 9:  there because she is this enormous podcaster.
Speaker 9:  I'm not sure who the right people are to keep expanding this idea,
Speaker 9:  but I do think Right, they're great phones, but
Speaker 9:  unless you are, I think, you know, a Vergecast listener, somebody who really
Speaker 9:  cares about getting the best phone and who's gonna go
Speaker 9:  wherever the winds are blowing and shift platforms as necessary,
Speaker 9:  you're probably locked in. You made your decision a while ago, you're either
Speaker 9:  on the team iPhone or on team Android and you're just gonna
Speaker 9:  stick with that. And what they have to fight here
Speaker 9:  is this cultural battle of, oh, actually there is something good here, right?
Speaker 9:  The the Pixel is a fantastic phone. It is, it is it
Speaker 9:  substantially better than an iPhone? Absolutely not, right? Yeah. And
Speaker 9:  if you're looking at the two side by side and one you're used to and you
Speaker 9:  know, is solid and reliable, what's gonna make you take that jump and that
Speaker 9:  gamble thi this feels like the kind of thing that can start to change that.
Speaker 9:  Totally. And it is very silly to be like, I,
Speaker 9:  I'm not saying that I am excited that, you know, Google
Speaker 9:  is spending money on things that are not developing a better product.
Speaker 9:  However, this feels like the thing that actually is going to matter in the
Speaker 9:  long run.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. If you actually wanna win, this is what you have to do. Yeah. And I
Speaker 7:  think like the, the part of me that always wondered when Google is going
Speaker 7:  to decide to stop caring about the pixel is the part of me that wonders
Speaker 7:  why Google doesn't seem to be interested in winning. And this is like, okay,
Speaker 7:  Google might actually be interested in winning and I think that's cool.
Speaker 7:  I agree. I also think the idea that they are going to use this in their
Speaker 7:  production process is nonsense and everyone should remember that
Speaker 9:  It's, that's just going to make production 5 million times more
Speaker 9:  difficult. Do not do that.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, no. Like,
Speaker 9:  Like, dear
Speaker 7:  Alex, like, don't do that
Speaker 9:  Using pixel raw photos and bringing them into light. Like don't No.
Speaker 9:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Don't bother. No. All right. For my first one, I just wanna tell you about
Speaker 7:  a thing that made my life better this
Speaker 9:  Week. Oh my God. Yeah. Tell me. Last week
Speaker 7:  We talked about the Spotify setting that will keep my son's
Speaker 7:  music taste from ruining my life this week. A small
Speaker 7:  change in iOS 26 that I think Mac Rumors found first.
Speaker 7:  That is called Keep Audio with headphones. And this does one very specific
Speaker 7:  thing, which is if you are listening to something on your headphones and
Speaker 7:  then you get into a car and automatically connect to CarPlay
Speaker 7:  or you turn on a speaker that you know can automatically connects via
Speaker 7:  Bluetooth, it will not any longer immediately
Speaker 7:  pipe the audio to that thing. It will keep it in your headphones.
Speaker 7:  This is the greatest thing that has ever happened to me.
Speaker 9:  Okay. I saw a lot of people who are thrilled about this.
Speaker 9:  And I have a question. Are you walking into your car listening to
Speaker 9:  music on AirPods? No. And you plan to keep the AirPods in the entire
Speaker 9:  ride?
Speaker 7:  No, let me, let me tell you the mainstream use case and the non-mainstream
Speaker 7:  use case, okay. The mainstream use case is I am on a phone call and I get
Speaker 7:  into the car. Okay. What happens now when I'm on a phone call and I get into
Speaker 7:  car is 15 seconds if we can't hear each other while the audio transfers.
Speaker 9:  Oh yeah. That's, that's, that
Speaker 7:  Just sucks. And
Speaker 9:  So a phone call should never come out of your, your, your car speaker. Correct.
Speaker 7:  And I think the like leave, leave one AirPod in while you drive
Speaker 7:  for a minute is like, listen, I'm not a lawyer.
Speaker 7:  I can't tell you to do that. I just know that lots of people do that. And
Speaker 7:  that is having that not just do the awkward, where is the audio coming from?
Speaker 7:  Dance is very good. My current reason for being excited about this
Speaker 7:  is that I have small children who are often asleep at inconvenient
Speaker 7:  times as we're getting in and out of the car. Oh yeah. Okay. And the idea
Speaker 7:  of whatever I am doing or listening to
Speaker 7:  not suddenly blasting through the car speakers or the speaker speakers, just
Speaker 7:  because I turn them on is wonderful. It's dumb that this is a setting,
Speaker 7:  this is evidence that what Apple can't do is actually figure out
Speaker 7:  proactively where your audio should go. Like Apple has the handoff thing
Speaker 7:  that always sucks and everybody hates it. So I just, I want
Speaker 7:  this to exist, which is great, but I also want the one that is like,
Speaker 7:  never ever, ever, ever, ever send my audio to my laptop
Speaker 7:  just because I opened my laptop. Like it's so sim like if
Speaker 7:  I'm, if I'm on the phone, keep it on the phone. Don't be like, do you wanna
Speaker 7:  transfer this call here to No. Like, it's, it's, this is not hard, but
Speaker 7:  I'm fine. It's a setting that you can turn on and everybody should, and I'm
Speaker 7:  glad it exists.
Speaker 9:  I I'm so happy for everybody who gets in and of cars and I
Speaker 9:  was also listening to AirPods a lot, but you are right. Handoff is both the
Speaker 9:  most amazing feature and just a tangle of popups sometimes. Yes.
Speaker 9:  And you're just like, it feels like you're dodging and weaving trying to
Speaker 9:  be like, no, do not transfer that there do not do that.
Speaker 7:  True. It's great. 'cause it is like, it is the, the description of handoff
Speaker 7:  is the sort of thing that only Apple can do and is a reason to
Speaker 7:  buy a bunch of Apple products and like buy into an ecosystem like this. But
Speaker 7:  it turns out Apple can't do it. It's just, it's it is a
Speaker 7:  very appley idea and a bad execution.
Speaker 9:  They just love handing things off too much. This is the like it's, they got
Speaker 9:  so good at it. They're like, you're over here now. Great. Great. Go, go,
Speaker 9:  go. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  They're like, it's impossible that you would ever be using two devices at
Speaker 7:  once. So we're just gonna shove everything onto whatever screen you are looking
Speaker 7:  at at this second, even though we don't know. Cool.
Speaker 7:  Thanks Apple. Anyway, more settings. Yes, please. All the time.
Speaker 7:  Jake, what's your second one? Okay,
Speaker 9:  My next one is that, do you remember Starry?
Speaker 7:  Yeah. That was like a, like a cool startup internet provider,
Speaker 7:  wasn't
Speaker 9:  It? Yeah. Yeah. I I think it, I think it was from like 2014. This was
Speaker 9:  So the guy behind ero? Yes.
Speaker 9:  I'm, I'm going way too far back. Whoa.
Speaker 7:  This is like deep verge lore. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. The guy by an area which was like the, the broadcast
Speaker 9:  retransmission startup that got shut down by the Supreme Court. Yeah. Then
Speaker 9:  went and launched Starry. Starry was an internet
Speaker 9:  service provider that gave, brought internet to your home using millimeter
Speaker 9:  wave, which would later be used for 5G.
Speaker 9:  That Startup Starry has now been acquired by Verizon,
Speaker 9:  which is is Okay. Just a lot, lot of feelings. A lot of
Speaker 9:  feelings. I, I generally see an acquisition by, you know,
Speaker 9:  Comcast or Verizon or other major ISP and assume. Okay. That's
Speaker 9:  like, it's weird, my initial thought o on seeing this is like, oh, okay,
Speaker 9:  so they're dead. Like you wouldn't buy 'em unless you were just gonna kill
Speaker 9:  me.
Speaker 7:  Right.
Speaker 9:  But Verizon like claims that they actually want to use
Speaker 9:  Star's technology to expand their reach,
Speaker 9:  particularly in cities and dense, dense urban areas. And
Speaker 9:  I, I'm not sure how I feel about it. I, I think it's really interesting
Speaker 9:  to see this technology get used. Starry kind of stalled out pretty
Speaker 9:  hard
Speaker 7:  To be fair. So did 5G like the, this just, this is why
Speaker 7:  this is in, there's a confluence of like the, there's an
Speaker 7:  overlap in these ideas that might sort of make sense
Speaker 7:  even though each individual idea kind of ran its course.
Speaker 9:  Yes. Starry has this incredible idea that runs
Speaker 9:  immediately into these huge problems. So they're like, okay,
Speaker 9:  it's number one really expensive to build out
Speaker 9:  ISP infrastructure and put wires everywhere. Number two, the
Speaker 9:  regulatory environment for that is just, is horrible. You just have to get
Speaker 9:  approvals left and right to run cables in different neighborhoods.
Speaker 9:  It's terrible. It takes forever. It's really, really expensive. They're like,
Speaker 9:  we're gonna skip all that. We're just gonna do it wireless and we can get
Speaker 9:  really fast speed because of millimeter wave. The thing about millimeter
Speaker 9:  wave is if there is, I don't know, rain or like a leaf
Speaker 9:  in the way it's blocked, it's
Speaker 7:  Done. Or you like step backwards. Yeah. Yeah. If you're here, it works.
Speaker 7:  If you're here it all falls apart.
Speaker 9:  It, it is like super precise line of sight. And so you need to have this
Speaker 9:  very clear, you know, through line from the
Speaker 9:  transmitter to the receiver, which is sticking out your window. It's tricky.
Speaker 9:  And, you know, maybe Verizon can scale that. It would be really
Speaker 9:  interesting. I, I think the other reason this is interesting to me is
Speaker 9:  as somebody who lives in a city, I have one choice of internet
Speaker 9:  provider. Mm. Or at least one choice of wired internet provider. And I do
Speaker 9:  think it's interesting, these 5G home internet things have become bigger
Speaker 9:  and bigger and I do not trust them at all. And
Speaker 9:  maybe this is just like, this is like a little bit of a pipe dream. I'm being
Speaker 9:  like really hopeful, but starry feels like it's this middle ground where
Speaker 9:  it's like it's 5G internet, but maybe it's actually fast and reliable.
Speaker 9:  Maybe, I don't know. Like I don't trust T-Mobile to give me
Speaker 9:  equivalent home internet service to an actual wired
Speaker 9:  connection. Even if the actual wired company is charging me just
Speaker 9:  crazy amounts of money because they know they're my only option.
Speaker 7:  Well this is the whole thing about 5G now, right? Is I think we, and like
Speaker 7:  Verizon all just also just appointed a new CEO and it's, it's going into,
Speaker 7:  I think it called it the next phase of growth, which is like, there's been
Speaker 7:  this real sort of quiet reckoning of like 5G just
Speaker 7:  didn't do the thing it was supposed to do. Like we've been making fun of
Speaker 7:  it for a long time. I don't think, I don't think it's that surprising, but
Speaker 7:  I think it is now fairly common knowledge that
Speaker 7:  actually wired internet is faster
Speaker 7:  and we're not beating it with 5G. Even even in the best case scenario,
Speaker 7:  we're not beating it with 5G and we're starting to see like a, a pull back
Speaker 7:  towards yeah, we're gonna go lay cable trenches and that's actually how we
Speaker 7:  get fast internet to people. And so the idea that we're gonna
Speaker 7:  like a, keep pushing on this because if you're Verizon, you kind of have
Speaker 7:  to, but B, try to figure out
Speaker 7:  what to do to move past this is just really interesting and
Speaker 7:  like, give it a minute and everybody's gonna start yelling about six G But
Speaker 7:  like even Verizon is out here being like, we are reinvesting in
Speaker 7:  digging trenches to get fiber internet to people because that's
Speaker 7:  what they want and that's what actually works.
Speaker 9:  I don't know. You say that David, but I, I can't think of a single surgery
Speaker 9:  that hasn't been performed over 5G.
Speaker 7:  That's true. I'm having surgery right now. My doctor's thousands miles away.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah. It's great. Here's what I wonder is
Speaker 7:  if Verizon is gonna use the Starry brand, 'cause
Speaker 7:  I think I'm, Verizon to me is fascinating. So I get visible
Speaker 7:  commercials all the time. Like Hulu in particular thinks that I
Speaker 7:  speak fluent Spanish and want visible wireless. Those are two things that
Speaker 7:  Hulu believes about me for reasons that I don't understand. So half of my
Speaker 7:  ads are in Spanish and the other half are for visible wireless. And there's
Speaker 7:  this very clear thing where it's like everybody understands that Verizon
Speaker 7:  has the best network that is just like taken for granted that Verizon has
Speaker 7:  the best coverage in the United States, but also everybody hates
Speaker 7:  Verizon and doesn't wanna deal with Verizon. Yes. So the shtick of like,
Speaker 7:  we have Verizon's network, but we're not, Verizon is actually like a
Speaker 7:  very compelling marketing case that a lot of these companies are making.
Speaker 7:  So I wonder if STARI is gonna start to be able to just do exactly the same
Speaker 7:  thing. Be like, we are Verizon, but we're not Verizon. Do you want our internet?
Speaker 7:  Okay.
Speaker 9:  Can I tell you something that I found adorable in this announcement?
Speaker 9:  Sure. They gave a line to this in their press release. Oh really? They said
Speaker 9:  Starry has a net promoter score that is nearly double the industry average.
Speaker 7:  There you go.
Speaker 9:  I realize that is like jargon and nonsense. But these companies care
Speaker 9:  so deeply about net promoter score.
Speaker 7:  All it means is people have good feelings about starry and bad feelings about
Speaker 7:  Verizon. Yes. It's like right. Fundamentally
Speaker 9:  What it's, and this is what they said in their press release, they're sayings
Speaker 9:  so funny. They're saying, by the way, people like Starry twice as much as
Speaker 9:  us and everybody else,
Speaker 7:  That's
Speaker 9:  A meaningful Yeah. There's something there.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Starry is also a good name.
Speaker 9:  Starry is a good name. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  That's that's very interesting. Like I was actually just looking this up.
Speaker 7:  So I have, I have Ting, which for t for my internet. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Which is like Blisteringly fast. And I switched away from Comcast the minute
Speaker 7:  they laid fiber outside of my house. And true story,
Speaker 7:  when we were house hunting, one of the things I looked for was to see if
Speaker 7:  they would still have Ting. And for the life of me, I can't remember, it's,
Speaker 7:  it's one of the carriers that I hate that owns Ting, but I can't remember
Speaker 7:  which one. And I'm like, every time I think about that, I'm like, oh, that's
Speaker 7:  why you do it. Nailed it.
Speaker 9:  Because
Speaker 7:  I don't remember which company I hate owns this.
Speaker 9:  I've always assumed that's the reason Xfinity exists, but Xfinity is
Speaker 9:  also an insane name and just
Speaker 7:  Xfinity is also bad. I think they've, they've now tarnished that reputation
Speaker 7:  so successfully.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, that makes sense. They,
Speaker 7:  They just have to run from, but it is still, it's better than Comcast. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And they would love you to not think it's Comcast, by the way. I guess we
Speaker 7:  should disclose Comcast through a music universal as
Speaker 7:  a, an investor in Vox Media or a parent company. They love us as you
Speaker 7:  can tell.
Speaker 7:  My second one is about Intel, the, the
Speaker 7:  beleaguered chip maker that everyone from
Speaker 7:  Nvidia to the US government is trying desperately to prop up.
Speaker 7:  We just got our first look at Panther Lake, which is Intel's next
Speaker 7:  set of chips. They're coming out end of this year, early next year. And it's
Speaker 7:  basically a three-tiered set of functionally
Speaker 7:  laptop chips. But this is like, I don't honestly care all
Speaker 7:  that much about like generational chip news. This one
Speaker 7:  matters and I think we should pay attention to it in a pretty big way
Speaker 7:  because this is the one that Intel has been promising for a long time
Speaker 7:  as it's gone through this huge change into being both a, a maker
Speaker 7:  of its own chips and a foundry to make other people's chips. This is like,
Speaker 7:  this is like the one the company has been saying is going to be
Speaker 7:  the one where we've been able to put all of our resources together, do all
Speaker 7:  the right things, get all the right pieces together and get back on the right
Speaker 7:  track. Like Panther Lake is supposed to be the one that is proof that that
Speaker 7:  works. And it, it's supposed to work from like these
Speaker 7:  sort of Qualcomm competing thin and light laptops all the way up to like
Speaker 7:  the more powerful GPU running intel
Speaker 7:  inside kinds of laptops.
Speaker 7:  I would say the correct approach to this is to be deeply skeptical of the
Speaker 7:  fact that any of this could work because Intel has made arguments like this
Speaker 7:  for every generation of chips, but this one does still feel
Speaker 7:  important, right. We have the, the competitors
Speaker 7:  particularly like a MD and Apple and even Qualcomm starting
Speaker 7:  to catch up. And in some cases, like runaway from Intel in the chip market,
Speaker 7:  Intel is a hugely important a American company if you believe in the sort
Speaker 7:  of global chip wars, like what this does matters
Speaker 7:  in sort of big macroeconomic ways, even if you never
Speaker 7:  end up buying a laptop with Panther Lake inside. And I just, I think it's,
Speaker 7:  it's gonna be a fascinating one to see what it does.
Speaker 9:  It's funny as you were saying that I was like, wait, I I would swear
Speaker 9:  they have said this before and Oh yeah. And it's like, this has been going
Speaker 9:  on for a while now. But you're right. You know, I
Speaker 9:  I think particularly as, you know, as Qualcomm was emerging and I think
Speaker 9:  as his ships were getting better and better as Apple started making their
Speaker 9:  own ships and, you know, blowing people outta the water, I, there
Speaker 9:  there was an element to which it was exciting. It was like, this is great.
Speaker 9:  We're, we're starting to see more competition. You know, things have been
Speaker 9:  very, you know, slow and steady with Intel for a really long time and it's
Speaker 9:  good to see some competition. I don't think we necessarily wanted to
Speaker 9:  see Intel fall apart and just disappear. And
Speaker 9:  this is like really starting to be the threat there. Yeah. Everyone else
Speaker 9:  is just so far ahead of them and just like has their business together
Speaker 9:  in a much more functional way. And
Speaker 9:  it, it is not clear to me that any one line of chips is really going to be
Speaker 9:  the thing that saves them at this point. At this point it seems like they
Speaker 9:  need a pretty substantial, like, evolution of their business. They need to
Speaker 9:  prop up this foundry business that they're trying to make happen. It seems
Speaker 9:  like the pieces are starting to fall into place, perhaps thanks to
Speaker 9:  the cajoling of the US government,
Speaker 9:  but they still have to make chips that matter. Yes. They still make chips
Speaker 9:  that matter and at this point we will see, I I'm not convinced that
Speaker 9:  any one line is gonna be the one that gets them there. No, but it, it is
Speaker 9:  true. Like I I think we are actually at a point where it
Speaker 9:  is, is we have to ask like, okay, how many more chips are they making?
Speaker 9:  Right? Like it, are they going to be able to get to the next one? It feels
Speaker 9:  like they have stabilized, it feels like they are getting there and this
Speaker 9:  is maybe the line that they need to, you know,
Speaker 9:  keep going.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. I think the, the thing to look at for this one is
Speaker 7:  Intel has this new thing called 18 a, which is just a new
Speaker 7:  process for making chips essentially. And this is like Pat Gelsinger
Speaker 7:  years ago, the now former CEO of Intel who didn't even like
Speaker 7:  get to stay in the job long enough to see the idea out.
Speaker 7:  That's how bad things have been at Intel. This was the, the thing that we're
Speaker 7:  betting was like, this is sort of a basket of changes in both what the chips
Speaker 7:  are and in how Intel makes them. That is supposed to prove to like the
Speaker 7:  world that Intel can do advanced stuff, right? This is
Speaker 7:  like, this is how they catch up to TSMC and this is how they prove that they
Speaker 7:  can do the kind of work at the kind of like bleeding edge of this
Speaker 7:  that is possible. So it's even like, even again, if you don't ever
Speaker 7:  wanna buy an Intel powered device, which given the last several
Speaker 7:  years is a pretty practical and reasonable decision,
Speaker 7:  this is still a big deal because even if you just want Intel to make chips
Speaker 7:  for other companies that are smarter about it, it still matters whether or
Speaker 7:  not this works.
Speaker 7:  I've, I've read enough about 18 a to know, I don't understand
Speaker 7:  anything about how chips get made, except that it's very impressive and they're
Speaker 7:  very small. But this is, this is one to keep an eye on and I think we're
Speaker 7:  gonna, like I generally roll my eyes at like tables full of benchmark
Speaker 7:  tests. This is one where I will be eagerly awaiting benchmark tests.
Speaker 7:  All right, let's your third one. Okay,
Speaker 9:  This is more small Apple features, but I think this is pretty interesting.
Speaker 9:  So Apple came out this week and they announced the changes they're gonna
Speaker 9:  make to the iPhone, to the app store to comply
Speaker 9:  with some new age gating laws. The immediate one is
Speaker 9:  happening Texas, there's gonna be some more in Utah and Louisiana
Speaker 9:  as time goes on. It seems like there's a lot of interest in these laws and
Speaker 9:  so these may not be the start, but what's interesting is Apple is a, is
Speaker 9:  putting these rules in place and they're saying if you're in Texas you
Speaker 9:  have to do it and everywhere else just keep doing what you're doing.
Speaker 9:  And so the, the specific rule here actually doesn't seem that wild
Speaker 9:  to me or unreasonable. It's that if for, for people who are under
Speaker 9:  18 for kids, they have to be part of a family account. They
Speaker 9:  have to get permission to buy and install apps. You know, maybe
Speaker 9:  that's a little bit restrictive. I'm sure that's not great if you want to
Speaker 9:  sell a lot of in-app purchases through the app store, but doesn't seem
Speaker 9:  egregious to me. What I find really fascinating about this overall though
Speaker 9:  is, you know, companies love to talk about how, you know,
Speaker 9:  oppressive the regulatory environment is and how they have to do all
Speaker 9:  these different, you know, jump through all these different hoops for different
Speaker 9:  countries and jurisdictions. And I mostly, I roll my eyes
Speaker 9:  at that stuff and you know, there continue to be laws on
Speaker 9:  around app stores and it's gotten to the point where Apple
Speaker 9:  is twisting itself into knots to have
Speaker 9:  different rules all across the globe and now
Speaker 9:  even within the United States and to some
Speaker 9:  extent, i I I think some of this at least is
Speaker 9:  a little self-inflicted. There are areas where perhaps they could go, oh,
Speaker 9:  we'll just take the l on this one. We're just, we're just gonna be, but at
Speaker 9:  this point, if you're a developer, you, you as a developer now
Speaker 9:  have to comply with these things to make your apps work in all these different
Speaker 9:  areas. If you want your apps to work in Texas, you have to apply this specific
Speaker 9:  API to make sure that it like gets the age range of
Speaker 9:  the kid. And it's, it's, it's wild. And I, I am just
Speaker 9:  fascinated to see how complicated the app store is getting because
Speaker 9:  Apple in part refuses to just apply these things
Speaker 9:  worldwide.
Speaker 7:  This to me is like full on malicious compliance from Apple
Speaker 7:  because it's not, when I, when I first read this
Speaker 7:  headline, my assumption was that Apple was gonna start to do some
Speaker 7:  of the things that we're seeing like social platforms do, which is basically
Speaker 7:  like look at your activity and behavior and try to guess what age you
Speaker 7:  are and make decisions about what to show you based on that.
Speaker 7:  I think that's a giant mess, but it's like fascinating to watch.
Speaker 7:  Like we've seen a lot of people who are like, I am
Speaker 7:  38 years old and YouTube thinks I'm 16 so it it age
Speaker 7:  gated my account. That stuff is a mess. But I think is actually coming
Speaker 7:  for a lot of these platforms, this thing about like actually
Speaker 7:  we can't just put a button that says are you over 18
Speaker 7:  and trust that that will work. It's like when you go to like a liquor website
Speaker 7:  and it's like, are you over 21 and you hit yes and it lets you in, it's like,
Speaker 7:  what was the point of this thing that we're doing here? That's what Apple's
Speaker 7:  doing here. All Apple is doing is if you're in Texas and you set up an Apple
Speaker 7:  id, it's going to say, are you over 18? And you say yes and it will say Needo
Speaker 7:  and let you in. Like, this is nothing that Apple is doing here.
Speaker 7:  This is the least you can do if you're Apple in order to cover your
Speaker 7:  ass and say, well they they told us they were over 18, what are we supposed
Speaker 7:  to do? And again, I I think there, there are huge reasons
Speaker 7:  to be worried about this. Like we're going to guess
Speaker 7:  your age based on what you do. But actually if any company were set up to
Speaker 7:  do that in a way that is both relatively privacy, preserving and successful,
Speaker 7:  it would be Apple. Like, do do you know, do you know what knows
Speaker 7:  my birthday is my phone like this, it's just sitting, you could,
Speaker 7:  apple could do it, but it is choosing not to just
Speaker 7:  as a middle finger to all of these laws. And it is both very funny and I
Speaker 7:  sort of appreciate that.
Speaker 9:  It is really strange. Like Apple is like really taking a stand where
Speaker 9:  they're like, we do not want to be the one who is responsible for checking
Speaker 9:  your age. And I get that because they're like, I don't want the legal liability
Speaker 9:  for
Speaker 7:  That. It's all downside for app.
Speaker 9:  But, but it, it's like, instead what if every single
Speaker 9:  app did it individually and you provided that information to
Speaker 9:  every single app that seems more private and secure
Speaker 9:  and, and you know, I, I get it from their point of view,
Speaker 9:  but the I your phone already has it, the app already has it. Like you've
Speaker 9:  got a credit card or you don't, they can kind of figure that out.
Speaker 9:  I it is more the broad trends of this, the broad stroke, this and I think
Speaker 9:  your, your point about malicious compliance is exactly
Speaker 9:  spot on, which is that has been apple's like mo
Speaker 9:  for all of these laws. Yes. They jump, you know, they, they
Speaker 9:  again, they twist themselves into knots to make their compliance as
Speaker 9:  weird and wonky and hard to follow as possible. I literally, when
Speaker 9:  they announced their revamped rules for
Speaker 9:  the Digital Services Act, I believe it is
Speaker 9:  to, you know, open up the app store in Europe. I
Speaker 9:  spent the weekend reading through them trying to make
Speaker 9:  sense of who, what, what you do and
Speaker 9:  who it applies to and, and what apps have to pay. It is
Speaker 9:  so wildly complicated and like that is exactly
Speaker 9:  how they want it. Yes. They want you to not understand this stuff. They wanna
Speaker 9:  make it seem so burdensome and outrageous that these the, the
Speaker 9:  governments just go, Ooh, we messed up. We're just gonna yeah, gonna walk
Speaker 9:  this back.
Speaker 7:  There's a team of lawyers at Apple who is just desperate
Speaker 7:  to be sued about this so that they can go in and be like, you look, look
Speaker 7:  what you made us do. Yeah. Look at this horrible thing that we had to create
Speaker 7:  because you demanded that we do. So. And I'm very much looking
Speaker 7:  forward to that. It's gonna be very funny. Alright, my last one, and then
Speaker 7:  we should get outta here is about Facebook.
Speaker 9:  They still make that
Speaker 7:  An app that neither you nor I have opened.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. On purpose in a very long time, I suspect. But
Speaker 7:  we've talked about this few times. The, there's a big push, particularly
Speaker 7:  from Mark Zuckerberg himself to make
Speaker 7:  Facebook, Facebook again, right? Like they're talking about the OG Facebook
Speaker 7:  and bringing back this idea that like, actually Facebook is a place
Speaker 7:  to hang out with your friends and not just like look at reels
Speaker 7:  from influencers. And the big changes that
Speaker 7:  Facebook is making in order to engender this is to just be TikTok
Speaker 7:  like in in, in, in a very real way. Facebook is like, oh,
Speaker 7:  you don't like Facebook and you like TikTok, so we're gonna do TikTok.
Speaker 7:  So they, they announced a couple of things this week. One is that they're
Speaker 7:  changing the recommendations engine in Facebook so that it will learn
Speaker 7:  what you like more quickly, which a, I think is very smart because
Speaker 7:  as I've been saying for years now, the thing that is magical about
Speaker 7:  TikTok, like the thing that works about that algorithm is it is so willing
Speaker 7:  to show you stuff you don't like and it is so quick to
Speaker 7:  figure out what you do like and start giving it to you that it will take
Speaker 7:  chances on that stuff over and over and over again. And because scrolling
Speaker 7:  is so easy and because we're so used to it, there's no penalty for being
Speaker 7:  wrong. And so Facebook is clearly leaning into that. Now,
Speaker 7:  inside of that is the admission that all Facebook is now is reels
Speaker 7:  like it's, it's just Facebook is reels. Instagram is increasingly reels,
Speaker 7:  right? Like the Instagram iPad app opens to reels. They're testing an Instagram
Speaker 7:  app for mobile that opens to reels like Facebook is becoming
Speaker 7:  WhatsApp and reels is is like that is, that is meta is
Speaker 7:  is they have smart glasses, they have WhatsApp and they have reels. Those
Speaker 7:  are the businesses and that's fascinating. But the other thing
Speaker 7:  is what Facebook is calling Friend Bubbles and basically
Speaker 7:  the idea is we're going to up rank and show you more
Speaker 7:  of the stuff that your friends make and like particularly that
Speaker 7:  they've made and liked recently. And this
Speaker 7:  to me suggests that everyone who worked at Facebook a bunch of years ago
Speaker 7:  has since left Facebook because this is the exact thing that Facebook
Speaker 7:  unwound because they realize that, oh, actually your friends are idiots who
Speaker 7:  post stupid stuff and what you care about actually has nothing to
Speaker 7:  do with who your friends are. And so Facebook just became
Speaker 7:  sort of random slop from influencers just like every other platform
Speaker 7:  because that's what people actually turned out to wanna watch. And so this
Speaker 7:  pivot back to friends as like a, they're going to be the curators of content
Speaker 7:  for you is like, we did this once already and you Facebook
Speaker 7:  didn't like it. So like, what are we doing here?
Speaker 9:  This is like the the disastrous proposition, right? They they're, they're
Speaker 9:  actually talking about two distinct things. You can either have
Speaker 9:  a service that is great for you and your friends, it is a small
Speaker 9:  community, right? Where you get updates about your friends and their lives
Speaker 9:  and you love it because there are people you care about there. Or
Speaker 9:  you can have TV where you watch different things than your
Speaker 9:  friends and that's fine and it's good and sometimes you talk about it but
Speaker 9:  sometimes you don't. But
Speaker 7:  Also the one, the first one of those is
Speaker 7:  demonstrably not a very good business. The second one is demonstrably a
Speaker 7:  fabulous business and it's a worst product and I like it less than it might
Speaker 7:  ruin democracy, but it is a way better business. Yes.
Speaker 9:  It also seems to be a much easier business to build your way into, right?
Speaker 9:  Yeah. I, it it is, I don't know, like next
Speaker 9:  to impossible it ha it can, can you think of any service
Speaker 9:  that e existed already that went, oh, we're gonna be
Speaker 9:  more social friendly and everybody and their friends are gonna move their
Speaker 9:  their network over to it. Right? This all happens from upstarts. Yeah,
Speaker 9:  it is, it is mostly upstarts who have something a little bit
Speaker 9:  new and a little bit fresh and everybody rushes there and that is why Facebook
Speaker 9:  exploded in the first place and it lasted for a really long time and
Speaker 9:  then it wasn't there. And you can kind of see that pattern repeating on every
Speaker 9:  single social network where eventually it just becomes a little stale,
Speaker 9:  becomes a little too stiff and something else comes along.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And I think it's bizarre frankly, that that
Speaker 7:  hasn't happened yet. I think. Yeah. And I think frankly the fact that it
Speaker 7:  hasn't happened to Facebook yet, the fact that it hasn't been sort of disrupted
Speaker 7:  on that particular side of things might indicate that actually we've just
Speaker 7:  solved that problem with like group chats and text messages. Yeah. And that
Speaker 7:  maybe this is a product that doesn't need to exist. And actually, even as
Speaker 7:  I'm saying this, I'm saying you, you know what has disrupted that is Snapchat,
Speaker 7:  which is a perfect example of terrific culturally relevant,
Speaker 7:  massively popular product, not a very good business. Yeah. And so it's like,
Speaker 7:  is is maybe if I'm Mark Zuckerberg, I'm willing to say I'm going to,
Speaker 7:  you know, chop off some of this business in the name of making it a product
Speaker 7:  that people actually like and use on purpose and makes them feel good.
Speaker 7:  But nothing about the history of Meta suggests that that's the case.
Speaker 9:  Well and the original Facebook I think is, is explicitly very
Speaker 9:  slow and rigid, which is just not how the internet works Now.
Speaker 9:  Maybe
Speaker 7:  It should be, but it's not. Yeah.
Speaker 9:  It it, it is not. And it doesn't work for people. And that is I think why
Speaker 9:  that side of the site does not feel fresh and lively anymore
Speaker 9:  and they have just pivoted to, you know, weird TV that is not as
Speaker 9:  good as rival networks.
Speaker 7:  Indeed. Alright, we need to get out of here. I've gone two
Speaker 7:  hours without looking at TikTok and that's too long. So I'm gonna go, I'm
Speaker 7:  gonna go scroll some TikTok. We need to get outta here. Thank you Jake for
Speaker 7:  being here. Thank you Hayden, who has, you know, long gone doing AI things.
Speaker 7:  This was a delight. That is it for the first cast. If you have questions,
Speaker 7:  if you have stuff you wanna talk about, if you have Facebook friends who
Speaker 7:  actually post cool things, I would love to hear about it. You can email us
Speaker 7:  Virgin cast@thevirgin.com, call the hotline eight six six Virgin one one.
Speaker 7:  Keep watching and listening to version history. Episode two is coming out
Speaker 7:  on Sunday. It's a very fun one. We all get very mad at each other at
Speaker 7:  various points. It's, it's a great time. You'll enjoy it. Keep telling us
Speaker 7:  how you feel about these episodes. Lots more of that coming. Vergecast is
Speaker 7:  a Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network shows
Speaker 7:  will be back next week. I'm very much looking forward to it. We'll see you
Speaker 7:  then. Rock and roll.