# Transcript
ID: 3648c1ae-57a6-4a44-bfe9-09d779cf1b18
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7467832685509688446/-2495978761223818700/s93290-US-5936s-1749205889.mp3
Description: Developer conference season is almost over, but we've got one show left to see: Apple's WWDC begins on Monday. Nilay, David, and Joanna Stern spend time going through both what they expect to see at the show, and why this year's WWDC might feel a bit different than in years past. Apple is in a tricky place with regulators, developers, and users alike, and has some genuine explaining to do. After that, they talk about the launch of the Nintendo Switch 2, and David's surprisingly easy adventure to acquire one. We also have a bit of smart glasses and AI gadgets news to discuss, so we do that too. Then it's time for Brendan Carr is a Dummy, and an update on a couple of the interesting new fediverse projects launching this week.
Speaker 7:  Hello
Speaker 5:  Joanna's live from her office at the Wall Street Journal. It's very fancy.
Speaker 5:  This might be the fanciest situation we've ever had in the Birch cast.
Speaker 7:  We have a map.
Speaker 6:  If you're watching this on YouTube, you should know that just outside of
Speaker 6:  Joanna's frame is like 6,000 square feet of her office
Speaker 6:  with several couches and a bunch of like glass
Speaker 6:  statues. Like that's the, that's the image I want you to have in your mind
Speaker 6:  through
Speaker 5:  This entire show. Have you ever seen succession? Yes,
Speaker 7:  Exactly. And we also have a bunch of typewriter. This is a
Speaker 7:  newspaper and we have news print everywhere.
Speaker 5:  Can you yell Stop the presses right now. What? What would happen?
Speaker 7:  All the people that work on video will stop their presses. So they sit right
Speaker 7:  out my office.
Speaker 5:  It's very good. The people who are tasked with like Joanna YouTube stunts
Speaker 5:  will be like, what presses where we supposed to get a press?
Speaker 7:  They're like, we did get that press two years ago. Yeah, it was a sandwich
Speaker 7:  press.
Speaker 5:  Like the person holding the kayak for your next trip to an island with a
Speaker 5:  robot will be like, I don't, is this a press?
Speaker 7:  We've done that in like three years. I,
Speaker 5:  It's still the best stunt you've ever done. I, I, I know. Go, if you're listening
Speaker 5:  this just type Joanna Kayak Island and you'll find it. Lots of stuff to talk
Speaker 5:  about. Next week is wwc, so we're gonna preview that e
Speaker 5:  Elon and Trump are in some sort of fight, but we're not gonna talk about
Speaker 5:  it too much. I just wanna bring that up in the context. It's going on with
Speaker 5:  starlink lot on starlink actually the switch to launched and David
Speaker 5:  has won. I do. So we gotta talk about that. But I wanna start with
Speaker 5:  a little news. We won some awards this week. It's a real
Speaker 5:  thing. We won best news and entertainment design. The American Society of
Speaker 5:  Magazine editors gave us the award for best news and entertainment design
Speaker 5:  for our 2004 package, of which I would say David is
Speaker 5:  at fault for 'cause it was his idea. And then everyone had to think about
Speaker 5:  2004 for like six months. That's basically how that turned out.
Speaker 5:  But that had incredible art. We'll link it. You can go see it. It's one of
Speaker 5:  the best interactions we've ever done. Our incredible creative director,
Speaker 5:  Kristen and our art director Kath, worked on that really hard. They got to
Speaker 5:  accept the award.
Speaker 6:  The award by the way, is spectacular. No worries. 'cause they just, they
Speaker 6:  just printed out the top of the website and put it onto like a, a
Speaker 6:  glass plaque and gave it to Cath.
Speaker 5:  Well, in a glass plaque. It's not, it's not like rubber cemented on the top.
Speaker 5:  It's in it
Speaker 6:  Fair. It's but it's just like a printed piece of paper. It is inside the
Speaker 6:  glass plaque.
Speaker 5:  Very good. It's very good. And then Mia au won the ASME next
Speaker 5:  award, which is for the best reporters under 30.
Speaker 5:  I wanna be careful distinguish it from 30 under 30. If you win 30 under 30,
Speaker 5:  you go to jail.
Speaker 6:  Yes,
Speaker 7:  Yes. You get handcuffs, golden handcuffs you would get.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's a, that's the fast track to being incarcerated. Mia just wanted
Speaker 5:  for being great young journalist and actually Nancy the word by saying, this
Speaker 5:  is the future of journalism and then I heckled her for being the future of
Speaker 5:  journalism for the rest of the night. It's very good. Congratulations to
Speaker 5:  them. Incredible work from our team. I will remind you that the way to support
Speaker 5:  our team and all that work is by subscribing to The Verge. It's
Speaker 5:  Developer conference season is almost over, means our sale is almost over
Speaker 5:  right now. They're 40 percent off. Go to The Verge dot com slash subscribe.
Speaker 5:  I'm getting better at pitching the subscriptions. Joanna,
Speaker 5:  I I've never been made to sell anything,
Speaker 5:  you know, that's just not what we do here.
Speaker 7:  You just sold me, but I already paid so
Speaker 5:  Cheaper than the Wall Street Journal. That's, that's,
Speaker 7:  I mean that is a good sale right there. That's true. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Alright, let's start. It's, It is developer conference season. We've had
Speaker 5:  Microsoft, we've had Google, there's been some other ones in the backdrop.
Speaker 5:  Anthropic had its first one just to, you know, join the, the fund. The
Speaker 5:  last one, traditionally, sort of the big one is
Speaker 5:  Apple's. WC it's coming up next week. I would, I would just
Speaker 5:  wanna start with a context of wwe. C So this week there was a, a huge
Speaker 5:  court ruling that said Apple can't block
Speaker 5:  web links in the app store. So right. Apple had the big case
Speaker 5:  with Epic. They went back and forth for five years. Eventually the judge
Speaker 5:  in that case got fed up with Apple accused it of lying on the stand of having
Speaker 5:  executives lie on the stand. Referred that executive for a criminal contempt
Speaker 5:  proceedings and said, screw it. We're done here. You have to allow alternative
Speaker 5:  payment systems in the app store. This is a huge threat to Apple's business.
Speaker 5:  They immediately appeal and said, stay the ruling while we appeal how wrong
Speaker 5:  this is. And they lost that fight. So the, the ruling is in
Speaker 5:  effect, while Apple goes through appeal, which effectively means four years
Speaker 5:  now Apple is gonna have to allow links in the app store,
Speaker 5:  allow payment links in the app stores.
Speaker 6:  It feels like that's done now. Like I'm, I'm sort of at the point where
Speaker 6:  the, and and we talked about this before, that like even if Apple had gotten
Speaker 6:  this particular victory, it, it would've felt
Speaker 6:  like putting toothpaste back in the tube in a certain way. And I think we've
Speaker 6:  already seen so many of these apps update to go with other systems
Speaker 6:  of linking out and all of a sudden you realize like, oh I can click the button
Speaker 6:  in the Kindle app and go buy the Kindle book. Like what a world.
Speaker 6:  And I think it was always gonna be very hard to go back from that. And I
Speaker 6:  feel like now at this point it feels very hard to me
Speaker 6:  to imagine Apple winning and undoing all of this. Like it's so crystal
Speaker 6:  clear how crappy a move that would be for Apple that I think
Speaker 6:  like even the company that is seems increasingly clear being or
Speaker 6:  increasingly happy being the bad guy. I don't, I don't know how you
Speaker 6:  do that one.
Speaker 5:  Yep. And Fortnite is back in the store. They had a big fight and the judge
Speaker 5:  VA said Figure this out or I'm gonna figure out for you. And Apple said,
Speaker 5:  we figured out Fortnite is back in the store. We have an interview actually
Speaker 5:  with Tim Sweeney. JP Peters interviewed Tim Sweeney this week and he said,
Speaker 5:  I thought this would be two weeks and it was five years, but we were happy
Speaker 5:  to wait it out and because 'cause they won of course he's happy to wait it
Speaker 5:  out.
Speaker 6:  Tim Sweeney's so full of shit. Yeah. Can we just say that
Speaker 5:  Tim Sweeney,
Speaker 6:  Who has at every point of this process been like, well we're just over here
Speaker 6:  trying to do our best and we just want to do what's, and it's like no, no,
Speaker 6:  no, no. What has actually happened is you have found every single way to
Speaker 6:  pick a fight with Apple in court that you have been able to for five years,
Speaker 6:  you have decided that It is worth all of the money that you make from V Bucks
Speaker 6:  to just knife Apple over and over for five years. Yeah. So it's like
Speaker 6:  if if they had put him back in the store, he would've found something else
Speaker 6:  to do to get kicked outta the store. I don like, I just, I just don't believe
Speaker 6:  him for one second.
Speaker 7:  Why didn't you interview Tim Sweeney? I feel like that would've been the
Speaker 7:  best interview there you are full of shit. Tim. Tim Sweeney. Yeah. I'd like
Speaker 7:  to open with that.
Speaker 6:  Tim, who else would you have sued
Speaker 5:  When you send the pitch emails to book the, the episodes or like here's our,
Speaker 5:  here's our angle. You're full of shit. I mean it's worth a shot. We'll send
Speaker 5:  that email at the end of the show. I mean I agree with that. I also think
Speaker 5:  they did think the fight would be over sooner. I assume that Epic thought
Speaker 5:  they would win faster than they did and it only is because
Speaker 5:  Apple was so non-compliant for so long that they've gotten to this
Speaker 5:  resounding victory. I do agree that the toothpaste is outta too, if Apple
Speaker 5:  succeeds in this appeal and they borrow links again,
Speaker 5:  well it turns out now there's a lot of data about
Speaker 5:  how much money was going to Apple instead of the app developers that different
Speaker 5:  countries and regulators around the world can all look at. Right. And it
Speaker 5:  that's gonna be the case in the eu. It's the case in Japan. It's like all
Speaker 5:  over the place. We're running this big AB test and the data shows,
Speaker 5:  oh Apple kept a lot of money that could have gone to developers and and created
Speaker 5:  jobs and
Speaker 7:  All this stuff. Right? And now like the Amazons and the Spotifys of the world
Speaker 7:  will have the other data that says look how much money.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And that this is just a big deal. The reason I bring this up ahead
Speaker 5:  of WWC preview conversation is this is the
Speaker 5:  developer conference. This is where Apple says, look at all these new capabilities
Speaker 5:  of our next generation operating systems. Can't you get excited?
Speaker 5:  Won't you get excited about building your apps using our new APIs and features
Speaker 5:  and hooks and like look at all the cool new stuff you can do on the iPhone.
Speaker 5:  This is why it's worth paying us 30% of every in-app purchase
Speaker 5:  because our operating system is better developers and I think they're
Speaker 5:  coming into this totally on their back foot with developers who are by and
Speaker 5:  large unhappy who are already starting new kinds of
Speaker 5:  companies and organizations to manage payments differently. Right? You're
Speaker 5:  you're seeing like an alternative payment ecosystem develop who are pretty
Speaker 5:  annoyed about the AI stuff, right? Like the energy is elsewhere in
Speaker 5:  AI and who are also just like we are tired of this company, this heel turn
Speaker 5:  that Apple is doing saying we're definitely gonna yell at everyone
Speaker 5:  and we have all these emails from inside of Apple basically being like, how
Speaker 5:  do we squeeze our developers from these court cases? And I just think it's
Speaker 5:  a weird spot for Apple to begin this developer conference season.
Speaker 7:  I agree. And I think the tide is turned for Apple not
Speaker 7:  only in the space of the developers and the
Speaker 7:  30% and the 70% and all of the the money, but also just in terms of
Speaker 7:  the fanfare for the company and the product. Which
Speaker 7:  as we all have gone to these conferences for, I don't know, 150 years
Speaker 7:  now. Like there's the excitement there. Not only about like, oh I'm gonna
Speaker 7:  build this app, it's just like I'm excited about Apple, right? Like people
Speaker 7:  are just excited about the devices, they're excited about the software and
Speaker 7:  to your point, like they're very, right now there's this big shift towards
Speaker 7:  these AI platforms. What can we do with ai? And Apple's been outta that
Speaker 7:  conversation. I know you guys have been discussing on the podcast too, like
Speaker 7:  the I'VE and Altman partnership. I mean there's, there's this
Speaker 7:  appetite and excitement for something else right now
Speaker 7:  and it's not Apple that seems to be delivering it. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And Apple's on this kind of sneakily
Speaker 6:  bad run recently of a mix of
Speaker 6:  launching things with incredible fanfare that it claims are going to be the
Speaker 6:  next big thing that either aren't or don't exist at all. And So I think
Speaker 6:  like I think about the, we, we've always talked about WWC differently than
Speaker 6:  some of the other ones and like the, the wrap on Google for a long time
Speaker 6:  was we would go to Google io and they would show us science projects and
Speaker 6:  then we would go to WWC and they would show us products and they were
Speaker 6:  like, apple was unusually clear at
Speaker 6:  showing things that were finished that were going to ship, that you were
Speaker 6:  going to use. And we've had a bad run of that with
Speaker 6:  all of the, there's been the CarPlay stuff that lingered a long time and
Speaker 6:  then changed and got weird Siri, which is the
Speaker 6:  biggest story of this year's WWDC because
Speaker 6:  I would bet you $500 it's just not gonna be there. Nope. Nope.
Speaker 6:  Is now a year old and we have not seen one lick of what
Speaker 6:  it's supposed to be. Then throw in the Vision Pro, which was supposed to
Speaker 6:  be the next big thing that was gonna change Ruby's mind that hasn't really
Speaker 6:  worked. There's just this sense of like, I think
Speaker 6:  WWDC was sort of the year Apple like set agendas for a long time
Speaker 6:  and it really doesn't feel like that is what's coming anymore.
Speaker 6:  And it's a very strange shift.
Speaker 5:  And I would add to that, they set design agendas for the year, right? 'cause
Speaker 5:  they would show you app designs and new features and new modes of interactions
Speaker 5:  and animation flourishes and all this stuff. And everyone would copy it.
Speaker 5:  And I, I don't know, we, you know, we're hearing that there's gonna be a
Speaker 5:  big redesign of all their operating systems this year. We've, we, and I think
Speaker 5:  Greg Jaw tweeted some joke about the word sleek,
Speaker 5:  right? Like it's coming.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And they sent it out in an email like a sleek, it's like a s
Speaker 7:  sleek
Speaker 5:  Peak. And those are the invites, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I don't, I I didn't like that
Speaker 5:  They're hinting that there's gonna be some some big visual redesign. And
Speaker 5:  it's fascinating because they're diverging from the rest of the
Speaker 5:  industry and I'm not sure the rest of the industry is gonna follow them into
Speaker 5:  their like glass based redesign language. Maybe. Maybe they
Speaker 5:  will. People tend to copy Apple quite a bit. But you can just see the rest
Speaker 5:  of the industry is kind of headed back towards Dimorphism, which is wild
Speaker 5:  and like weird. That's just weird. You know, like, like even
Speaker 5:  Apple not as design leader is truly novel.
Speaker 7:  But I actually think, I mean, we'll we will learn about this and I, I keep
Speaker 7:  having like a little bit of this nightmare that it, that it launches in September.
Speaker 7:  That operating cell operating system itself like looks great
Speaker 7:  and you know, hopefully works, fingers crossed everything sort of works.
Speaker 7:  We don't have this buggy situation but then the apps are in just
Speaker 7:  look completely different. I mean we had this with with when the iPhone 10
Speaker 7:  came out, right? There was like that gap in time that the apps had to catch
Speaker 7:  up and it looked like garbage on the phone. You remember that time that like,
Speaker 7:  I don't know, it was probably like six months, right? Where the app developers
Speaker 7:  had to update for the update with like the no home button design and all
Speaker 7:  that. It's like kind of like cringed at the apps that didn't have the update.
Speaker 7:  Oh yeah. Like there's a possibility that some of these developers don't get
Speaker 7:  on board or they don't get on board right away because they're put their
Speaker 7:  resources into something else. But I'm sure we're gonna hear a lot about
Speaker 7:  how easy It is to do x, y and z. I mean two
Speaker 7:  clicks, an X code, all of those types of things. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But it does seem like, to that point, I I like, this is another thing where
Speaker 6:  it's gonna be an interesting test for Apple because again, it has spent the
Speaker 6:  last few years just pissing off developers left and right
Speaker 6:  and essentially telling developers that they don't matter, that apple's in
Speaker 6:  charge, that it can do whatever it wants. And then also asking
Speaker 6:  developers to do more all the time. And I think this is the
Speaker 6:  thing I've heard a lot from folks over the last year or so is this question
Speaker 6:  of, okay, I'm being asked to make a really great iOS app
Speaker 6:  and last year it was all of the new like color tinting and all
Speaker 6:  the the dark mode stuff. And so they're like, okay, well now I have to rethink
Speaker 6:  the way that my widgets work and the way that my home screen stuff works
Speaker 6:  and there's the new control center stuff and there's the new lock screen
Speaker 6:  stuff. So I have to build this whole new controls thing, but then there's
Speaker 6:  also all of this new stuff being done so that I can port my iOS
Speaker 6:  app to other platforms, which is extra work that I have to do. And now Apple
Speaker 6:  also really wants me to build an app for the Vision Pro. And it's like if
Speaker 6:  you're Netflix, you can like figure out how to make apps for
Speaker 6:  lots of platforms. But if you're like one person or a small
Speaker 6:  team of developers, which is most of the apps in the app store, that's
Speaker 6:  a giant amount of work to give people. So
Speaker 5:  What's fascinating about that is how did that, how did that problem get solved
Speaker 5:  most often is they started using web frameworks to do all that stuff. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  To get the app logic in more places. And then you can just skin the sort
Speaker 5:  of app logic in the web framework. And so many apps now are just like,
Speaker 5:  like web apps and wrappers, which is fine and great and fascinating but it
Speaker 5:  means all the actions on the web. Yeah. And that's where all of the AI apps
Speaker 5:  are being developed. Like fundamentally all of the best AI apps are starting
Speaker 5:  as deployed on the web because you know the backend is in the, in the cloud
Speaker 5:  anyway. Right.
Speaker 7:  Which you talked about with Sundar in your interview, which was really fascinating
Speaker 7:  to me. Like that's where people are going to launch their, their apps.
Speaker 5:  I Sendar said that he had vibe coded in Rept and the CEO Rept
Speaker 5:  clipped that and he got a million views and he's just the happiest.
Speaker 7:  I was actually just thinking like maybe we should just show up to WWDC as
Speaker 7:  developers and just be like, now I'm a vibe coder. Now I'm gonna say with
Speaker 7:  the developers
Speaker 5:  I watch a lot of tiktoks of people one shot coding iOS apps. Right?
Speaker 5:  It's just like, here It is. And I don't know if that's good or bad. I just,
Speaker 5:  I know that the action isn't on Apple's platforms, right? The action of where's,
Speaker 5:  where's my app being first developed? It's kind of on the web and that is
Speaker 5:  remarkable. I I continue to think the web is remarkable but it just means
Speaker 5:  the part where you make it pretty for iOS is like
Speaker 5:  not important a second order phenomenon. And it used to just be the, the
Speaker 5:  first thing it used the first order bit was like, do I have a great
Speaker 5:  iOS app? 'cause that's how I make all the money.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean there are, there are legions of Android apps that are just
Speaker 6:  iOS apps. Like that's it because Apple was able to
Speaker 6:  lead that for so long, right? That it was, the assumption was that your
Speaker 6:  Apple version of your app was going to be the best one and then you would,
Speaker 6:  you would scale that in whatever way you needed to off to other platforms.
Speaker 6:  And like to your point about Apple sort of skating in the other direction
Speaker 6:  from all these companies, like that's a big swing because if you're not leading
Speaker 6:  now it's gonna feel bad. And it's like there, there
Speaker 6:  is a real perception that like people with great taste use
Speaker 6:  Apple products because they are cohesive and you can lose that really quickly.
Speaker 7:  I'll make a bet here. And I think again in our 150 years of going
Speaker 7:  to WWC, we know that Tim Cook usually opens talking
Speaker 7:  to the developers and like highlighting how much money they made for them,
Speaker 7:  right? Like so to play the other side of this, like Apple still makes
Speaker 7:  a lot of money for these developers probably the most. And so
Speaker 7:  they'll lean into that. People aren't gonna go anywhere.
Speaker 7:  Maybe they won't update as quickly, but Tim Cook will still be up there
Speaker 7:  talking about how much money he made for developers,
Speaker 6:  Right?
Speaker 5:  I know they're gonna do that 'cause Apple keeps putting out press releases
Speaker 5:  saying how much money they put out for they made for
Speaker 7:  Developers. Okay, so there's no bet here because we all agree.
Speaker 5:  I mean like literally today they're like, look at how big the global app
Speaker 5:  store ecosystem is, right? And the answer is $1.3 trillion in
Speaker 5:  developer buildings and sales. That's gonna be on a what 90% of
Speaker 5:  billings and sales went to developers with no commission paid Apple. These
Speaker 5:  are the first two bullet points. What are they trying to point out, right?
Speaker 5:  They're like, we don't take any money from, look at all this money we didn't
Speaker 5:  take. And it's like, well the 10% you did take is still a huge amount
Speaker 5:  of money, right? Like, I dunno what to tell you.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. That's gonna be the slide. That's like one of the first slides. You're
Speaker 7:  right. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And so you can just see that they're, they're trying to make the case, they're
Speaker 5:  providing all this value. I wanted to start there. Not to just be
Speaker 5:  negative, but to point out this is the context. Like the audience
Speaker 5:  at WWC is developers who are feeling these pressures.
Speaker 5:  The point of this conference is sometimes to launch a Mac Pro,
Speaker 5:  right? And to get some flash of consumer recognition. And obviously Apple
Speaker 5:  has a lot of fans. But the point is to get developers excited
Speaker 5:  about building for Apple's platforms as opposed to Microsoft or Google's
Speaker 5:  or Open or whoever. And they're just in a weird spot. Like I
Speaker 5:  think, I think that will be an undercurrent of this entire thing next
Speaker 5:  week that developers are, they need to be convinced in a
Speaker 5:  way that hasn't been true of Apple in the bear a long time. I
Speaker 6:  Do think though to Joanna's point there, there is a real, like, where
Speaker 6:  else are you gonna go thing that Apple continues to have going for it.
Speaker 6:  And this is again, like a lot of the, the sort of developer energy I hear
Speaker 6:  around AI stuff is like, maybe that's the platform shift, right?
Speaker 6:  It was like there was a minute where everybody was like, maybe we'll investigate
Speaker 6:  the metaverse and then that wasn't it. And then everybody's like, is it Web3?
Speaker 6:  And they're like, no, that's not it. And now there is this sense that, okay,
Speaker 6:  maybe AI is the thing that I can, I can build something
Speaker 6:  into that will not come with all of the problems and restrictions of
Speaker 6:  iOS. But like the, the people who have been making iOS apps for
Speaker 6:  20 years and are really pissed at Apple are gonna keep making iOS apps. And
Speaker 6:  the problem is Apple knows that and is, is going to continue to
Speaker 6:  bleed that fact and those developers for as long as It is able to,
Speaker 5:  Well except they can't take the money from the web links anymore. So they
Speaker 5:  have to fight.
Speaker 6:  That's yeah. Right?
Speaker 5:  Like this is the, this is the dynamic it this's, where else are you gonna
Speaker 5:  go? And the answer is, well somewhere else, like there's,
Speaker 5:  I can go somewhere else Now. Have you considered that Tim?
Speaker 6:  For that thing? For sure. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And but that's the money. Yeah. So I think that brings us the, the the operating
Speaker 5:  system updates and, and, and a bit of the preview here. We're expecting some
Speaker 5:  visual refresh across the operating systems. We are expecting
Speaker 5:  'em to mention the Vision Pro, which continues to exist. Obstinately continues
Speaker 5:  to exist. They're gonna rename them all to, you know, iOS 26
Speaker 5:  wherever in any year thing. Then there's like, wait, actually
Speaker 7:  Wait, can we, can we talk about that,
Speaker 6:  That Joanna, I wanna know how you feel about this. We've talked a lot about
Speaker 6:  this on this show, but you are a person who cares deeply about version numbers.
Speaker 7:  I care a lot about this. I have a lot of thoughts. I tweeted this. Okay,
Speaker 7:  first of all I get the year thing, but It is
Speaker 7:  2025 right now. This is what I said, said there are still a number of months
Speaker 7:  where we have to process that. And I'm still writing 2024
Speaker 7:  on my checks.
Speaker 5:  Oh my God. Yes. Well how many checks
Speaker 7:  Are you writing? Yes, I write checks. I knew you were gonna ask that and
Speaker 7:  I would like to talk about my checks.
Speaker 5:  This is what happens when you work at a print newspaper run by
Speaker 7:  Report. No, it isn't what happens when we're in a print newspaper. It's what
Speaker 7:  happens when you have an accountant who is old school and will only take
Speaker 7:  checks. It's when you have a lighting guy for your house and he
Speaker 7:  only takes checks. Your guy
Speaker 5:  Doesn't want you to pay him on Zelle under the table. This I've learned that
Speaker 5:  this is zealous for
Speaker 7:  I do so much. I do so much Zelle under the table. I mean I don't if you're
Speaker 7:  listening to this, someone who's trying to audit all the
Speaker 7:  people I pay for things, for houses stuff. Yeah. So much
Speaker 7:  Zelle. Anyway, I still write some checks. Okay.
Speaker 7:  It happens. Yeah. Mostly for house stuff.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it seems, yeah. Zelle under the table though. I feel
Speaker 7:  Like I need a spin off of the birch cast, which is just about my house and
Speaker 7:  things that do, would do my
Speaker 5:  House would show with you. We can stop this right now if you just wanna talk
Speaker 5:  about your house.
Speaker 7:  We did the garage. That was a great hit. I feel like that was
Speaker 6:  A great day. We still get emails about the garage and I delete them before
Speaker 6:  Neil. I can see them.
Speaker 7:  I know we had, you know, we did, we did a postmortem on that. I think there
Speaker 7:  were ways we could have done it better, but we'll, we'll work on that for
Speaker 7:  our next project anyway. I'm worried about the year thing.
Speaker 7:  I'll get over that. It's also so many numbers. My annual
Speaker 7:  tradition is to do the number of tips to correspond to the iOS version. And
Speaker 7:  so there's just no way. I think physically I can do 26 tips for iOS
Speaker 7:  26.
Speaker 5:  Oh this is your problem.
Speaker 7:  You're in trouble. I'm, I'm gonna try, I, there's, I'm I I'm up for the
Speaker 7:  task. I'm not too old to do it. I think I can, I
Speaker 7:  can overcome but that's a lot of tips to do.
Speaker 5:  It is a lot. They they jumped you by like eight. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It is. It's gonna get into like new formatting tricks in Apple notes
Speaker 6:  and it's like it's gonna be at the bottom where, but what I, my challenge
Speaker 6:  to you Joanna is, is to do 26 tips Fort VOS
Speaker 6:  26. That's the one. If you can do that
Speaker 6:  26, you deserve all 8,000 square feet of your
Speaker 7:  Office for all 26 viewers.
Speaker 6:  Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Exactly.
Speaker 5:  Listen, this is what chat GBT is for.
Speaker 5:  I need eight more tips buddy. Get out there.
Speaker 7:  You know, chat GBT tends to be wrong on the tips. They'll be like you need
Speaker 7:  to adjust this settings menu and this. And it's like that doesn't exist.
Speaker 7:  Okay. I've tried it.
Speaker 5:  That's the foundational stuff. And obviously Joanna is very annoyed 'cause
Speaker 5:  she has to do slightly more work than last year. Great. We should talk
Speaker 5:  about the actual features. Here's the thing that I'm most interested in,
Speaker 5:  in the context of making developers excited. The, everyone has an
Speaker 5:  incredible past process, right? It's the, It is the best mobile processor
Speaker 5:  on a phone. Qualcomm is caught up in some ways. I'm sure we'll get some emails
Speaker 5:  about someone's Nvidia shield that they're powering with the USB battery
Speaker 5:  pack or whatever. Like it's all happening, it's great, but they've got
Speaker 5:  the neural engine, they've got a best in class mobile processor. They can
Speaker 5:  run local models.
Speaker 5:  Do you think that they're gonna find a way to tell developers like just do
Speaker 5:  the AI stuff here instead of on Azure using an
Speaker 5:  open AI model. Like, 'cause that is the game, right? Where
Speaker 5:  your AI app logic is running right now is gonna tell
Speaker 5:  us a lot about the future of this industry writ large. And Apple
Speaker 5:  hasn't made a big play for, well actually a bunch of the stuff you wanna
Speaker 5:  do, you can do locally on the phone because we have the processors to do
Speaker 5:  it and all of the built for Apple intelligence stuff came to nothing.
Speaker 5:  But if they actually did build the phone for Apple Intelligence, well maybe
Speaker 5:  they built the phone to run some models that are useful for app developers
Speaker 7:  And private cloud compute, which like, I think they'll want to keep selling.
Speaker 7:  They obviously put a lot of investment we think into that. So
Speaker 7:  I think that that's like one way they get into the AI story this year
Speaker 7:  without getting into Apple intelligence, right? Like to all of our
Speaker 7:  conversation about the developers, they try to say, Hey, we are gonna give
Speaker 7:  you access to small language models that run on device. We're gonna give
Speaker 7:  you large language model access and private cloud compute and you can build
Speaker 7:  great things. We don't even know what you're gonna build. You go, go build
Speaker 7:  it. My issue there and like, you know, it's like are the models
Speaker 7:  any good,
Speaker 5:  Good is a, has a relationship to cost.
Speaker 5:  So if the model on the phone is like kind of crappy, but it's free to use,
Speaker 5:  it's fine. You know, like, right. I I think that that's the case for them
Speaker 5:  to make. 'cause I don't think that they can run a GPT-4 class model
Speaker 5:  on private cloud compute right now. I maybe they will. Maybe that's what
Speaker 5:  they're gonna announce. But like that's your problem if you, if you want
Speaker 5:  that thing, you gotta go pay open AI or you gotta pay Google for
Speaker 5:  Gemini or whoever. Like you got that class of model exists on someone else's
Speaker 5:  data centers right now.
Speaker 7:  But even like just all of our complaints that we probably have about Apple
Speaker 7:  intelligence, the issues are largely because the models just don't feel
Speaker 7:  that smart. Right? Yeah. Like you even just take the, you know, the
Speaker 7:  image editing, right? Where you're, you wanna get something out of the background
Speaker 7:  like that is not as good as what you see from a Google level type
Speaker 7:  of
Speaker 7:  experience or model or whatever. Take summaries and
Speaker 7:  notifications. Those summaries make very little sense and
Speaker 7:  to the point where most people have turned them off. Like yeah, that's the
Speaker 7:  intelligence. And so if the intelligence that they're going to give access
Speaker 7:  to isn't actually all that intelligent, I'm not sure what the sale, the sale
Speaker 7:  is
Speaker 6:  Cheap. It's, it's really interesting 'cause in theory if Apple were good
Speaker 6:  at this, It is actually like perfectly positioned to do this
Speaker 6:  in a really cool and coherent way where like, like you said, it has
Speaker 6:  more stuff to work with locally than almost anybody. And, and there are
Speaker 6:  a lot of good and useful things you can do on your phone with local AI
Speaker 6:  models, right? Like it solves a lot of search problems. It solves a lot of
Speaker 6:  like how do I do small things on my phone? Like what if it made timers faster?
Speaker 6:  Like there's just a lot of things you could do.
Speaker 5:  Wait, David, can we just unpack what if it made timers faster? Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Okay. I don't wanna cut you off. I was like, like transcription.
Speaker 5:  I sp up time. You're like these 30 seconds now goes by in 25.
Speaker 6:  No, I'm talking about the, the gap between me saying timer and the timer
Speaker 6:  stuff. Oh, I see. Okay. Like there, there have been these moments with
Speaker 6:  Siri in particular in the past where they, they took a thing that had to
Speaker 6:  go to the cloud and they made it run on the device and it immediately feels
Speaker 6:  better. So I,
Speaker 5:  All three of us are parents and we've often all made pasta and it's like
Speaker 5:  if I could get this done in six minutes instead of nine we're my god gold,
Speaker 5:  you know,
Speaker 6:  I would buy every iPhone. The
Speaker 5:  Power of Apple intelligence bap
Speaker 7:  Times just gets going from like 10 minutes to two and you're like, it's 10
Speaker 7:  minutes, I swear.
Speaker 6:  Yeah we this's, we we just solved some things.
Speaker 5:  Get on it Craig timers faster.
Speaker 7:  Wait, what was that quote? It was like time is not a
Speaker 5:  Trump's like head of like Yeah White House technology was like
Speaker 5:  we can now travel through time and space. Yeah, that's And everyone's like,
Speaker 5:  that's it. Are you sure
Speaker 7:  That's it? That's exactly what I'm thinking of because, because
Speaker 5:  I'm good on space. I know we can travel through space
Speaker 6:  Doing that already. Very
Speaker 5:  Confused about time.
Speaker 7:  Sorry David, go on.
Speaker 6:  Well now I, we'll come back to that, that that's The Verge cast.
Speaker 6:  But but you, you start with that and you, right and you have the, this sort
Speaker 6:  of base layer of on device private stuff. Apple gets to tell its
Speaker 6:  big story about privacy and all this stuff like that all works great. Then
Speaker 6:  the second thing is the, is the private cloud compute stuff that
Speaker 6:  Apple like by all accounts, the infrastructure for that is actually
Speaker 6:  pretty good. We have not seen it do anything interesting but like as a, as
Speaker 6:  a theory and a product, it seems to be pretty interesting to a lot of people.
Speaker 6:  That's where you, you can do a lot of stuff and then for the most
Speaker 6:  aggressive, impressive sort of needy stuff, you
Speaker 6:  have this seamless integration out to tragedy pt. And one of the rumors this
Speaker 6:  time is that they're gonna bring more partners into that. So you could, you
Speaker 6:  could route to Gemini, you could route to Claude. Like you basically have
Speaker 6:  this thing where you need your phone to do something and it
Speaker 6:  has every available option to choose from, from fast
Speaker 6:  to slow and from cheap to expensive. Right? That's very cool.
Speaker 6:  Except that Apple sucks at this. And it's like, and there is
Speaker 6:  just, it's so frustrating because like you, you can see the idea
Speaker 6:  being right and the execution just being a disaster over and over and over
Speaker 6:  again. And so with all of this, I do think one of the things Apple is gonna
Speaker 6:  do is point some of the Apple intelligence stuff
Speaker 6:  at developers as a bunch of APIs you could call, right? Yeah. That like it's,
Speaker 6:  it's gonna bring them in as features but it's also I think gonna start to
Speaker 6:  give developers more access to the underlying
Speaker 6:  models and technology. And that's again potentially
Speaker 6:  really interesting. And It is, It is a very appley thing to do to be like,
Speaker 6:  hey, you know, rewind all the way back and apple's like you don't have a
Speaker 6:  phone with a camera that knows where you are. What do you wanna do with that?
Speaker 6:  And people found really interesting stuff to do with that because there's
Speaker 6:  interesting stuff to do with that. But the product sucks. So
Speaker 6:  it's like Apple's gonna be like, Hey here's a bad model that doesn't do anything.
Speaker 6:  Is this interesting to developers? And I think developers are just gonna
Speaker 6:  be like no.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. 'cause they can just go build on the cloud on G PT four
Speaker 5:  or Gemini. Right. Or Claude or anything else. And that part to me is
Speaker 5:  fascinating. 'cause the history, the reason Apple has all this clout with
Speaker 5:  developers is 'cause you got a bunch of stuff in the eighties and nineties
Speaker 5:  developing for the Mac got you a bunch of stuff for free that like you had
Speaker 5:  to basically hard code in the windows and then nothing was cohesive,
Speaker 5:  right? So you got like proportional fonts. This was like Steve Jobs's favorite
Speaker 5:  thing to talk about is heated proportional fonts and windows, proportional
Speaker 5:  ponds and Windows proportional fonts were like really bad for a one time
Speaker 5:  you got that stuff for free. So a bunch of developers like, oh I wanna make
Speaker 5:  beautiful stuff here. You can go on and on and on down the line all the way
Speaker 5:  to, on the iPhone you got iPhone's like theming
Speaker 5:  toolkit for free. Yeah. Like they would upgrade to iOS seven and then everyone
Speaker 5:  like ran to use iOS seven's design language and that was cool
Speaker 5:  here the capability you're talking about, the thing you're supposed to get
Speaker 5:  for free is like, oh there's a bunch of AI on the phone that I can use and
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna build the next class of application. And I think developers are
Speaker 5:  like, yeah but I can just use Gemini in the web. Right? And then that that
Speaker 5:  rules,
Speaker 6:  I can get that from other places. Apple is by a mile not the best
Speaker 6:  provider of that stuff right now, even if you're building II apps.
Speaker 5:  But they do, to your point, they do own the phone. So until someone displaces
Speaker 5:  the phone, I think do with something, they do have a little bit of where
Speaker 5:  you're gonna go. So we should go through the other features that are rumored,
Speaker 5:  as David mentioned, more integrations with outside AI partners. I'm actually
Speaker 5:  really looking for how they integrate Google Gemini. I think
Speaker 5:  it's in, it's in both Apple and Google's interest to
Speaker 5:  move the money from Google paying Apple for Google search to
Speaker 5:  be the default in safari to something else. 'cause that is under
Speaker 5:  antitrust pressure. You know, there's this stat about Google searches and
Speaker 5:  safari falling anyway that Sundar basically doesn't want to talk about.
Speaker 5:  So if you move that money to a Gemini integration, interesting.
Speaker 5:  Right? Maybe you escape the problem. We'll see. But I'm curious how that
Speaker 5:  plays out. Have
Speaker 7:  You guys changed your search default on Safari No. To anything?
Speaker 7:  Is it It still goes to Google. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  No, I just added chat GBT to my action button.
Speaker 7:  Okay. So I changed my safari search to chat
Speaker 7:  GPT
Speaker 7:  and it's a really poor experience. Like chat
Speaker 7:  GBT has this extension so it's there It is an extension. And So I
Speaker 7:  think there's a lot of potential for them to change that to tap into.
Speaker 7:  And we know they're talking to perplexity, we know they're talking to these
Speaker 7:  other companies, whether they do it as a default or you know, they could
Speaker 7:  keep Google as a default 'cause we all, there's all that baggage. But
Speaker 7:  they could make it considerably easier for you to use the address bar in
Speaker 7:  Safari to get to an AI Yeah. Chat bot. Which I would love to see.
Speaker 7:  What I was gonna jump in and say is like the chat GBT integration with Siri
Speaker 7:  is terrible. It's
Speaker 5:  Awful. It's very bad. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  So either they have to improve that considerably and
Speaker 7:  add extra partners. Like if they do add an anthropic and they do add a Google
Speaker 7:  there, like they say, you know what, just like we let you change your whatever
Speaker 7:  default of whatever. Over the years they've given us more of those
Speaker 7:  options. We'll let you change the default on the, you know, Siri will default
Speaker 7:  to go to Claude or Gemini, but they have to
Speaker 7:  improve that experience because otherwise it's like no one, there's no benefit
Speaker 7:  in it.
Speaker 5:  Well the baggage you're describing to be clear is literal
Speaker 5:  bags full of $20 billion.
Speaker 7:  Yes.
Speaker 5:  Right? So like they have to move that money, right? And
Speaker 5:  to say to Google, okay, you were paying us to be the default search
Speaker 5:  provider. We might change that to perplexity 'cause it's a better experience.
Speaker 5:  We would still really like your $20 billion. Here's this other integration
Speaker 7:  And that integration is the Siri.
Speaker 5:  I don't know the answer. I just, I, I suspect because there's antitrust pressure
Speaker 5:  on the deals exist now they will find some other place to make
Speaker 5:  Google and Gemini the default that lets them preserve
Speaker 5:  $20 billion.
Speaker 6:  But then while this is happening, you also have the DOJ pointing at that
Speaker 6:  possibility going, we cannot allow that to happen. Right? Yeah. That that
Speaker 6:  is like, they're like we have to get this trial done now so that Google can't
Speaker 6:  make this next deal with Apple the way that It is currently attempting to
Speaker 6:  do with everybody. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But it's like, you know, I have, see I like the action button opening cha
Speaker 5:  g bt, this is a very dumb example, but because we are, whenever Joan is on,
Speaker 5:  we only talk about home repair. I hung up a light fixture yesterday and it
Speaker 5:  had weird connectors for the LEDs inside and one of them broke and I hit
Speaker 5:  the action button and I took a picture of the weird connector and I said,
Speaker 5:  how do I fix this? And Cha GBT just told me how to pry up the little pin
Speaker 5:  that was broken, re crimp it and stick it back in there and it was fixed.
Speaker 5:  And I was like, oh this is very useful.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, but you're not using Apple's visual intelligence to do that, which
Speaker 7:  could do it.
Speaker 5:  But, but I'm using Apple's button. Right? Right. It's like if Apple can get
Speaker 5:  $20 billion to set that button to Gemini instead of chat GBT we're like they're
Speaker 5:  in business.
Speaker 7:  Well and the visual intelligence taps into Google, so
Speaker 7:  maybe that's another place. And we've heard about that I believe a little
Speaker 7:  bit in the trial that that's another place that they're building that future
Speaker 7:  of the relationship.
Speaker 5:  So that's one aspect we're looking for those integrations and who will be
Speaker 5:  the providers and who will be defaults. I'm very curious about that. The
Speaker 5:  second one that's on the list is this idea that they're gonna redesign shortcuts
Speaker 5:  and then Apple Intelligence will help you like write better shortcuts, which
Speaker 5:  is super fascinating. Not 'cause I think it'll be any good.
Speaker 7:  David, you actually, when you worked at the Wall Street Journal, did a column
Speaker 7:  on shortcuts and I'm still go back to that column to try to figure out how
Speaker 7:  the fuck to use shortcuts. Okay. So
Speaker 6:  The thing I say on this podcast sometimes that I get emails about every single
Speaker 6:  time is that shortcuts is a bad app and a failed experiment by Apple. And
Speaker 6:  everyone who made it should feel bad. And people get very upset with me about
Speaker 6:  that. But also I am completely correct.
Speaker 7:  Yes. Yeah. But like it, the potential of It is amazing. Yes. It's such a
Speaker 7:  good idea. Back to home stuff. I know there's so many home things I can do
Speaker 7:  with shortcuts,
Speaker 5:  But none of them work. 'cause they, the the phone forgets to run your shortcuts.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. And David didn't write about it like six years ago. Yep. And I don't
Speaker 7:  know how to do it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You don't have a PhD in software engineering, so you can't possibly
Speaker 6:  use the shortcuts app. So
Speaker 5:  This is what AI should fix. Yes. Right. You have this automation engine inside
Speaker 5:  the phone already and then you're like, robot do something.
Speaker 5:  And it's like, I'm gonna use this automation engine. And so much
Speaker 5:  of AI stuff right now is just basic automation
Speaker 5:  wrapped up in a natural language interface. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like
Speaker 5:  It's, it's not as complicated as anybody is making some of this stuff. I
Speaker 5:  will say
Speaker 6:  You, you say that like it's, it's a small thing, but that's actually a huge
Speaker 6:  thing. Yeah. Like automation, natural language automation,
Speaker 6:  if that's the extent of what AI ever turns out to be, is still like an
Speaker 6:  enormously huge deal in how we use computers. Which is the thing that drives
Speaker 6:  me so crazy. It's like, it's just, it's sitting right there. It's also the
Speaker 6:  easy part. Like yeah you all the developers have said, here are all the building
Speaker 6:  blocks that I have and you have a thing that in theory is very good at assembling
Speaker 6:  those building blocks all by itself. What are we doing here? You know what
Speaker 7:  I'm sort of thinking, I know I'm cutting off your list. You, but
Speaker 7:  like the rest
Speaker 5:  List I would say is bad.
Speaker 6:  I have one more.
Speaker 7:  This conversation has like made me feel like maybe Apple really isn't gonna
Speaker 7:  fail at AI in the same way. Like Apple failed at mobile me, but still pulled
Speaker 7:  through on cloud. Like, let me go a little bit to explain that a
Speaker 7:  little bit more. Like Apple intelligence as a term is a
Speaker 7:  thing that is not good or associated with good
Speaker 7:  things, with at least our community of people that work
Speaker 7:  and think about tech a lot.
Speaker 6:  No. And everyone, okay. I don't know anyone in my life who has, who is like,
Speaker 6:  you know, what's tight is Apple intelligence.
Speaker 7:  Well I think actually those people in your life, like they didn't even know
Speaker 7:  it was there. Right? True. And so like true, maybe this is Apple's like mobile
Speaker 7:  me moment in AI and now we're going to,
Speaker 7:  they will unlock the things that where AI will actually play a,
Speaker 7:  a big difference on the iPhone and this race towards making Siri. Like
Speaker 7:  maybe we let them go for a little bit and go and hopefully fix that. It's
Speaker 7:  very important. Don't let me say like, it isn't important. It is absolutely
Speaker 7:  important. If they do not get Siri right, they will lose to these other companies
Speaker 7:  that are building great conversational ai. But
Speaker 7:  like I have hope in the things we are talking about right now.
Speaker 6:  I do too. And it's actually, it's the kind of thing Apple historically does
Speaker 6:  really well, including with like machine learning and the neural engine
Speaker 6:  stuff. Like so much of what everybody is now calling AI features, we
Speaker 6:  used to just call like features. I
Speaker 7:  Mean like Right.
Speaker 6:  It's just software. So in so many ways
Speaker 7:  It's like stuff you use.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And So I think there, there's a bunch of things, right? Like the idea
Speaker 6:  that you can, you can essentially prompt your way through shortcuts is fundamentally
Speaker 6:  just a, an AI feature, but it's, we don't think about it the same way. Right?
Speaker 6:  And like one of the big things that has been rumored is AI
Speaker 6:  powered battery management, which is also just called battery management.
Speaker 6:  Like, it's just, it's, it's just software. But It is using went
Speaker 7:  Through this with a cloud too. Like this is where I'm going with the mobile
Speaker 7:  me iCloud situation. Right. Like mobile me was not
Speaker 7:  good.
Speaker 5:  Well we famously prompted a meeting where Steve Jobs said, while Mossberg
Speaker 5:  said we were bad, whose fault is this? And got mad at everybody. Right?
Speaker 5:  Not great. But when you say they, they came around, they like, they did iCloud
Speaker 5:  and then they iCloud big innovation. iCloud is not giving enough storage
Speaker 5:  by default so that you have to pay them more money every month.
Speaker 7:  I don know photos iCloud works pretty great
Speaker 5:  Except that it fills up your storage and you gotta pay them more money every,
Speaker 5:  like that that's what they solved in the cloud, right. They backed everybody
Speaker 5:  up and they, they made a business out of it by selling it's
Speaker 7:  Capitalism. I don't know what to tell you, but it's
Speaker 5:  True. It's not broken. The way that mobile me was the, the problem you have
Speaker 5:  with shortcuts with a, you know, a prompt
Speaker 5:  engineering interface is shortcuts doesn't work.
Speaker 6:  Right.
Speaker 5:  Right. So it, it would be really cool to be like, Hey, every single day
Speaker 5:  when I wake up I check these four apps. I need you to just go check 'em for
Speaker 5:  me and tell me if anything good happened. Right. This is like a thing that
Speaker 5:  a lot of people would love to automate and shortcuts
Speaker 5:  today will be like, I am drunk and
Speaker 5:  I didn't do it. Like, you're like, well you are a bad friend. Like
Speaker 5:  you're just untrustworthy and I'm gonna check the apps on my own. And you
Speaker 5:  can put a whole layer of AI on top of that. But the, the, the core engine
Speaker 5:  of that product doesn't work. And like, I don't know if Apple can solve that.
Speaker 7:  I'm even gonna see what my shortcuts are.
Speaker 5:  You have shortcuts. I
Speaker 7:  Have short because I've tried over the years like I have.
Speaker 5:  You're the only shortcut I ever had that was any good. It was, it was, I
Speaker 5:  would say Vergecast famous in like the mid
Speaker 5:  2010s when Mike McCarthy was the coach of the Packers and would
Speaker 5:  consistently lose in the playoffs. Sure. I had a shortcut on my home screen
Speaker 5:  that just tweeted the words Fire Mark Mike McCarthy. And I pushed
Speaker 5:  it without fail every
Speaker 6:  Sunday. That's pretty good.
Speaker 7:  All my, okay. This is amazing. This is very virtual. All my failed shortcuts
Speaker 7:  are for the garage.
Speaker 7:  I tried so hard. I must have tried so hard. Siri, where my
Speaker 7:  keys, I, yeah, I've got some stuff.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna fix you around his garage one of these days. No,
Speaker 7:  We fixed it. My garage is great. I didn't want, like I I'm killing it. My
Speaker 7:  garage is great. Neither you saw my garage. It's great. Every time I say
Speaker 5:  I did,
Speaker 7:  I was there. It worked. Hey Siri, I'm gonna say it on the PO so everyone's
Speaker 7:  garages will open or like the two people that set up their garages. Every
Speaker 7:  time I say, Hey Siri, open the garage. It works
Speaker 5:  On the other one of those people in my garage is open opening the garage.
Speaker 5:  Did it actually just do it?
Speaker 7:  Yes. And my wife is gonna text me and say there's
Speaker 7:  somebody in the house who opened the garage. Yep. Just got an alert. All
Speaker 7:  my devices just said smart garage door opener.
Speaker 5:  This is great radio.
Speaker 7:  Hey Siri, close the garage.
Speaker 5:  Oh my gosh. Joanna
Speaker 7:  Closing the garage.
Speaker 5:  Very good. Two things on the list are kind of the same thing. One on the
Speaker 5:  iPhone and one on the iPad. And they're basically, it's every, every year
Speaker 5:  it's rumored that they will fix the iPad in some way. Yep. And by fix I mean
Speaker 5:  just make it a Mac or add better multitasking. So the the idea, they'll
Speaker 5:  add a menu bar, they'll add freeform multitasking. And then on the
Speaker 5:  iPhone there's the idea that they will add like stage manager
Speaker 5:  or make it more like decks that lets it the iPhone itself connect to a monitor
Speaker 5:  and be a computer. If they did no AI stuff and they
Speaker 5:  were just like, you can plug your iPhone into a bigger monitor and use it
Speaker 5:  like a computer. I think people would lose their minds.
Speaker 6:  I would, I would just die of happiness that day.
Speaker 6:  It would be managed so badly. It would be such an
Speaker 6:  unusably chaotic feature. And I would love it to absolute pieces and use
Speaker 6:  it every single day.
Speaker 7:  But isn't that what they did last year?
Speaker 6:  No. So now you can have it so that you have a separate monitor when it's
Speaker 6:  plugged in, but it's, you're, you're essentially just moving an app
Speaker 6:  and, and that's only on the, that's like the, the iPad is like slightly better
Speaker 6:  at this. You can do stage manager on an external display. Like it's all well
Speaker 6:  and good.
Speaker 7:  Sorry. I mean, I guess I mean iPhone mirroring
Speaker 5:  To your, that's you can like plug a mouse in your iPhone and, and look at
Speaker 5:  it on a monitor. This is, you have multiple monitors on iPhone and then ideally
Speaker 5:  what you have, Google basically announced a riff on this. Like Samsung's
Speaker 5:  had decks for a while where you like plug your Samsung phone into a monitor
Speaker 5:  and a keyboard and you get like a Linux desktop with a weird Samsung browser.
Speaker 5:  Right.
Speaker 6:  Neil, I valiantly tried to do it. This
Speaker 5:  Is my dream. I tried to use this for a while. It was not good.
Speaker 5:  But Google's gonna do it and I think that might be really interesting. If
Speaker 5:  that's part of Android, we actually get proper Chrome instead of weird Samsung
Speaker 5:  stuff. I
Speaker 6:  Mean plug your phone in and it becomes a Chromebook is like the dream. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like it, it would work. It's just sitting there. Just
Speaker 7:  Like this doesn't make any sense for Apple. They want you to buy a Mac, they
Speaker 7:  want you to buy the iPad. So why would they want you to plug your iPhone
Speaker 7:  into a monitor?
Speaker 5:  'cause they gotta compete. They gotta do stuff.
Speaker 7:  I don't think so. They're
Speaker 5:  Behind over here. What now? Your phone's a banana. Like they gotta come up
Speaker 5:  with ideas like let's do it.
Speaker 7:  I just think there's like no, there's no upside for them here on this.
Speaker 6:  This rumor is pretty thin. Yeah, I don't believe it. And I would bet against
Speaker 6:  it coming true. But it also like Neli, I just think about something like
Speaker 6:  you and I every year sit in meetings with Apple executives and every year
Speaker 6:  the Apple executives tell us the story about how the devices are different
Speaker 6:  and they're for different purposes. And It is like, It is reached a point
Speaker 6:  now where a, I believe Apple when it says these
Speaker 6:  things that, that it perceives the devices to be differently. But I also
Speaker 6:  think It is so obstinately clinging to that idea that these devices
Speaker 6:  cannot run into each other. That they're leaving. Like
Speaker 6:  obviously good ideas on the table. I think
Speaker 5:  The iPad is fully in a, the where are you gonna go Zone.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like they don't need to have more iPad ideas 'cause like someone's
Speaker 5:  gotta watch Disney plus, like where are you gonna go? And like, so
Speaker 5:  it goes and eventually I think it will just ease its way
Speaker 5:  into being more Mac like that's just happening every year. But the idea that
Speaker 5:  the phone itself would get this deck stuff kind of interesting.
Speaker 6:  It would be super
Speaker 5:  Interesting. There's other stuff we, we can just go through 'em. You're gonna
Speaker 5:  get ChatGPT access on watchOS maybe. We'll see. There's
Speaker 5:  literally no rumors about Macs except they're gonna name it Tahoe. Which
Speaker 5:  Mark Berman reported like it was a big deal. He's like, they've been waiting
Speaker 5:  for this one for, to use the name like Tahoe. 'cause they all have houses
Speaker 5:  in Lake Tahoe. They
Speaker 7:  All have houses there. Yes. They always are on vacation there.
Speaker 5:  I think they should start naming them after small Midwestern towns. Mac s
Speaker 5:  Wisconsin is available. Craig, there's much that AirPod
Speaker 5:  rumors, sleep detection, camera control.
Speaker 5:  Sure. I mean what they, the AirPod update everyone wants is you can just
Speaker 5:  talk to a voice assistant. Yeah. Still waiting on that.
Speaker 6:  The camera control thing is neat. I will say I think I, I'm, that would be
Speaker 6:  just from like a pure UI perspective. I'm fascinated to see that one.
Speaker 6:  'cause it's like, are we gonna get to a point where half of everybody's photos
Speaker 6:  now just have them with like two fingers on one of their ears? Or is there
Speaker 6:  gonna be like, we're gonna get the new like millennial pause while everybody
Speaker 6:  clicks the thing and then waits for it to start the video? Like, I don't
Speaker 6:  know. I have so many questions, but it's, it's like, it's a smart idea to
Speaker 6:  let you have a remote on your AirPods.
Speaker 7:  I would use this feature once a year at like our family.
Speaker 7:  You like you do the big family picture and you set your, like right behind
Speaker 7:  you, David, you set your like camera up on the exactly like above the fireplace
Speaker 7:  on that little mantle. And then you have to like, like struggle with your
Speaker 7:  watch to figure out how to take the photo. I don't know why I would have
Speaker 7:  my AirPods on in that show.
Speaker 6:  It's because you're not a cool zoomer who just wears AirPods all the time.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I guess like, but when am I ever gonna wanna take a pho? Like, I guess
Speaker 7:  like you wanna take a selfie
Speaker 7:  but you have your arm out. I don't know. It's, it's, this is what I, I'm
Speaker 7:  really interested to see the video let they like show this feature in or
Speaker 7:  like me the still shot. Like what is the real life scenario when you wanna
Speaker 7:  touch your iPad, your AirPod to take a photo.
Speaker 6:  A bunch of people in our Slack were suggesting that Apple should let you
Speaker 6:  just hold it in your hand and do it and just have it as like a little discre
Speaker 6:  clicker. Oh, that would be very cool. Oh,
Speaker 7:  Like the selfie clickers that they like sell the little like cheap China
Speaker 7:  Exactly button with the little camera button. All right, fine. I'm sold
Speaker 7:  on
Speaker 5:  That. There's, I can't think of a more dad situation than me being like,
Speaker 5:  oh yeah, get this out. I'm gonna get my AirPod out of its case. Hold it upside
Speaker 5:  down. As opposed to just being like, someone else will take this photo.
Speaker 5:  We'll see,
Speaker 6:  I don't know. Joanna's out here going everywhere and met us Smart glasses
Speaker 6:  so she can take pictures of her kids. I don't know their AirPods.
Speaker 7:  Oh, I love my metas smartt glasses.
Speaker 7:  I don't think we're talking about that here.
Speaker 5:  All right, last one. There's like half a rumor. I just wanna
Speaker 5:  do a time check on it. People think we might see Apple Smart
Speaker 5:  Home device. I I think this is 0%
Speaker 5:  happening. What do you guys think?
Speaker 7:  Same.
Speaker 6:  I'm pretty close to zero. I think the, the only thing I can think of
Speaker 6:  is if you're Tim Cook right now and you've gone through all
Speaker 6:  this stuff and you've said, we need, we need, we
Speaker 6:  need a thing there. 'cause there isn't, there isn't a thing in here unless
Speaker 6:  the redesign, I
Speaker 5:  Think the redesign is the thing.
Speaker 7:  It is the thing.
Speaker 6:  I assume it'll be the thing that they mostly talk about and it, it probably,
Speaker 6:  but like, I don't know, maybe my hopes should be higher. My hopes are not
Speaker 6:  super high for what that's gonna turn out to be. But like
Speaker 6:  maybe you're Tim Cook and you look at this and you're like, we need a one
Speaker 6:  more thing to just like get everybody's minds going
Speaker 6:  and they just preview it in some way and they're like, apple
Speaker 6:  has gotten increasingly comfortable being like, here is the thing that's
Speaker 6:  coming later. And I, I could see it, I
Speaker 6:  wouldn't bet on it, but I also like, I could see the logic for like
Speaker 6:  running the video at the end of the keynote. I could
Speaker 5:  See it. Yeah. I just think they got really burned with Apple Intelligence
Speaker 5:  last year and they can't do that again. Yeah. I also think the point of
Speaker 5:  the smart home device is
Speaker 7:  Siri
Speaker 5:  To, is Siri is to say like, you can just talk to this thing and I'll talk
Speaker 5:  back to you and you can do automations by just saying out loud. Like,
Speaker 5:  when Joanna gets home, just open and close the garage door 50 times in a
Speaker 5:  row
Speaker 7:  Just to like, and celebrate that it doesn't do a dance.
Speaker 5:  We'll see, I mean it would be exciting. Jan, are you gonna be there? You
Speaker 5:  gonna be there? We're gonna,
Speaker 7:  There gonna have be there. I have made a list of three things I would like
Speaker 7:  to see. Yeah. Would you guys like to hear that? Yes. Yeah. Maybe you guys
Speaker 7:  can share your list. We should have prepared this, but my number
Speaker 7:  one want is an iMessage in group
Speaker 7:  messages, typing indicators for everybody.
Speaker 5:  Oh, that'd be good.
Speaker 6:  Like multiples. Each person gets a typing indicator. Yes. Just like
Speaker 7:  I like that. Every other chat app has basically, I would love them
Speaker 7:  to fix this reactions problem on the Mac.
Speaker 7:  It's happening to me right now. Why does this popup come up
Speaker 7:  all the time?
Speaker 5:  I don't know. What's popup, what are you talking about? The one where
Speaker 6:  You do a thumbs up and it does the, it does the wild thumbs up emoji
Speaker 7:  Or just like has an like an alert here that says like, your reactions are
Speaker 7:  enabled.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, it sucks. It's terrible. Just turn it off. It's terrible. No one wants
Speaker 6:  this. This has a 0% approval rate. This feature, turn
Speaker 5:  It off. This is a real like COVID idea that just needs to go away. I I
Speaker 5:  know what you're saying. Yeah, a
Speaker 6:  Hundred percent. My
Speaker 7:  Last thing is a Siri thing because this happens to me every morning when
Speaker 7:  I want to ask the home pod to do something,
Speaker 7:  but all the other Siri devices are doing them like my iPhone or my
Speaker 7:  watch. And I just think like some improvement. And I actually think that's
Speaker 7:  one of the main reasons not, there's a lot of reasons people hate Siri, but
Speaker 7:  I think that's one of the most frustrating, real like
Speaker 7:  consumer pain points of Siri, which is like, you want your Siri here to
Speaker 7:  do a thing, but the Siri in the next room is doing it or your
Speaker 7:  spouse's Siri or whatever is doing it. You
Speaker 5:  Like a Siri power user? Yeah. I mean I have that problem with Google Assistant,
Speaker 5:  but I don't have a problem with Siri. I'm
Speaker 6:  So sorry to everybody whose devices just went off 25 times. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  I'm sorry.
Speaker 5:  In the garage door.
Speaker 7:  But I, yeah, like I have home pods, I've got iPhones, I've got watches,
Speaker 7:  I've got iPads.
Speaker 5:  Anyway, I I I have Siri Wakeboards disabled on all of those things. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I have a multiple device wishlist too, which is if they just spend an hour
Speaker 5:  being like, we've made it so that the important notifications
Speaker 5:  come to your actual phone instead of disappearing into the void on
Speaker 5:  whatever other device we think is alive. Fair. Yeah. That would make me very
Speaker 5:  happy.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. The this, it would be an interesting version of
Speaker 6:  this year's WWDC if if instead of like announcing,
Speaker 6:  you know, big giant sweeping changes to how everybody is going to do everything.
Speaker 6:  They were just like, hi, we spent a year just fixing things.
Speaker 5:  Snow leopard baby.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, this is Snow Leopard. We're just doing it again. And because there's
Speaker 6:  so many little things, it's like, for me it's like fix headphone
Speaker 6:  routing so that when someone calls me on my phone, it doesn't ring
Speaker 6:  every device and decide to put my AirPods on my MacBook, which is closed
Speaker 6:  in my backpack. Like, what if we did that? Wouldn't that be cool?
Speaker 6:  There's just so many of those little things that it's like actually
Speaker 6:  if put enough of those together and I think you might win a lot of people
Speaker 6:  over in the course of like an hour of talking
Speaker 5:  About Can I, can I just issue my wonkiest feature request related to headphone
Speaker 5:  writing? Yes. You ready? So I've got, I I have a computer
Speaker 5:  as many people know, I have a computer and my computer has multiple monitors
Speaker 5:  and one of the monitors is like the video conferencing monitor and it's got
Speaker 5:  like a little log tech speakerphone daily. And I
Speaker 5:  can't be like the windows on this monitor. The audio needs to come outta
Speaker 5:  that thing. And the windows on this monitor need to use these speakers. That's
Speaker 5:  a good one. Yeah. And if I could just assign speakers to a display so that
Speaker 5:  audio playing from a Chrome window on this computer on this screen
Speaker 5:  came out of these speakers and audio playing on this screen came out of the
Speaker 5:  I would just be, that's it. That's WC I'd be like, apple stock probably should
Speaker 5:  go up 30 to 40% today. Like, don't worry about this AI
Speaker 5:  stuff they fixed. I can assign speakers to displays and
Speaker 5:  I think I might be the only person in America with this problem. So
Speaker 7:  No, I have this problem not as like, I don't have as many monitors as you,
Speaker 7:  but I I feel that problem.
Speaker 7:  I this should, this should be the one more thing that Tim Cook announces.
Speaker 7:  It's a, you know, they did all the stuff around the calculator last year
Speaker 7:  was that last year? It's a tariff calculator.
Speaker 5:  Rough.
Speaker 6:  The numbers just magically change every five minutes for no reset.
Speaker 7:  It's like you wanted to calculate it today. Here you go.
Speaker 5:  That's what AI is good for is non-deterministic math
Speaker 5:  where you're like, how much does this cost? It's
Speaker 5:  All right, we're back. Yeah, switch two. Launch week. We, we we, we started
Speaker 5:  with Apple Rumors 'cause you know it's developer season and there's a lot
Speaker 5:  going on over there and also the Switch two literally came out this morning.
Speaker 5:  So there's not much to say except David has one
Speaker 6:  I do.
Speaker 5:  Lots of people on our staff have them actually. Yeah. What's it, what's it
Speaker 5:  like? Are you happy? It's,
Speaker 6:  Well I I really like it so far. So let me, let me, I had a really interesting
Speaker 6:  experience trying to get it. So the, it launched at midnight
Speaker 6:  and we've been covering kind of the runup to it and there are like discords
Speaker 6:  upon discords of people trying to figure out how to get one and gaming the
Speaker 6:  system and keeping an eye on what's in stock and when, and there are, I
Speaker 6:  live in a pretty sort of dense urban area, so there are lots of places around
Speaker 6:  me that were open at midnight, but there are two, two doors apart from each
Speaker 6:  other. There's a Best Buy and a target and I was like, all right, one of
Speaker 6:  them will have it for me. So I went over at like 10 30 last night
Speaker 6:  just to see, I was like, if, if the line seems plausible, I'll
Speaker 6:  sit in it and try and get one at midnight, like a hundred plus people in
Speaker 6:  line, super nuts. So I just turned around and bailed, came home
Speaker 6:  and I was like, well I guess I'm not getting a switch. I won't have one to
Speaker 6:  talk about on the podcast today. And then this morning I'm
Speaker 6:  sitting around looking at my phone ignoring my child as I am want to do from
Speaker 6:  time to time and I just like went to target.com and was like, I wonder if
Speaker 6:  they, and it just said like, oh, in stock at the Target right next to the
Speaker 6:  Best Buy. So I literally just drove to Target and bought
Speaker 6:  a switch to, it was like, it was the most mundane launch
Speaker 6:  day experience you could possibly imagine. And I got there and there
Speaker 6:  was a steady sort of rush of people, like as I was walking into people walked
Speaker 6:  out with switches, both of whom were like clearly pumped that they had scored
Speaker 6:  a switch. But then I went over and there was a case full of them. There were
Speaker 6:  probably 15 of them just sitting in this case. They had three bundles left.
Speaker 6:  The woman in front of me bought one for her 13-year-old son for his birthday
Speaker 6:  and was like the relief on her face that she had managed to get
Speaker 6:  like, I cannot describe to you how happy this woman was. And then I got one
Speaker 6:  and then the person behind me got the last bundle and nobody wanted anything
Speaker 6:  other than the bundle that comes with Mario Kart World. And so there's just
Speaker 6:  a bunch of them lying around. And So I just like shot just sort of
Speaker 6:  without even meaning to just like came home with a switch to
Speaker 6:  set the thing up, giant pain in the ass and then
Speaker 6:  like posted something and being like, I can't believe how easy this was.
Speaker 6:  And I have heard from so many other people who were like, yeah, Nintendo
Speaker 6:  put us through this weird rigamarole for months trying to, you had to
Speaker 6:  get an invitation from Nintendo for a specific time to
Speaker 6:  like insanity and then you could just wake up and go to Target and get one
Speaker 6:  like truly bizarre launch day experience. Should
Speaker 7:  I get one?
Speaker 6:  You should definitely get one.
Speaker 7:  What accessories does the bundle come with?
Speaker 6:  The bundle comes with, it comes with the dock,
Speaker 6:  it comes with the weird
Speaker 6:  controller thing that I can't find. It
Speaker 7:  Comes with that pillow. Amazing.
Speaker 6:  It comes with a pillow. I also bought the the camera. You
Speaker 7:  Bought the camera. I was gonna ask, so you have to buy the camera separately,
Speaker 7:  right?
Speaker 6:  I have not set this up yet. There's the, this was the switch to camera I
Speaker 6:  think was like $55, which is absurd for like a little camera on
Speaker 6:  a stick. And then there's the pro controller, which everybody on our team
Speaker 6:  tells me I need to buy, which is $85. So I'm like, I, I'm
Speaker 6:  like 650 bucks deep on this thing by the time I actually get it
Speaker 6:  fully like up and running. But I will say I played it a bunch this morning
Speaker 6:  because it was, it was journalism, it's for work and my,
Speaker 6:  like the first game I played was, was fifa, which secondly called
Speaker 6:  EAFC 25. And I get emails every time. I don't say that I'm aware of the name
Speaker 6:  of the game. It's still called FIFA unbelievably faster, like night and day
Speaker 6:  Faster from the switch that I was using. And that was the main thing I was
Speaker 6:  wondering about. There's lots of new games. Mario Kart World is, is
Speaker 6:  big and very fun and I've played a little bit of it,
Speaker 6:  but just the, the like raw speed upgrade of the old games that I had
Speaker 6:  been annoyed by on an 8-year-old console. Like it, like
Speaker 6:  new games, which was
Speaker 7:  Very exciting. Now I'm tempted to go buy one. I don't wanna buy one, but
Speaker 7:  my 7-year-old is like, he doesn't actually know that there's a new switch
Speaker 7:  out, I don't think. But I, Ima like It is a maddening
Speaker 7:  experience. Experience downloading games on his switch.
Speaker 7:  Oh yeah, like the slowness, the everything is just like the parent, the parental
Speaker 7:  control. I mean, talk about software that needs a refresh. Like, I don't
Speaker 7:  know if that's been done. Is that done on the, on the two? Is there like
Speaker 7:  it's
Speaker 6:  It's sort of stylistically similar, but it's it's clearly not the same software,
Speaker 6:  if that makes sense. Yeah. Like they didn't blow up the model, but It is,
Speaker 6:  It is noticeably better and faster in basically every interaction
Speaker 7:  That might be worth it. There's so is one
Speaker 6:  I've been, I've been very impressed so far, but what's been really interesting
Speaker 6:  is like the, the vibes around this launch are not that good, I don't
Speaker 6:  think we've been talking a lot about this internally, but also like
Speaker 6:  there were, there were these big lines, but also Nintendo
Speaker 6:  didn't do reviews ahead of time for a couple of different reasons, which
Speaker 6:  is like fine. But I think also there is something to the like
Speaker 6:  coverage in the lead up to this thing that would've been exciting for people.
Speaker 6:  But then also everybody I talk to is like, eh, I'll buy it when there's better
Speaker 6:  games.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That's kinda how I feel. You're six 50 deep into Mario Kart World and
Speaker 5:  like, eh, I can wait.
Speaker 6:  So that's where a surprising number of people seem to have landed. And I
Speaker 6:  think there's, there's the Donkey Kong game coming. Like they had the, the
Speaker 6:  announcement that the Nintendo direct of all these games, what in April.
Speaker 6:  And people came away from that being like, great, there's an awesome slate
Speaker 6:  of games. Lots of stuff is coming, but on day one it really is a
Speaker 6:  $500 Mario Kart machine. Like in, in a really real way.
Speaker 7:  But the bigger screen
Speaker 6:  With the
Speaker 5:  Bigger screen, yeah, it, I mean that's a big boy. Hold it up again. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  It is big. So this is the switch too. Oh yeah.
Speaker 6:  And I'll, I'll just, just to compare,
Speaker 6:  this is the regular switch so It is like, oh
Speaker 7:  Yeah, look at that.
Speaker 6:  A meaningfully bigger thing. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I mean the only game we play on the switch is UNT huddled Goose game. And
Speaker 5:  I think we can, we'll make it through,
Speaker 6:  Think about how fast the goose will be.
Speaker 7:  We play mar we tend play a ton of Mario Kart my son's obsessed with
Speaker 7:  among us.
Speaker 5:  Oh, I gotta start doing that with Max
Speaker 7:  Obsessed. So I mean like that like very simple 2D game I'm sure is not
Speaker 7:  necessarily any better on the switch too. So we're good. All
Speaker 5:  Right. We're gonna have lots of switch coverage coming 'cause like so much
Speaker 5:  of our staff has a switch to, they wanna talk about it a lot.
Speaker 5:  I suspect next week David, you're gonna have a whole switch to
Speaker 6:  Situation. So yeah, we, I can just tell people the schedule here. So Tuesday
Speaker 6:  is gonna be our big post WWDC episode and then I would say most of next
Speaker 6:  Friday and then all of the following Tuesday is all gonna be switched stuff
Speaker 6:  because that's when we'll have we, we will have reviewed the thing, we'll
Speaker 6:  have played all the games, we'll have tried all the accessories. Like we're,
Speaker 6:  we're sort of deliberately waiting a minute to like really do this thing
Speaker 6:  big. So we will, we have a lot more coming. And also call the hotline
Speaker 6:  and send us emails if you have questions because like two thirds of our staff
Speaker 6:  has one of these so we're, we're gonna get a lot of 'em on to talk about
Speaker 6:  it with us. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  All right Jen, I know you gotta, you gotta jump out here real quick before
Speaker 5:  we go. There is a bunch of new news but meta's like
Speaker 5:  experimental smart glasses, aria, you are like, you're, you know,
Speaker 5:  you're the Meta glasses Stan on the show. What are you, what you,
Speaker 5:  and then they're gonna start do wait, I mean you wear them and you take pictures.
Speaker 5:  I do. That's more than did
Speaker 7:  You wear them?
Speaker 5:  I bought the Clear Ray bands when they announce them and I was so
Speaker 5:  excited to get them and I bought them and I put them on my face and I was
Speaker 5:  like, no thank you. And I sent them back. You're
Speaker 6:  Mad that you have a big head. It's, it's fine.
Speaker 5:  They were not big enough for my head, like email a
Speaker 6:  Bed. I also have a big head like I get it, but it's not Meta's fault that
Speaker 6:  we have big heads. I
Speaker 5:  Was just like, I have good cameras that are fun to use and this is, I don't
Speaker 5:  know, what am I doing? And then they, there's some Quest stuff coming
Speaker 5:  along. Like there's a little bit of an arbitrage between Apple and Meta about
Speaker 5:  like exclusive VR content. I don't know, what do you think of the,
Speaker 5:  these new glasses? Because it seems like no one has solved the
Speaker 5:  display issue for augmented reality glasses, but we're adding more and more
Speaker 5:  sensors to the prototypes every single day.
Speaker 7:  Well I feel like this is what like a step towards, more towards the Orion
Speaker 7:  type of dream
Speaker 5:  And Orion were the augmented reality glasses that cost $10,000 a unit that
Speaker 5:  Meta could not manufacture at scale.
Speaker 7:  Right. And this is what a,
Speaker 7:  something that's supposed to come out later this year for researchers to
Speaker 7:  work with and developers to work with, I believe. So there's like some
Speaker 7:  real actual movement towards this, which
Speaker 7:  I think has like been what Meta does that I I think
Speaker 7:  and I think intentionally does that Apple doesn't, right? They're like building
Speaker 7:  out in front and there's just saying, hey, here's where we are having issues,
Speaker 7:  here's where we're trying to build. I think we're seeing Google try to do
Speaker 7:  that to a degree right now with, I get very confused, the
Speaker 7:  XR glasses, which are not the XR headset
Speaker 7:  that's supposed to come out this year, am I? Is that right? Right.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, there's there's the headset, which is Project Mohan, which I always
Speaker 6:  remember 'cause it's such stupid names. It's a very, and then there's
Speaker 5:  So SI Sundar referred to the headset as goggles. Right? Goggles. Which is
Speaker 5:  which an incredible term.
Speaker 7:  Oh, interesting. Well I loved that actually from him. He was like, we're
Speaker 7:  gonna have goggles or we're gonna have glasses.
Speaker 6:  Do you think he knows that Google already made a thing called goggles a
Speaker 6:  long time ago. Course they did.
Speaker 5:  No, no. Mohan
Speaker 7:  But Mohan back to Mohan. Mohan is
Speaker 7:  also like considered under Android xr, is that right? Yes. Like
Speaker 7:  is that Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Very confusing. But what's happening, like, it's like everyone
Speaker 7:  has these two paths going, right? Google, Meta Apple, we think
Speaker 7:  Apple at least on the glasses, but for sure they do. There are some efforts
Speaker 7:  that are going towards the goggles as Sundar said, and some
Speaker 7:  efforts that are obviously going towards the glasses and hopefully eventually
Speaker 7:  they think these things will converge and they'll, they'll come together.
Speaker 7:  But like the focus on the goggles right now is really interesting
Speaker 7:  that we had the, the journal had this story that Meta is trying to go after
Speaker 7:  Disney with exclusive content. It's like, is this
Speaker 7:  a world like we're gonna probably hear more about the Vision Pro last year.
Speaker 7:  Like where like you just feel like no one's really
Speaker 7:  using that type of device at scale. I mean mean not,
Speaker 7:  not we don't feel like It is. It's true. The numbers are there, right? Like
Speaker 7:  the number people aren't, but yet they still keep pushing into
Speaker 7:  those directions. My guess though is like for the hope that eventually that
Speaker 7:  stuff comes when we're down the path that it comes to the glasses.
Speaker 5:  Well so you look at these new glasses and I mean it's just a
Speaker 5:  bunch of sensors really, right? They've added more spatial
Speaker 5:  mics, they've added ambient sensors, more track
Speaker 5:  movement trackers, more eye tracking cameras. Like no one has solved the
Speaker 5:  problem of the display, right? The or Meta is Orion
Speaker 5:  glasses were an attempt to solve the display problem, which is why they were
Speaker 5:  so expensive and un manufacturable at scale, right? So like we can put stuff
Speaker 5:  in front of your eyes. The Google glasses we just saw were like,
Speaker 5:  we're gonna put stuff in front of your eyes. But they were teeny tiny field
Speaker 5:  of view and it wasn't like mapped to reality in any way. It was just a,
Speaker 5:  it's basically a screen in front of your face. There's this big problem where
Speaker 5:  no one has solved the core component of augmented reality glasses,
Speaker 5:  which is putting stuff on a screen that is like mapped
Speaker 5:  to the world. And I think that's why everyone is doing these like ski
Speaker 5:  helmets
Speaker 7:  Because they can do it there. You
Speaker 5:  Can do right camera pass through VR xr
Speaker 5:  and then it's like you built a simulator of the thing, but at least you're
Speaker 5:  working on it while you know, some mad scientist is solving your
Speaker 5:  display problem. But it's none of it's convincing. Well
Speaker 7:  That's how I know like how we all felt about the Vision Pro, but it's like
Speaker 7:  they still keep going at it. Which I guess if you're as the size of these
Speaker 7:  companies, you can, well
Speaker 5:  David, you were saying this, the sensor problem is so big that maybe they're
Speaker 5:  just focused on that while someone figures out the display problem. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I mean I think the, the thing I keep hearing about smart glasses is that
Speaker 6:  the people who are making them are like everybody is wildly underestimating
Speaker 6:  how hard every single part of this problem is. Like I remember years ago,
Speaker 6:  some of the folks who were running this at Google were like, you don't understand
Speaker 6:  how different a thing It is that I have to make a product that
Speaker 6:  if it gets in your way at the wrong moment, once it has ruined
Speaker 6:  the success of that product. Like if, if I, if I push a notification while
Speaker 6:  you're asleep or like, I don't know, whatever having sex, like
Speaker 6:  once the whole thing falls apart and they were like, the bar for the user
Speaker 6:  interface is so high and what it means is I have to have perfect awareness
Speaker 6:  at all times of both you and the world and both
Speaker 6:  directions of that are incredibly hard. And So I think what's interesting
Speaker 6:  to me about this Meta thing is like
Speaker 6:  the idea of how do we put all this stuff in these glasses that can just look
Speaker 6:  at your eyes all the time, right? It's like blink detection and and directional
Speaker 6:  like following your eyes where you go and looking at per eye detection, like
Speaker 6:  this stuff is so hard and it's such cutting edge science and It is just
Speaker 6:  one piece of the equation here.
Speaker 5:  I just have, sorry I just have this, you said this and now I have to think
Speaker 5:  about Micro Mark Zuckerberg is like, I need to know if you're banging,
Speaker 6:  We got a hotline question maybe 10 days ago that I will, we will answer on
Speaker 6:  the show from somebody who was like, I have smart glasses.
Speaker 6:  Do I need and they have my prescription, do I have to take them off before
Speaker 6:  I have sex? Otherwise there's cameras on my face while we're having sex.
Speaker 6:  And I have been not, I have not been able to stop thinking about it ever
Speaker 6:  since. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  I was wondering where that came from. David, get
Speaker 5:  Some other glasses bro.
Speaker 7:  It came from nowhere in your example.
Speaker 6:  That was the question, do I need dumb glasses for the bedroom and smart glasses
Speaker 6:  everywhere else?
Speaker 5:  Nowhere. It's like your Instagram followers have sent you three
Speaker 5:  messages and it's like no.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, pretty sure you're throwing those things in the trash the first time
Speaker 6:  that happens.
Speaker 5:  You know what I mean? Like a pure growth hacky Instagram notification would
Speaker 5:  be would be horrible
Speaker 6:  Vs. Song. Heard that hotline question and immediately demanded to talk about
Speaker 6:  it with me on the show as did my wife. So we will come back to that. But
Speaker 5:  The idea that like getting all the sensors, I mean we, we've gone
Speaker 5:  through this list so many times. Smart cloud, you need the display, the displays
Speaker 5:  are impossible but no one can literally, no one has built one. Yeah that
Speaker 5:  works at scale. That is manufacturable. You need to put compute in
Speaker 5:  there that you need a lot of it to detect the world and then
Speaker 5:  like immediately overlay graphics and then you need connectivity and
Speaker 5:  then you need a battery that can support all that compute and that connectivity
Speaker 5:  in real time that is running all the time. And then you need like a content
Speaker 5:  moderation system so that if you're looking at the United States capital
Speaker 5:  on January 6th, it doesn't tell you like this was the site
Speaker 5:  of Donald Trump's greatest triumph. Like you've got a million problems to
Speaker 5:  solve. Right. And bang detection apparently is very important to everyone.
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 6:  A big one.
Speaker 7:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I don't sex mode we're years away from this. I think this is why you get,
Speaker 5:  I think it would be better if the industry is like these mixed reality VR
Speaker 5:  headset. They are the simulators. Yeah. Like I think if
Speaker 5:  everyone was honest that these are not products meant to scale, but this
Speaker 5:  is how we're gonna work our way towards building the appropriate applications.
Speaker 5:  It might just like change how everyone perceives them.
Speaker 6:  But I think like also to your point Joanna, about the, the content thing,
Speaker 6:  I think one of the reasons everyone is chasing that idea so
Speaker 6:  hard is that it feels doable, right? If if
Speaker 6:  it's just we're gonna build all this wild stuff, but if the first thing we
Speaker 6:  can build is just like a sick personal television that you wear on your
Speaker 6:  face, maybe that'll work for people. And I'm, I'm suspicious of the idea
Speaker 6:  that that's a thing anybody wants, but I think It is, It is at least like
Speaker 6:  It is a version of this that feels achievable for these companies. And so
Speaker 6:  they are like pushing relentlessly after it.
Speaker 7:  Yeah and I mean obviously that's what Apple's been marketing
Speaker 7:  still with the Vision Pro, right? It is like your personal tv,
Speaker 5:  Have you seen an ounce of Vision Pro marketing in past five months? They
Speaker 6:  Just put out like a Bono video that no one watched
Speaker 5:  Bono's everywhere right now
Speaker 7:  Any of the pitches you get from pr, anything they post to the newsroom
Speaker 7:  like is all about the content. It's really not beyond that
Speaker 7:  at this point. Right. Watching sports, watching this, watching that. Like
Speaker 7:  maybe using your Mac right, they had the improvement or the Apple
Speaker 7:  intelligence came for that. I mean, yeah.
Speaker 5:  Did you see the price right clip where people try to guess the price to the
Speaker 5:  Vision Pro?
Speaker 7:  Yes. Amazing. It
Speaker 6:  Was very good.
Speaker 5:  People were like a hundred dollars.
Speaker 7:  It's funny as we have you guys, somebody I believe wrote about these there
Speaker 7:  you, you've seen these, these are the X reel glasses that are Yeah, with
Speaker 7:  the space top. I can't get them on right now. Those
Speaker 5:  Are pretty hot I have to say.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I mean they look pretty sick John. I
Speaker 5:  Mean they look like Wayfarers but they are very, very chunky.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, they look awesome. Everyone here keeps telling me that I look like,
Speaker 7:  you know, one of those like, like glasses with a mustache.
Speaker 5:  But they have a cord that's a cord.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. The cord connects to the laptop.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I'm gonna go ahead and say we're far away from air glasses.
Speaker 7:  I'll say the only use of those that I do like, there's everything
Speaker 7:  aside. I do like having multiple monitors when I don't ha when I'm away
Speaker 7:  from my computer.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that's fair. Joanna, you used to go and we should also take a break
Speaker 6:  here, but I, we have not heard what you think Johnny,
Speaker 6:  ive and OpenAI are building and we got a little bit of stuff this week. There
Speaker 6:  was like Johnny, ive did an interview with L Powell jobs talking about the
Speaker 6:  unintended consequences of the iPhone and how they wanted to fix all the
Speaker 6:  harms that smartphones have done and chat. GPT wants to be like a
Speaker 6:  universal life assistant, but we still don't know anything. What do you think
Speaker 6:  they're building?
Speaker 7:  I don't think they're building glasses. I mean they've basically said that,
Speaker 7:  right? I, there was a lot of chatter at Davos this year
Speaker 7:  there, like before this deal was announced, but there was a lot of
Speaker 7:  chatter already about the partnership between these two. Yes. And this Swiss
Speaker 7:  South everybody's
Speaker 6:  Clinking champagne glasses and talking about open eye.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. We're like, what are they building? What are they building? There was
Speaker 7:  chatter about the headphones, like earbuds with cameras or
Speaker 7:  like, which would make sense. But
Speaker 7:  I believe now like people have shifted and said they don't think that
Speaker 5:  I've been straight up told it's not headphones.
Speaker 6:  Interesting.
Speaker 5:  I'll just, I I don't think, I think it's like a, I think it's like a necklace.
Speaker 7:  Oh I hope it's not a necklace. But I will say, So I did a piece a few weeks
Speaker 7:  ago on these recording devices, Neil, I went to a dinner with me and I was
Speaker 7:  wearing the recording device. It's very weird. And I tested both the
Speaker 7:  Limitless and the B. These are both like AI recording devices. They listen
Speaker 7:  all the time and they summarize and make notes and to-do lists for you.
Speaker 7:  And I will say there were some very positive
Speaker 7:  uses of those. So if they can figure out
Speaker 7:  the privacy stuff and they can do this in a smart way where like
Speaker 7:  you can talk to your chat GT assistant all the time, but it's also listening
Speaker 7:  maybe looking.
Speaker 7:  And again, they need to get the privacy stuff right. There's a lot of
Speaker 7:  potential there. But all
Speaker 5:  Those things had phone apps, right? The interface was a phone app.
Speaker 7:  They all had phone apps.
Speaker 5:  It was just a little piece of hardware.
Speaker 7:  But you don't have to like be looking at that. You just live your life with
Speaker 7:  the device listening all the time. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I just don't think Johnny, Ivan and Sam Altman are building a device whose
Speaker 5:  fate lies with an iOS phone app. Yeah, yeah. Like that. That just seems
Speaker 5:  really hard to me. So by the way, it's all the same problems minus the display.
Speaker 5:  They need compute, they need connectivity and they need a battery. It needs
Speaker 5:  to be unobtrusive. And then I think they've got this other problem, which
Speaker 5:  is if at the end of the day the way that you set it up and use It is by
Speaker 5:  configuring it on an iOS device. Like, ooh, you, you've accomplished very
Speaker 5:  little.
Speaker 7:  I think that though, he said that in the video, he said that in the, I love
Speaker 7:  San Francisco, I wanna have sex with San Francisco video. Like
Speaker 5:  Why did this podcast get so horny in the past 10 minutes?
Speaker 7:  I know. Well I just, David dude, so we could say sex. So here we,
Speaker 7:  It is
Speaker 6:  The energy I bring. This is what we're doing.
Speaker 5:  Alright. Right. So Jony, Ive wants to bang San Francisco and he said something
Speaker 5:  about the iPhone during that time.
Speaker 7:  They said some, they said about the laptop and that we've moved beyond because
Speaker 7:  they're
Speaker 5:  Still this, they call those legacy products,
Speaker 7:  Legacy products that are still staples in your life. Like,
Speaker 7:  I mean, I don't remember exact wording, I don't have the transcript, but
Speaker 7:  there was a, there was a lot of like implication. Like we're not gonna replace
Speaker 7:  those things. We will still have them. This is the new thing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I don we'll see, I'm, I just, the only thing I know is
Speaker 5:  I, I've heard a lot of chatter about headphones and I was kind of told
Speaker 5:  it wasn't headphones and there's a lot of chatter about app pendant and I
Speaker 5:  have no idea if it will be appendant. That's it. That's what I got. I love
Speaker 7:  An, I love a new necklace,
Speaker 5:  But I, I think they've got, I think they have to build something that does
Speaker 5:  not rely on a phone. If they build basically a phone accessory, they,
Speaker 5:  they're, they're not gonna get to where they wanna go.
Speaker 7:  But then you have the same issues of the humane pen, which we, I you guys
Speaker 7:  have talked about, but like that had cellular built in and that was a big
Speaker 7:  problem. Yes, it was a big problem for that device. It might
Speaker 7:  have been the biggest problem for that device. There was a lot of it. Sorry,
Speaker 7:  let's not let's,
Speaker 6:  It's a long, it's
Speaker 7:  and I would be happy if they were
Speaker 8:  All right, we're back.
Speaker 5:  I'm excited to see Joanna in just mumbling to ChatGPT GBT in the corner of
Speaker 5:  WWC for a couple of days. It'll be good.
Speaker 8:  It's
Speaker 6:  Really like, give it to Joanna. She's like, she doesn't half-ass things,
Speaker 6:  you know what I mean? Like when Joanna decides to make AI her life,
Speaker 6:  she goes for it.
Speaker 5:  She's going for it. I mean, she's writing a book about it, making our lives.
Speaker 5:  So she's going for it.
Speaker 5:  That's the information. Still flavorful, I would say Very
Speaker 5:  flavorful. And in fact, I know it's gonna be flavorful 'cause David, it's
Speaker 5:  time.
Speaker 6:  Ugh. It is. It's once again it's summer, but It
Speaker 6:  is still time for America's favorite podcast. Within a podcast
Speaker 6:  future Webby award-winning podcast within a podcast.
Speaker 6:  Brendan Carr is a dummy. Eli, how does this keep happening? Like
Speaker 6:  every week I'm like, I, I have a line in the rundown that just says, Brendan
Speaker 6:  Carr is a dummy. And I'm like, oh God, there's not gonna be any links. This
Speaker 6:  is gonna be so great. We can finally not talk about this stupid man. And
Speaker 6:  yet here we are. We do this every time
Speaker 5:  We do and and there's no shortage of it. I will say this week usually
Speaker 5:  we get notes that are like, he's not a dummy, he's a threat to free speech.
Speaker 5:  And I I agree with those people. The thing is that he's also very stupid,
Speaker 6:  Right?
Speaker 5:  Right. So he, he does all these investigations and threatens the companies
Speaker 5:  for not being racist enough, threatening car stuff, stuff.
Speaker 5:  But he's also not good at executing or thinking more than
Speaker 5:  one step ahead. Right? He's a dummy. I i i, I
Speaker 5:  can't say this clearly enough. Brendan Carr, the chair of the Federal Communications
Speaker 5:  Commission aren't the regulator in charge of our nation's communications
Speaker 5:  infrastructure is a dummy. And sometimes it
Speaker 5:  just expresses itself because, well the only thing he succeeds in doing
Speaker 5:  is shooting himself in the foot. And I think it's starting to,
Speaker 5:  to weigh, unlike the other people at the
Speaker 5:  FCC, 'cause they're all quitting.
Speaker 5:  So we're down, we're supposed to have five FCC commissioners. And
Speaker 5:  depending on the president's party, you're supposed to have three of the
Speaker 5:  majority party and two of the minority. Right. And then, you know, you kind
Speaker 5:  of, the votes go either way. But you have this like bipartisan
Speaker 5:  agency committee that like, makes decisions altogether and ideally they make
Speaker 5:  unanimously 'cause they've done the hard work of hashing out good policy
Speaker 5:  from both sides. You know, stuff.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Government stuff, government stuff. The thing you're supposed to do. Brendan
Speaker 5:  is such a dummy that he's not doing that at all, where he's just like issuing
Speaker 5:  proclamations about how there should be more censorship in America or whatever
Speaker 5:  he wants. And I, I, I don know what he's doing. So this
Speaker 5:  week, two different FCC commissioners from different
Speaker 5:  parties just resigned. Jeffrey Starks, who has been on the Rich House before
Speaker 5:  as a guest Democratic commissioner, quit goodbye. I think he, people
Speaker 5:  kind of knew he was gonna leave, but he's gone. And then surprisingly, Nathan
Speaker 5:  Simington, who is sort of just like another
Speaker 5:  to like another revolving door, Verizon
Speaker 5:  to, he's just been there for a while. He was an assistant to, to pie in,
Speaker 5:  in car in different ways. And then he became a commissioner. He bailed too.
Speaker 6:  He was appointed by Trump in the, in the first Trump administration, wasn't
Speaker 6:  he? Yep. Yeah. Cool.
Speaker 5:  I don't have, I don't have a high opinion. These guys are all just sort of
Speaker 5:  like, we're here to do what the cable companies tell us. Do like fine, like
Speaker 5:  your, your interchangeable util But you would think that he'd be riding high
Speaker 5:  in a car FCC 'cause you know, he gets rubber stamp stuff
Speaker 5:  too. Yeah. But, but no, he's, he's gone and it, the, the reports are
Speaker 5:  that he wants to do other things. Presumably he's gonna go work for one of
Speaker 5:  our nation's telecoms like that revolving door is just gonna spin really
Speaker 5:  fast and spit out millions of dollars in lobbying fees. And Nathan Une is
Speaker 5:  gonna collect them. I know this is what happens to all of them. It's a lot
Speaker 5:  gpi the CEO of our nation's preeminent wireless industry lobby right now.
Speaker 5:  That's, that's how it goes. But, so we're down to two. We're supposed to
Speaker 5:  have five in a Trump administration. You have three Republicans and two Democrats.
Speaker 5:  And we're down to one Democrat, Anna Gomez, who's literally touring the company
Speaker 5:  saying that Brendan Carr is a threat to democracy and free speech right now.
Speaker 6:  And it's also like operating under the assumption that she's going to be
Speaker 6:  fired at any minute.
Speaker 5:  I think. I think she's trying to get fired.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So, and to, to prove a point, which is I think one of the reasons they're
Speaker 5:  not firing. What if it's just Brendan? Do you see what I'm saying?
Speaker 5:  And then there's Brendan, oh my God. And he's, he's pushed everyone else
Speaker 5:  out. And the government is such a disaster now. 'cause Elon and Trump are
Speaker 5:  fighting that like there's no chance we're gonna nominate
Speaker 5:  four more FCC commissioners, two of whom have to be Democrats
Speaker 5:  by by statute. Yeah. Like It is not gonna
Speaker 6:  Happen. No.
Speaker 5:  So we're, we're down to Brendan and Anna. I, they don't even, they don't
Speaker 5:  even have like a quorum. Like they can't do anything anymore because they
Speaker 5:  don't have enough of them.
Speaker 6:  Right? 'cause they'll just, they'll just, it'll be one-to-one on everything
Speaker 6:  and then they just
Speaker 5:  Leave. And there's a lot of stuff to get done. Like there's BroadB broadband
Speaker 5:  to roll out in America. There's spectrum auctions to be held. Like there's
Speaker 5:  all this stuff to do. And Brendan is so distasteful and so stupid
Speaker 5:  that he, you know, Brendan his way into not having
Speaker 5:  a functional FCC, very good Brendan, you succeeded
Speaker 5:  and the only other person who works there now hates you so much that she's
Speaker 5:  literally touring the country calling you a threat to free speech.
Speaker 5:  Well done. Just in, when I think of like pure
Speaker 5:  political operators, you know, like people who like really
Speaker 5:  just like work the system. Like they're playing a video game.
Speaker 5:  It's not Brendan Carr like I, whatever this is, is not bad outcome.
Speaker 5:  So that's one very funny, just like pure idiocy.
Speaker 5:  So distasteful that everyone else quit, including the other Republican who
Speaker 5:  is himself kind of a Toby. Insane. So then there's like,
Speaker 5:  this one is a winding road, but it might be even funnier.
Speaker 5:  So you will recall Brendan launched an investigation
Speaker 5:  into Dish network's use of spectrum to build a,
Speaker 5:  a what was supposed to be a Na Nation's fourth wireless network. And
Speaker 5:  he said, you're not using the spectrum. I'll come to why they are not using
Speaker 5:  that spectrum. But the reason he launched that investigation is because
Speaker 5:  starlink put out a report saying it had investigated dish all by
Speaker 5:  itself and they weren't using the spectrum. Right. That is just corruption.
Speaker 5:  That's not how that's supposed to work Straightforwardly. That's not how
Speaker 5:  that's supposed to work. You're not like, oh, starlink has a good point.
Speaker 5:  We should trust them and take the spectrum away from another private company.
Speaker 5:  I'm doing a great job, says me. It's like, so that they launched
Speaker 5:  this investigation. Now I believe wholeheartedly the Dish network
Speaker 5:  is not using the spectrum appropriately because it turns out there is not
Speaker 5:  a fourth wireless network in America. Correct. If you see it, if
Speaker 5:  you see the fourth nationwide wireless network that is
Speaker 5:  striking fear in a T-Mobile, you let me know. But I, I've looked around
Speaker 5:  and by look around I meant waved my phone in the sky.
Speaker 5:  However you look around it's not there. It's not there. It's supposed to
Speaker 5:  be there because Brendan's predecessor, a Jet Pi allowed
Speaker 5:  T-Mobile to buy Sprint consolidating the wireless industry, robber stamping
Speaker 5:  some telecom stuff. This is what these guys do. And made them promise
Speaker 5:  they would turn over Spectrum to EchoStar Dish Network and they would light
Speaker 5:  up a fourth wireless network, a 5G network. And EchoStar made
Speaker 5:  all these promises about how they were gonna take over Boost and then use
Speaker 5:  these MVNO agreements with at and t and T-Mobile and use that to
Speaker 5:  bootstrap a network while they built cutting Edge
Speaker 5:  5G network using open ran technologies running on
Speaker 5:  AWS. We've covered this at length and a G Pi
Speaker 5:  hoodwinked fully into believing this and said, okay, we're gonna let
Speaker 5:  T-Mobile by Sprint, we're gonna cut the amount of competition in America
Speaker 5:  and wireless. Sure. Prices go up, dish Network, we'll show up to save the
Speaker 5:  day and restore competition. It is 100 years later they have 20
Speaker 5:  subscribers. They still run Boost Mobile, but they're constantly roaming
Speaker 5:  onto at and t. None of this exists. Just none of this exists. This is
Speaker 5:  failed Republican policy from the first Trump administration.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Starlink has said they're not using the spectrum. We'd like it.
Speaker 5:  No process. Brendan's like, yeah, I'll give it to my buddy. Elon. Elon has
Speaker 5:  now fallen completely out with Trump. Like as we are speaking,
Speaker 5:  they continue to tweet at each other. Yep. About how much they hate each
Speaker 5:  other. It that seems like a poor political move from Brendan who
Speaker 5:  can't see two feet in front of his face and EchoStar Dish
Speaker 5:  network. What have they decided to start doing? They're gonna start missing
Speaker 5:  their interest payments on the loans they took out for the spectrum so they
Speaker 5:  can declare bankruptcy and get out of this whole deal. Wow.
Speaker 5:  They're actively missing their payments on the spectrum now. And they're
Speaker 5:  doing it in response to this investigation. They're saying, you investigated
Speaker 5:  us, we're we're headed for the exit. So Brandon,
Speaker 5:  who again threw his lain with Elon Musk to, to take Spectrum from a company
Speaker 5:  that wasn't using it under a plan that his own predecessor launched,
Speaker 5:  has now put himself on the wrong side of Donald Trump, his putative boss.
Speaker 5:  And in a position where EchoStar might outplay him by just declaring
Speaker 5:  bankruptcy, we will still not get a fourth wireless network in America out
Speaker 5:  of this super. Not gonna happen, but we'll burn a bunch of money in
Speaker 5:  jobs in the process. We're gonna burn a bunch of money in Jobs. Jobs. And
Speaker 5:  I, I think Brendan has, because he's so dumb, didn't see the
Speaker 5:  two moves ahead of him that perhaps Charlie
Speaker 5:  Ergen, the, the CEO of EchoStar, the parent of Dish would have another card
Speaker 5:  to play. He's just a moron. Right.
Speaker 6:  This is just what we're doing here.
Speaker 5:  That's been Brendan Carr's dummy. It is always Brendan, if you can show up
Speaker 5:  on the podcast and defend these moves or any others, you, you're welcome
Speaker 5:  to come. We, we'd love to have you, dude, you're not doing
Speaker 5:  anything else. All of your coworkers quit.
Speaker 6:  There's literally no one else. Anna Gomez is on tour. Go on tour, go on
Speaker 6:  tour to The Vergecast. That's, this is what we asked for.
Speaker 5:  Make, make the case that you didn't just get thoroughly outplayed by
Speaker 5:  like a Wildcat satellite operator who's gonna declare bankruptcy
Speaker 5:  and you're gonna have to resell the spectrum and you're probably not gonna
Speaker 5:  be able to just give it to starlink the way they want.
Speaker 6:  I also, I I was just reading Brendan Carr's blog post
Speaker 6:  on the FCC website that he wrote sort of announcing these changes.
Speaker 6:  He's just so annoying.
Speaker 5:  Like,
Speaker 6:  Lemme just read you a paragraph. There's a lot of time between now and our
Speaker 6:  scheduled June 26th commission meeting. So I wanted to lay out a couple of
Speaker 6:  items that I would like to get done at the meeting if we can stay tuned on
Speaker 6:  that front. What does he mean by that? I just said stay tuned. That's all.
Speaker 6:  I just read
Speaker 5:  Words. No, that's what he wrote. That's what he wrote. I, none of that was
Speaker 5:  me. What does he mean by that? In the third person
Speaker 6:  He wrote, stay tuned on that front and then in italics, what does he mean
Speaker 6:  by that? And italics, I just said stay tuned. We always make a final decision
Speaker 6:  about the commission meeting and its agenda closer to the meeting date. We
Speaker 6:  will do so again here. That's a whole paragraph of no words.
Speaker 6:  What are we doing, Brandon?
Speaker 5:  He's, again, he's not smart. I I I know a lot of people are like, you should
Speaker 5:  call the segment something else. You know, you should really, we we do get
Speaker 5:  this note. Yeah. You should really make sure that people understand the threat.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. There's some threats. I've called him a traitorous more on many times
Speaker 5:  on our podcast, which is not regulated by the FCC Sorry buddy,
Speaker 5:  but he's just stupid. Yeah. And like you, you see it
Speaker 5:  play out. Like he doesn't, he can't think two moves ahead. Anyway, again,
Speaker 5:  I repeat Brendan, you're, you're welcome. I know you listen, I, I know that
Speaker 5:  you hate it. If you can show up, you can show up on decoder. You know, people
Speaker 5:  come on decoder all the time. They answer their questions, they do their
Speaker 5:  best. They leave, you know, they can show up here. David will tell some jokes
Speaker 5:  about you to your face.
Speaker 6:  I'll just read him blog posts. You can yell at him. I'll just edit his writing
Speaker 6:  on his stupid website.
Speaker 5:  Anyhow, that's been Brennan Carr's dummy America's favorite podcast with
Speaker 5:  him. Podcast.
Speaker 6:  That was beautiful.
Speaker 5:  David, I think we need a, we need a little bit of a pal cleanser that we
Speaker 5:  gotta
Speaker 6:  You wanna talk about the Fedi verse for a minute?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I would love to. That's my favorite thing.
Speaker 6:  So Fed Forum, which is like a big fedi verse
Speaker 6:  event is this week, but did you see the, the news
Speaker 6:  about this tool called Bounce?
Speaker 5:  Oh this is the one that lets you move, move things around?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, so Bounce is basically, it's, it's pretty
Speaker 6:  straightforwardly just like a migration tool from Blue Sky
Speaker 6:  to Mastodon.
Speaker 6:  Not all that exciting. It's built on top of this thing called, I think it's
Speaker 6:  called Bridge Fed, which is some like underlying work that ties the two things
Speaker 6:  together. But it basically, it connects these two accounts so that
Speaker 6:  you can move all of your stuff from one to
Speaker 6:  the other and still be able to post where you were. This is like, this is
Speaker 6:  the stuff, right? It's just like every once in a while we get an announcement
Speaker 6:  or a new product or a thing that people are explaining that It is like
Speaker 6:  this is the stuff, this is the, yeah. What we're doing when we talk about
Speaker 6:  the Fedi verse and like bounce a in the fact that It is kind of
Speaker 6:  messy to explain. And the reason they call it bounce is because
Speaker 6:  they're trying to get you to bounce from blue sky to Mastodon, which is like
Speaker 6:  pretty good,
Speaker 6:  but it's like the idea that I can just pick up my stuff on a social
Speaker 6:  network and put it down on another social network. Like, that's it baby.
Speaker 6:  That's the stuff. Yeah. And we're like starting to see this,
Speaker 5:  There's a bunch of stuff out of Feta Forum where it's like new ways of
Speaker 5:  thinking about the protocols. I really, broadly, I think we spent the last
Speaker 5:  year or so talking about capabilities,
Speaker 5:  like here's some technologies that will enable capabilities and the Fed versus
Speaker 5:  absolutely that thing. Activity, pub, app, protocol, whatever. It's like,
Speaker 5:  look at these core technologies and you gotta build them. And now, and same
Speaker 5:  as rave, look at these models and now they can lie to you. And now we're
Speaker 5:  in the products phase and like you can see the Federalist products are, are
Speaker 5:  coming pretty fast and furious now.
Speaker 6:  It it's taking a little longer than I would've hoped. I will say
Speaker 6:  I think there's been, that was so much energy
Speaker 6:  18 months ago that I think got a little bit
Speaker 6:  wasted, is too strong, but didn't quite get fully utilized. And I
Speaker 6:  think a lot of people were excited about what Threads is doing. And the,
Speaker 6:  the threads fed averse momentum seems to have slowed pretty aggressively.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Blue Sky is doing great. Blue Sky is a version of the
Speaker 6:  Fedi verse, but is not sort of the whole story in a way. So it's like
Speaker 6:  we, we continue to be like right at the edge of the thing, but I think you're
Speaker 6:  right that the answer is just people just have to start building things people
Speaker 6:  like to use. Yeah. And then, and then we're gonna start to be there and It
Speaker 6:  is like every, every version of this that comes
Speaker 6:  out where it's like we're, we're getting another piece of the puzzle together.
Speaker 6:  And I think especially the stuff that touches Blue Sky, because that's just,
Speaker 6:  it's just the one with the juice right now. Right. And so like any piece
Speaker 6:  of it that is like, let me just attach a little bit of the open web to Blue
Speaker 6:  Sky, I think is, is super exciting. And I suspect there
Speaker 6:  will be more stuff coming out of the, the Feta forum. There was a lot of
Speaker 6:  news at the last one. I suspect there'll be more this time. But It is like
Speaker 6:  the, the momentum is still there. I just wish it were like shipping a little
Speaker 6:  faster, you know what I mean?
Speaker 5:  I feel like there was a, the momentum slowed because you had the VHS
Speaker 5:  versus beta moment with at Protocol and mast on and Activity
Speaker 5:  Pub and Threads. Yeah. And everyone thought threads are just make activity
Speaker 5:  pub win and Then it turns out Meta runs it.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And that just made
Speaker 5:  pick VHS for paid
Speaker 6:  is like everything is just going to be feeds. Yeah. And you can create feeds
Speaker 6:  from anywhere. You can consume feeds from anywhere and feeds can be anything.
Speaker 6:  And it's like, that is an incredibly powerful idea that we have like only
Speaker 6:  just begun exploring. And So I think every, again, every, every piece of
Speaker 6:  that that I see, I'm like, this is, this is the stuff.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's gonna get there. Yeah. The this is, it's it's product
Speaker 5:  time. You gotta, you gotta make some products, everybody. Yeah. It'd be great
Speaker 5:  if Apple's like, we're gonna do a full hour on the Fedi verse. That's
Speaker 6:  Best. We're bringing back ping's. Sure. And it's the Fedi verse this time.
Speaker 5:  That'd be great. All right. We are at WWC next week. We'll have lots of that.
Speaker 5:  We have lots of switch coverage to come, but
Speaker 6:  We should say, by the way, our, our WWC episode is going to be late on Tuesday
Speaker 6:  just because the way WWDC works. We're not gonna get to record until late
Speaker 6:  on Monday. And then we will, we will have it as up as early as we can on
Speaker 6:  Tuesday. But if you're like waiting for the episode for your morning commute,
Speaker 6:  just know that I'm sorry. And it will be an afternoon commute kind of show
Speaker 6:  for you. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I mean, have to get to a hotel room and record the episode after wwc. Exactly.
Speaker 5:  Just like us. Lots to come. That's Vergecast thanks to
Speaker 5:  Joanna.
Speaker 8:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 8:  you. Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one.
Speaker 8:  The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network.
Speaker 8:  Our show is produced by Will Por, Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer. And
Speaker 8:  that's it. We'll see you next week.