# Transcript
ID: 2838717b-60c1-4a46-a454-b72974ad0736
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-973751159165593575/-704454816661464998/s93290-US-5049s-1742297508.mp3
Description: Handheld gaming looks like the future — so why isn't it more popular? The Verge's Sean Hollister joins the show to talk about some new data about the handheld console market, what it says about the Steam Deck's dominance, whether the Switch 2 might change everything all over again, and why Sony and Microsoft don't appear to be in the game at all. After that, David reports on his trip to Florida to see TGL, the golf league aiming to bring the sport to new places and new fans, with the help of a truly enormous amount of technology. Finally, we answer a question on the Vergecast Hotline about iPads — and more specifically, one particularly good reason to upgrade to the Air or the Pro.
Speaker 1:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of the Handheld Gaming
Speaker 1:  Wars. I'm your friend David Pierce and I am sitting here messing around with
Speaker 1:  a new phone. It's the nothing Phone three A Pro.
Speaker 1:  I think this phone's actually sort of interesting. Nothing in general has
Speaker 1:  like big cool ideas about smartphones, but I've talked a bunch
Speaker 1:  already on this show about how I suspect this is going to be a
Speaker 1:  relatively uninteresting year in smartphones. Flip phones
Speaker 1:  and foldable phones aren't quite ready to go fully mainstream.
Speaker 1:  And I think the, the iPhones and galaxies and pixels of the world
Speaker 1:  just aren't gonna be that interesting. So one of the challenges for myself
Speaker 1:  this year has been to find new, interesting ideas about smartphones.
Speaker 1:  And I think the thing in this phone, it's called the
Speaker 1:  Essential Key, and it's basically a button on the side that is
Speaker 1:  designed to be an AI input. It's not like visual
Speaker 1:  intelligence in the way that, you know, apple is trying to do stuff for all
Speaker 1:  the complicated multimodal systems. This is just, right now, frankly, it's
Speaker 1:  a glorified voice recorder. But the idea is that it can also do things like
Speaker 1:  take screenshots and just ingest information from
Speaker 1:  you as you use your phone and then store it, organize it, make sense of it.
Speaker 1:  That's actually a thing AI is set up to do relatively well and strikes
Speaker 1:  me as a pretty good idea. It's super, super limited on this phone. It like
Speaker 1:  barely can do any of the things that I thought it might be able to do. But
Speaker 1:  cool idea and seems like the sort of thing that if AI is gonna come into
Speaker 1:  smartphones, this is what it should look like. Anyway, we are not here to
Speaker 1:  talk about really AI or smartphones today. We are gonna do two
Speaker 1:  things on the show. First, I'm gonna talk to Sean Hollister about some
Speaker 1:  data that he got about how the Steam Deck is doing compared to all
Speaker 1:  of the other gaming handhelds out there and what it says about
Speaker 1:  where the Steam Deck and the switch to and all the other handheld consoles
Speaker 1:  might go next. After that, I'm gonna tell you a story about
Speaker 1:  a golf tournament that I went to. I went to West Palm Beach, Florida to see
Speaker 1:  a thing that is, if not the future of golf, A
Speaker 1:  future of golf, or at least it desperately wants to be. And I think what
Speaker 1:  that looks like and what that means and how you even do that is
Speaker 1:  really interesting. So I'm gonna tell you a little bit about it. Then we
Speaker 1:  have a question from The Vergecast hotline. Lots of fun stuff coming in this
Speaker 1:  episode. I'm very excited about it and I hope you enjoy it. All that is coming
Speaker 1:  up in just a second. But first this thing lights up all the time and
Speaker 1:  it beeps at me and nothing has a lot of weird interface ideas that
Speaker 1:  I need to go turn off. So I'm gonna go do that. This is the verse
Speaker 1:  cast. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  Welcome back. All right, let's talk about video games.
Speaker 1:  I'm not the world's most qualified person to talk about the
Speaker 1:  bleeding edge of video games. I should just be honest about that. I have
Speaker 1:  a PS four right here and I have an original Nintendo Switch.
Speaker 1:  That's where I do most of my gaming. I've been waiting to upgrade
Speaker 1:  to a PS five. I don't know what four for something.
Speaker 1:  It's just that all of the games I wanted for so long were on the PS four
Speaker 1:  and then I mostly became a Switch person and I play some PC games too,
Speaker 1:  but like I am not the person, the
Speaker 1:  absolute cutting edge of PC graphics for everything, which I think might
Speaker 1:  be the reason I'm so interested in handheld gaming, which seem like
Speaker 1:  they have the possibility to give me what I want, which is something easy
Speaker 1:  and portable and uncomplicated, but also give me
Speaker 1:  access to this new generation of games. We've talked about handheld gaming
Speaker 1:  a lot on this show from the switch to the Steam Deck to
Speaker 1:  all this stuff from I Neo and other companies that are flooding the internet.
Speaker 1:  But it turns out that the market is a little bit different than I expected
Speaker 1:  in some ways that I was a little bit surprised by Sean Hollister
Speaker 1:  on our team, got some data, he's been testing all of these things and he
Speaker 1:  understands where we are in this space and where it's headed. So I figured
Speaker 1:  this is a good time to get into it. Let's check it out. Sean Hollister,
Speaker 1:  welcome to the show.
Speaker 5:  I'm
Speaker 1:  Back. I get to do this a couple times with you recently. This is very exciting
Speaker 1:  for me.
Speaker 5:  It's so good to be here.
Speaker 1:  We were talking just before we started recording about why we are both so
Speaker 1:  interested in gaming handhelds and I think the reason for you is because
Speaker 1:  you, you use a lot of them and care about them and are interested in them
Speaker 1:  and have them. I have no rational reason for my interest
Speaker 1:  in this category. I think, I think gaming handhelds are like the most interesting
Speaker 1:  hardware category on earth. And yet the only thing I play video games on
Speaker 1:  is my like first gen Nintendo switch
Speaker 1:  that sucks. Just like this is the thing I care about. You
Speaker 5:  Say it sucks, but a moment ago before we started recording, you told me that
Speaker 5:  you were happy with it. I
Speaker 1:  Am happy with it. So the thing that I learned is we, we talked about this
Speaker 1:  last fall and you guys, I would say did a
Speaker 1:  heroic job of trying to sell me on a Steam Deck, which I did not buy.
Speaker 1:  Oh, potentially should have. Oh, and, and we should come back to that. But
Speaker 1:  I did not buy it. And what I did instead was just resolve to never unplug
Speaker 1:  my switch ever again. And now It is, It is a, It is
Speaker 1:  a console that sits here on my desk plugged in and it works just fine.
Speaker 1:  That's it.
Speaker 5:  I thought the Nintendo Switch was a revelation. What it came about. It, it,
Speaker 5:  it really felt like that as soon as they got over the hump of it just being
Speaker 5:  only a Zelda machine, it was like, this is amazing. You have games
Speaker 5:  that are the same games when you're docked and the same games on the go.
Speaker 5:  They're the full games. You can play through full games now wherever
Speaker 5:  you are at any given moment on the toilet of course. And everywhere else
Speaker 5:  you might go in your daily life, not just there in front of your big
Speaker 5:  4K tv. And so that is, that was a revelation for me.
Speaker 5:  And then the Steam Deck when it came along was, and now
Speaker 5:  those games can be this giant library of games that you've owned on
Speaker 5:  PC for a decade, right? And it can be the new PC games that are coming out
Speaker 5:  and it's not just restricted to, again, Zelda and Mario. And I'm like,
Speaker 5:  okay, revelation on top of Revelation, I am so sold. You just
Speaker 5:  need to figure out all these bugs valve. And they did over the course
Speaker 5:  of like three to nine months and then they started selling more of
Speaker 5:  them. And apparently though the market isn't as big as anybody
Speaker 5:  hoped or expected, who talks about this as lovingly as you and I do. So yeah.
Speaker 5:  So let's, let's actually
Speaker 1:  Start there. I think there, there are a few pieces of what you just said
Speaker 1:  that I wanna, I wanna poke at. But you wrote a story recently where
Speaker 1:  you, you got some new data about
Speaker 1:  how well the Steam Deck is doing, but also how well the Steam Deck is doing
Speaker 1:  compared to its competition. Can you just walk me through a little bit of
Speaker 1:  what you learned?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. So I'll walk through it my way first and then I wanna
Speaker 5:  walk through it like the way everybody else has reacted to it. Okay. 'cause
Speaker 5:  the two very different ways, I wrote a story and I, I'm just gonna read you
Speaker 5:  the headline really quick. Three years later, the Steam Deck has
Speaker 5:  dominated handheld PC gaming was, was my headline,
Speaker 5:  which I put out on, on on the third birthday of the system launching. So
Speaker 5:  I was like, okay, let's do this as a curtain razor, why not? I didn't actually
Speaker 5:  grab this data thinking it was going to be for the third birthday. It just
Speaker 5:  happened to be a nice coincidence that when I started writing it, I was like,
Speaker 5:  you know, if I hold onto this two more days, love when that happens, can
Speaker 5:  publish shit on the birthday, why not? But so, so so I I, I went
Speaker 5:  out and a, I asked, I actually got tipped off during cs. Somebody was
Speaker 5:  like, I asked them, you know, well how big is the total addressable market
Speaker 5:  for, for gaming handhelds anyway? And they're like, well according to the
Speaker 5:  latest IDC numbers, it's prob IDC numbers. Well let me
Speaker 5:  talk to the guy at the IDC who compiles numbers. Yes. And, and I was,
Speaker 5:  I was so happy that guy at the IDC who compiles numbers, whose name is Louis Ward
Speaker 5:  by the way, was willing to share some of this with me. What
Speaker 5:  I thought this was going to be about was, we know the Steam Deck has sold
Speaker 5:  millions, multiple millions, but how big
Speaker 5:  a deal is it compared to the Windows handouts? 'cause there've been Jesus
Speaker 5:  rogue Ally, ROG Ally, for those of you who are
Speaker 5:  nitpicky about that, it's
Speaker 1:  RI don't wanna hear all it's, it's rock. Listen, I understand an acronym.
Speaker 1:  It's Rock.
Speaker 5:  I say rock I get made fun of every time it's great Lenovo
Speaker 5:  Legion go the MSI Claw and so on. And
Speaker 5:  at least two of those have had a big presence at retail. You know, best
Speaker 5:  Buy, you go there, you can buy two different kinds of Asus r Ally
Speaker 5:  and you can buy your Lenovo Legion Go. I was like, well the things that everybody
Speaker 5:  can just go buy, they probably have a big chunk of the market right now.
Speaker 5:  Right? And so what Lewis told me, what he showed me was that
Speaker 5:  not so much the Steam Deck is like at probably around
Speaker 5:  4 million and the Windows handhelds are probably at around
Speaker 5:  2 million total. So total, this is cumulative. Not
Speaker 5:  not per year. This is like since, but, but you're getting into the way everybody
Speaker 5:  else is reading this. So since, since 2022 when the Steam Deck came out,
Speaker 5:  and of course the Steam Deck had the entire first year, 2022 to itself.
Speaker 5:  So yeah, big head start building a new category.
Speaker 5:  What a lot of other people took away from my story is
Speaker 5:  handheld PC gaming is going nowhere fast. It's tiny.
Speaker 5:  It is tiny compared to PCs it's tiny compared to, you know, probably desktop
Speaker 5:  graphics cards probably tiny compared to gaming laptops. It's very
Speaker 5:  tiny compared to Switch of course, which sells more in
Speaker 5:  a quarter than all of these have sold in three years. Even now that everybody
Speaker 5:  knows the Switch two is coming, yes,
Speaker 1:  There are somewhere in the range of like six-ish million handheld
Speaker 1:  game consoles out there that are not the switch.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It with the, with the exception of China. China
Speaker 5:  is like the currently, and they're working on this, it's currently a hole
Speaker 5:  in the IDCs estimates. By the way, these are estimated shipments
Speaker 5:  not right. Actual consoles and not sold. So
Speaker 5:  shipments. So theoretically shipments does include things like
Speaker 5:  handhelds that are currently at retail and haven't been sold through yet,
Speaker 5:  or handhelds that are being stockpiled. It also may include, because IDC
Speaker 5:  is basing these estimates off of supply chain things like big batch orders
Speaker 5:  of components going from somewhere here in, you know, in Taiwan or somewhere
Speaker 5:  in China to the United States or to Europe. It is worldwide.
Speaker 5:  But the, it may also include, you know, they bought a whole bunch of
Speaker 5:  components for a handheld that hasn't been chipped or even maybe announced
Speaker 5:  yet. We don't know for sure that these are like actual handhelds,
Speaker 5:  but given what some of the other estimates out there, given what we Valve
Speaker 5:  has said about the multiple millions, these numbers seem right. The
Speaker 5:  one hole is China, IDC has not necessarily gone
Speaker 5:  one to look at what is being sold in China because again, it's tracking
Speaker 5:  supply chain components that are being shipped out right. Of China.
Speaker 5:  So maybe there's a decent sized handheld gaming market in China.
Speaker 5:  IDC is also not tracking the few, and I've always called them boutique
Speaker 5:  sellers of handheld gaming PCs like GPD in
Speaker 5:  Neo one X Player. There's other like ones like
Speaker 5:  this that might also sell a bunch of Windows handheld gaming
Speaker 5:  PCs. But when we look at like their Kickstarters, we're talking about
Speaker 5:  thousands of units, not millions of units. So we don't
Speaker 5:  think they're making a big dent yet. We just don't know.
Speaker 1:  So even in the very best case scenario, we're dealing with a
Speaker 1:  very small thing here.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. It's small and, and, and is small. Like,
Speaker 5:  is that good at three years? That's, that's like the question and
Speaker 5:  AMD's, Frank Ezor will be like, we're inventing a new category. Sure.
Speaker 5:  Three years, you know, this is great. You look over at Smart Glasses,
Speaker 5:  you look over at Metas Ray bands, metas Ray bands are like at
Speaker 5:  what, 2 million? And so, you know,
Speaker 5:  they're, they're talking about ramping up quickly to 10 million per year
Speaker 5:  at some point. Just Essilor Luxottica, the glasses
Speaker 5:  maker working with meta and smart glasses. Just one firm, pretty big firm.
Speaker 5:  Just one firm from 2 million cumulative to like
Speaker 5:  10 million annually. Maybe there's room
Speaker 5:  for Wind for Windows or for, sorry for, for Handels that play
Speaker 5:  Windows games, let's put it that way. Sure. To go that direction,
Speaker 5:  but I don't know, it's, it's not growing fast. And it
Speaker 5:  did grow a bit and then it shrunk in 2023
Speaker 5:  the year that that not that, that it was
Speaker 5:  no longer just valve with the Steam Deck, it was also the R-O-G-L-I, it was
Speaker 5:  also of Allegion. Go
Speaker 5:  say shipments, estimated shipments nearly doubled.
Speaker 5:  But then they have again in going into 2024. So
Speaker 5:  interesting. Maybe a bit of trough of disillusionment. Maybe a lot of people
Speaker 5:  bought those ROG allies and Le Legion
Speaker 5:  Ghost or even Steam Deck and decided to return them or decided that
Speaker 5:  they had as many as they wanted in the market and they, nobody needed to
Speaker 5:  buy another one. Right now. Maybe it's a wait and see thing. Maybe some of
Speaker 5:  those people are like, well why would I buy a Steam Deck when I'm
Speaker 5:  sure a Steam Deck too is coming and better things on the way.
Speaker 1:  I have, I have different, the, let me throw two theories at you. Yeah. And
Speaker 1:  I, I, and I wanna see if what you think about either of these. I think
Speaker 1:  there is one theory that holds that
Speaker 1:  actually the people who play PC games and the people who
Speaker 1:  want a relatively speaking low powered machine
Speaker 1:  for playing games on the go is like the, those Venn
Speaker 1:  diagrams do not overlap at all. Right? Like if I'm the person who is building
Speaker 1:  a gaming tower to play games on my giant
Speaker 1:  screen with my integrated GPU, I don't want a Windows handheld
Speaker 1:  because it won't play the games the way that I want. That's one theory. I'm
Speaker 1:  not positive how much I buy that theory, but that's one theory. The other
Speaker 1:  theory is just that these devices aren't very good. And
Speaker 1:  I think the, which is why I wanna talk about the Steam Deck, because I think
Speaker 1:  the question of how good is the Steam Deck really is actually like the most
Speaker 1:  interesting question in this category right now because all the other
Speaker 1:  ones seem to suck in, in one form or another. Like you just reviewed
Speaker 1:  the, the Lenovo Legion Go s which was supposed to be the one and
Speaker 1:  super Duper isn't the one. And it, it just seems to me that
Speaker 1:  maybe what is happening is this is like a discerning group of people
Speaker 1:  who would want something like this right now. And they're looking at all
Speaker 1:  of these devices and saying, oh, these are bad. I'm not going
Speaker 1:  to buy any of them. Is it just that simple?
Speaker 5:  I wanna accept but also reject this idea
Speaker 5:  that these things aren't very good. That, that it's like such a discerning
Speaker 5:  audience. Okay. What I see anecdotally,
Speaker 5:  but all the time are reports of people,
Speaker 5:  you know, in Reddits and social media, in my comments in
Speaker 5:  et cetera saying, my gosh, I didn't know I could
Speaker 5:  do this kind of gaming on the go. Or I'm
Speaker 5:  elapsed game PC gamer or, or a console gamer who never got
Speaker 5:  into the PC space to begin with. And wow, there's just
Speaker 5:  this, all these riches at my fingertips now. All these riches, literally
Speaker 5:  the palm of my hands I'm taking with me everywhere. I
Speaker 5:  don't see a hundred of these every time I walk into an airport. Sure. These
Speaker 5:  days I'm seeing like two or three when I walk into the airport, I'm like,
Speaker 5:  okay, that's great. It's great to see that many of them. I think that if,
Speaker 5:  if, if, if I were to put my finger on one thing, I think it's awareness
Speaker 5:  that a good one of these exists that the Steam
Speaker 5:  Deck is very good or that one
Speaker 5:  of the windows handhelds with a Steam Deck like os on It
Speaker 5:  is very good, fair that, that, that's like a, a a nerdy niche, which most
Speaker 5:  people are not gonna go. That they're not gonna go install Bazi on their,
Speaker 5:  on their thing and ex right? And if, if they're coming from the I'm aaps
Speaker 5:  PC gamer, they're probably not going all the way to Bazi right away. I think
Speaker 5:  that that message could well be getting washed out
Speaker 5:  by a bunch of other things that seem to suck. Because if I'm
Speaker 5:  getting into this market and I'm like, handhelds are super cool
Speaker 5:  and my first, and, and and, and then I go to a store and I look for a handheld,
Speaker 5:  and that handheld is the original ROG ally or the
Speaker 5:  original Legion Go and, and I'm like, oh, I heard
Speaker 5:  about this Steam Deck thing, but windows windows are where my games are and
Speaker 5:  that windows thing looks great and, and, and it looks like it's
Speaker 5:  not too much money either those things are on sale. I might well go
Speaker 5:  buy that Asos RG Ally or Lenovo Legion go and then be like,
Speaker 5:  what is this bullshit? The battery dies after like an hour.
Speaker 5:  These these controls feel a little bit weird in my hands.
Speaker 5:  I have to touch the screen constantly to get to, to make things,
Speaker 5:  to go where I want and to launch this program and, and to like,
Speaker 5:  I have to, when when you open the box on one of these things, you, you plug
Speaker 5:  it in, you turn on your As or your, your Lenovo and then you
Speaker 5:  spend 45 minutes installing mandatory updates and adding
Speaker 5:  away prompts for black dark pattern prompts for various pieces
Speaker 5:  of Microsoft software that you don't want subscriptions that you would never
Speaker 5:  pay for before you even get to the windows of desktop to begin
Speaker 5:  installing your games through game launchers that may not be there yet. And
Speaker 5:  then you have to go and touchscreen your way through a web browser to go
Speaker 5:  download them first. And what is this bullshit? If that is your
Speaker 5:  first experience getting into handheld gaming, handheld PC of gaming,
Speaker 5:  you're gonna think that the whole category is, is bullshit too. And
Speaker 5:  I don't know why Microsoft has not addressed this meaningfully. If you
Speaker 5:  instead trust a company that's mostly known
Speaker 5:  for games, not for hardware and has had some
Speaker 5:  weird failings in hardware in the past to
Speaker 5:  ship you a console that uses Linux, an operating system that you're
Speaker 5:  likely wholly unfamiliar with and do not know whether it will
Speaker 5:  play your games. And in some cases people will rightfully say will not
Speaker 5:  play certain games. It did not play your fifa. It did not, it's not gonna
Speaker 5:  play. Yeah. It, it, it's not gonna play your, your Call of duty, which
Speaker 5:  you please do not try to play Call of Duty on a seven inch screen
Speaker 5:  regardless of whether it's Windows or Linux. Right? If you
Speaker 5:  jump through the mental hoops of, ooh, there
Speaker 5:  seems to be a lot of mental friction here. And then you turn that thing on,
Speaker 5:  you will be confronted with a wonderful experience that is designed
Speaker 5:  for handheld gaming and plays lots of games you can get very
Speaker 5:  cheaply. Games often will come out on PC before they
Speaker 5:  come out on consoles if they are, especially from the indie variety. Like
Speaker 5:  if you wanted to play tro, which is now an amazing addiction on phones.
Speaker 5:  Yep. It was an incredible addiction on handhelds like the Steam Deck first.
Speaker 1:  Totally. So I, that's a really interesting way of thinking about it. 'cause
Speaker 1:  I think that is a piece of that that is just like these
Speaker 1:  devices make you ask a lot of questions and ensure a lot of
Speaker 1:  things that buying a PlayStation doesn't, right? Like you buy
Speaker 1:  a PlayStation and that you are going to plug it in and It is going to play
Speaker 1:  all of your games the way It is supposed to play your games and the
Speaker 1:  whole handheld space, even the things that do that
Speaker 1:  passively well, it's not as straightforward and
Speaker 1:  simple and obvious and you have to just crosscheck
Speaker 1:  compatibility and quality and do a lot more work.
Speaker 1:  So what we need then, this is where I come around to like where on earth
Speaker 1:  are Sony and Microsoft in doing this? Because what we need
Speaker 1:  is the thing that is just the simple one. And, and my next
Speaker 1:  question for you was gonna be why hasn't the Switch
Speaker 1:  sort of turned everybody onto the idea that this is a thing that's possible
Speaker 1:  because it's been so successful, it's been out for a long time. It is truly
Speaker 1:  mainstream. The idea that like I can hold this device in my hands and play
Speaker 1:  video games. But I think it's also true that Nintendo just sort of permanently
Speaker 1:  exists off to the side of the rest of the gaming world. So what we need
Speaker 1:  is something that is as straightforward and simple and mainstream
Speaker 1:  as the switch, but for these other kinds of games. And that is the thing
Speaker 1:  I feel like the Steam Deck has not yet accomplished. And it
Speaker 1:  seems like you agree with that.
Speaker 5:  The Steam Deck has not accomplished it in the market yet, but
Speaker 5:  it has accomplished becoming the wake up call
Speaker 5:  for those companies you just named for Microsoft. Okay. And for Sony,
Speaker 5:  Microsoft and Sony for a very long time have known the
Speaker 5:  wisdom in the industry is that you cannot compete
Speaker 5:  with Nintendo on a handheld. Every
Speaker 5:  handheld that is faced off against Nintendo from the earliest game Boy days
Speaker 5:  has utterly failed beyond. That's interesting.
Speaker 5:  A very specific pair of niches. The PS
Speaker 5:  VDA was what had a wonderful niche of indie games.
Speaker 5:  And both the PS VDA and PSP had a a, an a
Speaker 5:  great niche in Japan very specifically and, and some
Speaker 5:  other countries that that rely heavily on wonderful
Speaker 5:  transit, public transit when you have
Speaker 5:  a public transit country where handheld gaming is
Speaker 5:  valuable and you might have several other people on that train with you to
Speaker 5:  do like local network things together. Mm. The DS Light did a
Speaker 5:  great job of that from Nintendo, but also the PSP and Vita did some, some,
Speaker 5:  some good jobs of that for Sony. But for the most part,
Speaker 5:  for the entire history of handheld gaming, the collective wisdom has been
Speaker 5:  don't mess with Nintendo. And if you are going to make a
Speaker 5:  handheld, it's the place that you, you shovel things that, that
Speaker 5:  aren't going to maybe do as well on your, on your big console, you'll,
Speaker 5:  you'll make, you'll make some games for that thing. But they have to be,
Speaker 5:  you know, small ports of things that you know, that you think
Speaker 5:  might might work there. And, and, and anytime you spend one of
Speaker 5:  your game ideas there like, like gravity rush on on Navita
Speaker 5:  or or or Uncharted on Navita as well, those games are going to be
Speaker 5:  watered down versions. 'cause you don't wanna put your A teams on that. You
Speaker 5:  don't wanna take too much ammunition away from your primary console to do
Speaker 5:  that. Well first with Nintendo and now with
Speaker 5:  the Steam Deck, the realization is that
Speaker 5:  maybe handheld gaming is the future. Maybe this is an
Speaker 5:  existential crisis for them. If they don't have
Speaker 5:  some irons in that fire then maybe they miss out on
Speaker 5:  what gaming is all becoming. Hmm. Because the switch and
Speaker 5:  the Steam Deck again prove that it doesn't have to be the port of the game.
Speaker 5:  It doesn't have to be your B team putting a game on there. It can
Speaker 5:  be any game that runs on your
Speaker 5:  main system. Any game that doesn't require the horsepower
Speaker 5:  of a constant AC plug into the wall
Speaker 5:  that can be portable now and portable
Speaker 5:  also doesn't have to mean outside of the house. It can mean your couch. For
Speaker 5:  many people it means your couch. So Sony got started with
Speaker 5:  the PlayStation portal for those couch folks, right? And the portal for all
Speaker 5:  we know may have sold better than all these CK big handouts so far.
Speaker 5:  But it right now it just plays your, your game streamed from your
Speaker 5:  PlayStation box. You're on the couch with somebody else. Maybe they're
Speaker 5:  watching tv, it's
Speaker 1:  A controller with a screen much more than It is like an actual console. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah, yeah. But it, but it lets you beep with somebody else who's watching
Speaker 5:  TV on the main screen and then you can do the thing next, which is also what
Speaker 5:  I do with the Steam Deck and I also stream my PlayStation from the Steam
Speaker 5:  Deck because by the way, the Steam Deck doubles as the PlayStation portal.
Speaker 5:  If you install the right app Chiaki, go look it up. It's amazing. There you
Speaker 5:  go. Now they also know they need to make
Speaker 5:  real handouts and both Microsoft and
Speaker 5:  Sony one praised the Steam Deck as
Speaker 5:  it came out and was like, this is great. We're gonna put some of our games
Speaker 5:  on there. 'cause they want that money from the games. Right Now both Sony
Speaker 5:  and Microsoft have realized that putting games on PC is basically
Speaker 5:  existing games on pc. They're existing PlayStation games, they're existing
Speaker 5:  Xbox games, they put them on pc, it's like printing free money for the most
Speaker 5:  part. There's a little bit of work involved in, you know, in getting it ported
Speaker 5:  properly, but pretty much printing free money. And both of their
Speaker 5:  strategies have shifted over the years from we have to sell a
Speaker 5:  box and the box will have an attached rate of games for sure. That
Speaker 5:  justify making the box to, we want to be in the business of
Speaker 5:  selling games. The Xbox is every
Speaker 5:  screen you own, right? That's what Microsoft says. Not just internally but
Speaker 5:  in its advertising. Now Sony's been moving that direction too.
Speaker 5:  And so both of them praised it. They started putting their games
Speaker 5:  on it. They started not only putting their games on but, but making sure
Speaker 5:  the games ran well on a handheld form factor. Making them
Speaker 5:  Steam Deck, you know, verified and they've dropped
Speaker 5:  hints that they will have bigger handhelds
Speaker 5:  later. The reports, which I should cite both of them to
Speaker 5:  Bloomberg by the way, are that Sony and Microsoft will have
Speaker 5:  something in the next few years. Not right away, it's not a
Speaker 5:  reason to not buy something existing right now, but in the next few years
Speaker 5:  they're both looking into this, they're both building around this, what
Speaker 1:  Is the holdup here? Like the, the Steam Deck has been out long
Speaker 1:  enough that people are demanding a new one because it seems to be
Speaker 1:  at the end of a cycle before there should be a new one. And yet
Speaker 1:  we're still at a few years for Sony and Microsoft. And I think the, the reason
Speaker 1:  I'm particularly interested in this is from Microsoft's perspective because
Speaker 1:  like you said, Microsoft is on this whole game pass
Speaker 1:  all your games everywhere, every screen is an Xbox thing and it strikes me
Speaker 1:  as the most obvious thing in the world for
Speaker 1:  Microsoft to just build a handheld console and say, well you're streaming
Speaker 1:  most of your games anyway. You don't even need a ton of power. Here is what
Speaker 1:  amounts to a controller with a screen. Let's go nuts. And yet we're
Speaker 1:  still at a few years out like it did. That just does not make sense to me.
Speaker 5:  My, my gut is that it's infighting. I think, I think not every,
Speaker 5:  I think not every team at these companies convinced there have been some
Speaker 5:  major restructurings at Sony recently
Speaker 5:  in terms of like who, which, which people have the power and which
Speaker 5:  departments. It's Sony Interactive Entertainment, I should say the
Speaker 5:  the games arm, PlayStation we call it. And then on the
Speaker 5:  Xbox side of things, there's always been infighting forever.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Microsoft, not famously the chillest company in the world. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And and the key thing there has always been
Speaker 5:  Windows versus Xbox and more recently Windows versus
Speaker 5:  services versus Xbox. And so there's
Speaker 5:  been, there's been the question of do you make an Xbox
Speaker 5:  handheld or do you make a Windows handheld?
Speaker 5:  Do you make both and have them cannibalize each other and you know,
Speaker 5:  dilute your marketing message? Do you let the handheld cannibalize the
Speaker 5:  Xbox? All of these kinds of conversations have probably been
Speaker 5:  percolating for years now. Totally. There are, there are
Speaker 5:  some canceled devices in the past too. I mean we, we, we reported on Xbox
Speaker 5:  tablet years ago. We reported on Xbox streaming stick. They,
Speaker 5:  they've thought about ways to, you know, to branch this out and at the end
Speaker 5:  of the day they've, they've canceled the ones we've heard about
Speaker 5:  rumored coming out at some point in the future. There, there have always
Speaker 5:  been questions about, you know, whether they can just go straight to
Speaker 5:  streaming instead of local performance hardware. Which is also
Speaker 5:  very key if you're building a handheld because you think in
Speaker 5:  three years the world is going to be streaming all its games over the internet.
Speaker 5:  You're building a very different handheld than if you're assuming that people
Speaker 5:  are going to have to run that game on the actual hardware with all of that
Speaker 5:  performance that's required for it.
Speaker 5:  Historically, cloud gaming has gotten better over time in terms of
Speaker 5:  the image quality. But at the end of the day it's, it's, there's so
Speaker 5:  many like friction questions in people's minds of what's gonna work. Will
Speaker 5:  I own my games? Is your house close enough to the
Speaker 5:  servers? What happens if other people in your house suddenly use the internet?
Speaker 5:  People's home routers and wifi points aren't really
Speaker 5:  designed to be like, I'm going to make sure that this one device's connection
Speaker 5:  is rock solid unless you are an IT admin setting that up at
Speaker 5:  your own home with that proper quality of service. Nvidia and ex
Speaker 5:  Microsoft have worked on baking some of that into the routers, some of that
Speaker 5:  you know, but you can't expect the average person to buy one of those things
Speaker 5:  and just have it work yet. And that we don't know when that's going to change.
Speaker 5:  So I don't know how far Microsoft is down that road,
Speaker 5:  but we did, so at CS we caught up with Jason
Speaker 5:  Ronald whose title is VP of Next Generation
Speaker 5:  at Xbox and he says that the idea
Speaker 5:  is going to be bringing the best of Xbox to Windows.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So boiling that down,
Speaker 5:  they still wanna do the big platform play where
Speaker 5:  they help a lot of Windows handhelds happen, which is great for
Speaker 5:  them 'cause they sell Windows licenses on those handhelds and then they sell
Speaker 5:  Windows subscription services and apps and they can say it's also a PC and
Speaker 5:  all these kinds of things. But the big problem with Windows
Speaker 5:  right now is you turn it on and it's Windows and they would like what you
Speaker 5:  see to be Xbox. They would like what you see and I would like what
Speaker 5:  you see to be here are your games instead of here is
Speaker 5:  45 minutes of installation and prompts, right?
Speaker 1:  It's like set top boxes. Like when when I turn on the thing, you should show
Speaker 1:  me the things that I am here for and nothing else. It's pretty simple.
Speaker 5:  There's so many things on top of that that you could theoretically do. And
Speaker 5:  the Steam Deck does that. I don't think a Windows
Speaker 5:  handheld that is Xbox Tomorrow would necessarily do.
Speaker 5:  The Steam Deck has touch pads, two of them
Speaker 5:  that let you play decades of PC games more easily because
Speaker 5:  many of them expect you to have a mouse cursor to do things.
Speaker 5:  Steam Valve has worked tirelessly to make sure that the
Speaker 5:  controls are the most customizable not just of any handheld but of
Speaker 5:  any gaming device ever made. So that you can map
Speaker 5:  any of them to do any number of things and not just map one to one, but also
Speaker 5:  create cords, multi key chords that do various things
Speaker 5:  or fine tune exactly how far
Speaker 5:  your character or camera turn when you move it this much based on the
Speaker 5:  gyroscope. I have a setup in a first person shooter game, which by the way
Speaker 5:  you can play first person shooter games on a Steam Deck because of Gyro,
Speaker 5:  because of Wonderful Gyro I can set up so that when I do a quick movement
Speaker 5:  or press a certain button, it will rotate me exactly 180 degrees in the game
Speaker 5:  or exactly 90 degrees to the left or right snap turns and things like that.
Speaker 5:  There are layers upon layers of
Speaker 5:  customizability that you can do there. And they've set up a community
Speaker 5:  profile system where if you don't wanna spend any time mapping
Speaker 5:  controls, you can just load a set that somebody else has made
Speaker 5:  and upload it to the internet and be like, oh, I wonder what this does here
Speaker 5:  is the mapping. It shows right you on a, on a, on like a picture of the Steam
Speaker 5:  Deck, here's how all these things work. And you're like, oh that sounds great.
Speaker 5:  I'll download that and try that. Wow that one didn't work for me. May download
Speaker 5:  another one, try that right now I have controls that feel native to this
Speaker 5:  system for a 10, 15-year-old PC game. If you
Speaker 5:  want. The other thing that I think will be
Speaker 5:  difficult for Microsoft to do if they just attack this
Speaker 5:  as here is a new layer we're adding on top of Windows
Speaker 5:  is that many games don't run as well on Windows.
Speaker 5:  Let me back up. Many Windows games do
Speaker 5:  not run as well on Windows as they currently do on
Speaker 5:  Linux on a Steam Deck. Seems
Speaker 1:  Bad, Sean seems bad. It's not great,
Speaker 5:  It's not great. Recently I, I had somebody from Microsoft reach out
Speaker 5:  to me about my Lenovo Legion go benchmarks and ask me,
Speaker 5:  are you sure you turned off this setting and benched it that way? 'cause
Speaker 5:  we've noticed some errant behavior. And I'm like, yep, notice that behavior.
Speaker 5:  That's why I turned it off every time.
Speaker 1:  That's rough. So this makes me think that
Speaker 1:  the Steam Deck and Valve in general is maybe
Speaker 1:  like one very big marketing budget away from being able
Speaker 1:  to make this thing happen because I, I think in a very real way, like
Speaker 1:  there is Xbox, there is PlayStation and then there's a huge big
Speaker 1:  giant monster gap all the way down to everything else in terms of like the
Speaker 1:  way that people think about gaming brands and if your valve your
Speaker 1:  options are, don't try to compete with that or
Speaker 1:  basically spend billions of dollars trying to compete with that. And at least
Speaker 1:  from what I've understood of Valve over the years, it's not interested in
Speaker 1:  like having Super Bowl commercials every year where it tells you about Steam
Speaker 1:  Deck. But it also seems like based on sort of your
Speaker 1:  experience, and again, what we've seen in these IDC numbers is like to the
Speaker 1:  extent that this market exists, the Steam Deck is winning it.
Speaker 1:  And if I'm valve what I should be doing is saying we have a pretty commanding
Speaker 1:  lead here. What we need to do is grow this market as fast as possible because
Speaker 1:  everybody thinks it's gonna be the next thing and somehow
Speaker 1:  no one else is doing a good job. And so it's like,
Speaker 1:  where where is valve pouring gasoline on this fire to make it
Speaker 1:  a bigger thing all of a sudden?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I mean to some degree I really think
Speaker 5:  that if there were, you know, demo stations in every Best Buy around the
Speaker 5:  country and if there were, you know,
Speaker 5:  mall pop-up stores and things like that, that yeah, they could
Speaker 5:  sell a lot more of these. On the other hand, I don't know how much
Speaker 5:  they care about pouring gasoline on fires.
Speaker 1:  That's
Speaker 5:  Fair. They're a very small company. They're, I don't wanna say they're
Speaker 5:  very focused because, because one of the tenets of Valve
Speaker 5:  is that you can physically or virtually roll your desk around
Speaker 5:  to different jobs there if you want. Oh, that's right. Yeah, yeah. This is
Speaker 5:  this. They put, they, they put it out in a handbook. They released, I wanna,
Speaker 5:  I wanna say in 2012, I guess they wanted to attract some new employees at
Speaker 5:  that point and they're like, oh yeah, if it ever snows you don't come into
Speaker 5:  work. This was before remote work was really a thing. You just work from
Speaker 5:  home. If, if, if you want to join a new project. The way we
Speaker 5:  do new projects around here is somebody will say, I've got a new project
Speaker 5:  and people roll their desk over there and the projects that have the most
Speaker 5:  desks are the ones that we're, we're working on. So, 'cause all the desks
Speaker 5:  have wheels and they decided to do it that way. A little different now they're
Speaker 5:  a little more distributed, but I hear the rolling desks are still a thing.
Speaker 5:  Okay. As of the last time I was there in 2023. So
Speaker 5:  I don't wanna say that they're, they're focused, but I do wanna say that
Speaker 5:  something like that would require a lot of concerted effort
Speaker 5:  from the kinds of people that may be Valve doesn't spend
Speaker 5:  all its time hiring, it doesn't spend on
Speaker 5:  marketing so much or retail. It's not, it's not its
Speaker 5:  thing it wants to build, it wants to build games and certainly
Speaker 5:  somebody could step in and say, hey, you know, best Buy could say, oh, we'll
Speaker 5:  do it for you. But Valve also wants to have pretty
Speaker 5:  strong degree of control. They wanna make sure the message is right. They
Speaker 5:  wanna make sure they're, they're seen as this benevolent entity, which many
Speaker 5:  PC gamers are happy to hold them up as because you know,
Speaker 5:  hey, this Steam Deck wouldn't exist without them and look at all the, the
Speaker 5:  way they handle themselves with this game and that game and they
Speaker 5:  must have poured a ton of money into this that they're not recouping to make
Speaker 5:  the Steam Deck happen to begin with. Then other field people are saying,
Speaker 5:  well yeah, but they take 30% off of all of these games in Steam
Speaker 5:  and they make ridiculous amounts of money. And I don't know.
Speaker 5:  What I'll say there though is I don't know if they would just say yes
Speaker 5:  because to anybody else wanting to do it for them because they like that
Speaker 5:  amount of control.
Speaker 1:  That's fair. So, but it does seem like we're, we're due for a race. If you
Speaker 1:  believe this market is going to get much, much bigger in the coming years,
Speaker 1:  and I think you and I both do, and I think if we're wrong it's because
Speaker 1:  people are stupid, not because this isn't a good idea. So I just, I'm gonna
Speaker 1:  plant that flag now. Like handheld gaming is, is the future we should
Speaker 1:  have. I, I fervently believe that. But anyway, if that is
Speaker 1:  the case, if, if the 6 million you talk about is gonna turn
Speaker 1:  into 60 or a hundred in the next however many years,
Speaker 1:  it seems to me that the race is essentially can valve
Speaker 1:  convince the world that the Steam Deck is good before
Speaker 1:  somebody else can build a really good Windows
Speaker 1:  or Xbox handheld? Is that the
Speaker 1:  race? Is that where we are right now?
Speaker 5:  I think that valve would be fine
Speaker 5:  if they didn't win that race. And I, I, I don't know, I
Speaker 5:  don't, I don't
Speaker 1:  Know why that frustrates me, but that frustrates me. It does. It
Speaker 5:  Frustrates me too. It frustrates me too. Like I want everyone to
Speaker 5:  experience the glory of peace of gaming and the glory of handheld gaming.
Speaker 5:  I want those two things for everybody and I want them to be intertwined,
Speaker 5:  but, but
Speaker 5:  Valve, I feel like they think about a lot of these projects
Speaker 5:  as we, we want to
Speaker 5:  uplift our people, our PC
Speaker 5:  gamers. Here is another thing that would make that we want for ourselves,
Speaker 5:  that we want our PC gamers to enjoy. And now that they
Speaker 5:  have that, you know, guests, ve has said there's gonna be
Speaker 5:  a Steam Deck two someday and a Steam Deck three someday and so on. They,
Speaker 5:  they, they're planning this as a generational thing with maybe up to four
Speaker 5:  of them that they were willing to be like, yeah, we think we're gonna do
Speaker 5:  that.
Speaker 5:  But, but I don't know if they feel like they need to
Speaker 5:  go much further, as long as somebody is letting
Speaker 5:  people do this. And so yeah, I I
Speaker 5:  I think they will keep doing it, but I think they might be fine if the sales
Speaker 5:  are just enough to, you know, recoup what they put into
Speaker 5:  it when they combine the, the handheld and the game. But yes, as, as a watcher,
Speaker 5:  somebody wants this stuff to happen, yes, please
Speaker 5:  find the chip and the screen that'll make it happen. I wrote another story.
Speaker 5:  I wrote a story what handheld PC makers should do
Speaker 5:  to fight the Switch too. And I wrote it 'cause there was a lot of interest
Speaker 5:  in the Nintendo Switch at that moment, but I do believe that there was
Speaker 5:  this moment for me where I was buying all my
Speaker 5:  India games on Nintendo Switch. I was like, I want
Speaker 5:  my Mario, my Zelda obviously, but I also wanna take all these other
Speaker 5:  beautiful games. I would otherwise not have the time to play with me on the
Speaker 5:  go to the bed, to the couch, et cetera
Speaker 5:  where I can find the time to play them. And
Speaker 5:  I was doing that for Switch and as soon as Steam Deck came out, I was like,
Speaker 5:  I can do them there better, cheaper,
Speaker 5:  longer without typing my password into Nintendo
Speaker 5:  store every time
Speaker 5:  and, and dealing with the Nintendo things arou around that.
Speaker 5:  And now I was buying all my indie games on Steam Deck
Speaker 5:  and maybe there's this moment now where the switch to
Speaker 5:  could be that next platform where people do that. If
Speaker 5:  Nintendo decides it's wants to be the place where all these indie games
Speaker 5:  live and if it just massively overhauls its store,
Speaker 5:  it has attracted the same kinds of games as the Steam
Speaker 5:  Deck and it has Nintendo behind it and it's going to have so, so
Speaker 5:  very many more sales than any of the handheld gaming
Speaker 5:  PCs right. For a very long time to come if, if
Speaker 5:  previous switch sales are any indication, if they don't screw it up royally
Speaker 5:  and make it a flop like the Weu, which by the way, the Weu has also sold
Speaker 5:  more than all these handheld gaming PCs. Neither here nor there, but people
Speaker 5:  love to bring that up when they're talking about my earlier story Fair. So,
Speaker 5:  so I I give this advice like if you want to build
Speaker 5:  the system that's going to beat the Steam Deck and to, that's going to meaningfully
Speaker 5:  compete against the switch to, it's gotta have a
Speaker 5:  true handheld operating system, not just a fresh coat of paint on windows.
Speaker 5:  Yep. But it's also gotta, it's, it's, it's gotta have a great screen.
Speaker 5:  It's gotta have a screen that doesn't suck up too much battery life. That
Speaker 5:  doesn't suck up too much processing power, but it also has to have a chip.
Speaker 5:  It has to have a chip that is more efficient
Speaker 5:  than anything else that we've seen on the market. Save the Steam
Speaker 5:  Deck and it needs to be more powerful than the Steam Deck chip to get us
Speaker 5:  anywhere further. And that's what Valve keeps saying, it's waiting for
Speaker 5:  interesting because that chip doesn't exist yet. Or if it exists, you know,
Speaker 5:  nobody's been able to talk about it publicly yet the chip makers,
Speaker 5:  they build chips for the big slice of the
Speaker 5:  market. They build them for the laptops, they build a few of them for the
Speaker 5:  tablets like the Surface Pro. They don't build chips
Speaker 5:  that are designed to go in anything much smaller than a laptop
Speaker 5:  unless they get some custom or semi-custom orders for that.
Speaker 5:  And so when Sony's building a new PlayStation, when
Speaker 5:  Microsoft's building a new Xbox, they order semi-custom chips.
Speaker 5:  They say, I want this chunk of a MD graphics and I want that chunk of
Speaker 5:  A-M-D-C-P-U pair those things together, give me some custom
Speaker 5:  interconnect, gimme some custom logic,
Speaker 5:  bake this as small as you can in terms of nanometers on a wafer so that we
Speaker 5:  can get good yields out of that. And that's what I'm gonna order for my future
Speaker 5:  console. Right.
Speaker 1:  And give me 30 million of them.
Speaker 5:  Exactly. Yeah. Gimme, gimme a lot of
Speaker 5:  valve did the same for the Steam Deck, but
Speaker 5:  none of these other handheld gaming PCs have that
Speaker 5:  style of customer semi-custom chip. They've got a laptop chip, which
Speaker 5:  a MD did some extra work to change the power
Speaker 5:  profile, make it a little bit more efficient because they know
Speaker 5:  they're, we're not gonna be throwing as many watts at it in a handheld form
Speaker 5:  factor. But fundamentally they do not have the
Speaker 5:  efficiency that you need to build something
Speaker 5:  that scales down to low wattage long
Speaker 5:  battery life like the Steam Deck. Instead, windows manufacturers have to
Speaker 5:  brute force it by putting in twice the size of battery like Asy did with
Speaker 5:  the ROG Ally X. Right. Great system because they did that. But
Speaker 5:  imagine if it had more efficient chip valve keeps coming
Speaker 5:  out and saying one of their, one of their developers in particular, one of
Speaker 5:  the Steam Deck designers, Pierre Lou gr I hope I got his name right,
Speaker 5:  sorry if I butchered it just now. He keeps having
Speaker 5:  to shoot down every new rumor, oh, valve's gonna use this new
Speaker 5:  chip in their new thing. He came out and said, we are not putting the Z two
Speaker 5:  in a Steam Deck. And until I reviewed the Lenovo Legion go
Speaker 5:  s which has the Z two in it, I did not know why. And then I reviewed it,
Speaker 5:  I'm like, this steam dig is beating
Speaker 5:  this new a MD chip. How is that possible? That's
Speaker 1:  A, that's a tough comparison. Yeah. So maybe what we're actually waiting
Speaker 1:  for, rather than a bunch of belief in this new industry is just
Speaker 1:  somebody to build the chip and, and like floodgates will open
Speaker 1:  when suddenly this thing is possible because that trade off you're describing
Speaker 1:  is what everybody wants, right? Like that that is the thing that unlocks
Speaker 1:  this and, and maybe that is the thing that we're waiting for more than anything
Speaker 1:  else who
Speaker 5:  Pays for the chip is the question, right? Is It, is it Qualcomm
Speaker 5:  that wants to get into the gaming space, started toying
Speaker 5:  with it with the copilot plus PC chips, but didn't really get there
Speaker 5:  and then suddenly Qualcomm, who's a giant player in modems
Speaker 5:  and is beginning to be a small player in laptops, becomes the handheld PC
Speaker 5:  gaming chip and this stuff has to move to ARM because Qualcomm makes
Speaker 5:  arm chips and all of a sudden you're, you're running steam on arm and running
Speaker 5:  Windows games on arm, which people have experimentally done and it
Speaker 5:  kind of works. And there was even some code in the valve code base
Speaker 5:  suggesting that the valve has maybe experimented with this too. Or
Speaker 5:  is It, is it Microsoft building something
Speaker 5:  special is Nvidia, Nvidia is the one who, by the way, Nvidia
Speaker 5:  is the one that builds the chip in the Nintendo Switch
Speaker 5:  Nvidia, it sets Nvidia graphics in there. That's Nvidia, even CPUI believe
Speaker 5:  Nvidia does Nvidia say, well we've, we've already got
Speaker 5:  this chunk of the handheld gaming market, why don't we have all the handheld
Speaker 5:  gaming market? And again, things move to arm and we're running Windows
Speaker 5:  games on arm and and so on and so forth. Is it a bunch
Speaker 5:  of these PC makers banding
Speaker 5:  forces and saying a MD
Speaker 5:  instead of giving us a laptop chip this year, how about we all foot the bill
Speaker 5:  for something better for handheld gaming PCs and then we're, we're all on
Speaker 5:  the same footing as one another, but we were there anyway and now we think
Speaker 5:  we can sell a lot more than, well if you look at 2 million
Speaker 5:  cumulative sales for handheld, for Windows based handheld GIM
Speaker 5:  PCs over the past, you know, two years, maybe they can't afford to
Speaker 5:  do that quite yet. Maybe it'll be longer before that happens.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, somebody's either gonna have to go all in or
Speaker 1:  something is going to have to happen externally that winds
Speaker 1:  back. It seems like I have to say this is all really validating my theory
Speaker 1:  that I made the right call by just buying into the switch and never unplugging
Speaker 1:  it and it's gonna be fine for a while. This is all making me feel better
Speaker 1:  about that decision. Ah,
Speaker 5:  David.
Speaker 1:  All right Sean, we gotta take a break, but thank you for coming on as always.
Speaker 1:  It's good to see you.
Speaker 5:  Thanks.
Speaker 1:  All right, we gotta take a break, but then we're gonna come back and we are
Speaker 1:  going to talk about the future of sports and why the future of
Speaker 1:  sports is really humongous, truly
Speaker 1:  gigantic displays because of course it's, we'll be right
Speaker 1:  back
Speaker 1:  few weeks ago I got on a plane down to West Palm Beach, Florida to go see
Speaker 1:  a match in a new league called TGL Golf. The golf I went to see
Speaker 1:  wasn't on this big beautiful outdoor course though there are lots of those
Speaker 1:  in West Palm Beach. I was indoors, I was in this small arena
Speaker 1:  called the SoFi Arena that had only been open for a few weeks.
Speaker 1:  I'll explain how the game works in a minute, but first let me just walk you
Speaker 1:  through the arena outside. It's just a big white box with a
Speaker 1:  giant SoFi logo on it. It honestly looks more like a data center than
Speaker 1:  a sports arena. When you kind of get there, you walk in the door and there's
Speaker 1:  a TV set for filming pre-game shows. There's a merch store and there's
Speaker 1:  really not that much else. This whole thing, honestly, to stand there feels
Speaker 1:  barely finished. It has a bunch of high top tables and
Speaker 1:  a few bar carts that all just kind of appeared on the polished
Speaker 1:  concrete and that's it. There's a walkway that goes all the way around the
Speaker 1:  edge of the building and it's all kind of like this, but there's another
Speaker 1:  structure inside of the building and this is where all of the good stuff
Speaker 1:  happens. It's like a mix of a movie set and a sports arena.
Speaker 1:  So just picture this with me, if I'm standing in the middle of the arena,
Speaker 1:  I'm on a flat patch of turf in the middle of a space that feels
Speaker 1:  maybe a little larger than a football field. On one side of me
Speaker 1:  there's a round area which has a couple of sand filled bunkers and a
Speaker 1:  small hill and a bunch of different golf holes around it.
Speaker 1:  That's the green, that's the spot where every single TGL hole
Speaker 1:  ends. It's 41 yards across and the whole thing sits on a
Speaker 1:  turntable so it can rotate up to 180 degrees. There are
Speaker 1:  hundreds of tiny actuators underneath the green that can change its shape
Speaker 1:  and its slope in just a few seconds too. It's one green, but
Speaker 1:  it can be almost anything. That is where all TGL golf holes
Speaker 1:  end. They begin on my other side where players stand on a patch
Speaker 1:  of grass that's actually grown in a field outside of the arena and they hit
Speaker 1:  balls into a giant screen. And when I say a giant screen,
Speaker 1:  I mean a giant screen, it's 53 feet high
Speaker 1:  and 64 feet across and however big you think a
Speaker 1:  thirty three hundred and ninety two square foot screen looks in person.
Speaker 1:  I promise you it's way bigger than that. In between the screen
Speaker 1:  and the green, there's just tech everywhere you look. So as I'm
Speaker 1:  standing here, there's a robotic camera wheeling around, like a go-kart capturing
Speaker 1:  video from these super low angles. There's a SkyCam overhead
Speaker 1:  on wires like the ones you see at an NFL game filming everything from
Speaker 1:  above. There are sensors I can see there are sensors I can't see.
Speaker 1:  There's a huge lighting grid up above. This is what I mean
Speaker 1:  by it feeling like a movie set. There's no sense here that the
Speaker 1:  technology is separate from the field. There's a huge sensor
Speaker 1:  array, just a few feet behind every golfer as they swing. And that robot
Speaker 1:  camera I mentioned does this cool swoopy motion thing in front
Speaker 1:  of them before just about every shot. It all adds up
Speaker 1:  to something that feels like a cross between a movie
Speaker 1:  and a video game and a sporting event. It's a little bit we golf
Speaker 1:  and a little bit professional golf and I have to be honest with you, I kind
Speaker 1:  of love it. Okay, this is probably the point where I should explain
Speaker 1:  how TGL works and why it works the way that it does. The how is
Speaker 1:  both weird and fairly straightforward, at least for our purposes
Speaker 1:  here is how Ricky Fowler, who's a pro golfer, explains it in a YouTube
Speaker 1:  overview that TGL made a while ago.
Speaker 7:  There are two sessions, the first triples a nine
Speaker 7:  hole three versus three alternate shot. The second
Speaker 7:  singles, six holes of players going head to head. Each
Speaker 7:  hole is worth one point if tied at the end and overtime determines the winner.
Speaker 7:  TGL is also bringing the golf a shot clock, a ref, a timeout to ice the
Speaker 7:  golfer, a hammer to raise the stakes. And the players are all micd up to
Speaker 7:  get you in on the action.
Speaker 1:  There are more rules than that and some quirks to the system, but it's ultimately
Speaker 1:  not terribly complicated. It's just golf as a team sport. It's really fun.
Speaker 1:  I had a good time at the match I went to, which was really competitive and
Speaker 1:  went into overtime, which was a a chip off sort of like penalty kicks in
Speaker 1:  soccer, but they were just chipping to get close to the whole super fun.
Speaker 1:  The vibe of the whole thing is more goofy exhibition match
Speaker 1:  than like high level golf tournament. But it's a fun thing.
Speaker 1:  And actually the thing that surprised me the most was that most of that tech,
Speaker 1:  including that giant turntable green works pretty seamlessly.
Speaker 1:  You don't even really notice it as it's happening. TGL is above all
Speaker 1:  a TV show. No one who makes It is unclear about that fact.
Speaker 1:  It's 15 holes long instead of 18 so that a whole match can be played in two
Speaker 1:  hours of primetime television matches are early in the week so
Speaker 1:  that they don't conflict with the golfer's more important tournaments and
Speaker 1:  they're in the early evenings to fit with the rest of ESPN schedule. Hell,
Speaker 1:  the whole thing is in Palm Beach because that's where a lot of the golfers
Speaker 1:  live, and so most of them can just drive to the matches. One of them,
Speaker 1:  I won't name who because it wasn't their fault, almost hit me with their
Speaker 1:  car in the parking lot, but that's not important. The reason the
Speaker 1:  TGL Arena looks like a movie set is because more than anything, It is
Speaker 1:  a movie set. This thing is a product made to be watched on ESPN.
Speaker 1:  The TGL folks actually borrowed from lots of other sports. In making this
Speaker 1:  TV show work, all the players come in with these wrestling
Speaker 1:  style entrances that were lit by the same person who did some of the wrestling
Speaker 1:  entrances,
Speaker 8:  The 2020 PGA champion and 2021
Speaker 8:  Open champion, a two time member of the Ryder Cup
Speaker 8:  and Presidents Cup teams makes some noise for Colin
Speaker 1:  During the match. The players are micd up, so you get lots of the banter
Speaker 1:  you might hear from players in a football or a basketball game. And honestly,
Speaker 1:  hearing golf pros trash talk is pretty fun.
Speaker 7:  I played with 'em all day Saturday. I heavily didn't hit one shot like that.
Speaker 1:  The overhead sky cam is also borrowed from the NFL and it adds some really
Speaker 1:  cool stuff to golf. In a normal tournament, you'd never get to see a
Speaker 1:  shot from directly overhead, and I've been seeing golf lovers all over
Speaker 1:  really geek out over getting new views of pros form and swing
Speaker 1:  because it's right over top of their head. The reality is all of this
Speaker 1:  adds up to something way more interesting on television than in person.
Speaker 1:  When I went, it was late January and it was the fourth ever match in the
Speaker 1:  history of TGL. The match I went to was actually a big one. It was Tiger
Speaker 1:  Woods and Rory McElroy who are two of golf's biggest names and two
Speaker 1:  of the best players of this century and two of the investors who actually
Speaker 1:  made TGL happen and they were facing off against each other, or at least
Speaker 1:  their teams were Noah Kahn and Nile Horen were hanging out in the team box
Speaker 1:  right across from my seat. They seemed like they were friends. I don't know
Speaker 1:  the baseball players, David Ortiz and Mike Trout were in the house. It was
Speaker 1:  a whole thing, you know, it was a big celebrity evening in West Palm Beach.
Speaker 1:  The TGL folks are pretty much all either golf people or TV people
Speaker 1:  or both, and they're still clearly learning how to make great
Speaker 1:  arena sports. They had only just hired folks to come and
Speaker 1:  like fire T-shirts into the crowd to get people psyched, but there were
Speaker 1:  still a bunch of commercial breaks where all of us in the audience just kind
Speaker 1:  of sat and waited for things to start up again. You never notice how long
Speaker 1:  a commercial break is until you're just sitting there quietly waiting for
Speaker 1:  sports to start. At one point, the in arena announcer alerted us that
Speaker 1:  we were coming back like we were like a sitcom crowd supposed to cheer as
Speaker 1:  we came back from commercial. There wasn't a big applaud now sign,
Speaker 1:  but it honestly felt like that might be coming. I knew all of that would
Speaker 1:  be the case though. They're pretty straightforward. Once again that this
Speaker 1:  is a TV product first and foremost. Even Tiger Woods would tell you that
Speaker 1:  I really went to West Palm Beach to find out one thing and one thing only,
Speaker 1:  which is the big question that I and a lot of other people have been wondering
Speaker 1:  since we first heard about TGL. Is this
Speaker 1:  golf? Can you replace a golf course with a screen and a
Speaker 1:  turntable and still call it the same sport? We actually started getting
Speaker 1:  answers to this question pretty quickly. In one of the very first
Speaker 1:  matches of the season, tiger Woods may the greatest golfer of all time
Speaker 1:  stepped up and hit a shot from about a hundred yards out and just
Speaker 1:  absolutely drilled it into the water. He hit it way, way,
Speaker 1:  way too long
Speaker 9:  I think. I think that up box goes too far.
Speaker 9:  I think the up box goes miles.
Speaker 1:  He hits the ball into the screen and the screen shows the ball bouncing off
Speaker 1:  of the green and into the water. And the water by the way, is kind of shoddily
Speaker 1:  rendered because I don't think anyone thought we'd need to look at the water
Speaker 1:  very much. And Tiger just sort of stares down like
Speaker 1:  he's confused that this just happened. Golfers this good can usually
Speaker 1:  tell how a shot went the second they're finished swinging and you could
Speaker 1:  tell this ball didn't do what he expected. A little while later,
Speaker 1:  tiger hit another short shot like this one and hit it way left.
Speaker 1:  He didn't like that shot very much either. He threw something I think a t
Speaker 1:  at the tracking sensor behind him as he walked away and since he had his
Speaker 1:  mic on, it was pretty clear how he felt
Speaker 9:  That easy. That sucked. Thank you. So,
Speaker 1:  And then not long After that, tiger hit it into the water again
Speaker 1:  and this time all he did was look at the screen and laugh.
Speaker 9:  Hang on. How many penalties have we had?
Speaker 1:  Tiger's team, which is called the Jupiter Links golf club, got absolutely
Speaker 1:  demolished in that match. Tiger chalked the whole thing up to him, just not
Speaker 1:  playing well. But a lot of people started asking, is the technology here
Speaker 1:  actually working? We've all seen what Tiger Woods can do with a golf club.
Speaker 1:  So when it goes wrong, are we gonna blame him or
Speaker 1:  are we gonna blame the technology? There's the saying in sports
Speaker 1:  that ball don't lie. The idea is that whenever something happens that
Speaker 1:  feels wrong, the game itself kind of auto corrects
Speaker 1:  it's karma basically. But for sports, there was this NBA player, his name
Speaker 1:  was Rashid Wallace, who would famously yell ball don't lie when
Speaker 1:  he'd get called for a foul, but then the player who he didn't think he fouled
Speaker 1:  would miss the free throw. I think Rasheed Wallace might've invented the
Speaker 1:  saying, I'm honestly not sure, but the message is simple. The game
Speaker 1:  tells the truth and the ball keeps the score. On a
Speaker 1:  real golf course, we'd know what happened. If Teer Woods is shot, went into
Speaker 1:  the water, it would mean that Tiger hit a bad shot ball, don't lie.
Speaker 1:  But in this case, we didn't see where Tiger's shot went. We
Speaker 1:  saw the beginning of the shot and then it hit a huge giant screen and then
Speaker 1:  a half second later we saw an animated ball fly through the air, bounce off
Speaker 1:  the green and hit the water.
Speaker 1:  There is an awful lot that happens in that half second that is
Speaker 1:  designed to make sure that the virtual ball still don't lie.
Speaker 10:  So there's the, this pole here that's got two cameras we go
Speaker 10:  further up little green light from the back. Oh yeah, there and the same
Speaker 10:  on the opposite side. So it's,
Speaker 1:  That is Andrew McCauley, he's the CTO at a company called Tomorrow Sports
Speaker 1:  and the Technical Mastermind behind all of TGL from the
Speaker 1:  turntable to the screen, to the sensors, to the cabling. That puts it all
Speaker 1:  together. That's all Andrew. And right now, as he and I are talking, he's
Speaker 1:  standing on the middle of the TGL Arena turf, right behind the T box
Speaker 1:  pointing to a bunch of different stuff and explaining to me how it all works.
Speaker 1:  Each of those poles with two cameras that he mentioned is a full system from
Speaker 1:  a company called Top Tracer, which tracks a golf ball through the air
Speaker 1:  top. Tracer is everywhere in golf. If you go to a driving range, there's
Speaker 1:  a decent chance you're using top tracer tech just to see how far your shots
Speaker 1:  go. This is the same idea, just way more complicated. There's
Speaker 10:  A redundancy and an accuracy play to this from a redundancy
Speaker 10:  standpoint, we could lose three systems, we could be down
Speaker 10:  to just one pair left. Sure still get an accurate trace
Speaker 10:  with all four running,
Speaker 10:  they do, this is where, where it differs a little bit from the range. They,
Speaker 10:  they stitch together the results from as many as
Speaker 10:  it gets. Okay, so all four is it and chooses,
Speaker 11:  Does it like improve linearly that way? Like is having four things pointing
Speaker 11:  at it gonna give you better data than having one or two or three?
Speaker 10:  That won't be linear because it, there's probably, there's a, there's a
Speaker 10:  point where it's not gonna, it's gonna matter. Okay, but, but
Speaker 11:  It helps more, more than one helps. Okay. But
Speaker 1:  It helps.
Speaker 10:  Okay.
Speaker 1:  In addition to the top tracer cameras, which are capturing the flight of
Speaker 1:  the ball in stereoscopic 3D, there's another sensor array
Speaker 1:  right behind the tee box, lower down on the ground. This is called a launch
Speaker 1:  monitor and it's made by a company called Full Swing.
Speaker 10:  One thing that top tracer doesn't do is give us that anything from moment
Speaker 10:  of impact, right? It's just looking at the ball. If you go fly from the
Speaker 10:  rough, the ball behaves that way and it models it that way, right? If you
Speaker 10:  don't, it doesn't. So, but we added false false
Speaker 10:  swings, obviously the sim, the big simulator game software
Speaker 10:  customized for us and we added there an array
Speaker 10:  of their launch monitors so that we could also
Speaker 10:  get moment of impact information that gives us
Speaker 10:  stuff with Club Trace that doesn't like club speed and things and things
Speaker 10:  like that. Anything to do with the club, it gives us a second spin number
Speaker 10:  as well.
Speaker 1:  I called up Andrew later after this conversation and asked him to explain
Speaker 1:  to me again how all of this stuff gets combined to figure out what happens
Speaker 1:  to the ball. Basically what he said is it starts as soon as a player walks
Speaker 1:  up to the box to hit their shot, the screen switches to show that their
Speaker 1:  spot on the course pointing at the hole and everything resets.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. So we've activated the system to be watching, right? And then as soon
Speaker 12:  as the ball is hit and starts flying, the first thing that
Speaker 12:  happens is the top tracer tracking system
Speaker 12:  observes that ball flying and it's, it's 35 yards to the
Speaker 12:  screen and it starts to
Speaker 12:  calculate or extrapolate like where that ball
Speaker 12:  would've continued to fly, what trajectory, speed, angles,
Speaker 12:  et cetera, with that ball of continued to fly on if that
Speaker 12:  screen hadn't happened to be there to stop it flying
Speaker 12:  in parallel with that, the full swing radars that
Speaker 12:  are behind the tee box give us moment of impact information.
Speaker 12:  So that's where we get the club head speed from. We get some spin information
Speaker 12:  from that top tracer also gives us spin
Speaker 12:  with their calculations of the trajectory. So I think, as I mentioned,
Speaker 12:  you know, when you were here, this is customized versions of
Speaker 12:  all these people's technology and they're layered together
Speaker 12:  to make this kind of a, you know, one, one of one tech stack
Speaker 12:  for, for tracking golf balls accurately in a, in an indoor
Speaker 12:  short field environment if you wanna call it that.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So it's taking like one set of data
Speaker 1:  is the, the impact, and that's if I'm right, that's basically what you get
Speaker 1:  from, but like a normal simulator, right? It's all about that
Speaker 1:  like immediate impact.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, most certainly launch monitors simulators that are
Speaker 12:  based on just a launch monitor sitting down by the ball and
Speaker 12:  capturing that moment of impact and then they extrapolate what would've
Speaker 12:  happened from a relatively small amount of data. Okay, since
Speaker 12:  we're capturing using top tracer data, we're watching the actual
Speaker 12:  bull fly a long period of time and then extrapolating the rest of the flight.
Speaker 12:  So that's much more like a well top tracer is, is a, is
Speaker 12:  a range, right? It's the number one technology and range is out there tracking
Speaker 12:  balls, right? So you know, it's the best in the business in terms of, in
Speaker 12:  terms of that, so, so we're actually tracking the flight of the ball and
Speaker 12:  then extending it versus taking moment of
Speaker 12:  impact information and extrapolating it from that, if that makes sense.
Speaker 12:  Sure.
Speaker 1:  Why 35 yards? I feel like obviously if you were just gonna
Speaker 1:  do the entire length of a golf course, that sort of defeats the purpose,
Speaker 1:  but like would it be better if it were 50 or
Speaker 1:  75 or a hundred yards of data that you could get
Speaker 12:  The 35 yards was, was absolutely
Speaker 12:  based on the testing and the algorithms and the, and the
Speaker 12:  logic that says that's, you know, with some room
Speaker 12:  in there that's more than enough to get all the data you need to be
Speaker 12:  accurate for the rest of the shot. And then we literally
Speaker 12:  size of the building, size of the field of play, how much real green do
Speaker 12:  we want map as much as we can get.
Speaker 1:  This is all designed for, like Andrew said, accuracy and redundancy
Speaker 1:  and after those messy tiger wood shots at the very beginning a lot
Speaker 1:  of people had a lot of feelings, but TGL seemed to still be really confident
Speaker 1:  that its technology worked, but lots of fans weren't.
Speaker 1:  There were theories floating around that TGL chose to not
Speaker 1:  use better technology because Tiger Woods is involved with full swing
Speaker 1:  or that something in the physics engine of the TGL system was just fundamentally
Speaker 1:  broken. The thing is, and I think this is the problem, there's really
Speaker 1:  no way to know for sure and for an organization like TGL that
Speaker 1:  wants to be seen as a real honest to god sport,
Speaker 1:  that is a hard problem to solve. This is easy in the real world, right?
Speaker 1:  The ball goes where the ball goes and even in a video game,
Speaker 1:  at least everyone's playing by the same rules in a game that is typically
Speaker 1:  consistent. But when we combine the real world and the virtual
Speaker 1:  one and the virtual world's job is to figure out what's going on in the real
Speaker 1:  world and then make guesses about it, the translation gets really tricky.
Speaker 1:  There've been a couple of other issues along these lines over the course
Speaker 1:  of the season. A few weeks After that, tiger Woods night, Tommy Fleetwood,
Speaker 1:  another very good professional golfer stepped up and hit a really
Speaker 1:  confusing shot.
Speaker 14:  What just happened?
Speaker 1:  Fleetwood got up, swung the club normally hit it really well and according
Speaker 1:  to the screen, hit it about 40 yards instead of the 167
Speaker 1:  that he needed. That's like a shot that I would hit on a
Speaker 1:  bad day on the golf course. Pros don't hit those shots and
Speaker 1:  Fleetwood hadn't either. This time it turns out there was actually a pretty
Speaker 1:  simple explanation.
Speaker 12:  What actually happened was that that the top trace system that I talked
Speaker 12:  about sitting there waiting for a golf ball to stop flying through on track,
Speaker 12:  it tracked the golf ball and Tommy Fleetwood hit a a, a beautiful
Speaker 12:  divot with that shot that flew in a beautiful
Speaker 12:  arc and unfortunately we tracked that as well as the golf ball and
Speaker 12:  the system decided that that was, that was the shot that got
Speaker 12:  hit.
Speaker 1:  What that means is that Fleetwood hit the ball and at the same time chopped
Speaker 1:  up a bunch of grass with his golf club. When he did, that's what a divot
Speaker 1:  is. The tracker, instead of picking up the ball, picked up the divot and
Speaker 1:  tracked it like the shot.
Speaker 12:  So it was an what we call an invalid reading in the rules. It was
Speaker 12:  fairly obvious very quickly to us what had happened. So we were able to
Speaker 12:  huddle with the rules, official inform 'em, and they were told the referee,
Speaker 12:  Hey, that this is a invalid reading. Our rules say that a
Speaker 12:  re-hit is allowed for no penalty. Please do that. And within a few seconds
Speaker 12:  that's what happened and Tommy hit the hit the shot again and
Speaker 12:  there was no issues with the second one.
Speaker 1:  Like Andrew said, that's in the rules, it went fine. It was a tough look
Speaker 1:  for TGL, but everyone got past it pretty fast. But it's also just
Speaker 1:  in a way fundamentally wrong. You know, I saw the ball
Speaker 1:  fly, I saw him hit it and it didn't do what the screen said it did.
Speaker 1:  That will never stop feeling strange and every time it happens, it gets
Speaker 1:  a little harder to undo. Andrew says that TGL can fix
Speaker 1:  problems like that and that in fact they've made changes to the tech even
Speaker 1:  since that match and that tummy fleet would shot. But he does know there
Speaker 1:  will be more edge cases and there's another challenge that the team is trying
Speaker 1:  to sort out, which is that no matter how big the screen is, it's still just
Speaker 1:  a huge two dimensional thing. When the TGL team was starting
Speaker 1:  out, they looked into 3D screens, bigger screens, smaller screens, more screens,
Speaker 1:  screen arrays, and Andrew did say he'd love to have as much screen as
Speaker 1:  he could possibly have. He at one point pointed up to the gap between the
Speaker 1:  screen and the ceiling and was basically like, what if there was more screen?
Speaker 1:  But this one is humongous and you still can't see it
Speaker 1:  the way that you see the real world, which I think created one of the most
Speaker 1:  fascinating moments of the whole year in TGL, which again happened
Speaker 1:  to Tiger Woods. So it's his turn to hit, he steps up and
Speaker 1:  he leans over to somebody and asks how far away he is, how
Speaker 15:  Far
Speaker 16:  99
Speaker 1:  Again, this is Tiger Woods we're talking about. So he knows what to do to
Speaker 1:  hit the ball 99 yards and it would be different if it were 101 yards or
Speaker 1:  96 yards. That's how dialed in these guys are. These tiny
Speaker 1:  differences matter. But the thing is, tiger misheard, he
Speaker 1:  wasn't 99 yards away, he was 199
Speaker 1:  yards away. And so this happened.
Speaker 15:  No, I I heard you say 99, not 1 99
Speaker 15:  I I'm gonna have to do some investigative journalism. You know what the
Speaker 15:  hell? What the hell just happened? No, I I heard 99 yards. Sorry, I
Speaker 15:  grabbed my 56 and I hit a hundred yards.
Speaker 1:  This just wouldn't happen in real life golf. I mean I guarantee
Speaker 1:  you and I would both know the difference between being 99 yards away from
Speaker 1:  something and 199 yards away from something, you know what I mean?
Speaker 1:  But in Tiger's case, in this moment, he's 35 yards away from the screen.
Speaker 1:  He's always 35 yards away from the screen. He has to rely on the
Speaker 1:  technology to tell him the rest. The TGL players have actually been
Speaker 1:  saying all season that this has been one of the biggest challenges. They
Speaker 1:  play by sight and by feel and you just can't get that hitting the
Speaker 1:  ball into a screen even when it's a really big screen. The same is true
Speaker 1:  on the green by the way. One thing I heard tiger say is that the fact that
Speaker 1:  the TGL green is the same green but also a different
Speaker 1:  green every single time because they're able to change its rotation and its
Speaker 1:  shape really tripped him out. It's the same hole over and
Speaker 1:  over, but it's never ever the same hole and wrapping your head around that
Speaker 1:  turns out to be really complicated. Ultimately, this is why I think the
Speaker 1:  TGL question is fundamentally a technology one, can this
Speaker 1:  be golf or is it just something else? Take out
Speaker 1:  all of the issues that there have been. The truth is TGL doesn't even need
Speaker 1:  to play by the rules of golf or even of physics or course design.
Speaker 1:  There are already a few holes in the TGL world
Speaker 1:  that are played around lava or on almost impossible
Speaker 1:  terrain. So like why not play TGL on the moon or in
Speaker 1:  some wild tron looking universe? The TGL folks
Speaker 1:  say that they're trying to strike a balance there, but it's a tricky one.
Speaker 1:  They want it to feel real. They want people who care about golf to care about
Speaker 1:  this, but they also need to embrace what's
Speaker 1:  possible here. And at least from where I sit, the more TGL tries
Speaker 1:  to feel like outdoor golf, the more obvious it becomes that the tech just
Speaker 1:  can't get there. That balance is tough for the golfers, but I think it's
Speaker 1:  even harder for viewers. How are you supposed to trust the
Speaker 1:  technology? Especially after seeing all the ways it can fail. There's
Speaker 1:  something pure and honest about sports. You watch the game and one team wins
Speaker 1:  and that's it. You sure fine complain about the refs and stuff and
Speaker 1:  everything's always unfair when your team loses, but fundamentally the game
Speaker 1:  tells the story. Ball don't lie. But here I look
Speaker 1:  at the YouTube comments on every TGL video and they're all just like, how
Speaker 1:  am I supposed to trust the physics engine here? TGL wants you to
Speaker 1:  bet on these matches. That's actually a big part of the plan. Are you gonna
Speaker 1:  bet on golf or are you gonna bet on computers working like they're supposed
Speaker 1:  to? And are those the same thing? Wouldn't you be easy to tweak the computers
Speaker 1:  to make people miss those shots? There's just something unknowable here,
Speaker 1:  something removed from real life that feels hard to overcome
Speaker 1:  in a way that even playing a video game doesn't feel so hard to overcome.
Speaker 1:  The morning after the match, I went to the TGL folks were doing a tour for
Speaker 1:  a bunch of golf creators showing them how the tech works and letting them
Speaker 1:  hit into the huge screen to get a sense for themselves. I just sort of
Speaker 1:  sneakily jumped the line in jeans and sneakers, grabbed a club and
Speaker 1:  stepped out in front of the thing. All right, I gotta hit one good shot here.
Speaker 17:  Feel like I'm nervous. Whew.
Speaker 17:  I don't even have anybody watching.
Speaker 1:  The TGL team told me that the whole setup, this whole arena is designed for
Speaker 1:  there to be one sweet spot where all the onscreen depth and
Speaker 1:  viewing angles and everything aligns exactly right. And that spot is right
Speaker 1:  here in the center on the tiny patch of grass where the player hits from.
Speaker 1:  It's kind of true standing there in the center. As the grass slopes away
Speaker 1:  down from me and toward the screen 35 yards away, it does
Speaker 1:  feel more like I'm hitting a ball on a golf hole, but it also
Speaker 1:  feels like I'm hitting into a really big screen. I hit five shots,
Speaker 1:  some of which went okay and some of which went well,
Speaker 1:  not okay.
Speaker 18:  Ooh,
Speaker 1:  That's not going anywhere.
Speaker 18:  I,
Speaker 1:  Yeah, just seeing if it works. This was frankly very embarrassing to do in
Speaker 1:  front of a bunch of golf professionals, all of whom seem to have gorgeous
Speaker 1:  swings even though they're in marketing or it. But you know, I'm here for
Speaker 1:  journalism, right? Gotta see what happens when you suck. And they did
Speaker 1:  promise me that I'm not the worst they've ever seen, but they did also make
Speaker 1:  me promise not to reveal which celebrity hit a shot so bad. It broke part
Speaker 1:  of the screen on the side where it shows the scoreboard and stats, which
Speaker 1:  is why there's now a net that covers that screen. I really enjoyed my TGL
Speaker 1:  experience, I've enjoyed it all year and TGL has been a hit this year.
Speaker 1:  It's only year one and basically everybody who works there tells me they
Speaker 1:  have lots of ideas about how to make it better for next season. That has
Speaker 1:  to do with both the technology and with the way that the
Speaker 1:  game itself is actually played. They all understand that even the rules of
Speaker 1:  this are not fixed yet. There are also still a lot of golf
Speaker 1:  purists and fans who think the whole thing is weird and bad and just
Speaker 1:  kind of hokey, but the ratings have been solid. People are talking about
Speaker 1:  the league, tiger and Rory and the others seem to be having fun
Speaker 1:  honestly, and that might be the most important part. The playoffs start this
Speaker 1:  week and I'll definitely be watching, I've been watching more of this season
Speaker 1:  than I actually expected, but the question is still right there and someone
Speaker 1:  is going to need to answer It. Is this golf or is this video games?
Speaker 1:  Does the distinction even necessarily matter? And when one
Speaker 1:  of the world's best golfers steps in and wax the ball into the screen,
Speaker 1:  what is supposed to happen in the real world ball? Don't lie,
Speaker 1:  but on the screen it can actually do pretty much whatever you want it to,
Speaker 1:  but you at some point have to decide what that is.
Speaker 1:  All right, that's enough golf talk for now. We need to take a break and then
Speaker 1:  we're gonna come back and take a question from the forecast hotline. We'll
Speaker 1:  be right back
Speaker 19:  I am, my name is Ben, I'm a senior in college. I'll be graduating here in
Speaker 19:  a couple weeks. Wanted to talk about iPad. I know you
Speaker 19:  recommend that everyone stick with the base iPad and that's probably a good
Speaker 19:  recommendation for most people. But I wanted to advocate
Speaker 19:  for the iPad Air just a little bit for one group of
Speaker 19:  people in particular, which is college students. I, like many
Speaker 19:  of my friends in college use an iPad for note taking and use an app like
Speaker 19:  Notability or
Speaker 19:  Good Notes and I don't know if you've used either of these apps, but they're
Speaker 19:  a lot better for the type of note taking that college students do than Apple's
Speaker 19:  inbuilt Notes app. And they also tend
Speaker 19:  to be pretty intense on iPads. Like my
Speaker 19:  2021 iPad Pro can get pretty warm while I'm working
Speaker 19:  with a big document in Notability.
Speaker 19:  So you know, the other thing I wanted to say is a lot of college students
Speaker 19:  come out of high school with some gift money or some more money
Speaker 19:  to spend. So five 50 for the extra head room with
Speaker 19:  the M three processor now I believe It is for an iPad air
Speaker 19:  is pretty reasonable because you know, I just had to
Speaker 19:  replace my laptop halfway through college 'cause my X PS 15
Speaker 19:  crapped out on me. And I think that spending the additional money up front
Speaker 19:  to get that more headroom, especially for someone who's using the
Speaker 19:  iPad for something that's not just Netflix is probably worth it in
Speaker 19:  my opinion. I think that's what a lot of people are doing in school and
Speaker 19:  I think that's where the biggest chunk of iPad air users come from,
Speaker 19:  especially when it's five 50 with an education
Speaker 19:  discount. So that's just my thoughts.
Speaker 1:  I picked this one to play this week because this reflects feedback
Speaker 1:  we've heard a lot over the last several weeks in a few ways actually.
Speaker 1:  One is just that it turns out that people who
Speaker 1:  want to take notes with a mix of a keyboard
Speaker 1:  and a pencil much more popular than I expected. That sounds sort of silly
Speaker 1:  to say now that is like the whole purpose of the iPad, but
Speaker 1:  I've always thought of that as kind of a cool feature. But one of
Speaker 1:  those things that you think you're gonna wanna do a lot more than you actually
Speaker 1:  wanna do and that most people gravitate towards one or the other. But I think
Speaker 1:  in certain parts of the world and in certain kinds of jobs and
Speaker 1:  certainly for students, which is a thing I heard a lot about the last few
Speaker 1:  weeks, that is really powerful. That mix of
Speaker 1:  I can set this down on a desk and use it like a laptop with really long battery
Speaker 1:  life but I can also just flip it flat on the table and use it with a
Speaker 1:  pencil. Super powerful. And I think that
Speaker 1:  as we said in the hotline, here is one of the best cases
Speaker 1:  both for the iPad in general but also for upgrading from the base iPad
Speaker 1:  to something like the Air or even the pro you get the better
Speaker 1:  accessories, you get that versatility, you get just
Speaker 1:  the sheer everythingness of the iPad and if you're gonna
Speaker 1:  buy an iPad, the point is to get something that can do things your laptop
Speaker 1:  can't, right? Like I really think if you are thinking about should I use
Speaker 1:  this as my main computer, the question is not will it be better on an iPad
Speaker 1:  or will it be more seamless on an iPad or can I do more stuff on the iPad?
Speaker 1:  'cause the answer is usually no. The iPad is a pretty locked down system
Speaker 1:  compared to the Mac or Windows. But there are things you can do on
Speaker 1:  it like physically that you can't with a Mac. And so if you start
Speaker 1:  from I need something I can write on with a pencil sometimes
Speaker 1:  of course you should buy an iPad and you should buy something that gives
Speaker 1:  you access to the best accessories. So that right there might be the best
Speaker 1:  case I've ever heard for an easy upgrade from the base
Speaker 1:  iPad to the air or the pro thing. Number two, there
Speaker 1:  are apps like Notability and Good Notes, both of which are fabulous apps
Speaker 1:  by the way. Notability in particular is one of the apps that Apple will
Speaker 1:  often show in its demos to show you how good some
Speaker 1:  of the new features are. It requires a ton of processing power. It does
Speaker 1:  really interesting stuff with handwriting. It's built in some of the AI features.
Speaker 1:  Notability in particular I think is like one of the best and most iPad,
Speaker 1:  iPad apps anywhere. It's excellent and It is as
Speaker 1:  we were just talking about, the kind of thing you can't do in the same
Speaker 1:  way on any other device. And those things do want a lot of extra performance.
Speaker 1:  So again, if you want to do something like that, I think I may have slightly
Speaker 1:  overrated how powerful some of these powerful
Speaker 1:  apps need to be, right? I think a lot about things like
Speaker 1:  Photoshop and Lightroom and Logic and Final Cut, these like heavy
Speaker 1:  graphics intensive editing processes that some people do and some people
Speaker 1:  like to do on an iPad. But there is a level below that that is like
Speaker 1:  I just need to have lots of images in my notes and I need to be
Speaker 1:  able to write quickly and I need to be able to flip between a thousand pages
Speaker 1:  and do the character recognition and search. And that stuff requires real
Speaker 1:  performance and you can do it on a base iPad, but again you will notice
Speaker 1:  the difference. So I think that's meaningful. Thing number three, and this
Speaker 1:  is another one I've been thinking a lot about the last few weeks. The price
Speaker 1:  of an iPad is not a simple thing to understand.
Speaker 1:  I think this is true of phones too in a way that with laptops it really isn't.
Speaker 1:  Laptops kind of cost what they cost sometimes that are on sale, but the price
Speaker 1:  there is reasonably assumed to be the price most people
Speaker 1:  are going to pay. Not true with iPads. iPads have huge corporate discounts.
Speaker 1:  iPads have huge education discounts. You can often get last year's model
Speaker 1:  on a pretty big discount. You can find them on like holiday
Speaker 1:  discounts in a way that a lot of Apple products in particular don't get discounted.
Speaker 1:  So the idea of I can upgrade a little
Speaker 1:  and either get last year's model much cheaper or this year's model with some
Speaker 1:  discount that I have access to and thus instead of spending you know, 300
Speaker 1:  more dollars on an iPad, I'm spending like 150 more dollars on an
Speaker 1:  iPad, then the upgrade becomes very compelling. So I think
Speaker 1:  this is a path that I maybe have underrated in thinking about the iPad.
Speaker 1:  I still think that if you are a person who wants to like hold an iPad in
Speaker 1:  your hand and watch movies on a plane or give it to your kids so they can
Speaker 1:  play games or I don't know, do the New York Times spelling D
Speaker 1:  every morning, that's like perfect iPad activities and they are
Speaker 1:  so well served by every iPad in the line, including the base one.
Speaker 1:  But there is a kind of base productivity
Speaker 1:  device that the iPad can be that isn't quite laptop replacement.
Speaker 1:  In fact part of the point is that it's not a laptop replacement but
Speaker 1:  It is almost that kind of thing. It can do things
Speaker 1:  your laptop can't, it can do things, your laptop can, but it gives you that
Speaker 1:  same kind of all in one machine. You do want
Speaker 1:  the performance upgrade there, especially if you're gonna use it even through
Speaker 1:  all four years of college, right? Like that's, that's a long time in device
Speaker 1:  cycles. And I think buying something with more power based on the idea that
Speaker 1:  I might want to do more with it and also it's just going to get harder
Speaker 1:  to do these things over time. That's great reason to upgrade an iPad.
Speaker 1:  So I just wanted to share this because this and all the feedback I've gotten
Speaker 1:  like this has really changed how I think about the upgrade path of an
Speaker 1:  iPad. And I think Apple really would like to lead you all the
Speaker 1:  way up to the pro. And I think that's harder, right? Like I think the leap
Speaker 1:  from, I need all this stuff so I should get an air all the way up to like,
Speaker 1:  oh look at that screen and it's so thin and on now I'll get a pro for several
Speaker 1:  hundred more dollars. That's a bigger leap. But the one from the base iPad
Speaker 1:  to the iPad Air that says I just need to like use this
Speaker 1:  device instead of just look at it. I think It is real. So that's
Speaker 1:  how I've been thinking about it and just wanted to share. Also, I'm hopefully
Speaker 1:  going to get a base iPad in front of me here very soon
Speaker 1:  and we will be able to compare these things for real. 'cause right now I
Speaker 1:  have four iPads stacked on my desk and as soon as it's
Speaker 1:  five I will have all the answers and I'm very much looking forward to it.
Speaker 1:  Alright, that is it for The Vergecast today. Thank you to everybody who came
Speaker 1:  on the show and thank you as always for listening. As always, if you have
Speaker 1:  thoughts, questions, feelings, or other iPad use cases you'd like to tell
Speaker 1:  me about, you can always call the hotline eight six six VERGE one one or
Speaker 1:  send us an email vergecast at The Verge dot com. We absolutely love hearing
Speaker 1:  from you and we are so grateful always to everybody who reaches out.
Speaker 1:  This show is produced by Eric Gomez, Brandon Keefer and Will Poor
Speaker 1:  Vergecast is VERGE production part of the Vox Media podcast network. Neela
Speaker 1:  and I'll be back on Friday to talk about everything going on at Doge, everything
Speaker 1:  going on in tech, more AI news, more gadget news.
Speaker 1:  'cause that just keeps happening. There's lots going on. We will be on top
Speaker 1:  of all of it. We will see you then. Rock and roll