# Transcript
ID: 2d321f1a-0787-474b-8da0-01736b95b12b
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/2344100497317498720/-7311977716220385858/s93290-US-4036s-1751967753.mp3
Description: On this episode of The Vergecast, we kick off Hot Girl Vergecast Summer with a classic Vergecast segment: the mic test. Guest host Victoria Song is joined by Vergecast producers Andru Marino and Erick Gomez to see how the Nothing Headphone 1, Sony WH-1000XM6, Apple AirPods Max, and Bose QuietComfort Ultra hold up against what’s possibly the noisiest street in Brooklyn.
After that, Victoria is joined by Ladder CEO Greg Stewart to talk about what it takes to build a successful strength training app — especially for people just starting out. As it turns out, it’s quite challenging, between curating playlists, accommodating users’ different access to equipment, skill levels, and preferences for coaching styles. (And maybe, some occasional beef with Peloton?)
Lastly, we answer a question from the Vergecast Hotline (call 866-VERGE11 or email vergecast@theverge.com) about AI fitness summaries, whether people actually like them, what’s frustrating about them, and what scenarios they might actually be useful for.
Want to learn more about the topics in this episode? Here are some handy dandy links for your reference:
Nothing Headphone 1 review
Sony WH-1000XM6 hands-on
Apple AirPods Max review
Bose QuietComfort Ultra review
A lazy person’s guide to getting into shape
Ladder isn’t done trolling Peloton
The unbearable obviousness of AI fitness summaries
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (20 ads detected)
Speaker 2:  Hello and welcome to the inaugural episode of Hot Girl VERGE Cast
Speaker 2:  Summer, the flagship podcast where the hot girls of The Verge
Speaker 2:  replace our stinky old men for a summer. No, we
Speaker 2:  love you. We love you. We're you're not stinky and you're not
Speaker 2:  old. But anyway, I'm your friend Victoria Song,
Speaker 2:  And I am filling in this week for David Pierce now that he's officially
Speaker 2:  on parental leave. I'll be your guest host for the next two weeks, and
Speaker 2:  then I will be handing it off to another one of my beautiful colleagues.
Speaker 2:  It's gonna be a really fun summer And I think you guys are totally gonna
Speaker 2:  have a blast with us. But today the itinerary for today's
Speaker 2:  show is we are gonna be testing out the mics from a bunch of different
Speaker 2:  over your headphones, and I'm bringing in our producers, Andrew Marino and
Speaker 2:  Erica Gomez to help me out with that because they're the Audio kings
Speaker 2:  And I'm just the wearable lady. You know what? That's not true. I test a
Speaker 2:  bunch of fitness headphones, so I'm an audio queen in my own right.
Speaker 2:  And then, you know, once we're done with the microphone test, we're gonna
Speaker 2:  talk to the CEO of a strength training app called Ladder
Speaker 2:  isn. The reason why is because it turns out it's very difficult to
Speaker 2:  build the strength training app. Trust me, I've tested dozens
Speaker 2:  cardio apps, really easy strength training.
Speaker 2:  For whatever reason, it's a lot more challenging any who I really enjoy
Speaker 2:  ladder. So I wanted to get him on and to talk about
Speaker 2:  the challenges of making one. That's actually pretty good. And once
Speaker 2:  we're done with that, we are going to take a question from The Vergecast
Speaker 2:  hotline. So you know all that coming up today and more. But
Speaker 2:  first I wanna know what you're gonna listen to on these over
Speaker 2:  your headphones once we figure out which one is the winner from the
Speaker 2:  mic test. I personally will be listening to the entire
Speaker 2:  soundtrack of K-Pop Demon Hunters, because I was not
Speaker 2:  expecting it to rock as hard as it does, but it does let
Speaker 2:  me know if you watch this movie, what your favorite song from it is and why
Speaker 2:  it's take down because that song is Chef's Kiss. Don't, don't Come At
Speaker 2:  Me. If you like Soda Pop Anyw, who we'll be right back.
Speaker 2:  And we're back. So one of the most signature
Speaker 2:  vergecast segments is the in the field microphone test. And in the
Speaker 2:  past we've tested microphones from consumer electronics like earbuds,
Speaker 2:  laptops, smart glasses, the whole shebang. So now let's do
Speaker 2:  over the ear headphones. So audio quality obviously a
Speaker 2:  huge top concern when you're buying over the ear headphones, but we often
Speaker 2:  forget to think about microphone quality, AKA, how you're gonna
Speaker 2:  sound when you talk to people over the phone on these headphones. So
Speaker 2:  to test this, we sent our good friend Andrew Moreno into the field
Speaker 2:  with a bunch of new over ear headphones. And to help me out, we have
Speaker 2:  our producer Eric Gomez. How you doing Eric?
Speaker 4:  Good, ve how you doing?
Speaker 2:  I'm good. And how are you doing Andrew?
Speaker 6:  Hi, ve. I'm good. I'm out in deep in Brooklyn
Speaker 6:  on a street corner. It's one that I take phone
Speaker 6:  calls a lot from, So I think this is a good place to do headphone tests.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I can definitely hear all the cars behind you, which is, it's pretty
Speaker 4:  Noisy.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, which is peak New York City vibes. So
Speaker 2:  which headphones are we gonna test first?
Speaker 6:  Okay, so we have four headphones. Today we're gonna do the
Speaker 6:  AirPods Max, the Bose Quiet Comfort Ultra, the
Speaker 6:  Sony WH 1000 XM Sixes,
Speaker 6:  and the New Nothing Headphone one just was
Speaker 6:  announced this on July 1st. So we'll get to
Speaker 6:  try all those out in this field. Let's start with maybe
Speaker 6:  the nothing ones so we can hear 'em right off the bat.
Speaker 2:  Love to hear what nothing has in store. Is it something,
Speaker 2:  is it nothing? We'll find out.
Speaker 6:  Okay, now I'm wearing the Nothing Headphone one.
Speaker 6:  Look at, look at this interesting design. Okay, how do I sound out in
Speaker 6:  the field now?
Speaker 2:  You sound not too bad. I can't hear the giant
Speaker 2:  garbage truck that was behind you or any of the hustle and bustle.
Speaker 2:  Your voice sounds a little, I don't know, compressed. A little like
Speaker 2:  muffled. Not the worst, but also clearly
Speaker 2:  the the You're clearly on a pair of something. Yeah,
Speaker 7:  Yeah, yeah. It's doing a great job of canceling out all the
Speaker 7:  noise behind you when you were on your MacBook microphone
Speaker 7:  before you could hear everything and now it's completely canceling out all
Speaker 7:  the, the noise. And it's doing actually a good job of
Speaker 7:  separating your voice from the, the background noise. However,
Speaker 7:  yeah, like we said, it, it is kind of, kind of
Speaker 7:  compressing your voice a little bit, modulating a little bit, but at least
Speaker 7:  we could hear you.
Speaker 6:  Oh, okay. So, so there's like some sirens that just went
Speaker 6:  off while you were talking. Did you hear any of that?
Speaker 2:  Not, not a single thing. Wow. So that's
Speaker 6:  Pretty cool. Okay. That's pretty good. Okay, so we have to say
Speaker 6:  that we did attest of this before,
Speaker 6:  earlier this week, And I wore the headphones backwards
Speaker 6:  and it sounded horrible and you could not understand anything I was saying.
Speaker 6:  Is that correct? It
Speaker 2:  Was garbage. That is correct. It was the absolute garbage. Like it was just
Speaker 2:  super underwater. You could only hear, hear part of every third word.
Speaker 2:  It was, it was, it was not great.
Speaker 6:  Okay, now I have,
Speaker 6:  how do I sound?
Speaker 2:  You sound awful. God. Yeah. Oh my God.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Let me just turn these around and actually see if they sound bad
Speaker 6:  when I wear them wrong. Sure.
Speaker 6:  Okay. How do I sound
Speaker 2:  With you? Sound awful. Okay.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, yeah, really bad.
Speaker 2:  It's kind of funny because I think lots of people don't always check
Speaker 2:  whether they're wearing the right and the left ear cup in the right
Speaker 2:  direction. So this is a one of those things where it's like if you have these
Speaker 2:  headphones and someone tells you they can't hear shit, you
Speaker 2:  might be wearing them the wrong way.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. So I noticed the reason why this happens is because the way they fold
Speaker 6:  down and then when you take them out of the case, the right
Speaker 6:  is on your left hand and the left is on your right hand. Ah. So then
Speaker 6:  when you pick them up, you have to turn them and then put them on, which
Speaker 6:  is very confusing And I think that's why I got mixed up there.
Speaker 6:  But I am glad to hear now that we bore them correctly, they sound
Speaker 6:  better.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, totally. We could totally have a conversation right now, despite all
Speaker 7:  the, the traffic going up behind you, you're coming in pretty, pretty clear.
Speaker 7:  I'm actually pretty impressed. Did you truly
Speaker 2:  Unintelligible when you were the, the wrong way versus Yeah, you know,
Speaker 2:  pretty decent when you have it on the right way. So that's kind of nuts.
Speaker 2:  And like, these are 3 99, 2 99, not 3 99.
Speaker 2:  I think the design looks pretty neat from afar. I don't know how you feel
Speaker 2:  about it up close and how does it feel in your head?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I feel a little silly wearing 'em outside. They look make me look like
Speaker 6:  a robot, like with these like designs under here, Andrew
Speaker 6:  bought
Speaker 7:  4,000. Definitely got that cyborg look going on right now.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah. But I, I do really like the buttons on the back.
Speaker 6:  There's like this nice cool scrolly wheel thing and
Speaker 6:  there's a little paddle switch that you can like skip songs and stuff.
Speaker 6:  And I guess there's a button over here on the side that you can
Speaker 6:  like assign to your voice assistant if you wanna do that. Yeah. Too. It's
Speaker 6:  a pretty cool design, but it's a little silly. I like the black version.
Speaker 6:  Those actually look a lot cooler than these ones. I think these stick out
Speaker 6:  a lot
Speaker 7:  More. The designs is definitely very divisive for sure.
Speaker 2:  It's a fashion statement. Yeah. Good. If you love making a fashion statement,
Speaker 2:  maybe not so great if you're in a boardroom. I I don't Unless you
Speaker 2:  have a fellow boardroom full of ai bots, which
Speaker 2:  I don't know, we live in a dystopia. That could be true. That's
Speaker 2:  any who shall we move on to the next pair of headphones? Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Which one should we try next?
Speaker 2:  Let's do the Sonys. Those are, those are also relatively new to Okay, cool.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Currently talking from the Sony W
Speaker 6:  1000 XM sixes, I have said this model number enough that
Speaker 6:  I know what they're called now.
Speaker 2:  The Sony alphabet soup. I dunno, you sound pretty good.
Speaker 2:  Yeah. The, the noise again, can't hear anything behind you, your voice is
Speaker 2:  pretty clear.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, it's actually pretty remarkable continuing to
Speaker 7:  be impressed by these headphones and their ability to cancel out so much
Speaker 7:  background noise and, and traffic noise. I think your voice is slightly less
Speaker 7:  compressed and modulated, so it's a little more natural sounding.
Speaker 7:  But yeah, you're, you're coming in pretty, pretty clear
Speaker 6:  Wearing these it sounds like. I am in a room,
Speaker 6:  I hear more of the sounds outside though than I did in
Speaker 6:  the last one, but it makes it sound like the sounds are in a
Speaker 6:  box. I don't know if that makes sense.
Speaker 7:  It's kind of interesting you say that because it, your voice is coming across
Speaker 7:  as if you're in a small space and it's kind of like you're getting some reflections
Speaker 7:  off a wall or something as if it's like, like a visa, like
Speaker 7:  a boardroom or a small phone booth or something.
Speaker 7:  So it's, it's adding a little bit to your voice to make it a little bit more
Speaker 7:  natural sounding, which is pretty interesting.
Speaker 6:  Interesting. Okay, so these use six mics for a
Speaker 6:  voice pickup compared to four and the last time there's 12
Speaker 6:  mics total on these. So I, I thought that was interesting. So
Speaker 6:  these are pretty, I mean Sony is such an audio focused company, so it makes
Speaker 6:  sense.
Speaker 2:  All right, cool. So that's the Sony's, we got those. Let's
Speaker 2:  do the AirPods Max next. Okay.
Speaker 6:  Alright, now I'm calling from the Apple AirPods Max.
Speaker 6:  How do I sound here?
Speaker 2:  You know what's surprising is how much more I hear of your surroundings.
Speaker 2:  There was like a, one of those big, I dunno, was a bust, was
Speaker 2:  it a truck of sun coin? It, it was, you know, like it sounded like a, an
Speaker 2:  old man going. Definitely heard that in
Speaker 2:  the background. Voice wise,
Speaker 2:  I think it's okay, but maybe not the most amazing.
Speaker 2:  Not as good as the Sonys or the nothings that we've heard so far. I can definitely
Speaker 2:  hear that truck behind you though.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, you're coming in a little muffled. I think these are letting
Speaker 7:  in more of the natural ambience of whatever's going on behind you, but
Speaker 7:  at the same time it's also cutting into your voice so you kind of sound
Speaker 7:  like you're on a zoom call, like that kind of Okay.
Speaker 7:  Underwater type of effect that you get sometimes from like the
Speaker 7:  Fidelity audio over the internet. Yeah. So
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I found this in our last test, like a lot more
Speaker 6:  background noise came through And maybe my voice sounded a little more
Speaker 6:  realistic, but it also just took in everything else.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It's, it's not as compressed as the Sonys or the nothings, but you
Speaker 7:  sound a little thin, I guess is the best way to describe
Speaker 6:  It. Sure, sure. Okay.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I guess if you want someone to know that you're outside,
Speaker 2:  this is what you want. But, you know, you don't wanna sound horrible on
Speaker 2:  the call, but you wanna say, oh god, someone's
Speaker 2:  breaking and they need to oil those breaks.
Speaker 6:  Oh wow. You heard that? Okay.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, we did. Yeah, yeah, definitely. It was completely silent for the last
Speaker 2:  two headphones, but I can definitely hear what's going on outside.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Yeah. With you right now, there there are three microphones for voice
Speaker 6:  pickup with eight microphones for active noise cancellation.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. That's interesting. Yeah, you heard all that,
Speaker 2:  Huh? And it's, it's interesting because this is I think the most expensive
Speaker 2:  pair of, of headphones that we have in, in this test. They're
Speaker 2:  5 49 5. Yeah. So the, the others like
Speaker 2:  the nothings were 2 99 and the Sonys were 4 49.
Speaker 2:  So you were paying the most to hear
Speaker 2:  trucks behind you when you're outside,
Speaker 6:  Do you hear any of the wind noise? It's, it's getting pretty windy.
Speaker 7:  Yes. A little bit. Yeah. Yeah. Get some of that rustling. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  I would say that Apple's AirPods throw but earbud
Speaker 6:  ones, I think they sound great for voice calls. I use those all the time
Speaker 6:  for voice calls. So it's funny like if you were to pick
Speaker 6:  these over the earbuds, I would pick the
Speaker 6:  earbuds just because like you get so much more use outta 'em because the
Speaker 6:  voice calls are better. And that's my opinion though.
Speaker 2:  I mean you don't get as much of a fashion statement as you do with the max.
Speaker 2:  Sure. I mean these are cool. I definitely feel they are they they're a very
Speaker 2:  specific look. I see people in New York City all the time on the subway wearing
Speaker 2:  them. So I guess it's a matter of what you're looking for,
Speaker 2:  but cool. No, we're onto our final pick The vs. Quiet
Speaker 2:  Comfort Ultra. Let's see how those do.
Speaker 6:  Alright, now I'm calling on the Bose Quiet Comfort Ultra.
Speaker 6:  How do I sound? What do you hear? What do you don't hear?
Speaker 2:  You know, when you were talking I could hear the stuff around you a lot
Speaker 2:  more. Yeah. Then when you're not talking, it
Speaker 2:  sounds a lot damper elbow Now I do hear those
Speaker 2:  police sirens hear the sirens going by. I do hear the sirens going by
Speaker 2:  and you sound a little compressed, but okay. Not awful.
Speaker 2:  You're intelligible a little bit like you're in an echo chamber underwater
Speaker 2:  a little bit.
Speaker 6:  So these did the best in our previous test.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Yeah. You hear this siren going by here?
Speaker 2:  Yeah. Oh yeah. Oh, depo.
Speaker 7:  It, it's interesting. I think it's like it's bringing, it's bringing up the
Speaker 7:  noise floor every time you speak and then once you stop talking it, it
Speaker 7:  kind of dampens it down a little bit more.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I noticed this before too.
Speaker 2:  Wow. God,
Speaker 6:  Sorry.
Speaker 2:  Wow. No, it's, it's accurate but I do think it's gonna depend on
Speaker 2:  what context you're using these headphones and like how much you want
Speaker 2:  other people to know where you are. I don't want anyone to know anything
Speaker 2:  about where I am at any given point in time. I wanna be like a mystery. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Enigmatic. So that's not something that I would love
Speaker 2:  personally. But you are intelligible on the call. You do
Speaker 2:  kind of sound like you're like, if, if you had a swimming pool
Speaker 2:  and you got rid of all the water and you were kind of standing in the swimming
Speaker 2:  pool, there's a little bit of that effect going on, I think, but Oh,
Speaker 6:  Echoey.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. Yeah. It's, it's a little echoey me. It's adding some kind of
Speaker 7:  processing to the voice where it's kind of letting it ring a little bit more
Speaker 7:  than it would normally or naturally. Yeah. And
Speaker 7:  it, it's it's, yeah, I'm picking up the birds as well. Yeah. Okay. I'm not
Speaker 7:  picking up any low end at all. Just really high frequency
Speaker 7:  Sure places. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that makes sense.
Speaker 2:  You got some yappy birds near you.
Speaker 6:  Okay. So what do you, what do you think who wins?
Speaker 2:  I think my number one pick would be the Sonys actually.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. The voice calls.
Speaker 8:  Yeah. What what? Oh my god, what do you think?
Speaker 7:  I was gonna say the same thing. It's, I think it's a close tie
Speaker 7:  or, or at least a very tight race between the Sonys and the nothings. I think
Speaker 7:  it would be Sony number one, nothing. Number two, the Bose
Speaker 7:  number three and AirPods max number four.
Speaker 6:  Lemme put them on one more time and we'll just say goodbye.
Speaker 6:  Okay. And then Aaron, I'm back on the, nothings just the comparison
Speaker 6:  still sound pretty good or still easy to hear me. Second place
Speaker 6:  you're gonna say. Yeah,
Speaker 2:  I'm still gonna say I think second place just because you're a
Speaker 2:  little loud and a little more compressed sounding to my ear
Speaker 2:  at least. Yeah. Than you were on the Sonys, but it's, it's a lot
Speaker 2:  closer than it was on our last test when the nothings were
Speaker 7:  Yeah, I, I think we are just coming to realize,
Speaker 7:  you know, that these headphones for the most part do a pretty good job of
Speaker 7:  canceling out background noise, you know, some better than others and
Speaker 7:  that's always gonna add a little bit of color and compression to your voice.
Speaker 7:  But you know, as, as long as we're able to hear you, I think that's a good
Speaker 7:  trade off. Yeah. You know, because otherwise you're not gonna
Speaker 7:  wanna wear these and take a call because you're always gonna have complaints
Speaker 7:  from other people saying that they can't hear you. Or if you can, you know,
Speaker 7:  go to a quieter space, you know, you can confidently go out with a,
Speaker 7:  you know, with the Sonys or the the nothing headphones and take a call and
Speaker 7:  and not worry about it at all. Yeah, pretty
Speaker 2:  Much. Yeah. Yeah. And I think another thing we were saying is just the scenarios
Speaker 2:  that you're in, 'cause they might perform slightly differently. I think you
Speaker 2:  sounded like you were in the apiary section where all the birds were yapping
Speaker 2:  in the zoo a little bit when you added in like
Speaker 2:  outdoor noise with the bows. So I think it's important to think about
Speaker 2:  where you're gonna be using these headphones when you know prime day. Prime
Speaker 2:  day is happening, right. So
Speaker 2:  yeah, I was gonna go buy myself a pair of bows but maybe you'll get a
Speaker 2:  pair of the Sonys just 'cause I think they did better all
Speaker 2:  around. Oh wow. Now I have to think hard. I don't like having to think hard.
Speaker 2:  That's very rude
Speaker 6:  For voice calls the Sony beat out. But for sound quality
Speaker 6:  I'm always going back to the AirPods max between those
Speaker 6:  four. Yeah, I do think but
Speaker 2:  So we're back and you know, I test all the wearables and fitness
Speaker 2:  tech at The Verge And I gotta tell you I've tested a million of them
Speaker 2:  and it is really hard to find something that I personally feel like
Speaker 2:  gets strengths training down Pat And I'm not even exaggerating when I say
Speaker 2:  I've tested a million of them. I it it's, it's probably
Speaker 2:  close hundreds at the very least and strength training is just
Speaker 2:  so hard to get down pat. And I think ladder of all the apps
Speaker 2:  that I've tried has definitely gotten the closest to the point where I
Speaker 2:  almost feel like I enjoy lifting weights, which if you've read
Speaker 2:  my reviews, you know how much I hate lifting weights. Like I know it's good
Speaker 2:  for me but I hate it. In any case, I wanted to call up
Speaker 2:  CEO Greg Stewart and have him tell me why this app
Speaker 2:  is actually good at this. So here's that.
Speaker 2:  I really wanted to talk to you about Ladder because
Speaker 2:  you know, personally speaking I have always struggled with strength
Speaker 2:  training. We have like approximately
Speaker 2:  40,000 running in cardio apps. Why is strength
Speaker 2:  training so hard to get right?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, I think I think to start, it's not just strength training, it's delivering
Speaker 10:  workouts or programming through an app experience. And I think
Speaker 10:  if you look at the spectrum of apps and content,
Speaker 10:  it's really designed as a library of almost
Speaker 10:  scattered random workouts which you have to navigate
Speaker 10:  yourself and it's really hard to figure out the right style,
Speaker 10:  what your programming should look like versus your goals, how to
Speaker 10:  start a new modality like strength training. And so people will
Speaker 10:  gravitate towards what they're comfortable with or what they know.
Speaker 10:  And a lot of times that leans to cardio, which is great, all
Speaker 10:  movement is great but it doesn't really help you start a new
Speaker 10:  consistent routine versus completing
Speaker 10:  a workout any workout in a particular day. And
Speaker 10:  there's lots of resources out there but it's hard to find one
Speaker 10:  source of truth. What we invented
Speaker 10:  was a system and that system's been designed to do two
Speaker 10:  things to get you the desired outcomes and body composition that
Speaker 10:  comes with teaching you the movements and programming to get there
Speaker 10:  and to keep you excited and having fun, which is
Speaker 10:  motivation, which becomes consistency. When we designed
Speaker 10:  the experience we, we looked at personal training and
Speaker 10:  personal training from our perspective is the best way
Speaker 10:  to get into strength training, to get into fitness, to maintain a consistent
Speaker 10:  routine. But it's really hard to get access to that. It's really expensive,
Speaker 10:  it's hard from a timing perspective, it's just not really
Speaker 10:  accessible for most people. But the anchors of
Speaker 10:  personal training were super interesting and relevant to us and how we saw
Speaker 10:  that were really three kind of core pillars.
Speaker 10:  Programming. So you know what to do, it's designed by an expert,
Speaker 10:  it's demystifying strength training, so no matter what style you're looking
Speaker 10:  for or level of strength training, you're coming in with coaching.
Speaker 10:  So you've got someone there to guide you through each workout, someone to
Speaker 10:  answer your questions and accountability. So really trying to
Speaker 10:  replicate the feeling of having a coach there.
Speaker 2:  Our listeners who may not know what the ladder experience is
Speaker 2:  like, can you give them a quick rundown of what ladder
Speaker 2:  looks like for them? Yep,
Speaker 10:  Absolutely. So again, it starts with our core goal of giving
Speaker 10:  you a plan and demystifying strength training for beginners
Speaker 10:  or or any level. And for us it starts with bringing on
Speaker 10:  the best coaches, true experts in strength coaching and the
Speaker 10:  specific modality that they represent, which we test before they
Speaker 10:  join the company. So for the consumer we spend a lot of time
Speaker 10:  constantly tweaking maybe what you experienced this matching algorithm
Speaker 10:  to make sure that we're asking you the right questions, understanding
Speaker 10:  who you are, what you're solving for, where you're coming from a fitness
Speaker 10:  perspective, beginner or advance and mapping you
Speaker 10:  to the right program based on all those inputs. We
Speaker 10:  have a wide range of of programs we call 'em teams. Some are geared
Speaker 10:  towards folks who are new to strength training, others are geared to those,
Speaker 10:  those are advanced coaches represent personas and personalities
Speaker 10:  and we use that to match to the right user who's coming in
Speaker 10:  in the app itself. Like we're over emphasizing real coaching
Speaker 10:  and proper form. So the value prop is we give you playing, we remove
Speaker 10:  all the guesswork that comes with strength training. You have movement videos
Speaker 10:  featuring your coach who's performing each exercise. We make it really
Speaker 10:  easy to review and preview those moments before you get started.
Speaker 10:  But you can think about it as a system. It isn't just a
Speaker 10:  a basket of content and you're choosing your own adventure. We're figuring
Speaker 10:  out who you are. We're mapping each to the right program. That program is
Speaker 10:  called a team. That team has a coach that coaches actually programming
Speaker 10:  workouts every week that are progressive so that every day
Speaker 10:  you're looking to work out you know exactly what you should be doing and
Speaker 10:  you can have confidence that they're building on top of each other and actually
Speaker 10:  purposely designed by an expert that is in line with
Speaker 10:  the goals that that you are solving for.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, I don't wanna touch on like a lot of what you talked about there because
Speaker 2:  one of my biggest struggles, like I'm in the fitness tech space, I
Speaker 2:  work out, I know how important like
Speaker 2:  conditioning and strengths training and mobility work is, but
Speaker 2:  you know there's, it's just so hard to, to be like, oh I'm a
Speaker 2:  runner. Let me Google or ask chat GPT what the best program for me
Speaker 2:  is, oh no I have to look up the proper form. Oh no, I have to think
Speaker 2:  about do I have access to a gym? Do I have home
Speaker 2:  equipment? Yep. Oh I am injured, I don't
Speaker 2:  have that equipment. What can I swap it out for?
Speaker 2:  What's a modifier the way that ladder does it? When I
Speaker 2:  first tried it I was like, oh this makes sense,
Speaker 2:  this is like a lot easier for me now because you can
Speaker 2:  swap out a move that you don't like that made me much more likely
Speaker 2:  to stick with it. So I was wondering like how do
Speaker 2:  you get those concepts into an app? Like
Speaker 2:  how, how do you develop that process? Because I was like, oh I didn't even
Speaker 2:  know that was something I wanted. Even the concept
Speaker 2:  of training blocks for people who've never used ladder, you have six week
Speaker 2:  training blocks. That was something I struggled with when I was trying to
Speaker 2:  do this all on my own, saving money, not going to get a
Speaker 2:  personal trainer in person. So just would love to touch on
Speaker 2:  on those aspects.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, on on the blocks, like if you were to hire a personal trainer, they
Speaker 10:  would think about increments of time that you're working towards
Speaker 10:  so it wouldn't just be a random Monday workout. They would say,
Speaker 10:  alright, over the next six or eight weeks or 12 weeks we're gonna work
Speaker 10:  on developing something very specific and your workouts are gonna build
Speaker 10:  to that. And we use the strength series to create
Speaker 10:  a similar experience. They have specific goals that you
Speaker 10:  are working on. It has a beginning and an end so it doesn't feel like this
Speaker 10:  never ending experience or never ending road. Like you
Speaker 10:  have a moment in time, very specific thing that you're focused on,
Speaker 10:  which is different at each team and you're doing it alongside a whole bunch
Speaker 10:  of people who are going through the same thing as you.
Speaker 10:  When we think about launching a new team or even
Speaker 10:  managing our teams, we're hyperfocused on the
Speaker 10:  persona, the person that is relevant to that team
Speaker 10:  and we work backwards based on what we're learning
Speaker 10:  from that quiz. So we have millions of people going through that
Speaker 10:  quiz where we help you match to a program. But we also use that
Speaker 10:  quiz to figure out what are the gaps in personas or
Speaker 10:  training styles that aren't well served by our current coaching
Speaker 10:  roster. And we're in a fortunate position where we don't have to go launch
Speaker 10:  new coaches and teams to grow. We'll launch a new coaching team
Speaker 10:  when it's very clear that there's an underserved persona.
Speaker 10:  So someone very specific, similar goals, training style
Speaker 10:  that isn't currently met by our, by our coaches. So we
Speaker 10:  have like a very specific person mind when we're working with
Speaker 10:  our coaches and programming reflects that. So
Speaker 10:  upfront when we're working with a coach, whether it's launching a new
Speaker 10:  team or or constantly iterating, it's very, very clear
Speaker 10:  where's this person working out? What equipment do they have access to?
Speaker 10:  Where are they on their fitness journey? How many days a week are they working
Speaker 10:  out? Do they need more motivation or they're looking for
Speaker 10:  technical form and training advice. And if you
Speaker 10:  go across our teams, they're extremely different.
Speaker 10:  I think the, the fact that we didn't launch ladder with
Speaker 10:  like one core face that represented the brand, like you'll see in a lot
Speaker 10:  of other fitness products, we created this concept of ladder
Speaker 10:  under ladder lives teams and teams are a wide range of
Speaker 10:  personas. If you go to Limitless with Coach Kelly,
Speaker 10:  that's an advanced gym goer, that's a woman who's going to the gym five
Speaker 10:  or six days a week, knows exactly how to navigate around
Speaker 10:  equipment and machines and is looking for expert
Speaker 10:  programming and a coach who really understands the technical fundamentals
Speaker 10:  and is gonna convey that in their programming. If you join
Speaker 10:  a line, it has a yoga infused influence. So someone who might not be coming
Speaker 10:  from a ton of strength training experience wants to incorporate that but
Speaker 10:  wants to have some of the familiarity and benefits of
Speaker 10:  incorporating a a yoga routine. So we're very, very
Speaker 10:  particular on the, the person that these coaches
Speaker 10:  are serving within these teams and we're constantly working with that to
Speaker 10:  make sure that our assumptions are correct and that we have the right
Speaker 10:  person in mind and we're using our data to inform that process. So
Speaker 10:  for us it comes from not not having a blanketed view of
Speaker 10:  this is just workouts and a fitness consumer, it's who is this person,
Speaker 10:  where are they coming from, what are they solving for? What equipment do
Speaker 10:  they have? Where are they training? And then building a team around that,
Speaker 2:  You know, this this new era of fitness apps, it kind of
Speaker 2:  sort of feels like your mini content media production
Speaker 2:  companies and that comes with its own challenges. Like,
Speaker 2:  you know, one of the core tenets of strength training is you kind of have
Speaker 2:  to do the same few movements over and over again
Speaker 2:  with heavier weights to progress. It's very easy to get bored when
Speaker 2:  you're doing that. So like how do you keep that
Speaker 2:  interesting? Yeah, obviously the the the trainers, they're,
Speaker 2:  they're thinking about that too. They're putting that in and then, you know,
Speaker 2:  how do you make the decision of do we go for
Speaker 2:  curated playlists that are instructors create
Speaker 2:  or do we go for your own music? Which I,
Speaker 2:  I deeply appreciate the ability to listen to my own playlist on ladders,
Speaker 2:  like love Apple Fitness plus Love Peloton,
Speaker 2:  but sometimes I'm like your guys' music taste and mine don't
Speaker 2:  align. You guys have no K-pop playlist And I need stray kids to,
Speaker 2:  to really get pumping. So Yep. Like how do you think about
Speaker 2:  the media side of that and the content production?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, the, the music side was almost an
Speaker 10:  accidental discovery. So when we launched the app
Speaker 10:  in 2020, we had very little money. We
Speaker 10:  couldn't go invest in content that was owned, we
Speaker 10:  couldn't purchase licenses, we just didn't have any resources to think
Speaker 10:  about solving music and doing it in a way that was
Speaker 10:  like legal and compliant with the laws of ownership. So like
Speaker 10:  we just couldn't solve that. But like from our perspective we were like,
Speaker 10:  I don't know, when you go to the gym are you listening to the
Speaker 10:  music in the background or do you have your headphones on and are you picking
Speaker 10:  it and is it a personal decision? And for us it was, it was
Speaker 10:  personal but we, we launched just having no other option
Speaker 10:  but giving the option of an integration with Spotify and Apple Music so
Speaker 10:  that it's clean to go, you know, pick your music and then integrating
Speaker 10:  the experience so that the music is ducking down when voiceovers are happening
Speaker 10:  when the coach is talking and just making it feel like it's purposeful
Speaker 10:  in how the two systems are talking to each other. What we learned
Speaker 10:  really quickly early on was that that was a core value prop for people.
Speaker 10:  If you go to our app store reviews and we've got
Speaker 10:  75,000 written app store reviews, it's like a third of them will reference
Speaker 10:  playing their own music. And so it became a differentiator, one
Speaker 10:  that was like better for the business but it became a differentiator 'cause
Speaker 10:  we learned that like people actually who are consuming our content wants
Speaker 10:  to be picking their own music and using their own apps and their own
Speaker 10:  services that they're already paying for. And so like that, that has been
Speaker 10:  true from the beginning but we kind of fell backwards into
Speaker 10:  it not having a ton of other options.
Speaker 2:  We love a happy accident. And kind of along that line,
Speaker 2:  were there features that you thought would work and then
Speaker 2:  didn't and then vice versa. Were there features that
Speaker 2:  you were like this will never work and then it did
Speaker 10:  Sort of like the whole thing has been a game of like
Speaker 10:  extreme iteration. Like we spend a lot of time
Speaker 10:  listening to our members both unprovoked feedback
Speaker 10:  that's coming in surveys, constantly surveying the team and platform level
Speaker 10:  and like listening for what people want. So when we make a big
Speaker 10:  bet on a core product feature, it's pretty
Speaker 10:  directly informed from the user building. A Ladder journal was a clear example
Speaker 10:  of that. People were tracking rep and weights outside of the app. They wanted
Speaker 10:  an integrated experience. Modifications is another great example.
Speaker 10:  People were modifying on their own but they were making up the modification
Speaker 10:  or asking in Team chat, which is basically a big group chat inside
Speaker 10:  all of these programs. Not a great experience, but people were screaming
Speaker 10:  at us for these features. And so when we hear it that loudly and we go make
Speaker 10:  a huge bet, we we're, we're extremely confident that
Speaker 10:  it's gonna be well received and we've got a beta group of 2000 members
Speaker 10:  and we're getting feedback through this whole process and we're learning
Speaker 10:  what we got right and what we, what we got wrong. There were some features
Speaker 10:  early on that we weren't sure how important they
Speaker 10:  would be. One of those was a one-to-one chat. We had a
Speaker 10:  one-to-one chat in in the app that was just part of the, the
Speaker 10:  membership. And because of that we had a expensive price. So when we
Speaker 10:  launched we were 60 bucks a month. It wasn't meant to be like chat with
Speaker 10:  your coach as a buddy, more like an OnStar button where you had a very specific
Speaker 10:  thing you needed a modification, you have an injury or asking about the
Speaker 10:  programming and the coach can give you a response. And when we
Speaker 10:  first launched the, the app, most of our users were coming from
Speaker 10:  the audiences, the social audiences of our early coaches and they had, you
Speaker 10:  know, 10, 20,000 followers on Instagram. And that
Speaker 10:  person who was following them knew that coach knew the style, had all the
Speaker 10:  context that coach was their hero. And yeah, they were really excited Bill
Speaker 10:  to talk to that coach and they valued chatty
Speaker 10:  one-to-one. When we started growing and investing in growth and growing
Speaker 10:  outside of our coach's audience, what we learned through a whole bunch of
Speaker 10:  work was one, the price was way too expensive. Like
Speaker 10:  people were anchoring to their content subscription apps, so they're thinking
Speaker 10:  about Spotify and Netflix, right? And we were multiples of that. So the
Speaker 10:  price value equation was completely outta whack and we learned that most
Speaker 10:  people weren't willing to pay extra for this chat feature.
Speaker 10:  On the flip side of that, like the cheer, the Cheers feature that
Speaker 10:  we thought was pretty cool early, early on where you
Speaker 10:  open up the app, you're on the home screen, you can see avatars of members
Speaker 10:  who are in their workout with a ring that shows how far they are into the
Speaker 10:  workout and you can send them a cheer and it's just kind of a fun right
Speaker 10:  gamified experience. That feature
Speaker 10:  has become unbelievably important to retention. And we've spent a
Speaker 10:  ton of time looking at, you know, what is the minimum number of cheers per
Speaker 10:  workout that leads to longer term retention or what
Speaker 10:  is when you come into the welcome workout, your first workout of ladder,
Speaker 10:  like how many cheers like actually are impactful and we've like correlated
Speaker 10:  this to retention. So that feature is on the home screen for
Speaker 10:  a reason. It might feel a little different when you come in there, but it's
Speaker 10:  really, really important and really powerful and it brings, you know, kind
Speaker 10:  of the atmosphere and feeling of being on a team and doing it with other
Speaker 10:  people who, who are like you. So certainly have had features that have
Speaker 10:  outperformed what we would've guessed on the impact that they would drive
Speaker 10:  to our membership.
Speaker 2:  Yeah, that's like a really good segue. It's like you're reading my mind,
Speaker 2:  but I wanted to talk about gamifying and community
Speaker 2:  because one thing I noticed is, okay, So I am
Speaker 2:  not the most social person while working out, I'm very much lone wolf
Speaker 2:  leave me alone. I tried the run clubs and I'm the type of
Speaker 2:  runner and I'm like, don't talk to me, I'm gonna go at my pace. All that
Speaker 2:  sort of stuff. So I was so surprised to see how much I was lurking
Speaker 2:  in the team chats and being like, oh, I don't participate much in them,
Speaker 2:  but I'm like, oh, here's Monday morning, here's, here's Nicole's little message,
Speaker 2:  let me see what everyone else is saying. Oh yep. My gut feels that feels
Speaker 2:  nice. And then to your point, the cheers sometimes, you know,
Speaker 2:  Nicole loves a plank. I do not, but I try
Speaker 2:  and when I'm, when I'm struggling in, in the plank, sometimes someone
Speaker 2:  will send a cheer and I'm like, oh, that's nice. I can't let this random
Speaker 2:  person down, let me, let me, let me hold out an extra 10 seconds in the plank.
Speaker 2:  And I was so surprised to see how that actually impacted
Speaker 2:  me. So, you know, but that's kind of the positive side of
Speaker 2:  gamifying. There are other kind of more mixed,
Speaker 2:  I have complicated feelings about streaks for example,
Speaker 2:  and getting really mentally fixated
Speaker 2:  and obsessive about streaks to the point where I get injured where I don't
Speaker 2:  take the rest in. So how, how, how do you think about an
Speaker 2:  approach the gamified features so that you
Speaker 2:  keep people engaged, you, you do keep them feeling positive but you don't
Speaker 2:  overload them and you make Yep. Their mental health worse in, in some
Speaker 2:  cases.
Speaker 10:  Yeah, e every feature we design and So I, this is true, everything
Speaker 10:  you've seen in the app is all aimed at helping to keep you
Speaker 10:  consistent with your workouts. So they're not just random features to be
Speaker 10:  there, they're there because they have some correlation to
Speaker 10:  motivation or correlation to, to workouts streak
Speaker 10:  mapped well to our value prop of helping you stay consistent with a
Speaker 10:  plan and rewarding co consistency. But we made
Speaker 10:  changes to shrinks based on some of the points that you just made.
Speaker 10:  When we first launched the app, our user was on the more
Speaker 10:  advanced end of strength, strength training that's changed as we've grown
Speaker 10:  and added new modalities and found fits with a broader basket
Speaker 10:  of users. But our streak was four workouts per week, which
Speaker 10:  we learned pretty quickly was not realistic for many of our
Speaker 10:  members. And so it was like this, it was having the opposite effect.
Speaker 10:  It was not motivational, it was like, well I can't do that So I don't really
Speaker 10:  care about this and I'm constantly underperforming. And so that was a, that
Speaker 10:  was an important insight and we, we changed the streak based on feedback
Speaker 10:  for our members and watching what was happening and we moved it to three
Speaker 10:  and we had a core group of people that said like, you're making this softer
Speaker 10:  and easier, but for the most part, most folks were excited about it
Speaker 10:  and, and thought that it made a ton of sense and actually was now a motivational
Speaker 10:  feature. Fast forward to last month, we launched
Speaker 10:  Streak Freeze because we know that life gets in the way and we would get
Speaker 10:  support tickets folks saying, Hey, I got married this week, I
Speaker 10:  had a death in my family, I had a 53 week streak
Speaker 10:  And I losses or anything you could do and we would help 'em and we would
Speaker 10:  repair the streak. Like we would, we would repair it. And Streak Freeze
Speaker 10:  was introduced to help solve some of these motivational elements or
Speaker 10:  deter defeat when it's just not possible to, to
Speaker 10:  reach the goal from a consistency perspective.
Speaker 2:  Cool. And then, you know, just getting on the, the sense of quitting, like
Speaker 2:  how do you get people back on the horse because I think that's a, that's
Speaker 2:  a problem that a lot of fitness tech, wearable tech
Speaker 2:  basically my entire beat is, is like obsessed with
Speaker 2:  is is just never getting you to quit. How do we get people to stick with
Speaker 2:  it? Because behavioral change is really hard. Like yep, I am, I'm dedicated
Speaker 2:  to fitness and even I have like months long slumps where I'm like, Ooh, I'm
Speaker 2:  not doing as much as I should be. So how do you get people back on the horse?
Speaker 2:  How do you approach that challenge?
Speaker 10:  Yeah, I, I think like making sure the experience is fun and motivated
Speaker 10:  has been core from our, to our product from
Speaker 10:  the beginning. So whether that's your on a routine and we're trying to keep
Speaker 10:  you excited for the next workout, all of those experience and levers
Speaker 10:  are designed to keep you going. I think one, like you have to get
Speaker 10:  results, right? It has to prove that it's working and we need to tell
Speaker 10:  you that it's working and that doesn't mean that the scale is changing.
Speaker 10:  It could, it could mean you feel better, it could mean that things are
Speaker 10:  happening to your mood that are driving outcomes that are positive to your
Speaker 10:  life. And so we use these features to reinforce
Speaker 10:  that, hey, you just hit a pr, like that's a new accomplishment for you.
Speaker 10:  We celebrate badges, micro wins that aren't about the actual
Speaker 10:  outcome but that you did, you did something hard. All of those are motivating
Speaker 10:  and helpful I think to, to stay excited even though weekly
Speaker 10:  drop. So our workouts are new every week, they're progressive,
Speaker 10:  but no two workouts have ever been the same. And so even
Speaker 10:  that is really unique versus other, other apps in our
Speaker 10:  space. We work with our coaches on programming, looking at the data every
Speaker 10:  single week. It's informing what's happening the next week. But that element
Speaker 10:  of surprise and variability or what are we doing this week is a
Speaker 10:  real motivator for folks. So we, we use that as a moment.
Speaker 10:  We call it the drop We release workouts on Sunday evening, it's the highest
Speaker 10:  moment engagement of the week. People come into the app to see what the
Speaker 10:  workouts for the week will look like. There's anticipation and fun.
Speaker 10:  If you, again, if you look at our app store reviews, 'cause we, we always
Speaker 10:  trust the words of our members. What they'll say is like, I'm having way
Speaker 10:  more fun than I would've expected or I'm way more motivated than I thought
Speaker 10:  I was. When people are falling off, like we have moments that
Speaker 10:  are like natural reentry points that we use to
Speaker 10:  bring you back in and the strength series is a big, a big part of that.
Speaker 10:  Maybe you fell off for reset the first strength series of the year. Well
Speaker 10:  we have another one coming and we'll use that moment, those two weeks in
Speaker 10:  between to try to pull you back in and get you excited and say
Speaker 10:  it's, it's now a great time to restart. Like you're not behind. We're all
Speaker 10:  starting together tomorrow and that, that is really effective. I mean if
Speaker 10:  you look at everyone who has left our app or turned our app, almost a third
Speaker 10:  have come back,
Speaker 2:  Oh that's pretty wild.
Speaker 10:  It's a really important motion from the company side, which is like,
Speaker 10:  hey, maybe it wasn't the right time for you, like un understand, but we're
Speaker 10:  gonna try to bring you back in and get you completing workouts again and
Speaker 10:  trying to help you stay consistent and getting to the goals that you're
Speaker 10:  looking to achieve.
Speaker 2:  I guess one thing I wanted to ask was what's next
Speaker 2:  for Ladder? Obviously you're iterating, you're thinking, do you ever feel
Speaker 2:  like you get to a point where you're like, hey we we've we've got a pretty
Speaker 2:  cool formula or or is it just a, a case where
Speaker 2:  everyone has ideas all the time and it's fine tuning,
Speaker 10:  It never stops it it, which is a good thing. Like there
Speaker 10:  we, we have more things that we know we need to build
Speaker 10:  than time and resources, which is a good problem that we're, that we're
Speaker 10:  solving. There are some like big exciting
Speaker 10:  projects that are, that are jumping out at us from our members words
Speaker 10:  like we built the Ladder journal. The Ladder journal helps you track reps
Speaker 10:  and weights. We now have 200 million data points from our members
Speaker 10:  that have been inserted into that journal and
Speaker 10:  now we wanna figure out how do we take all that data and then help tell
Speaker 10:  you what to do. Not just looking backwards at what you did, but what weight
Speaker 10:  you should pick up when you should push harder when you're getting close
Speaker 10:  to a pr, let's use all of this information just like a coach
Speaker 10:  who would be standing with you and saying these things, reacting and watching.
Speaker 10:  Let's use that information and help customize the experience even more.
Speaker 10:  Giving you perspective on what to do next. That's at the user level, not
Speaker 10:  just at the, at the T-Mobile. So I think there's a lot of opportunity on
Speaker 10:  Ladder Journal and using all this incredible information that
Speaker 10:  we have to make the experience better and more, more personal.
Speaker 10:  There's a lot of exciting things on community that we're excited about.
Speaker 10:  People want private tribes or small groups,
Speaker 10:  whether that's opting into a smaller group. It could be
Speaker 10:  women in New York who go to the gym. It could be
Speaker 10:  you started on a team or a program at the same time, but creating a micro
Speaker 10:  experience that's even more relevance to the people who are in that group
Speaker 10:  with you. Not degrading team chat but additive to the
Speaker 10:  experience. So there's a whole bunch of things we're excited about on the
Speaker 10:  community side now that it's growing and there are people
Speaker 10:  coming to the app who know of other people, their friends and there
Speaker 10:  isn't really a great way to go find them and have a shared experience. You
Speaker 10:  can imagine, you know, a lot of our members have a text group with their
Speaker 10:  workout buddies where they're talking about progress and they're sharing
Speaker 10:  what's going on. That stuff should be in the app, especially as you have
Speaker 10:  more and more people who are using Ladder. We should create an ability to
Speaker 10:  let you challenge your friends or cheer on your friends away
Speaker 10:  or aside from the team or agnostic to what team you are on.
Speaker 10:  So we're really excited about, about those components. And the third like
Speaker 10:  big, big chunk from our perspective that we're, we're
Speaker 10:  on learn mode right now is on nutrition. Like our members are, are
Speaker 10:  screaming at us to think about nutrition and think about how do you
Speaker 10:  consolidate this experience into one 'cause if, if you think about it,
Speaker 10:  it's really one consumer with one goal or one problem.
Speaker 10:  So they're looking to lose weight or put on muscle mass.
Speaker 10:  That goal has inputs and outputs. Outputs are
Speaker 10:  workout or physical activity. What's coming out of your body as a
Speaker 10:  result of the workouts that you're doing and inputs is food and diet
Speaker 10:  and nutrition. And those two things have to work together
Speaker 10:  to get to the outcome that you are solving for.
Speaker 2:  Cool. And you know, So I gotta ask, you know I'm a wearables reviewer,
Speaker 2:  I test a lot of this stuff. Everybody's adding in a ton of
Speaker 2:  ai, AI summaries. Yep. AI
Speaker 2:  chatbot coaches. What's your take on that?
Speaker 10:  AI in general has been central to our team and how we work for
Speaker 10:  a long time. Like we have 20 x this business
Speaker 10:  over the last couple of years and our team is roughly the
Speaker 10:  same size. So we're 40 people including all of our coaches
Speaker 10:  who are full-time teammates with us. So it's a very small team for the work
Speaker 10:  that we're doing. And the, the reason is we've, we've used AI to
Speaker 10:  10 x every individual and so we, we don't have many people or
Speaker 10:  any who are managing folks as a job, but
Speaker 10:  they're using AI to amplify the work that they're doing. We use
Speaker 10:  AI a lot with our coaches in a variety of ways
Speaker 10:  like Team Chat, some of our teams have a hundred thousand people in 'em
Speaker 10:  and it's not a good use of time for the coach to read thousands of
Speaker 10:  messages to understand what's happening in team chat, what's the temperament,
Speaker 10:  what questions are people asking, where are people getting stuck? And so
Speaker 10:  we've created tools on the backend that let them very quickly
Speaker 10:  ingest all the content from the day, understand the mood and the temperament,
Speaker 10:  identify top questions members who have questions that have never been
Speaker 10:  responded to and we help the coach prioritize what
Speaker 10:  to say and when using tools like that. So it's very much
Speaker 10:  integrated from a workflow perspective. I think over
Speaker 10:  the next, you know, year or so, you'll start to see
Speaker 10:  it driving more personalization in the experience itself.
Speaker 10:  The latter journal for example, that will all be powered by ai which is
Speaker 10:  we have all this information, how do we help use it to tell you or help
Speaker 10:  you know what to do next if we enter nutrition will be
Speaker 10:  a very similar approach and you can imagine long term like we had
Speaker 10:  that coach chat that one-to-one I talked about in the beginning. There's
Speaker 10:  probably an opportunity to have a companion in the app that knows
Speaker 10:  everything from a fitness and food perspective and is able to
Speaker 10:  interact with you and on a one-to-one basis to help you get closer
Speaker 10:  to to your goal. So I would say chapter one for us is, is
Speaker 10:  workflow and using these tools to deliver a better experience with the team
Speaker 10:  that we have. And chapter two will be using it to improve the
Speaker 10:  experience but personalize, not degrading the team atmosphere but using
Speaker 10:  all of this data and information to help give it back to you in a way
Speaker 10:  that's consumable and helps navigate you know, what the next thing should
Speaker 10:  be that you're, you're solving for.
Speaker 2:  Very cool. Thank you so much for taking the time to chat.
Speaker 10:  Of course. Thanks for having me. It was a lot of fun. I appreciate it. Yeah.
Speaker 2:  Alright, so we're gonna take a quick break and then After that we've got
Speaker 2:  a question from The Vergecast hotline.
Speaker 2:  All right, we're back. Let's get to the hotline as always. The number is
Speaker 2:  8 6 6 VERGE one one and the email is vergecast at
Speaker 2:  The Verge dot com. Very, very, very easy email. Anyway, we
Speaker 2:  love all your questions and we try to answer at least one on the show every
Speaker 2:  week. And this week we have an email about
Speaker 2:  AI Fitness insights, which this is a follow-up conversation
Speaker 2:  to one that David And I had before he abandoned us for, you know,
Speaker 2:  fatherhood. Again, the rudeness.
Speaker 2:  Anyway, the email is from Kevin from San Diego and it says,
Speaker 2:  I have two questions slash prompts related to your recent discussion of Apple
Speaker 2:  Fitness Buddy, or whatever it is called, and other AI and fitness
Speaker 2:  tracker offerings. For background, I'm a very happy whoop user. Ooh, I got
Speaker 2:  the whoop on right now. It's my favorite wearable I've ever used.
Speaker 2:  Having said that, I don't find their AI coach useful and agree with David
Speaker 2:  and V's. Takes my questions. Are the optimistic,
Speaker 2:  does some set of users out there enjoy these and why? What
Speaker 2:  prompts are they putting in and what are we missing out on? And the
Speaker 2:  cynical, do the companies themselves whoop or a Garmin Apple even
Speaker 2:  see these are good? Or if you gave them the truth serum, would
Speaker 2:  they just admit that they suck and they just have to offer one because everyone
Speaker 2:  else does? Ooh, ooh goodness.
Speaker 2:  Kevin from San Diego, very spicy, a very spicy email.
Speaker 2:  And it's a really well timed email because I actually just wrote up
Speaker 2:  a story on The Verge called the Unbearable Obviousness of AI Fitness
Speaker 2:  Insights call back to my, one of my favorite books, the Unbearable
Speaker 2:  Lightness of Being. And you know what? Let's take the optimistic
Speaker 2:  question and the cynical question because do some set of users
Speaker 2:  out there enjoy these and why? So when I was doing
Speaker 2:  research for that story, I actually reached out to Aura, I reached
Speaker 2:  out to Strava And I reached out to B to
Speaker 2:  say like, you know, what's the feedback that you've gotten from
Speaker 2:  people using this? Because I personally,
Speaker 2:  I like to go on the subreddits for these companies and read
Speaker 2:  the, the, the discourse. Anytime I get a really
Speaker 2:  stupid AI fitness summary.
Speaker 2:  And you know, as you can imagine, what the companies told me was
Speaker 2:  that, yeah, people actually really like it. But the numbers that
Speaker 2:  they gave me, and it's, it's in the article, which we'll put in the show
Speaker 2:  notes, they were kind of, let's just say there was some words that were
Speaker 2:  doing heavy lifting. I think, you know, they were like, they
Speaker 2:  use them weekly. Okay. Like of
Speaker 2:  the weekly users who decided to give feedback, well, you know,
Speaker 2:  the decided to give feedback is doing a lot of heavy lifting there.
Speaker 2:  But I do think that if you have people who are enjoying
Speaker 2:  these very milk toast summaries, they are gonna be the
Speaker 2:  beginners. They're gonna be people who are very new to fitness, who don't
Speaker 2:  necessarily have the foundational knowledge of like, what makes
Speaker 2:  a good habit? What are good nutritional things to think about?
Speaker 2:  How does rest interplay with your diet and nutrition? So
Speaker 2:  for those people, they might bring insights that are,
Speaker 2:  you know, not really insights, but they're there in the app and they're convenient
Speaker 2:  and easily summarized. So maybe
Speaker 2:  as for what prompts they're putting in, well that depends. 'cause there's
Speaker 2:  two types of AI fitness features, and one of them are these just very
Speaker 2:  blanket regurgitated AI summaries. There's no prompts being put into those,
Speaker 2:  but some like Aura and whoop actually have chat bots that you can
Speaker 2:  somewhat interact with. There's generally little prompts that they like
Speaker 2:  pre-filled out prompts that you can do.
Speaker 2:  I don't necessarily think we're missing out. I found that you can
Speaker 2:  get a decent response if you spend a lot of time
Speaker 2:  talking to this chat bott. It's like you got, I had to train the oral chat
Speaker 2:  bot quite a bit by like kind of taking its
Speaker 2:  non-existent AI hand and going like, okay, I've had a very stressful week.
Speaker 2:  I think my glucose is up because I'm really stressed out. Is that a
Speaker 2:  factor that affects glucose Also, I got injured also. I did this also. I
Speaker 2:  did that. And then the answers that it gives to me are a little more tailored
Speaker 2:  to that specific situation, but it's still stuff that I could
Speaker 2:  have found on Google and or through common sense in that
Speaker 2:  respect. I think the people who do enjoy them
Speaker 2:  again, are those who just don't, they're coming into this fitness
Speaker 2:  journey completely new, completely fresh. They don't
Speaker 2:  have the basic know-how that you might have as,
Speaker 2:  as someone who is a extensive whoop user. 'cause
Speaker 2:  let's be real, the whoop user set, they're generally very experienced
Speaker 2:  athletes or they're very comfortable with these concepts of rest
Speaker 2:  and recovery and how that plays into fitness where you play up
Speaker 2:  or play down the, the intensity based on the amount of
Speaker 2:  strain you've taken on. And so let's get to the cynical part of
Speaker 2:  Kevin's question where it says, do the companies themselves even see these
Speaker 2:  are good? Or if we gave them a truth serum, would they admit they suck?
Speaker 2:  Well, I've made it my personal mission to ask the CEOs of
Speaker 2:  all these companies when I interview them, you know, let's
Speaker 2:  be real here. And the media training absolutely kicks on,
Speaker 2:  and they, I don't blame them at all for that. They, they absolutely have
Speaker 2:  to kind of sell this because let's be real, they do have to offer
Speaker 2:  this because this is what investors wanna see from them at
Speaker 2:  this point in time with the AI zeitgeist. But, but,
Speaker 2:  but, but, but I'm gonna give them a little credit because
Speaker 2:  the problem with AI fitness and with wearables at
Speaker 2:  large is that you are generating a huge amount of data. I've been testing
Speaker 2:  this, this particular
Speaker 2:  category or beat for close to a decade now. I have close to a
Speaker 2:  decade's worth of personal data amassed across
Speaker 2:  several different platforms. And I'm pretty
Speaker 2:  adept at looking at it, understanding my baseline and pulling out insights
Speaker 2:  naturally. But even I need help from time to time to
Speaker 2:  contextualize what it is that I'm seeing. And I can't crunch
Speaker 2:  those numbers all by myself. So theoretically,
Speaker 2:  if we could have an AI that was saying something along the
Speaker 2:  lines of, you know, I'm gonna use my personal life, for example, I ate
Speaker 2:  it recently while on a run, I just completely,
Speaker 2:  I was overly optimistic about what my body could handle after taking a break
Speaker 2:  because I had a crazy last two months. So I'm
Speaker 2:  coming off of a prolonged training break where I was mostly doing maintenance,
Speaker 2:  And I was like, yeah, you know, it's, it's hot outside And I'm gonna do my
Speaker 2:  heat acclimation training with a 3.25 mile run because that
Speaker 2:  is so easy for me. It's so easy for me when I am at, at
Speaker 2:  i on the top of my game, I can do a 3.25 mile run in my sleep
Speaker 2:  in the history of my running history. But in the last two months,
Speaker 2:  you know, 3.25 is actually a bit more when you're putting it in the
Speaker 2:  context that it was 88 degrees And I hadn't done
Speaker 2:  a proper heat acclimatizing training regimen for two weeks. It takes
Speaker 2:  about two weeks for your body to get used to the new heat and humidity when
Speaker 2:  you switch seasons. So I ate it. I absolutely ate it. And that's
Speaker 2:  despite the fact that I had all the hydration that I needed with me, that
Speaker 2:  I was prepped And I went at an early time of day. I completely ate it.
Speaker 2:  I have, you could see this bandage that I have on my hand.
Speaker 2:  And what I would've wanted from these AI to be like, Hey,
Speaker 2:  girl, you had real bad sleep the last two months and
Speaker 2:  your training was extremely reduced. You've probably lost some fitness.
Speaker 2:  And given the 10 years of history we have on you, you tend
Speaker 2:  to come back from prolonged breaks, way too ambitious and have a
Speaker 2:  ton of self-reported injuries from doing all that. See, I know that because
Speaker 2:  I can sit back and reflect on my patterns and where I went wrong, the AI
Speaker 2:  was just like, wow, you had a real intense run. Good job.
Speaker 2:  And that was across multiple platforms. And I was like, okay, so you not
Speaker 2:  only could not synthesize the insight that I wanted
Speaker 2:  from my years of data, you just basically gave me a book
Speaker 2:  report that was the equivalent of a fourth grader
Speaker 2:  who decided not to do the assignment and read the summary on Wikipedia, and
Speaker 2:  it reads like that. You know? So I think
Speaker 2:  that's kind of the state of where AI fitness summaries are
Speaker 2:  at. They're there because they are trying to solve a
Speaker 2:  very real problem, which is data without context doesn't mean much, but
Speaker 2:  they're not as good as you are. Once you've learned your own context
Speaker 2:  and your own patterns and reflected on all of that,
Speaker 2:  they're not as good as you are at knowing yourself. So
Speaker 2:  that's just where we're at now. They're gonna pursue it. I keep, you know,
Speaker 2:  looking at 'em going, eh, eh, raising my eyebrow. And they keep going,
Speaker 2:  like their eyes are frozen and they, I know they're being held
Speaker 2:  captive by their capitalist investors, And I understand it's the little dance
Speaker 2:  that we do, but there is a time and place for them
Speaker 2:  if you're a textual learner And maybe the charts that are right there
Speaker 2:  with the same exact information, but for some reason you see it
Speaker 2:  regurgitated in a little sentence, maybe that's more digestive for you. I'm
Speaker 2:  not saying that there's absolutely no purpose for it, but for the vast majority
Speaker 2:  of people looking for these features, wanting to have those
Speaker 2:  insights, we're just not there yet. We just aren't. So yeah,
Speaker 2:  that's it. Thanks for your question, Kevin. It was a really good one. I got
Speaker 2:  to have my little monologue and that's it for The Vergecast today. Thanks
Speaker 2:  to everyone who came on the show, and thank you as always for listening.
Speaker 2:  There's a whole lot more stuff from this conversation at The Verge dot com.
Speaker 2:  We'll put links in the show notes, but also read The Verge dot com, find
Speaker 2:  your bylines. You're very smart people, you know how to do that. As always,
Speaker 2:  if you have thoughts, questions, feelings, you can always email us at
Speaker 2:  vergecast at The Verge dot com or keep calling the hotline. 8 6 6
Speaker 2:  VERGE 11. We love hearing from you. Send us all your thoughts
Speaker 2:  and questions and ideas for what we should do on the show. And we do a hotline
Speaker 2:  question every week, so keep 'em coming. This show is produced by
Speaker 2:  Eric Gomez, Brandon Kiefer, Travis Uck, and Andrew Marino.
Speaker 2:  All very excellent guys. The Vergecast is The Verge production and part of
Speaker 2:  Vox Media podcast network. Jake will be back on Friday to discuss
Speaker 2:  all the news from this week, but that's not hot girl. For cast Summer
Speaker 2:  Anyhoo goodbye.