# Transcript
ID: 0341e570-13fc-4e82-a11d-a21232896567
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/8619930506113865002/7830846010305701506/s93290-US-5773s-1758505944.mp3
Description: There’s a lot of gadget news this week! But we begin the show in an unprecedented way: with a bit of Brendan Carr is a Dummy, America’s favorite podcast within a podcast. Nilay pops on the show to discuss what happened to Jimmy Kimmel, why the FCC’s assault on speech is so dangerous, and why a couple of broadcast TV companies matter so much to the story. After that, Jake Kastrenakes and Richard Lawler join to talk about all of Meta’s new smart glasses, including the company’s first pair with a built-in display. Finally, in the lightning round, we talk about Reddit’s new AI deal with Google, Nvidia’s new chip deal with Intel, and Samsung’s terrible plan to put ads on your fridge.
Speaker 4:  Welcome
Speaker 5:  To the Birch Cast flagship podcast of parental leave. Sometimes you
Speaker 5:  take it and then sometimes things happen and suddenly you are
Speaker 5:  no longer taking it. All of which is to say ne patella is here. Honey
Speaker 5:  lie.
Speaker 6:  I would like to say that my default position is to hate and fear the government.
Speaker 6:  And the fact that Brendan Carr has made me return to work early has done
Speaker 6:  nothing but underline and fortify that
Speaker 6:  position, which I hold deep in my soul.
Speaker 5:  I just want to imagine kind of what your last 24 hours have been
Speaker 5:  like emotionally. Can you just, can you, you're, you're In theory
Speaker 5:  sitting on a couch with a, with a young baby, just living your
Speaker 5:  best parenting life.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Headphone Jack Patel is doing great. He,
Speaker 6:  he's what, nine weeks? He found his thumb. He's doing great. How's your
Speaker 6:  baby? That's
Speaker 5:  Exciting. He's good. Big pacifier fan. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  we're finally out of the screams for two hours at 6:00 PM for no reason phase.
Speaker 5:  So life is, life is terrific.
Speaker 6:  Our baby is very chill, which
Speaker 6:  it's scary. Like, you know, it's coming like it's all bottled
Speaker 6:  up in there And I, I can feel it. 'cause
Speaker 6:  yesterday we were there was rocking the baby and all this Brennan Carr, Jimmy
Speaker 6:  Kimmel stuff went down. And this, this Porsche Hele just received a
Speaker 6:  full lecture on the FCC, just a full, a
Speaker 6:  full lecture on what is going on with our nation's government. And in
Speaker 6:  particular, the incredible, completely
Speaker 6:  hypocritical Republican desire to control speech from, from the top levels
Speaker 6:  of our government.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So we're gonna get to most of the show is gonna be Richard
Speaker 5:  Lawler and Jake Kakis. We have a lot of news to talk about. We have a lot
Speaker 5:  of smart glasses stuff. We have a lot of AI things. There's a lot to talk
Speaker 5:  about, but the people demanded America's favorite podcast within a podcast.
Speaker 5:  So we are going to lead The Vergecast with Brendan Carr as a dummy. And
Speaker 5:  from what I understand, Jimmy Kimmel went
Speaker 5:  on his show and said a relatively milk toast
Speaker 5:  thing.
Speaker 7:  We hit some new lows over the weekend with the MAGA gang desperately trying
Speaker 7:  to characterize this kid who murdered Charlie Kirk as anything other than
Speaker 7:  one of them, and doing everything they can to score political points
Speaker 7:  from it.
Speaker 6:  That's it, that's all that happened. And to be clear, we have asked the FCC,
Speaker 6:  what about this is objectionable and they have not told us.
Speaker 6:  Right. Which is, we'll get to it, which is the most dangerous thing of
Speaker 6:  all. If you don't know what the rules for acceptable speech in society are,
Speaker 6:  then no speech is actually acceptable. You can tell that I'm just like amped
Speaker 6:  up. Sorry David.
Speaker 5:  That is very much the point. But, but so, okay. So that happens, and sort
Speaker 5:  of in the background, there has been a, a lot of people on the right who
Speaker 5:  don't like Jimmy Kimmel for one reason or another. Trump has posted many
Speaker 5:  times about not liking Kimmel, that he's, he's just an
Speaker 5:  enemy of that group of people for many reasons. So Brendan Carr
Speaker 5:  then immediately starts making the threats that Brendan Carr
Speaker 5:  as the head of the FCC seems to always make. Which is that like, I don't
Speaker 5:  like that thing you said, wouldn't it be terrible if I took away your broadcast
Speaker 5:  licenses? Jimmy Kimmel show is on a, B, C, which is owned by Disney.
Speaker 5:  Disney has all kinds of, you know, dealings with the government over time.
Speaker 5:  Like basically goes on. And I would say makes a pretty naked threat
Speaker 5:  that if you don't do something about Jimmy Kimmel, I am going to use the
Speaker 5:  force of the government to do something to you.
Speaker 6:  It's not even a naked threat. He went on Benny Johnson's YouTube show and
Speaker 6:  said, we can do this the hard way or the easy way. Right? Right. The,
Speaker 6:  it's not, I mean it's, it's, he's a cartoon. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Like this is literally what gangsters say in movies. And Brendan,
Speaker 6:  I dunno if you've ever seen a picture of Brendan, he can't do it with like
Speaker 6:  being physically imposing. So he is just saying cartoon gangster
Speaker 6:  stuff.
Speaker 8:  The broadcasters and you've gotten this right, are entirely different
Speaker 8:  than people that use other forms of communication. They have a license
Speaker 8:  granted by us at the FCC and that comes with it, an
Speaker 8:  obligation to operate in the public interest. And we can get into some ways
Speaker 8:  that we've been trying to reinvigorate the public interest and some changes
Speaker 8:  that we've seen. But frankly, when you see stuff like this, I mean, look,
Speaker 8:  we can do this the easy way or the hard way. These companies can find
Speaker 8:  ways to change conduct, to take action, frankly
Speaker 8:  on Kimmel, or, you know, there's gonna be additional work for the FCC
Speaker 8:  ahead.
Speaker 6:  And it's not Disney that has the broadcast licenses. It's a bunch of
Speaker 6:  Disney affiliates in cities and towns across the country
Speaker 6:  that have broadcast licenses. And importantly,
Speaker 6:  two major conglomerates that own a bunch of these local affiliates are
Speaker 6:  trying to merge. So they have business before him. And so when he says, we
Speaker 6:  can do this, the hardware or the easy way, he's putting pressure on a deal,
Speaker 6:  right? Which is just classic Trump administration stuff, right? Yes. And
Speaker 5:  The two companies you're talking about are nexstar and tegna, which would
Speaker 5:  like to merge. And if the deal goes through that
Speaker 5:  combined company would own, I think it was
Speaker 5:  80% of local affiliates around
Speaker 5:  the
Speaker 6:  Country. No, they would reach 80% of US households. Oh,
Speaker 5:  I see. Oh, okay. So
Speaker 6:  There's an underlying framework here, which
Speaker 6:  is important to understand. Back in the day,
Speaker 6:  all media was distributed over radio waves or print
Speaker 6:  newspapers, shout out to print newspapers. But back in the day, broadcast
Speaker 6:  media was literally broadcast from towers in, in cities and towns. There
Speaker 6:  were
Speaker 5:  Big s pointy towers, and that's how you got your television.
Speaker 6:  But those were basically created regional monopolies, right? You're the local
Speaker 6:  NBC affiliate, you own the NBC affiliate the next time over the next time,
Speaker 6:  over the next time over the government did not want you to also own the A
Speaker 6:  BC affiliate, right? It wanted media competition. So it set
Speaker 6:  rules over how many households you could reach as a, as a affiliate
Speaker 6:  conglomerate. And the rule right now is that you can hit 39% of US households
Speaker 6:  for a number of reasons. There's lots of criticism in this rule.
Speaker 6:  Meta hits 100% of households, right? Google hits
Speaker 6:  100% of households. Like the, the media landscape has fully changed the idea
Speaker 6:  that the broadcast owner in your town is a
Speaker 6:  commanding presence in the media landscape, I, I think has fallen by the
Speaker 6:  wayside, right?
Speaker 5:  It's the sort of rule that like the spirit of it made and
Speaker 5:  makes sense, but it is completely
Speaker 5:  voided by the actual existence of the world in which we live
Speaker 6:  Now and there and there. But there are good arguments to still have the rule
Speaker 6:  people make them, right? Lots and lots of people still get
Speaker 6:  a lot of their news from broadcast television, big events like the
Speaker 6:  Olympics and the Emmys, all this stuff happens on broadcast television. There's,
Speaker 6:  there's still a lot of power there. And so one of the reasons you don't want
Speaker 6:  massive consolidation of broadcast stations is then you get control over
Speaker 6:  the information flow, right? So the 39% rule has
Speaker 6:  held for a long time, and in order for Nexstar and Tenet to merge, they
Speaker 6:  have to get a waiver of this rule to hit 80% of US households.
Speaker 6:  So now one company will have enough broadcast stations to
Speaker 6:  reach 80% of US households, which is literally double the limit, right?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Not only do they need the, the actual
Speaker 5:  merger to be approved, they need the rules to be changed so
Speaker 5:  that the merger can be approved, which is now two points of leverage
Speaker 5:  that our buddy Brendan has over this deal for many billions
Speaker 5:  of dollars.
Speaker 6:  And, and just to stay on the, but Google and Meta hit a hundred
Speaker 6:  percent of the people. Yeah, they, they sure do. And this is the complaint,
Speaker 6:  And I think it's a good one. Like by all the broadcast stations, man,
Speaker 6:  have, have, have fun. You're dead anyway. It does. You know what I mean?
Speaker 6:  Like, that thing is dying. We know it's dying, but in the meantime,
Speaker 6:  they're the ones who make the news. Do you know what? Google and Meta do
Speaker 6:  not pay for the fucking news. That's why all the websites are
Speaker 6:  going outta business because there isn't money from those big distributors
Speaker 6:  to pay for the news. So when you think about NBC's News division,
Speaker 6:  or ABC's News Division, or CBS's News Division, which just got
Speaker 6:  a government monitor because they wanted a deal to go through. Well the,
Speaker 6:  that's where the news comes from. So you can put a lot of pressure on those
Speaker 6:  news organizations. And even if they die, there isn't a
Speaker 6:  parallel structure online for news there. There really isn't. Like,
Speaker 6:  however you feel politically, you cannot look
Speaker 6:  at the digital media landscape and say there is a thing here
Speaker 6:  that has the resources, the history, the depth, and the experience
Speaker 6:  of broadcast news divisions, which just doesn't exist. Yeah, maybe it
Speaker 6:  will one day, but it doesn't right now. So you're just in this transition
Speaker 6:  period, and Brendan Carr knows he has a lot of leverage,
Speaker 6:  is those companies try to thrash their way into the future,
Speaker 5:  Right? So the the first companies that bend to
Speaker 5:  Brendan Carr's threats on Benny Johnson's YouTube channel, like, do you ever
Speaker 5:  say a sentence and you're like, how is this any of this actually, what's
Speaker 5:  going on? That's the thing that happened. These
Speaker 6:  People are all the most terminally online posters in history. Yes. They all
Speaker 6:  run the government now, and they are playing out the most petty
Speaker 6:  forum grievances in particular Brendan Carr. He's just a troll. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So, but some of these companies, particularly Nexstar and Sinclair, two
Speaker 5:  big broadcasters, they are the first ones
Speaker 5:  to basically bend or cave or bite or whatever you wanna call it,
Speaker 5:  after these threats. And they start to say, we're gonna not show Jimmy
Speaker 5:  Kimmel, essentially we're gonna put on something else instead of Jimmy Kimmel's
Speaker 5:  show. And then that immediately spirals into a, b, c saying,
Speaker 5:  we are going to pull Jimmy Kimmel's show indefinitely.
Speaker 5:  Yep. Which now, like it is, it is one of
Speaker 5:  the more straightforward, like this is what censorship looks like. Brendan
Speaker 5:  Carr kinds of stories we've had in a while, which I think is a, a useful
Speaker 5:  time to bring this particular second. This is just, this is the straightest
Speaker 5:  line between what we have been talking about
Speaker 5:  and free speech disasters that we've had in a pretty long
Speaker 6:  Time. You publish what the government wants, you broadcast what the government
Speaker 6:  wants, or the government will punish you. If you publish something the government
Speaker 6:  doesn't like and you don't take actions to, to remediate it, the
Speaker 6:  government will punish you. That that's what he said. It's not,
Speaker 6:  it's not even shaded. He said, we can do this the hard way or the easy way.
Speaker 6:  There's no dancing around his actual statement. And then the next
Speaker 6:  turn was a bunch of these stations, the, these big
Speaker 6:  conglomerates, these are not little heartland TV stations in the middle
Speaker 6:  of the country that just, you know, we've had a, a really rural audience
Speaker 6:  and they don't like it when No, these are huge conglomerates in the middle
Speaker 6:  of a $6.2 billion merger, right. That
Speaker 6:  are trying to get government approval to change a rule that has existed for
Speaker 6:  years and years and years about how big media companies can be.
Speaker 6:  And there's just, I like politically that is just a
Speaker 6:  total realignment, right? Do you want big companies to get bigger? May maybe
Speaker 6:  you do. Do you want big companies to own a bunch of speech in America?
Speaker 6:  Probably you don't it. And that usually cuts in a bipartisan way.
Speaker 6:  Like what have Republicans yelled about the most over the past
Speaker 6:  half a decade? It's how big the platform companies are and how much control
Speaker 6:  they have over speech. Right? What does Brendan Carr say? I, Ben Smith from
Speaker 6:  SE four interviewed Brendan Carr at an event a couple months ago,
Speaker 6:  and he said, do you agree with me that the biggest threat to speech in America
Speaker 6:  is the government? That's that's the foundation, right? Like most people
Speaker 6:  agree with this. And Brendan Carr said, no, the biggest threat to speech
Speaker 6:  in America is the platform companies. And I, the government will, will take
Speaker 6:  care of it. And it's like, no, that's, that's still wrong, right? When
Speaker 5:  You're also kind of, you're, you're kind of answering your own question while
Speaker 5:  you try to say the other thing, right? Yeah. The government is
Speaker 6:  Gonna stop who has enough power to bring the platform companies in line?
Speaker 6:  It's me, the government. It's like, no, that's why you're not supposed to
Speaker 6:  use that power. Right?
Speaker 5:  That is In fact the problem we're trying to solve
Speaker 6:  Here. And so you just end up in this place where, and And I, you
Speaker 6:  can see this throughout, I think the, the aftermath of
Speaker 6:  the horrific murder of Charlie Kirk,
Speaker 6:  that Republicans are totally happy to abandon
Speaker 6:  everything they said about free speech and free expression on the internet
Speaker 6:  when they are the ones in control of the speech. Yep. And I,
Speaker 6:  this is why, I mean, for years I've come on the show I've hosted on social
Speaker 6:  media, government speech regulations are bad and the pushback is, but we
Speaker 6:  should have some because you don't want racism, you don't want this. You
Speaker 6:  like, and I'm always like, but then the bad guys will be in
Speaker 6:  charge
Speaker 6:  and they will do the things that always happen, which is they will start
Speaker 6:  to put pressure on speech they don't like because you've given them the tools.
Speaker 6:  You've opened the door over and over and over again. We have made this point
Speaker 6:  on The Verge for 15 years. We've made this point on The Verge, Addie turned
Speaker 6:  that story about the Republicans wage war in the First Amendment in like
Speaker 6:  five minutes. Why? Because she And I have written that story 5,000 times.
Speaker 5:  It's just sitting there. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  It's just, and she like, I think that she's just auto completed it on her
Speaker 6:  computer. Like she's got a keyboard macro that's like do the first Amendment
Speaker 6:  story, you know, it comes out Right. Because we've done it so many times.
Speaker 6:  And Brendan in particular does not know
Speaker 6:  he's playing with fire. Like he knows that he has power, but
Speaker 6:  he's a dummy. He, he, he can't see
Speaker 6:  the obvious hypocrisy of all of his positions add up to
Speaker 6:  now I'm the guy who canceled Jimmy Kimmel. And I actually think most
Speaker 6:  Americans look at the government directly censoring speech
Speaker 6:  and say, no, that's too far. That's it. It it, I don't think that's a
Speaker 6:  political situation. I think the government directly
Speaker 6:  saying Get this comedian off the air is like, there
Speaker 6:  isn't a better way to launch Jimmy Kimmel's YouTube career then the
Speaker 6:  government trying to cancel him for not even making a joke, for running a
Speaker 6:  clip of Donald Trump.
Speaker 5:  This is the thing about this that I think is, is so interesting and is so
Speaker 5:  different. And I think the, the thing we've learned obviously
Speaker 5:  since, since Charlie Kirk was things are
Speaker 5:  different now, right? Like, there there are a bunch of confusing,
Speaker 5:  complicated sort of inflection points that seem to be happening after
Speaker 5:  he was murdered. And this one just all,
Speaker 5:  all of this is so wrapped up together. But, but I think your your point is
Speaker 5:  right, that this is such a straight line from
Speaker 5:  the government is telling them to cancel Jimmy Kimmel that I, it it, it
Speaker 5:  seems to have resonated differently for people. And I, I'm curious if it
Speaker 5:  has felt that way even to you. Like you, you track this more closely than
Speaker 5:  most because you're like a specific kind of lunatic. But I think
Speaker 5:  this one just feels so visceral and so clear and there are so few
Speaker 5:  steps in the intimidation and the
Speaker 5:  corruption and the coercion that it is, like, people seem to get it. And
Speaker 5:  I've just even been watching this on social for the last like 18 hours. Like
Speaker 5:  in, in all the ways that Brendan Carr was this sort of like, kind of
Speaker 5:  confusing dictator. Now he's just a very straightforward
Speaker 5:  dictator. And that's actually like a more dangerous thing to be if you're
Speaker 5:  Brendan Carr. Yeah. And people see it differently Now, do you, like, do you
Speaker 5:  think this one is different because it is so a, it's high profile
Speaker 5:  because it's Jimmy Kimmel who's a person everybody knows, but also just because
Speaker 5:  the the wrong thing is so straightforwardly obvious this time. I
Speaker 6:  Mean, we've just done a decade of comedians saying they can't say whatever
Speaker 6:  they want. Right? Like this thing you're saying about being legible,
Speaker 6:  man, I, how much do I run into about Brendan Carr? Like my wife doesn't give
Speaker 6:  a shit. Becky doesn't give a shit. Yeah. Becky loves a comedy podcast. She
Speaker 6:  listens to all of them. They're always on in the background of our house.
Speaker 6:  And I said, Jimmy Kimmel got canceled because of Trump yesterday and her
Speaker 6:  eyes got huge. Mm. And she said, I can't wait to hear everyone has to say
Speaker 6:  tomorrow because if you've done this much
Speaker 6:  cancel culture, I've gotta push back against the woke mob. You
Speaker 6:  can't just say whatever you want for so long, if that is your brand. And
Speaker 6:  boy are there a lot of cultural commentators and comedians who've made that
Speaker 6:  their brand. And then you look at not even a joke,
Speaker 6:  not even a Charlie Kirk show. No.
Speaker 6:  If, if what we're saying is merely saying this man's name
Speaker 6:  is enough for the full force of the government to cancel your show.
Speaker 6:  Well we have a problem. I don't think that's actually very confusing at all.
Speaker 6:  And underneath that is, yeah, there's a whole
Speaker 6:  bunch of business stuff that's happening, right? The the, the, the broadcast
Speaker 6:  television empire is fully in its last days,
Speaker 6:  it's not coming back. Sinclair I think said, we're gonna
Speaker 6:  preempt Kimmel and we're gonna run a special honoring Charlie Kirk instead.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah dude. That's not gonna do ratings.
Speaker 6:  All those people are gonna look at their phones instead. Like, you're not
Speaker 6:  gonna get numbers from that. There's no coming back, there's no bringing
Speaker 6:  the audience back to broadcast television in this way.
Speaker 6:  So I dunno what's gonna happen with Jimmy Kim, I'm assuming he's a lawyer
Speaker 6:  up, he's gonna sue Disney. Everyone's gonna get their money and he is gonna
Speaker 6:  launch a YouTube show and then he is gonna start doing ag one supplement
Speaker 6:  brand integrations. He is gonna make millions of dollars like everyone else
Speaker 6:  does. Yep. Because that is the shape of the modern media. And
Speaker 6:  Brendan will get to preside over his empire of shit, of
Speaker 6:  decaying broadcast networks. 'cause he, that's what he has the statutory
Speaker 6:  power to control until the day he realizes that, oh,
Speaker 6:  that's not any good. And I should censor what Americans say on social media
Speaker 6:  platforms instead. And you can, it's just coming. You, you don't have to
Speaker 6:  guess, do I want to rule over the dead thing or do I want
Speaker 6:  actual control over what Google and Facebook distribute? And it's pretty
Speaker 6:  obvious what he wants.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean, do you think this one comes back on Brendan in
Speaker 5:  a different way because of it? Like, on the one hand, this is entirely internally
Speaker 5:  consistent with everything that Brendan Carr has been doing since he has
Speaker 5:  been in this shop. Yeah. So like the fact that he would play this card,
Speaker 5:  not at all surprising, but I think I, this one seems like
Speaker 5:  it might reflect back on him differently.
Speaker 6:  He's, he's a character now. I mean like what have we done? We've been doing
Speaker 6:  nothing but try to make this guy a character. Yeah. And thank you a huge
Speaker 6:  thank you to our audience who was like, it's neli,
Speaker 6:  the people demanded this. He's scared. We know we've been paying attention
Speaker 6:  to him since the beginning. 'cause this has been his move. Right.
Speaker 6:  And we've been inviting him on the show since the beginning because I think
Speaker 6:  he's too dumb to defend these things in a, from a coherent standpoint.
Speaker 6:  I actually understand them from an exercise of power standpoint. This
Speaker 6:  is what sensors do when given the keys. Yeah. They find leverage.
Speaker 6:  They don't immediately say, I would like you to delete this content. They
Speaker 6:  say things like, we can do this the hard way or the easy way. You can get
Speaker 6:  your $6.2 billion merger or you or you
Speaker 6:  cannot. And to get it, you gotta get Jimmy Kimmel off the air car was on
Speaker 6:  CNBC. And he said, look, these are just local stations making decisions.
Speaker 6:  And it's like, dude, you're trying to run, he's already trying to run, he's
Speaker 6:  already trying to pretend that these are little local TV stations just saying
Speaker 6:  we are, you know, we're, we're upset about what these big Hollywood liberals
Speaker 6:  are saying. No, these are billion dollar companies in the middle of a $6.2 billion
Speaker 6:  merger that will let them reach 80% of American households.
Speaker 6:  This isn't ma and pa with a local a, b, C affiliate. What's that weird Al
Speaker 6:  movie? UHF. That's what I want it to be. It's not that.
Speaker 6:  Sure. These are some of the most evil suits in America. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And what is their $6.2 billion merger gonna do? It's gonna lay off thousands
Speaker 6:  and thousands of people. That's 'cause it always does. That's an inevitable
Speaker 6:  result of these mergers. Yep. So I, I just, I feel no sympathy for any of
Speaker 6:  these characters, but I know that if Brendan came on this show or he came
Speaker 6:  on decoder or I, and we did a walk and talk in the streets of dc like
Speaker 6:  whatever you wanna do it Brendan, I just know that all of your ideas would
Speaker 6:  fall apart under the slightest scrutiny of are these coherent
Speaker 6:  d Does the way you feel about Twitter moderation and COVID
Speaker 6:  the lineup with the actions you are taking right now when it comes
Speaker 6:  to Jimmy Kimmel? 'cause boy you were pissed
Speaker 6:  about Twitter moderation during COVID, like super pissed about it.
Speaker 6:  And that was just Twitter. But that was like, you know, not
Speaker 6:  everyone in America. Yeah. It was not the force of the government interfering
Speaker 6:  in business deals to get favorable speech. And I, it just doesn't
Speaker 6:  line up. So Brendan as always, I will come back from my leaf early. I'm
Speaker 6:  pretty sure the baby can take you. He's not rational and he is a little bit
Speaker 6:  of a terrorist, but I'm pretty sure he can take you. Yeah. But I'll do it
Speaker 6:  anytime you want, man.
Speaker 5:  There you go. Brendan, you, you heard it here also. This is a useful time
Speaker 5:  to remind people, subscribe to The Verge so that we become
Speaker 5:  ungovernable, subscribe to The Verge so that there is no way anyone
Speaker 5:  can stop us and nothing anybody can do.
Speaker 6:  My joke about a G one, first of all, I I just keep, did you do this when
Speaker 6:  you were on David? I just have a list of stories. Oh yeah. And my desire
Speaker 6:  to ever go to a management meeting again is like basically zero. 'cause I
Speaker 6:  just wanna do my list of stories. Yes. We're gonna have to figure that out.
Speaker 6:  But this thing I'm describing where the money in broadcast media
Speaker 6:  is just rapidly declining and the solution is scale and
Speaker 6:  consolidation because that's what dying industries do. Yep. That's real.
Speaker 6:  So all that attention is going somewhere else and it's going onto platforms.
Speaker 6:  The platforms do not pay enough money to creators. Just
Speaker 6:  they don't, Spotify does not pay enough money to artists.
Speaker 6:  Instagram pays literally no money to in Instagram influencers. It's all
Speaker 6:  brand deals. I think it was Samir from calling in Samir was on CN BBC a
Speaker 6:  few weeks ago and he said literally the platforms don't pay enough money.
Speaker 6:  You have to go be an advertiser. Alex Earl was at Can and said, I'm not an
Speaker 6:  influencer, I'm a marketer. That's, that's the money.
Speaker 6:  Yep. The advertising money has come directly into the content
Speaker 6:  because the platforms themselves do not pay enough money to the people who
Speaker 6:  make the work. That's just true. There's a lot to say about that. I, I
Speaker 6:  don't know if how sustainable that is even over time, that's why I had Hank
Speaker 6:  Green was guest hosting decoder. That's why I really wanted him to talk to
Speaker 6:  Amy Lan, who's the CEO of Digitas, the big ad agency. That that's a, that's
Speaker 6:  a perspective I don't have, I'm not a creator like that. All this is to say
Speaker 6:  we don't do the brand deals. You can't, you can't do a brand integration
Speaker 6:  here. I'm saying this And I know that like the executives of Vox Media are
Speaker 6:  like, why? 'cause they, they want us to, that that's the money they can all
Speaker 6:  see the money we're not making. And the promise that we make them is our
Speaker 6:  audiences will pay, will pay us money and we'll make up the game. So
Speaker 6:  that's how we're gonna keep talking about it. But the, the thing that I don't
Speaker 6:  want to get into is, oh boy, our big Nike
Speaker 6:  brand integration is on the rocks because
Speaker 6:  a bunch of gamer Gators said I said Charlie Kirk's name on our show,
Speaker 5:  Right? Because we invented a podcast called Brenda Car. A dummy. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  You see what I'm saying? And like that is where the next set of pressures
Speaker 6:  is gonna come in the media ecosystem because no one's actually making enough
Speaker 6:  money just making the work. The work has been devalued almost nothing.
Speaker 6:  It's brand integrations. It's literally Ag one supplement reads
Speaker 6:  what you gonna do. That's, I mean, fine everyone go make their money. I'm
Speaker 6:  not Right. The people have solved the problem. I I can just see where the
Speaker 6:  next set of pressure points is. And like David said, I don't like it. Nope.
Speaker 6:  We, I I don't like being told what to do. So yeah, that's, that's
Speaker 6:  my pitch for the subscription. Let's have
Speaker 5:  Fewer things to be used against us. Make
Speaker 5:  Neli more. Ungovernable the first.com
Speaker 5:  subscribe. All right, NELI, you go back to break. We're gonna take a break.
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna be back with Richard and Jake. We're gonna talk through all the
Speaker 5:  rest of the news of the week. You're gonna be back with us for real in a
Speaker 5:  few weeks, but not, not just yet. For now. Go, go Enjoy baby time, but thank
Speaker 5:  you for coming to doing this. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean, I'll I'll bring the baby next time. It'd be
Speaker 5:  Great. Yeah, good. And hopefully, hopefully Brendan does not require this
Speaker 5:  again of us until that No, he will.
Speaker 6:  We're yeah, we're, we're coming back and forth. Where Brendan Car Daily is
Speaker 6:  our next podcast. It's gonna be amazing.
Speaker 5:  Oh boy. All right, we gotta take a break. We'll be right back.
Speaker 5:  government for making us do the first 20 minutes of the first cast
Speaker 5:  about this. I will never forgive them, but it was nice to have Neli
Speaker 5:  back. We have released Neli into his baby care and weekend.
Speaker 5:  Now let's get on with the good stuff. Jake Kakis is here. Hi Jake. Hey there.
Speaker 5:  What did Neli do? Neli just came in firing. It was nice
Speaker 5:  to have him back. Richard Lawler's also here. Hi Richard. Hello.
Speaker 11:  Let's talk about sports but not the Packers.
Speaker 5:  Who have you been yelling about the FCC too recently?
Speaker 11:  So, Steve Ballmer, of course.
Speaker 5:  Richard, you And I are gonna do a sports thing because one of the angry feelings
Speaker 5:  I've had this summer is that watching sports is a nightmare. And maybe I
Speaker 5:  just don't like sports anymore. Maybe the the simplest thing to do is just
Speaker 5:  not like sports anymore. So we're gonna come back to that. Do
Speaker 11:  You ever like sports?
Speaker 5:  Listen, not now, Richard. Not now.
Speaker 5:  We're gonna talk about Meta because Meta Connect was this week, big week
Speaker 5:  for Smart Glasses, big week for awkward demos in front of large
Speaker 5:  audiences, full of people big week for Mark Zuckerberg wearing sunglasses
Speaker 5:  that may or may not look very good on his face. We have a lot to talk about.
Speaker 5:  So we're gonna go through Meta Connect, then we have a lightning round full
Speaker 5:  of like a lot of surprisingly huge news. This is like an easy
Speaker 5:  four hour VERGE cast kind of week. But we are gonna do our best not to do
Speaker 5:  that three hours maximum. But let's start
Speaker 5:  with Meta Connect. So the, the top line of the news here
Speaker 5:  is that Meta announced a bunch of new smart glasses. I wanna get into all
Speaker 5:  of them, but basically there is a new product called, And I have to look
Speaker 5:  at these names because they're such horrendous name crimes. There is the
Speaker 5:  Meta Ray Band display, which is smart glasses with a little
Speaker 5:  display that we'll get into V Song who has worn all of these
Speaker 5:  and reviewed all of them said they're the best smart glasses she's ever tried.
Speaker 5:  And that is not a thing V says lightly. I think that's a big deal. There's
Speaker 5:  also the Oakley Meta Vanguard. Sure. And then
Speaker 5:  there is the new Meta Ray band. Smart glasses.
Speaker 12:  Sorry David. That's the RayBan Meta. No, did they? Unless they changed it.
Speaker 12:  Ah,
Speaker 5:  It's so I thought I had it right.
Speaker 12:  This is, this is like super inside baseball, but like the, the original
Speaker 12:  product is the RayBan Metas or RayBan Meta.
Speaker 12:  But like nobody knows that. And we're like, oh, it's the Meta Ray band.
Speaker 12:  And so it's just, it, it like writing about these on our website is just
Speaker 12:  constantly switching the Meta back and forth as we figure out which way
Speaker 12:  it goes. They need, they need better naming. I
Speaker 5:  Absolutely guarantee you that behind all of these names
Speaker 5:  were teams of executives and lawyers sitting in conference rooms
Speaker 5:  debating whose name comes first. It's like, if you ever watch the credits
Speaker 5:  of a movie and, and you wonder there's like, you know, they'll, they'll say
Speaker 5:  a bunch of names and then at the end it'll be like, and you know, Alec
Speaker 5:  Baldwin or like, and also guest starring
Speaker 5:  whatever Peter Gallagher, the order in which those names
Speaker 5:  appear and the the like prepositions that come before them is
Speaker 5:  like endlessly litigated and contracted. And I just, I just want
Speaker 5:  everyone watching and listening to this podcast to imagine the meeting in
Speaker 5:  which they decided which glasses would be the Meta RayBan and which would
Speaker 5:  be the RayBan Meta and be so, so happy that you
Speaker 5:  are not in a life that makes you be inside of that meeting.
Speaker 5:  That's all, that's all I have. Just be glad that whatever choices you have
Speaker 5:  made, you did not have to be in the meeting where you decided which one was
Speaker 5:  the Meta Ray band and which one was the RayBan Meta?
Speaker 12:  They're not even names, they're just a collection of brands
Speaker 12:  listed together.
Speaker 5:  It has such like Mark by Mark Jacobs starring Mark Jacobs energy in a,
Speaker 11:  Sorry, I gotta go the other way on this. You guys are out here disrespecting
Speaker 11:  the Meta Ray band Gen two.
Speaker 11:  My favorite pair of smart glasses.
Speaker 12:  I I get, I mean I know who makes it.
Speaker 5:  It's do you
Speaker 11:  Are you sure have, have you looked at their blog posts? They, they go back
Speaker 11:  and forth between calling the the Meta Ray band. I'm sorry, the RayBan Meta
Speaker 11:  Glasses Gen two. See I I did it myself. I I'm I'm there
Speaker 11:  also and the Ray Band Meta Glasses Gen two. So
Speaker 11:  is Gen two part of the name or is it not? So even,
Speaker 5:  Even the company that wants us to buy these things doesn't
Speaker 5:  know what they're actually called. This is the first time ever I've been
Speaker 5:  like, maybe Sony has it right just by having endless hexa decimal
Speaker 5:  situations every time they want to sell a new phone instead of headphones.
Speaker 11:  I still remember when we had to ask if it's iPod Shuffle or iPod Shuffles
Speaker 11:  or iPods shuffle.
Speaker 5:  Oh God. And Apple's whole thing where you can't put the in front of the
Speaker 5:  name. They don't call it the iPad. It's just iPad. Anyway,
Speaker 5:  if we keep talking about names, I will actually go insane because I could
Speaker 5:  do this forever. Let's start with the display. Well the
Speaker 5:  screen one, as we are going to call it from now on,
Speaker 5:  this is one we've been hearing a lot about for a while. Our, our
Speaker 5:  former colleague and current contributor Alex Heath, has been like scooping
Speaker 5:  this roadmap for years. And we got a demo of
Speaker 5:  Orion, which is, I would say like the, the more impressive version of this
Speaker 5:  idea last year. And then this year
Speaker 5:  it, this is the first sort of relatively
Speaker 5:  mainstream available version of smart glasses with a screen, which
Speaker 5:  we've known Meta is gonna be working on, but now it actually exists.
Speaker 5:  Let me just run through the specs real fast before we get into it. 'cause
Speaker 5:  I'm very curious what you both make of this because I, I have reacted to
Speaker 5:  this in a way that I did not expect. Basically they, they look like sunglasses.
Speaker 5:  They're a little thicker and a little heavier than the, the, even the smart
Speaker 5:  glasses we've seen before. They weigh 69 grams, which if that means nothing
Speaker 5:  to you, it's like double the weight of an AirPods case. So just
Speaker 5:  do without what you will tie two of those to your head and see how it feels.
Speaker 5:  They get about six hours of battery. They have 5,000 knits of
Speaker 5:  brightness on this little screen that sort of shows up in front of
Speaker 5:  your, it looks like your right eye. And it's, it's just a little tiny heads
Speaker 5:  up display. It's not like a full augmented reality thing. It's just a little
Speaker 5:  600 by 600, I think it's 20 degree field of view
Speaker 5:  screen that sits right in front of your eyes and it's very bright
Speaker 5:  and everybody who has m worn it says they're able to see it in,
Speaker 5:  even in bright Light V Song said if you look directly into the sun, you
Speaker 5:  won't be able to see it, but also don't do that. So that's fine. It's just
Speaker 5:  a, it's a pair of smart glasses with a little tiny display that does some
Speaker 5:  stuff. And I think that is like, that's both kind of it
Speaker 5:  and kind of enough to me And I wanna get into the control system in a
Speaker 5:  minute. But the glasses alone I feel like are actually
Speaker 5:  pretty exciting. But I'm curious, Richard, what was your, what was your reaction
Speaker 5:  to these?
Speaker 11:  I still wonder if there may be a little bit too early with these, And I
Speaker 11:  understand they're maybe still planning only on selling limited amounts
Speaker 11:  of these. I I don't know how many they think they will, will move. But one
Speaker 11:  of the things that they mentioned, And I I think we'll get to their conversation
Speaker 11:  with with Alex Heath is that lots of
Speaker 11:  people wear glasses already.
Speaker 11:  And as a person, I don't know David, are you a glasses contacts guy or,
Speaker 5:  I'm not a glasses contacts guy.
Speaker 11:  Oh, you one of those 2020
Speaker 5:  Actually it's better than 2020 vision. Like not to brag it is bragging. I
Speaker 5:  always knew there
Speaker 11:  Was some weird impression. It's fine.
Speaker 5:  I don't have a lot going for me. I've,
Speaker 11:  I've been trading the ability to look a little bit more punchable
Speaker 11:  for being able to see for basically my whole life. And
Speaker 11:  I don't know if I want to wear slightly thicker glasses just to have a screen
Speaker 11:  in 'em and to have to charge 'em all the time.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. So can I just read you the quote that Mark Zuckerberg said about this?
Speaker 5:  'cause I actually thought it was really instructive and interesting about
Speaker 5:  how they were talking about this. So this is an interview with Alex Heath
Speaker 5:  and he said there are between one to 2 billion people who wear glasses on
Speaker 5:  a daily basis today for vision correction. Is there a world where in five
Speaker 5:  or seven years the vast majority of those glasses are AI glasses in some
Speaker 5:  capacity? I think that's kind of like when the iPhone came out and everyone
Speaker 5:  had flip phones. It's just a matter of time before they all become smartphones.
Speaker 5:  I would say the iPhone comparison there doesn't make any sense like that
Speaker 5:  is he, he just described two completely different things where it's not that
Speaker 5:  everyone who had flip phones upgraded to smart like that, that's just none
Speaker 5:  of that is how it worked.
Speaker 5:  I think it's fascinating to hear him say that our target
Speaker 5:  market is people who wear glasses because we've had a lot of conversations
Speaker 5:  on this show and elsewhere, basically asking the question,
Speaker 5:  are any of these companies going to be able to convince people who don't
Speaker 5:  wear glasses to wear glasses? And I think that is a steep, steep, steep,
Speaker 5:  steep hill to climb for all of these companies. But the idea
Speaker 5:  that they're just saying, okay, how do we take the glasses you're already
Speaker 5:  wearing and try to put some intelligence and smarts into them
Speaker 5:  vastly more achievable. Like yes, smaller market, hard for
Speaker 5:  lots of different reasons, people's prescriptions are complicated. Managing
Speaker 5:  this stuff is complicated. These things get expensive really fast, like on
Speaker 5:  and on. But I think thinking about that as the target market is just
Speaker 5:  really interesting to me and not at all what I expected. So like he's, he's
Speaker 5:  after the two of you who wear glasses and he, he is trying to convince you
Speaker 5:  way before he tries to convince me that these things are worth wearing all
Speaker 5:  day every day.
Speaker 12:  Also like to Richard's point, I I'm wearing wire frame
Speaker 12:  glasses right now, like wire frame glasses are, are I, listen,
Speaker 12:  I'm, I'm not gonna put myself out there as like a fashion expert, but I
Speaker 12:  feel like they're much more in than the like super chunky, thick
Speaker 12:  hipster glasses that I think the Meta Ray Ban
Speaker 12:  Display glasses are, are much more in line with they had those
Speaker 12:  15 years ago, oh man, that they would be right on target.
Speaker 12:  These things are cyclical. Maybe they'll come back around, maybe they can
Speaker 12:  convince us. But right now these are, they're, they're thicker than a standard
Speaker 12:  pair of Wayfairs And I
Speaker 12:  I'm not sure that's even the, you know, most popular type right now. So
Speaker 12:  look, these are a fashion product. It has to be fashionable first and foremost.
Speaker 12:  You know, whether the tech can get there is, is a whole other question.
Speaker 12:  So I think they have a, a challenge number one in just like bringing these
Speaker 12:  two different styles of glasses right now it is in one style as far as I
Speaker 12:  can tell, and it is bigger than a standard pair of glasses. They
Speaker 12:  look, they look all right. They're like, it's stylized. It's like heavily
Speaker 12:  stylized.
Speaker 12:  Can they make that work in smaller pairs of glasses? It's gonna take a while.
Speaker 12:  And I think that's like a big part of the
Speaker 5:  Story here. Yeah. And for whatever sort it does seem like Meta is
Speaker 5:  better set up to do that than almost anybody, right? This, this huge
Speaker 5:  partnership they have with Esler Luxottica is a big deal. And
Speaker 5:  that's like, that's the company that makes most people's glasses. And so
Speaker 5:  the the ability to move this stuff through
Speaker 5:  styles and lines and brands over time is there. But
Speaker 5:  I agree like Jake, the gap between what we saw today
Speaker 5:  and your glasses is enormous. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  We're nowhere close. Even
Speaker 12:  Like Richard's glasses,
Speaker 5:  Which have some plastic to them, I don't think we're anywhere,
Speaker 11:  Anywhere close to this. No. It it's, it's massive. And and they are big
Speaker 11:  in a way that when someone sees you wearing them, they, they, they're saying,
Speaker 11:  oh, you've got those on. Yeah. Which as the glasses
Speaker 11:  wear, I can say is not the thing that you want to hear from someone who's
Speaker 11:  noticed that you wear glasses.
Speaker 5:  Oh, you've got those on is is such a real thing that's
Speaker 5:  happening right now in all of these spaces. 'cause I think to me,
Speaker 5:  like I, I wear the, I have the, the original Meta Ray bands
Speaker 5:  that I like a lot And I, I wear them mostly to use as headphones And
Speaker 5:  I ironically, as they've become more popular, people are noticing
Speaker 5:  them more on my face, which is not what I expected. Like you, you, you expect
Speaker 5:  this stuff to sort of blend in as you start to see more
Speaker 5:  people wearing it. You like, like you don't notice somebody wearing AirPods
Speaker 5:  anymore, right? Like you don't clock AirPods as they go by. If I wear these,
Speaker 5:  I get constant notif notices because like you can tell because
Speaker 5:  people inadvertently make eye contact with you because they're looking at
Speaker 5:  your eyes. And so as I'm walking down the street, I'm constantly giving people
Speaker 5:  who are just like sort of giving me these sideways glances as I walk by them.
Speaker 5:  And yeah, I get that is not what anybody is looking for with
Speaker 5:  their pair of glasses. I don't think
Speaker 11:  The screen does seem to be good, right? They they
Speaker 11:  did it.
Speaker 5:  It is, and this is, this is the thing that is like fascinating about this
Speaker 5:  whole road that Meta is on right now is it seems like the screen
Speaker 5:  works. And to me, if you're, if you're gonna get a pair of glasses like this,
Speaker 5:  a screen makes absolute perfect sense, right? A bunch of the stuff that they're
Speaker 5:  talking about doing on this is simple things like
Speaker 5:  being able to, you know, get turn by turn directions in your
Speaker 5:  heads up display, perfect use case for this kind of thing. Live translation
Speaker 5:  in front of your eyes as you're talking to somebody. Perfect use case for
Speaker 5:  this kind of display. Like using your vision
Speaker 5:  to line up a photo that you're taking with the camera in your glasses.
Speaker 5:  Perfect use case for this kind of like, if we're gonna do smart
Speaker 5:  glasses, they need displays. I think we've known that for a while and
Speaker 5:  it seems like if you're Meta you've got it,
Speaker 5:  if not right, then, then largely right. Like it, we will have to see and
Speaker 5:  you know, use the thing and review it properly. But, but I think you're right,
Speaker 5:  it does seem like the early returns on this thing are that
Speaker 5:  Meta kind of got it right. The question is just even more so
Speaker 5:  is this a thing that I want? I don't know. And I think the thing that I'm
Speaker 5:  so struck by with this one in particular is there is
Speaker 5:  this weird kind of distant look you get
Speaker 5:  in your eyes when you're looking at a heads up display that is just
Speaker 5:  awkward in life. And, and a lot of our coverage pointed
Speaker 5:  this out And I think it's, it's just a strange thing that like, no, you're
Speaker 5:  not gonna be able to see my screen if I'm wearing these glasses, right?
Speaker 5:  Like if you And I are just sitting here looking at each other and we're both
Speaker 5:  wearing glasses, you're not gonna be able to see that my screen is on, but
Speaker 5:  you're gonna be able to see that I'm focusing my eyes kind of up
Speaker 5:  here and not on you. And it, like a lot of the pictures I've seen
Speaker 5:  kind of make it look like people are just sort of staring
Speaker 5:  at nothing and it's, it's just this weird
Speaker 5:  distracted thing that's happening. And at the same time, the not knowing
Speaker 5:  is just as big a problem to me. Like, we went through this with
Speaker 5:  glass holes and this question of like, are you recording is a problem?
Speaker 5:  And so not only are you, are you recording, but are you
Speaker 5:  listening to me? Are you paying attention to me? Can you, are you looking
Speaker 5:  at me? Is like, there's so many like social cues that
Speaker 5:  a pair of glasses like this totally destroys. And I just, I don't
Speaker 5:  know how we figure that out.
Speaker 12:  I I sorta worry that we are completely
Speaker 12:  past that, right? You think, oh yes, because Google Glass came
Speaker 12:  very early smartphone era, right? People were not used to
Speaker 12:  screens and cameras being everywhere yet. You know, 10,
Speaker 12:  15 years on, you can strap 10 cameras to your face and
Speaker 12:  somebody's just like, yo, what's up? Like, that's nor right, like the, the
Speaker 12:  other pair of glasses, they make their headphones and cameras on your
Speaker 12:  face. Nobody cares. Right?
Speaker 5:  But that's, that's kind of the point, right? Like I think if I have a, if
Speaker 5:  I put a GoPro on my face, you, you, you know the answers to all of
Speaker 5:  your questions already, right? Like, I'm wearing a GoPro on my face. Yes.
Speaker 5:  I have a camera on that is recording you. If I'm just wearing a pair
Speaker 5:  of glasses that has a camera in them, like the, the subtlety
Speaker 5:  is actually the problem. In a strange way, if this thing just had a big
Speaker 5:  ass screen that like came out of the glasses and folded down and
Speaker 5:  you just saw it right here,
Speaker 5:  that would be worse in some ways, but better as a, in, in
Speaker 5:  a, in a like human interaction kind of way because then at least I know what's
Speaker 5:  going on. Whereas my read of you as a person is
Speaker 5:  now totally incongruous with reality. It's like the transparency mode in
Speaker 5:  AirPods, which I think this has borne out in a lot of interesting ways. Like
Speaker 5:  when, if you guys are wearing headphones and you go into a store, what do
Speaker 5:  you do if you're gonna, you're, you're like, you're, you're up at the counter
Speaker 5:  at the coffee shop, you have both headphones in. Do you take one out? Do
Speaker 5:  you just pause your music and talk through your headphones? Like what do
Speaker 5:  you, what do you do? I
Speaker 11:  Usually just pause the music and talk.
Speaker 5:  Okay, Jake, what
Speaker 12:  Do you do? Oh yeah, I'm, I'm I'm taking them out. Yeah, I, it's like, it's
Speaker 12:  in the way, I mean, it's like the same thing if, if I, if I go into the
Speaker 12:  store And I'm wearing sunglasses, like I'm gonna take them off to talk to
Speaker 12:  somebody,
Speaker 5:  I will always like performatively take out one of my headphones to be like,
Speaker 5:  like as I'm walking up, just to make it very clear that like, yes, I'm listening
Speaker 5:  to you. Like, 'cause I think it, it communicates something right? And there's
Speaker 5:  like, you can see sometimes when somebody is
Speaker 5:  talking to you and you're wearing headphones, they don't know if you can
Speaker 5:  hear them. And there's just like, there's just a million things like this
Speaker 5:  in, in modern life and smart glasses exacerbate every single one of them.
Speaker 5:  And Jake, you're, you're probably right that if we're not over that yet,
Speaker 5:  we will get there quickly. And
Speaker 12:  I, I'm not saying we should
Speaker 5:  Or we'll get used to it or whatever, but it's just, just, I don't know, this
Speaker 5:  is just a thing I keep thinking about. And even looking at pictures, it's
Speaker 5:  like there's something uncanny about
Speaker 5:  some of the pictures we took even a v where she's looking at the camera,
Speaker 5:  but she's not looking at the camera and you can feel it and it's strange.
Speaker 5:  I don't know. That said, these glasses seem awesome.
Speaker 12:  I, I mean I'm
Speaker 5:  Torn on, well
Speaker 12:  This is the thing, like they've been building toward this for
Speaker 12:  many years now and they've been pretty public about the fact that they're
Speaker 12:  building toward this and they're one of many companies, right? Snap has
Speaker 12:  also been racing toward this and it's, I don't know, it, it hasn't been
Speaker 12:  clear to me that we were going to get to a
Speaker 12:  consumer product version this quickly. And obviously we still
Speaker 12:  have to test them, but you know, in these, in these initial
Speaker 12:  demos, it seems like they have built a reasonably functional product
Speaker 12:  and a reasonably functional form factor. A little thick, a little chunky,
Speaker 12:  but you know, that's, that's farther than I think anybody expected. Meta
Speaker 12:  the company that makes Facebook to get with a hardware product, let alone
Speaker 12:  to, to be leaders in the field.
Speaker 5:  Totally. Yeah. I I think that's exactly right. And I think this
Speaker 5:  is probably where we should also talk about the neural band, which is a,
Speaker 5:  a thing that Meta is doing differently from a lot of these other
Speaker 5:  companies that I happen to think is maybe the
Speaker 5:  smartest single decision that Meta has made. So the way that
Speaker 5:  you control a lot of the stuff on these smart glasses is not with
Speaker 5:  like eye tracking or wacky, you know, camera hand tracking
Speaker 5:  stuff. You wear this thing on your arm
Speaker 5:  that actually measures and responds to your motor
Speaker 5:  movements and it uses the, the term it's called electromyography,
Speaker 5:  which is a thing that I know a lot about. So if you'd like to talk about
Speaker 5:  it, we, we please can, but basically you, like you, you put this thing on
Speaker 5:  and then you don't have to have your hands up in view of your glasses, you
Speaker 5:  don't have to have your hands anywhere. You can just, you can just sort of
Speaker 5:  sit here with your hands in your lap and you, you, I think you pinch to
Speaker 5:  select or to go back depending contextually on where you are, you double
Speaker 5:  pinch your fingers to get the display up or
Speaker 5:  dismiss it. You like make a fist and sort of joystick swipe on it to do
Speaker 5:  other stuff. You, you pinch and rotate to, to
Speaker 5:  do zoom in photos or to change the volume. It is like
Speaker 5:  the closest thing we've done yet to the Minority Report interface. It's just
Speaker 5:  like a smaller, more subtle version of Tom Cruise, like moving all the windows
Speaker 5:  around with his hands. And again, this is another thing that
Speaker 5:  like all the demos say it works. Everybody says it is vastly more natural
Speaker 5:  than what you have to do with a lot of these other devices, which is like
Speaker 5:  in the Vision Pro, you have to get used to really carefully
Speaker 5:  focusing on every single thing you wanna do, which is just like, not how
Speaker 5:  people exist in the world and on a lot of these other devices,
Speaker 5:  you spend your time like putting your hands up in front of you
Speaker 5:  in order to take actions and that's awkward. And so I think
Speaker 5:  the idea of it being a separate accessory is probably not
Speaker 5:  ideal in the long run, but is to me
Speaker 5:  a way better system of controlling this kind of thing than basically anything
Speaker 5:  else we've seen before. Am I crazy?
Speaker 12:  It it's subtle too. It like, it, it looks like a wristband and, and like
Speaker 12:  my immediate, the immediate thought is like they, they're gonna put a watch
Speaker 12:  on this thing, right? Like,
Speaker 5:  Ooh, that's a good call.
Speaker 12:  Like th this feels like it becomes something. It's, it seems
Speaker 12:  like it's cool tech on its own regardless of the glasses.
Speaker 5:  Oh man. If this was just, if it was like this but also a Fitbit, like yes.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 12:  I mean
Speaker 5:  I'm
Speaker 12:  So in
Speaker 5:  Makes sense it, I don't even need the screen stuff. Like I got all the screen
Speaker 5:  up here. Just, just give me like step and
Speaker 5:  sleep tracking And I'll wear that thing all the time. Done. That's a great
Speaker 5:  idea. Mark, get at us. I
Speaker 5:  dunno. Richard, what do you think?
Speaker 11:  I think that's definitely the right decision. We've, we've shown this is
Speaker 11:  how controls work. Have you ever played a video game?
Speaker 11:  Like have you ever used a computer? We we've had,
Speaker 11:  we've had this battle. Yeah, like being able to use your, your hands to
Speaker 11:  control something is, is just better than voice or eye tracking or
Speaker 11:  like head or trying to, to wave in front of you at virtual
Speaker 11:  things. Like, like even if you're not holding something, it's just, it,
Speaker 11:  it's just a correct way. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  I agree. And I think making it like a core part of this
Speaker 5:  system
Speaker 5:  probably again alienates some people. 'cause again, it's like if the goal
Speaker 5:  is just to get people who wear glasses
Speaker 5:  to wear these different glasses, you've now asked me to do even more stuff.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, right. I'm spending more money on bigger glasses
Speaker 5:  with a different style And I have to wear this other thing. But for like
Speaker 5:  if, if you sort of back your way down from what the technology can do,
Speaker 5:  this feels like exactly the right road to be going down.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I just think, I think these are very cool And I'm very curious to see
Speaker 5:  how they do. I think,
Speaker 5:  I think it was Andrew Bosworth, one of the Meta executives told Alex Heath
Speaker 5:  that they're only planning to make a couple hundred thousand of them, which
Speaker 5:  suggests that these are not supposed to be like a huge
Speaker 5:  mainstream product. Even the, the RayBan metas we've been hearing single
Speaker 5:  digit millions for what they've sold, which is like a
Speaker 5:  hilariously different term, single digit millions can mean an awful
Speaker 5:  lot of different numbers.
Speaker 5:  But even that compared to, you know, a couple hundred thousand makes
Speaker 5:  clear really kind of what they're going for here. Which brings
Speaker 5:  us to the next one, which I think I have come to think might be
Speaker 5:  sneakily the coolest thing Meta launched this week, which is
Speaker 5:  the Oakley Meta Vanguard, which are some deeply
Speaker 5:  baller ass wraparound Oakley sunglasses
Speaker 5:  with a camera in the nose bridge, like essentially the way I've come to think
Speaker 5:  about these things, it is, it's a GoPro on your sunglasses. And
Speaker 5:  that strikes me as maybe exactly
Speaker 5:  the correct thing to have done here. Jake, you wear
Speaker 5:  wraparounds to and from work every day if, if memory serves.
Speaker 12:  Yeah. As you can tell, I'm big into extreme sports,
Speaker 12:  so no, I,
Speaker 5:  Whenever Jake is not on The Vergecast, I want you to picture him bass fishing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, that's, that's important to me. Yeah.
Speaker 12:  IE even what's the opposite of extreme sports? Like
Speaker 12:  I animal don't ask you much. For me, these
Speaker 12:  look outrageous and kind of amazing. And
Speaker 12:  the, the, the thing is there really is just like a big
Speaker 12:  chunky camera right above your nose and it looks a little goofy,
Speaker 12:  but also the, the entire like
Speaker 12:  vibe of these oakleys is like boom in your face. It
Speaker 12:  kind of works. And for like that, for, for what you're trying
Speaker 12:  to film. Oh, that's perfect. Well,
Speaker 11:  So they do fitness tracking too and the camera bit.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, they'll do, they have a heart rate monitor. They do the, the camera
Speaker 5:  stuff and it has like a bunch of
Speaker 5:  partnerships with Strava and Garmin and it, you can do,
Speaker 5:  you, you can use the LED that I think is supposed to show you heart rate
Speaker 5:  stuff also to give you like pacing information as you're going for runs.
Speaker 5:  So there's, there's a lot of like knowledge about who is actually
Speaker 5:  buying sunglasses that look like this anyway. Like, again, it's, it's the
Speaker 5:  same sort of thing we were talking about where it's like we want to take
Speaker 5:  people who might buy something that look like this anyway and give them all
Speaker 5:  these new things to do for this price, but instead of everyone who wears
Speaker 5:  glasses, it's people who buy glasses that look like this. And that to me
Speaker 5:  is such a smart way of thinking about this, right? We're like,
Speaker 5:  wayfarers are, are a choice you make if what you want is sort of the
Speaker 5:  least offensive thing that looks good on the most
Speaker 5:  people kind of glasses. This is the opposite. It's like here is a slice
Speaker 5:  of people and it is a very specific place of people who are going to wear
Speaker 5:  tinted rainbow colored cool ass
Speaker 5:  wraparounds and we're just gonna give them things that those people might
Speaker 5:  want. And that is a completely different way of thinking about what smart
Speaker 5:  glasses might be. But to me is like, if you wanna make one that works right
Speaker 5:  now for people, that's how you do it.
Speaker 12:  I also like, I think there's a really interesting distinction there. The,
Speaker 12:  the Meta Ray band displays the display smart, those
Speaker 12:  are smart glasses. They're glasses with a screen that show you stuff.
Speaker 12:  The all of these other ones, they're fancy headphones in the shape of
Speaker 12:  a pair of glasses, right? Yes. Like, well the air pods now do heart
Speaker 12:  rate tracking. These are just AirPods that also like block
Speaker 12:  the sun, right? That that is a thing people want and buy,
Speaker 12:  right? People like fitness tracking people like headphones, people like
Speaker 12:  sunglasses. Combining all three makes a ton of sense.
Speaker 12:  And being good at one doesn't necessarily mean you're gonna be good at making
Speaker 12:  true smart glasses. So I, I think like there's still
Speaker 12:  a lot they have to prove out with that idea, but were they early
Speaker 12:  to this let's stuff headphones into a glasses form factor and
Speaker 12:  let's start making that, you know, even more useful and more valuable.
Speaker 12:  Absolutely. And the, the vanguard like as kind of ludicrous of a product
Speaker 12:  as it seems. Oh, they're just putting more and more like useful
Speaker 12:  things that people already buy and want into a pair of sunglasses. Which
Speaker 12:  again, to your point, David, there's already a market for these sunglasses
Speaker 12:  right now. They're just making them better.
Speaker 5:  It's cool, right? Yeah. And, and it's like, I think if, if that's, if you're
Speaker 5:  a Meta and you want this stuff to be useful to people, that's the way to
Speaker 5:  do it. Find sunglasses, people are already buying and give,
Speaker 5:  put the things that people are doing when they wear those sunglasses into
Speaker 5:  the sunglasses. And one of those things is like bass fishing
Speaker 5:  with a GoPro on. And, and again, there there are like a bunch of features
Speaker 5:  on this that suggest that who this is for
Speaker 5:  again, right? The, the battery's even longer. It's nine hours of battery,
Speaker 5:  like, like you said, Jake, they're pretty chunky and thick. But again, that's,
Speaker 5:  that's to get a pretty big camera in here.
Speaker 5:  It does up to three K and up to 120 frames per second of video, but not at
Speaker 5:  the same time. The more frame rate you get, the less resolution you're gonna
Speaker 5:  get because otherwise you would essentially let your face on fire. I think
Speaker 5:  these things would get so hot, but yeah, they had, they have the heart rate
Speaker 5:  monitor. It's like, it is so distinctly obvious who these glasses are for
Speaker 5:  And I I just think that's very smart. They are a total name crime again
Speaker 5:  because they're the Oakley Meta Vanguards, which is just a, just a bad name.
Speaker 5:  But the other ones were, were just called HSTN the last time Oakley and
Speaker 5:  Meta did one together and it's like the Houston, Houston whatever glasses.
Speaker 5:  Those were dumb. This is better. That's my take.
Speaker 12:  I agree. And the and the the Oakley of it all is so essential to it, right?
Speaker 12:  Like again, this literally is a product. People are already buying,
Speaker 12:  people already want these specific sunglasses from Oakley. Yeah. Now you're
Speaker 12:  just giving them an upgrade version.
Speaker 5:  Richard, I feel like you'd look cool in wraparounds. What are your thoughts?
Speaker 11:  Never tried it, but maybe
Speaker 5:  I think The Verge cast fashion show in which you try them on no one
Speaker 5:  can see and we talk about it. Fabulous idea. Podcast fashion
Speaker 5:  show is a, is a thing we're gonna pioneer here on this show. It's gonna be
Speaker 5:  amazing. So the other device that Meta
Speaker 5:  announced is the more like main Streamy
Speaker 5:  RayBan Smart Glasses. This is like the new version of the ones
Speaker 5:  that have been out there for a while. And like you said, Jake, they are headphones,
Speaker 5:  they're functionally they are like I I I compare these to
Speaker 5:  like Alexa devices a lot where there are
Speaker 5:  technically lots of things that they can do and are for everybody does the
Speaker 5:  same two things and, and on on Echo devices, people play music and
Speaker 5:  they set timers and then there's a long list of other things that almost
Speaker 5:  nobody does on, on these glasses. You can listen to music
Speaker 5:  and you can take pictures and there's a long list of stuff that people can
Speaker 5:  do. You can do the live ai, lots of interesting ideas about what you
Speaker 5:  might do with a pair of smart glasses. They are sunglasses with speakers
Speaker 5:  and a camera. That's it. That's the whole pitch. And so if that's your whole
Speaker 5:  pitch doing what Meta did here I think is,
Speaker 5:  is correct. The new model is
Speaker 5:  it's more expensive, which is a bummer, but pricing is
Speaker 5:  goofy. Tariffs and inflation and everything has made the cost of everything
Speaker 5:  insane. So like do with the $80 price increase, what
Speaker 5:  you will, it's 379 $9 instead of 2 99,
Speaker 5:  but it has double the rated battery life eight hours on a
Speaker 5:  charge, which is a big deal. The difference between getting four hours of
Speaker 5:  battery on your sunglasses and getting eight is actually the difference between
Speaker 5:  like the battery being annoying and the battery not being annoying. I think
Speaker 5:  in most cases, especially if you have the charging case, which puts it up
Speaker 5:  to, I think it was 48 hours of total battery life.
Speaker 5:  So this is like a, you're charging your sunglasses once a week kind of thing,
Speaker 5:  and that's a pretty solid setup. They also have a bunch of the camera improvements.
Speaker 5:  So you can do up to three K video and up to 60 frames per second, but not
Speaker 5:  at the same time,
Speaker 5:  all four up to three minutes at a time. Again, to keep your face from lighting
Speaker 5:  on fire with the heat of your sunglasses. That would be a
Speaker 5:  tough way to go to the hospital by the way. They're like, what happened to
Speaker 5:  you? What, what are these third degree burns all over your face? And you're
Speaker 5:  like, well I was taking some sweet beach picks
Speaker 5:  and here we are. But anyway, this is like
Speaker 5:  the mainstream version of this thing And I think it continues to be
Speaker 5:  good and interesting and, and kind of more compelling than anybody else who
Speaker 5:  is doing this sort of thing. This
Speaker 12:  Is a tricky upgrade. Like on one hand, double the battery, great. They did
Speaker 12:  the exact thing they should do perfect eight hours is
Speaker 12:  in the ballpark of where you should be. On the other hand, you know, to,
Speaker 12:  to keep repeating my argument, these are headphones and
Speaker 12:  they're now three $79 pair of AirPods Pro three
Speaker 12:  are $250. Those things are gonna be on sale for, for lower
Speaker 12:  than that in a couple of months. So I don't know, this gets tricky.
Speaker 12:  Like I feel like when the old model, which I guess is still available for
Speaker 12:  2 99, but you know, those were when they were available at that price, I
Speaker 12:  think that's closer in price to what you might pay for a pair of wireless
Speaker 12:  headphones. Anyway. Thi this seems like it's
Speaker 12:  getting a little up there. Maybe a little tricky if you're a big fan of
Speaker 12:  these already. Maybe this, this makes sense. I do wonder if this is gonna
Speaker 12:  make it harder for them to get sort of that impulse buy that maybe
Speaker 12:  they were banking on for the original model where people were kind of just
Speaker 12:  like, wow, I can't believe I can get a pair of sunglasses that do that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I think I, if you're at a point where it's like a a hundred dollars
Speaker 5:  markup to get all this stuff in it, you, you, you start to have a, an
Speaker 5:  easier case to make, but when it's like double the price and
Speaker 5:  now it'll play music when you already own a pair of headphones. I do agree
Speaker 5:  that's it's a different set of things that Meta
Speaker 5:  is trying to get you to be into here. Yeah, and it really depends on the,
Speaker 5:  the AI being good and my experience
Speaker 5:  with Meta's live AI and frankly all of these live AI
Speaker 5:  systems is that they're not very good. Sometimes they're good, sometimes
Speaker 5:  they're trash. And actually, wait, can I, can I play you a
Speaker 5:  clip from Meta Connect, which was, I would say we, we've
Speaker 5:  all been to a lot of these events. We've covered a lot of these events. We,
Speaker 5:  we have more sympathy than most for the
Speaker 5:  cringey demo fails. But in the, in the annals of cringey
Speaker 5:  demo fails, Meta Connect was a tough one this year. So let me,
Speaker 5:  let me just set this up for you and then I'm gonna play you the full 53 seconds
Speaker 5:  of this clip. Oh no. Because you need to experience every second of it. So
Speaker 5:  in, in a, in an effort to test the live AI stuff on the smart glasses,
Speaker 5:  we have a chef standing up on stage or he's standing up
Speaker 5:  somewhere in front of a table with a bunch of ingredients on it. And the
Speaker 5:  idea is he's gonna use the live AI with the,
Speaker 5:  with the camera and all of the different systems, the the whole multimodal
Speaker 5:  AI setup to make some food.
Speaker 5:  Here's what happens.
Speaker 13:  You can make a Korean inspired steak sauce using soy sauce,
Speaker 13:  sesame oil. What
Speaker 14:  Do I do first French,
Speaker 14:  what do I do first?
Speaker 13:  You've already combined the base ingredients. So now create a pear
Speaker 13:  to add to the sauce.
Speaker 14:  What do I do first?
Speaker 13:  You've already combined the base ingredients, so now grate the pear and
Speaker 13:  gently combine it with the base sauce.
Speaker 14:  All right. I think the wifi might be messed up. Sorry, back to you, mark.
Speaker 14:  It's all good. You know what,
Speaker 14:  it's all good.
Speaker 14:  It's the irony of the whole thing is that you spend
Speaker 14:  years making technology and then the wifi at the day kind of
Speaker 14:  catches you. Alright?
Speaker 5:  Can we just say, first of all, that was obviously not a wifi problem.
Speaker 5:  Nope.
Speaker 12:  Like extremely
Speaker 5:  Not a wifi problem
Speaker 12:  And, and not the only time that happened. Yeah, that it was, well that was
Speaker 12:  the start of the demo fails of the
Speaker 5:  Day. Yeah, it was tough. Yeah. But it, it's like that to me was so
Speaker 5:  illustrative of like the whole AI experience. Like imagine
Speaker 5:  being in front of lots of people doing this demo
Speaker 5:  and even just in your own kitchen trying to talk
Speaker 5:  to the ai and it is like you've put all the base ingredients together and
Speaker 5:  actually what's happening is you're standing in front of an empty bowl and
Speaker 5:  you've done nothing. That experience is so awful
Speaker 5:  and, and because it's ai, because it's voice, because it's, it's sort of
Speaker 5:  directionless like this, it's not clear where to go. It's not clear how
Speaker 5:  to go back. It's not clear how to fix things. It's not clear how to start
Speaker 5:  over. Like the UI of this is so unfinished
Speaker 5:  and the quality of it is so intermittent. I've been stuck in this thing
Speaker 5:  so many times too, where it's like you're just trying to ask a simple question,
Speaker 5:  but you need the answer before you can do something. But because you're doing
Speaker 5:  with ai, you've gone down some insane impossible rabbit hole.
Speaker 5:  And the idea that I'm going to like trust my ongoing
Speaker 5:  day-to-day life to this thing that I can chat with is like
Speaker 5:  that's, you can just see why it breaks all the time and it's not because
Speaker 5:  of the wifi, it's just not
Speaker 12:  So, okay. I I'm curious, are you guys
Speaker 12:  pro these live demos, like, do you think that
Speaker 12:  companies should still do these despite the very obvious
Speaker 12:  possibility of failure embarrassment like this, right? Because like the
Speaker 12:  obvious thing is that then everybody makes fun of you, right? It's just
Speaker 12:  very easy for 'em to not do these and to script these.
Speaker 5:  Yes. I mean, I I have spent years
Speaker 5:  wondering how valuable these events are at all for these companies,
Speaker 5:  but also like I, I love live demos And I think the the
Speaker 5:  flip side is when these live demos work
Speaker 5:  and are cool, it's really impressive. What we've seen is a lot
Speaker 5:  of even quote unquote live demos are not live. So even the ones that seem
Speaker 5:  live, you should take with a real grain of salt at this point. These things
Speaker 5:  are so on rails and like I think about the, the
Speaker 5:  truck demo where the, the so-called self-driving truck was just
Speaker 5:  rolling down the hill. Like it's, it's, some of this isn't, is
Speaker 5:  not real, but I I I genuinely applaud Meta for trying to do this
Speaker 5:  stuff live on stage and Google sometimes tries to do it live on stage. Although
Speaker 5:  ev even it is going more towards some of these canned demos. Like
Speaker 5:  it's just, you should be able to do this in front of people if you're gonna
Speaker 5:  ship it to the world, right? Like if you, if the demo fails, maybe your
Speaker 5:  product's not done, I think is is kind of where I land.
Speaker 11:  Yeah. I mean if you're telling me it's gonna work at my house, you know,
Speaker 11:  sometimes the wifi is bad, sometimes a step has been missed
Speaker 11:  or the AI just doesn't catch something the right way.
Speaker 11:  If, if it can't recover, then that, that kind of is the question that is
Speaker 11:  the whole sales pitch and, and you should make it. And I think largely that
Speaker 11:  when these failures happen, if the product is good when it comes out, people
Speaker 11:  forget about it very quickly.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But then when it, when it sucks, everybody goes back to these launches
Speaker 5:  and it was like, oh right, it sucked. What what they really did is they
Speaker 5:  should have taught this poor chef how to actually use the glasses. Like
Speaker 5:  this is such a a, like, he was given a set of things
Speaker 5:  to say, knowing the responses he was gonna get, and they just put the whole
Speaker 5:  demo on rails and it's like, what, what actually needs to happen if you wanna
Speaker 5:  use one of these systems, is you need to learn how to use it. Like if, if
Speaker 5:  you want to be good at ai, you need to learn how to do
Speaker 5:  good prompting and you need to learn how to engage with the thing and you
Speaker 5:  need to learn how to back it up and you need to learn how to start over.
Speaker 5:  Like they're going to fail. And actually we, we've seen some of
Speaker 5:  these moss open AI has actually done this a lot in, in some of its product
Speaker 5:  launches where it is people who are clearly like conversant
Speaker 5:  in speaking with an AI system. And you see the difference where it's like
Speaker 5:  even when stuff fails, they're able to sort of redirect and they understand
Speaker 5:  how the system works and they're able to back up and start over and try new
Speaker 5:  things. And that ends up actually seeming more impressive
Speaker 5:  in a lot of cases because it's like, oh, this is this imperfect thing
Speaker 5:  that you are interacting with, but you understand how to bend it to your
Speaker 5:  will. And it's like, if this AI stuff is gonna work, that's the bar for
Speaker 5:  all of us. We all have
Speaker 5:  I'm sure Facebook is gonna sell me ads based on what we've been talking about
Speaker 5:  here. But let's, let's just run through some stuff. There's actually like
Speaker 5:  a surprising amount of news this week, so we're gonna try to plow through
Speaker 5:  a bunch of it as quickly as we can. Richard, why don't you go first? What
Speaker 5:  do you have
Speaker 11:  Reddit, if we haven't talked about enough AI already, let's talk about what
Speaker 11:  really powers ai. You posters people who post on the internet
Speaker 11:  who say have their opinions about things. Something that, And I, And I think
Speaker 11:  Josh Je had had an article that we published a while ago about how
Speaker 11:  humans really power these AI tools that you see. And
Speaker 11:  Reddit has been profiting from that. They have a deal with Google that they've
Speaker 11:  had for a while and Bloomberg reported this week that they're trying to
Speaker 11:  renegotiate. And part of it seems to be that they want not only to
Speaker 11:  provide results and data for Google and other companies to
Speaker 11:  process, to use for, for ai, for AI training, but
Speaker 11:  also for Google and whoever else to do things that feed back
Speaker 11:  into making people post on Reddit more, which would improve those
Speaker 11:  tools because they would've more data to be sourced from. And you kind of
Speaker 11:  see how there's this very interesting thing where we think about how
Speaker 11:  generative AI works and oh, it's just these computers doing things, but
Speaker 11:  really it's people, and in this case it's posters. We, we broke down
Speaker 11:  the type of guy who posts and you sir are very
Speaker 11:  valuable.
Speaker 5:  This is, to me it's like this is just Reddit saying the quiet part loud,
Speaker 5:  right? Which is like, we made this deal with Google.
Speaker 5:  The the open web is, is just falling into complete chaos.
Speaker 5:  There are no good websites left except The Verge dot com subscribe to The
Speaker 5:  Verge. And without
Speaker 5:  Reddit results, Google is effectively useless, which is more and more true
Speaker 5:  every single day. Like it, it is, at least in my own day-to-day
Speaker 5:  experience, it is wild how often I
Speaker 5:  end up on Reddit after doing a Google search. Like more and more all the
Speaker 5:  time. It feels like that's where people land. And so Reddit is like, okay,
Speaker 5:  well you've now hitched your wagon to us because we're the only thing left
Speaker 5:  on the web
Speaker 5:  payout. Like this is, this is how, this is how you make it
Speaker 5:  more valuable for all of us. You're gonna give us, you're gonna give us money
Speaker 5:  and you're gonna give us users and in exchange we're gonna keep this whole
Speaker 5:  flywheel going for you. And I wonder if Google
Speaker 5:  is already starting to regret the extent to which it is
Speaker 5:  relying on Reddit because it's actually Google specifically
Speaker 5:  is making Reddit very, very, very powerful. And I think that's so
Speaker 5:  fascinating. And this company that could for years couldn't figure out how
Speaker 5:  to be effectively run or rub two nickels together is all of a sudden
Speaker 5:  like the last bastion of the web. And
Speaker 5:  boy would I not have predicted this a couple of years ago, but it is now
Speaker 5:  and now it's in a position where like Reddit's really powerful because you're
Speaker 5:  right Richard, like it is, it is the most valuable
Speaker 5:  consistent resource of humans on the internet
Speaker 5:  right now for so, so many different things. Yeah. And
Speaker 11:  Part of the reason why it's so valuable and so consistent is because it's
Speaker 11:  moderated and so many other areas aren't. Yeah. But that's really the difference.
Speaker 5:  And because Reddit is willing to then structure and sell all of the data,
Speaker 5:  which is like, and that's, that's the flywheel and, And I think it seems
Speaker 5:  to have decided that it's fine and users will not
Speaker 5:  revolt and it will be okay and now it's just gonna,
Speaker 5:  it's just gonna milk that for all it's worth.
Speaker 12:  This is such a power play from Reddit. Like we talked about this last week,
Speaker 12:  right? Like every change they're making is is built around the
Speaker 12:  fact that they know at this moment in time, they have a huge
Speaker 12:  influx of traffic from Google and they have the leverage, they have
Speaker 12:  no idea how long it's gonna last, right? And so as they're going back,
Speaker 12:  they're just being really blunt about it. Give us our users,
Speaker 12:  right? Because they know long term this deal may maybe doesn't work out
Speaker 12:  for them, but right now Reddit just is Google
Speaker 12:  search. Google is just giving you Reddit results, which is
Speaker 12:  bewildering. But
Speaker 12:  yeah, this makes complete sense. Like they're just trying to move Google's
Speaker 12:  users over to being their users before Google takes cuts that fire hose
Speaker 5:  Off. Well, and you would think, and we talked a little bit about this last
Speaker 5:  week too, so we shouldn't spend too long on it, but the, there's
Speaker 5:  one way to look at this that is like Reddit is in this incredibly precarious
Speaker 5:  position, right? Because as soon as Google turns down the algorithm,
Speaker 5:  it'll, it'll die, right? So there's like, is a, is Reddit trying to like
Speaker 5:  get while the Gettin's good, but then the reporting we've been reading particularly
Speaker 5:  from Bloomberg, suggests that actually Reddit is trying to get a lot more
Speaker 5:  money out of Google, which, which really makes
Speaker 5:  it seem like Reddit knows Google has nowhere
Speaker 5:  else to go. Like, yeah, it, it is genuinely possible
Speaker 5:  that Reddit is the last thing, keeping plain
Speaker 5:  vanilla Google search from being useless for lots and lots of things because
Speaker 5:  it it, it's being totally overrun by AI slop and nonsense.
Speaker 5:  And so, so for Reddit to come in and say not just like, we need
Speaker 5:  guarantees that you're gonna keep sending us traffic, but we want more money
Speaker 5:  is such an interesting, like, inversion of power from the way that
Speaker 5:  any other website that relies on Google for traffic is able to negotiate
Speaker 5:  with Google. It's just nuts. Alright, Jake, you're up. What do you got?
Speaker 12:  Okay, this has been going on for a while. We're finally coming to the end
Speaker 12:  of the saga. Allegedly the US and China may finally have come to a
Speaker 12:  deal on TikTok. TikTok was supposed to get banned earlier this year.
Speaker 12:  There's like a federal law about this.
Speaker 12:  The, the, I don't know what is held it up. I do not know exactly what the
Speaker 12:  problem is.
Speaker 5:  Yes, you do. Yeah, I corruption and chaos. Like we, we can just say
Speaker 5:  what it is. Yeah. Like that
Speaker 12:  That is, that is correct. So apparently maybe
Speaker 12:  possibly this week or this month or soon, who really knows where these things,
Speaker 12:  there's some forward motion, it sounds like they have buyers, da da da da.
Speaker 12:  The thing that has interesting to me, and this has been coming out with
Speaker 12:  the past like several weeks or maybe months, but there's apparently
Speaker 12:  still a point of the current deal is that
Speaker 12:  TikTok has built a new version of its app just for the
Speaker 12:  US and once this deal goes through, everyone in the US is going to have
Speaker 12:  to stop using the current version of TikTok and go download this new version
Speaker 12:  of TikTok. And I amm curious if you guys think that that
Speaker 12:  is going to be a disaster for them or if everybody just gonna be like, okay,
Speaker 12:  new TikTok, whatever, like that seems that's a lot to ask of people.
Speaker 5:  I think disaster. I think like on the one hand,
Speaker 5:  my general belief is that most
Speaker 5:  people don't wanna download apps.
Speaker 5:  I also think TikTok is very important to society Yeah.
Speaker 5:  At this moment in time. So like if, if anybody could bully
Speaker 5:  a hundred million people into downloading an apple on the same day, it's
Speaker 5:  probably TikTok,
Speaker 5:  but the, it just feels like
Speaker 5:  a mess. Like it, there's just no way this
Speaker 5:  transition goes any kind of smoothly. The report
Speaker 5:  has been that basically Andreessen Horowitz, silver Lake and
Speaker 5:  Oracle are gonna be the major owners, which is like it's own
Speaker 5:  mess. And like what's less cool than Oracle owning
Speaker 5:  TikTok. Like I, I literally couldn't think of a less cool owner for
Speaker 5:  TikTok in the United States. But yeah, to me it's the new app
Speaker 5:  thing is like if anybody can do it is it's TikTok, but I kind of doubt
Speaker 5:  anybody can do it
Speaker 11:  Well to, so your last point David, I wonder if one, one of the questions
Speaker 11:  I have is who do you trust less with your data? The Chinese government or
Speaker 11:  Larry Ellison and Anderson Horowitz. And I'm not sure
Speaker 11:  what the answer to that question is. Terrific. It's kind of where, where
Speaker 11:  we are, but I I I think they might be able to pull it off
Speaker 11:  if they have enough support. Is it even gonna be noticeable? Like is it
Speaker 11:  gonna be something where it just happens on your device, you had an app
Speaker 11:  and now it has been replaced in the app store by another app, you don't
Speaker 11:  even have to sign in again and you never know. Is it still good? Is the
Speaker 11:  algorithm suddenly putting some very political videos in your feed
Speaker 11:  all the time? Or is it the same as it was? I feel like now even sometimes,
Speaker 11:  like the TikTok algorithm can vary wildly from from se
Speaker 11:  one session to another. But if it's still the same TikTok and if it's
Speaker 11:  not too much of a lift, I mean this is the app where people were learning
Speaker 11:  Chinese and downloading red notes. So yeah, they need their TikTok.
Speaker 5:  That's real. Yeah, I mean we've seen a little bit of what it looks like when
Speaker 5:  you have to get to a new app to do TikTok things. I
Speaker 5:  deleted TikTok off my phone for the summer because I was like on leave
Speaker 5:  and just wanted fewer reasons to look at my phone. And what that actually
Speaker 5:  meant is I just ended up looking at YouTube shorts a lot all summer
Speaker 5:  YouTube shorts. Not good. Not good. Don't do that. It's
Speaker 11:  Amazing how something with 20 years of data on what videos I like is so
Speaker 11:  bad,
Speaker 5:  Right? I I feel the same way. It's like YouTube does
Speaker 5:  the thing that Instagram used to do that would always drive me crazy, where
Speaker 5:  it's like if you watch one short about something
Speaker 5:  and you watch it for like 45 seconds, something in the YouTube algorithm
Speaker 5:  goes, oh, that's the stuff. And then it shows me 600
Speaker 5:  consecutive videos of that thing again until I'm like, I
Speaker 5:  never wanna see this again as long as I live. And now the whole
Speaker 5:  shorts algorithm has been ruined for me because there's no way to start over,
Speaker 5:  which is like the thing that TikTok has gotten so good at is the way that
Speaker 5:  it, it it explores and it bounces around and it changes and it moves. Like
Speaker 5:  I, there is something still different about what TikTok is
Speaker 5:  doing that no, even all the ones that ever tried to copy it have not
Speaker 5:  successfully copied it. So we'll see. I just wanna say before we move on,
Speaker 5:  I call bullshit on all of this. I don't think any of this is real. I don't
Speaker 5:  think the deal's gonna happen. I don't think TikTok is gonna get banned.
Speaker 5:  I think we are just going to live in this limbo state forever. If I'm wrong,
Speaker 5:  please play me this clip of me being wrong because I will be thrilled to
Speaker 5:  never talk about this again. But I think all of this is nonsense.
Speaker 12:  I think that's a reasonable prediction.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Alright, I have, I have two that we're gonna just talk about very quickly.
Speaker 5:  One is I would just briefly like to yell at Qualcomm
Speaker 5:  for its name Crime of the Week, which is that it took
Speaker 5:  the Snapdragon eight Elite
Speaker 5:  and updated it to the Snapdragon eight Elite Gen five.
Speaker 5:  And if you're saying, David, what about gens two, three and four?
Speaker 5:  I don't know. They, they don't exist. And here is
Speaker 5:  Qualcomm's blog post explaining this stupid naming decision. It says it might
Speaker 5:  look like we skip generations, but the truth is simpler and more powerful.
Speaker 5:  Snapdragon eight Elite Gen five marks the fifth generation of our premium
Speaker 5:  eight series platform since we introduced our new single digit naming and
Speaker 5:  visual identity. So while the naming may look new, it's actually a continuation
Speaker 5:  of our established framework that says nothing means nothing. And
Speaker 5:  this is a bad name. I
Speaker 12:  Don't understand. Every couple of years they have to just like fully change
Speaker 12:  up the naming scheme and the thing, I'm not saying their earlier naming
Speaker 12:  scheme was good, it was like only tech obsessives could
Speaker 12:  follow what what what it was 800. It was 800
Speaker 12:  series. I don't know what numbers they were at, but they incremented them.
Speaker 12:  It was fine. I could say the eight whatever was higher than the eight other
Speaker 12:  thing. Now I don't know what they're doing, they're just adding more words.
Speaker 5:  So just, I just wanna read you the, the names in order. Okay. There was the
Speaker 5:  Snapdragon eight gen one, Snapdragon eight, gen two, Snapdragon eight,
Speaker 5:  gen three, Snapdragon eight Elite, and Snapdragon eight Elite
Speaker 5:  Gen five. Good.
Speaker 12:  Good. Very good. Well well done marketing team. I'm glad you
Speaker 12:  were all earning salaries.
Speaker 5:  You're all fired. The next thing is a brief follow up to last week
Speaker 5:  we, we had seen some info on the new nothing year three
Speaker 5:  earbuds. We got the full reveal this week and as it turns out, we
Speaker 5:  predicted what the talk button on the side of the charging case was
Speaker 5:  gonna be. Almost exactly. It is primarily meant to be
Speaker 5:  used when you have your headphones paired to your phone and it's essentially
Speaker 5:  just an external microphone. You can hold it to your mouth to make phone
Speaker 5:  calls, which should sound better. You can do voice notes, you can do memos
Speaker 5:  into the essential space AI app, which we also predicted like we,
Speaker 5:  we crushed it. And I just think good job. Us. I also think this is a very
Speaker 5:  good idea that this idea, I, I had this thought
Speaker 5:  when I saw somebody out the other day EarPods in or AirPods
Speaker 5:  in holding their phone up to their mouth, talking into their
Speaker 5:  phone. And I had the unbelievable urge to be like, that's not how it works.
Speaker 5:  Your phone is accomplishing nothing with you holding it like this right now.
Speaker 5:  But it is true that when you have a microphone closer to your mouth,
Speaker 5:  it is going to sound better. Like one way to sound better on a phone call
Speaker 5:  is to put the microphone closer to your mouth and something like this,
Speaker 5:  when, when you want to sound good, whether you're like on a
Speaker 5:  Zoom call out in the world or you're making content or
Speaker 5:  whatever, having a a thing that is like attached to the device that you're
Speaker 5:  already using that is just a sort of always on immediate external
Speaker 5:  microphone, I think is very clever And I think people will use this. So kudos
Speaker 5:  to nothing and also to us for getting it exactly right. I second that,
Speaker 5:  Richard, what's your second one?
Speaker 11:  My second one, yes. YouTube this week they had their big made
Speaker 11:  on YouTube event that they have pretty much every year, but for this time
Speaker 11:  it's been 20 years. They were talking about the next 20 years and one of
Speaker 11:  the things they were talking about is what might actually get the lightning
Speaker 11:  round to sponsor. If we get a sponsor later, we can use AI to
Speaker 11:  dynamically insert the ads. So it'll just, oh my suddenly appear with
Speaker 11:  new ads. And I, and it's one of those things that's a little change, but
Speaker 11:  also kind of changes things in a big way because we've seen how creators
Speaker 11:  have gotten used to saying, oh, and my sponsor for this video is blah, blah,
Speaker 11:  blah, blah. But they don't have to do that if they can just change it
Speaker 11:  like next week or next year when they get a different sponsor. And the way
Speaker 11:  that you make money on YouTube is getting some pretty big revamps the way
Speaker 11:  that people use AI to do different things on YouTube to
Speaker 11:  enable shopping. But one of the things that it seems like is that YouTube
Speaker 11:  is in a, a pretty significant way becoming a shopping
Speaker 11:  channel.
Speaker 5:  Yes. This seems to be every video platform's
Speaker 5:  best idea about how to make money is like, what if we just let you buy the
Speaker 5:  products shown on screen and, and I'm, I'm not saying that's a, a
Speaker 5:  bad idea or the wrong one or won't work, it's just the only idea
Speaker 5:  anybody has is like ads and also click
Speaker 5:  to buy the cool wraparound sunglasses that somebody is
Speaker 5:  wearing. Like that's it. That's all, that's all we're doing here. But I agree
Speaker 5:  with you that I think the dynamic ads thing is a big deal. It's
Speaker 5:  gonna mean a lot of deals shift
Speaker 5:  for creators away from like basically
Speaker 5:  making sponsored videos to like, if you can get to the point where you just
Speaker 5:  make a lot of videos that get a lot of views, that's gonna be much easier
Speaker 5:  to monetize than it has been in the past. Or if
Speaker 11:  You have an old video that suddenly becomes popular now you can sell a new
Speaker 11:  sponsorship on it,
Speaker 5:  Right? And you're gonna, yeah, you're gonna be able to make brand deals across
Speaker 5:  your whole channel all at once. And that's like, there's just a lot of ways
Speaker 5:  in which
Speaker 5:  YouTubers only get to make a specific kind of deal. And now this
Speaker 5:  is a different new kind of deal that I think might make
Speaker 5:  everyone's viewing experience much worse
Speaker 11:  Probably. But what we've seen from YouTubers is that they respond very quickly
Speaker 11:  And I think in, in maybe ways that we didn't expect to change in the way
Speaker 11:  that you make money. Why does everyone make 20 minute videos now? You know,
Speaker 11:  a lot of the different things that you see
Speaker 5:  Take it midrolls when
Speaker 11:  When the incentives change, they, their actions change.
Speaker 5:  Totally. And this is like yet another push from YouTube into just
Speaker 5:  being live television, right? Like there's a reason
Speaker 5:  every 30 minute comedy is structured the way that it is and it's because
Speaker 5:  of ad breaks and there's like every, everything is tuned
Speaker 5:  to, you know, every, every x number of minutes there's gonna be an ad break
Speaker 5:  and we don't have control of what's there. We don't, we're we're not sort
Speaker 5:  of seamlessly integrating it in, we just have to stop the thing. But make
Speaker 5:  sure you come back and, and like you said, I suspect we're gonna start to
Speaker 5:  get a lot of, like, there's gonna be cliffhangers six minutes into every
Speaker 5:  YouTube video so that you keep watching after like all of this stuff is
Speaker 5:  going to happen. And you're exactly right that the, the people
Speaker 5:  making this stuff have absorbed and
Speaker 5:  morphed to what the platform wants and especially how the platform
Speaker 5:  monetizes really fast. And so I think you're gonna start to see this super
Speaker 5:  quickly all over YouTube. Like the, the era of the
Speaker 5:  30 minute multi-camera comedy on YouTube legitimately
Speaker 5:  might have just begun. Like it's gonna be fascinating.
Speaker 5:  There's also a, a thing that you can do now with side by
Speaker 5:  side ads in live streams, which I hate in principle and
Speaker 5:  hope no one ever uses, but I'm confident that they will.
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna go next because Jake, I want you to go last. Okay, my next one
Speaker 5:  is a fascinating bit of weird
Speaker 5:  chip machinations, which is that Nvidia just invested
Speaker 5:  $5 billion into Intel essentially just by
Speaker 5:  buying a bunch of Intel stock, but they have a plan between the two companies
Speaker 5:  to jointly develop chips both for PCs
Speaker 5:  and for data centers using a lot of NVIDIA's technology. So I think
Speaker 5:  the, the idea is essentially like Intel CPU,
Speaker 5:  Nvidia, GPU in chips together.
Speaker 5:  It's weird times for both of these companies. Intel
Speaker 5:  just sold part of itself to the government and part of it itself to
Speaker 5:  SoftBank, Nvidia made weird revenue
Speaker 5:  sharing deals with the government. Like all these companies are just like
Speaker 5:  tied up with each other in really bizarre ways.
Speaker 5:  But there's just a fascinating thing here where like I think Richard, you're,
Speaker 5:  you're more, I would say up on the PC chip game
Speaker 5:  than I am, but my impression recently has been that a MD
Speaker 5:  is like a real threat in the mirror of both Intel and Nvidia.
Speaker 5:  And this is a way for them to combine, to try and push back.
Speaker 5:  Is that, is that a fair way to look at
Speaker 11:  This? I think it really is. It's, it's something where Intel has been behind
Speaker 11:  and Nvidia has at least in certain ways been ahead, but by combining,
Speaker 11:  they do some of the things that a MD has been doing where they, they can
Speaker 11:  do both the CPU and the GPU side of it that is so crucial to these
Speaker 11:  AI applications and, and having that, that integration
Speaker 11:  and also kind of on a personal computing level, gaming,
Speaker 11:  if you can have a system where you're buying suddenly an Nvidia
Speaker 11:  GPU slash GPU that's quite different than what we've seen before
Speaker 5:  And feels like, I mean, again, we'll we'll have to see how this actually
Speaker 5:  nets out, but the idea of being able to buy like Nvidia integrated graphics
Speaker 5:  in your, your high-end laptop seems like potentially a very exciting
Speaker 5:  idea. Yeah. Also, poor intel is just like this
Speaker 5:  pathetic little company that no one wants to let die, but maybe you should
Speaker 5:  just die and ev like if this company
Speaker 5:  can't figure out how to turn it around now with the, the support of
Speaker 5:  everybody trying to keep it alive no matter what the cost,
Speaker 5:  I don't know. I don't know what we do here.
Speaker 12:  This does feel related to that, right? Like one of the problems Intel and
Speaker 12:  its foundries have had is customers are like, I dunno if you're gonna
Speaker 12:  be here, like should I make a deal with you if you, and you
Speaker 12:  know, I say what you will about the, the US government
Speaker 12:  taking a stake in it for money that Intel was already being given,
Speaker 12:  but some of that was meant to I think send a signal like, hey Intel,
Speaker 12:  they're gonna be here. And I think Nvidia doing the same thing
Speaker 12:  is kind of in the same ballpark, right? Nvidia is saying like,
Speaker 12:  Hey, we have some faith in Intel. Not only do we have faith in Intel, we
Speaker 12:  have skin in the game now. So thi this is like, feels
Speaker 12:  pretty meaningful for Intel in terms of their ability to turn around. They
Speaker 12:  still have to do it, they still have to do the thing and make good products,
Speaker 12:  which apparently has been a challenge for them. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  It's
Speaker 12:  Hard work, but they just got a bunch of money and they've got,
Speaker 12:  you know, NVIDIA's expertise so that, that certainly, certainly would,
Speaker 12:  should help.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it was funny. There was like a huge stock rally after this because
Speaker 5:  like just rubbing elbows with Nvidia instantly makes
Speaker 5:  your company exciting to a lot of people. Like this one's gonna be fascinating
Speaker 5:  to watch shakeout Jake end us with some
Speaker 5:  sheer abject rage.
Speaker 12:  Yeah, I mean I know you guys are always saying like, man, the screen on
Speaker 12:  my refrigerator is not big enough. The, the screen on my refrigerator is
Speaker 12:  one of the most valuable useful screens in my house. I wish you could do
Speaker 12:  more things. I love gaming on it. I love being productive on it.
Speaker 12:  Samsung loves that screen too. And in good
Speaker 12:  news for everyone everywhere, but specifically in the US where this is happening,
Speaker 12:  there're now going to be advertisements displayed on the screen
Speaker 12:  of your Samsung Smart Fridge. Okay.
Speaker 12:  Like that how that, that's actually like I I'm like,
Speaker 12:  this is galling, this is like really bad, right? They sold you a product,
Speaker 12:  this is a product that lives in a major room of your house
Speaker 12:  and now they are changing the product. They sold you to put ads in your
Speaker 12:  face like this. This should not be allowed. Number one,
Speaker 12:  this is like a terrible product feature. Number two,
Speaker 12:  stop putting screens on fridges number three. That's all I got.
Speaker 5:  Okay. Allow me to make the other case. Oh
Speaker 12:  Alright, alright.
Speaker 5:  I'm just kidding.
Speaker 12:  No, not subsidize the fridge. Go the tele route. Ooh.
Speaker 12:  Zero cost fridge. But it's always showing advertisements.
Speaker 5:  It's always showing advertisements, but okay, here's how you do the advertisements
Speaker 5:  on my fridge. You make it, you you you use the camera on my Samsung fridge
Speaker 5:  to take a picture of the inside of my fridge. Yeah. And then you fill it
Speaker 5:  with sponsored products.
Speaker 12:  Oh my God. And you're
Speaker 5:  Like, wouldn't it be great if you had all this stuff in your fridge? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  yeah, yeah. And I can just be like, boop, boop boop, give me those and it
Speaker 5:  immediately instacarts them to my house that
Speaker 12:  Just fill it with
Speaker 5:  A perfect advertising scheme that I would fall prey
Speaker 12:  To prime energy drinks. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  You're just like, oh dope. I have some chocolate Haagen-Dazs in my freezer.
Speaker 5:  And it's like, no you don't, but you could
Speaker 12:  What
Speaker 5:  They would get me. But no, I think, I think this is a total disaster. And
Speaker 5:  I also think in April,
Speaker 5:  Jen Tuey asked Samsung executives if there were
Speaker 5:  going to be ads because like the smart person that she is, she
Speaker 5:  looked at an enormous screen and a prominent place in your house and said,
Speaker 5:  I bet they're gonna sell ads on that. And the quote
Speaker 5:  said they don't currently have ads and quote no plans
Speaker 5:  regarding the inclusion of advertisements on AI home screens, which we took
Speaker 5:  back then as like, oh thank goodness they're not gonna do ads. Now what I'm
Speaker 5:  hearing is we still haven't figured it out, but we're gonna do it for sure.
Speaker 5:  We just, we don't have our plan yet is what they meant. Plans
Speaker 5:  is not no correct, no plans is not no
Speaker 5:  is a useful, useful thing. This is like
Speaker 5:  genuinely like throw out your fridge and get a new one. Possibilities
Speaker 5:  here. If, if they're doing this ad in the wrong, like if you play an autoplay
Speaker 5:  video ad on my fridge screen, I'm just
Speaker 5:  un I like that thing is going either off of network or
Speaker 5:  into the for sale section of my Nextdoor app
Speaker 5:  very quickly.
Speaker 11:  You, you don't want going to the fridge for a snack to be like pumping gas
Speaker 11:  now that that's, that's not what you love.
Speaker 5:  Wow. So all the podcasts that I've been listening to recently have been
Speaker 5:  advertising for Jordan Peel's new movie, which is about
Speaker 5:  football players. And it's this very like creepy low voice.
Speaker 5:  He kind of sounds like Harrison Ford talking about. And I'm just imagining
Speaker 5:  every time I walk into my kitchen, it's like coming this fall,
Speaker 12:  I'm
Speaker 5:  Just like, I'm gonna, I'm gonna walk into my fridge at two o'clock in the
Speaker 5:  morning and there's just gonna be some scary person on my fridge to promote
Speaker 5:  Jordan Peel's new movie. And I'm gonna, I'm gonna throw my fridge through
Speaker 5:  a window. The end. This is the worst idea of all time.
Speaker 5:  And I hope Samsung just immediately walks it back because it
Speaker 5:  should. Jake, you're not mad enough about this.
Speaker 12:  You're, I I know I've, I've just been so pro fridge
Speaker 12:  ads just all this time. I'd be like, the money they're leaving
Speaker 12:  on the table, they put a screen in everybody's kitchen.
Speaker 12:  No. Yeah, they, this
Speaker 5:  Is, it's really on us for not seeing this coming.
Speaker 12:  I mean, I, to be clear, I don't think we've been all that pro
Speaker 12:  fridge screen. I know there are people out there, they have screens in their
Speaker 12:  fridges. I don't know how they got their, is anyone using them?
Speaker 12:  Are they, are they valuable to you? I don't have a, a screen on my fridge,
Speaker 12:  but
Speaker 12:  yeah, I think don't trust Samsung with that. I if
Speaker 12:  is the lesson. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  That said, if you work for telly and you decide to go ahead with your refrigerator,
Speaker 5:  Jake would like some credit. Alright, we have gone way over. There's
Speaker 5:  too much happening. If everybody could just stop for like a, like a minute
Speaker 5:  and not do all of your news in September, it'd be great. We would be very
Speaker 5:  grateful. There's more coming. By the way, there's a, an Amazon event scheduled
Speaker 5:  for September 30th. So in two weeks we think we're gonna see the next
Speaker 5:  generation of echo stuff now that Alexa plus exists and now that
Speaker 5:  Anos pane who used to run windows and hardware at Microsoft is running the
Speaker 5:  stuff over there. That should be interesting. There's some more Google stuff
Speaker 5:  coming. There's just a lot going on this fall. So we'll be here a lot, but
Speaker 5:  also if everybody could stop, that'd be great. But for now
Speaker 5:  we should get outta here. Richard, Jake, thank you for being here with me.
Speaker 5:  This was a delight. Mila is off doing. God only knows what. We'll see him
Speaker 5:  next time. There are speech crimes, so presumably very soon. If
Speaker 5:  you have questions about any of this or other things you want us to talk
Speaker 5:  about or feelings about whatever is going on in the world, you can always
Speaker 5:  email us at Vergecast at The Verge dot com. You can call us eight six six
Speaker 5:  Virgin one. One is the hotline. There are an increasing number of
Speaker 5:  people who want to get in the Slack room that automatically pulls in all
Speaker 5:  the voicemails we get on the hotline. So keep 'em coming. We love
Speaker 5:  the hotline. The Vergecast is VERGE Production and part of the Vox Media
Speaker 5:  podcast network. It's produced by Travis Lara, Brandon Kiefer and Eric Gomez.
Speaker 5:  We will be back next Tuesday. We're gonna talk about YouTube. We're
Speaker 5:  gonna do some more takes. I have feelings I need to get out and we're gonna
Speaker 5:  talk about them. See you then. Rock and roll,