# Transcript
ID: 0bb25736-b8ee-42a7-ac3c-62ee06f8b5a1
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/6381193469980436667/-7875472395051204865/s93290-US-4090s-1759661287.mp3
Description: In 2015, self-balancing scooters (which quickly became known as hoverboards) exploded in popularity, and then began literally exploding. Andrew Hawkins and Sean O’Kane join David Pierce to explore the multiple conflicting origin stories behind the hugely popular rideable, the many knockoffs, and why a device that doesn't actually hover ended up being called "hoverboard."
If you like the show, subscribe to the Version History feed to make sure you get every new episode.
Let us know what you think: 866-VERGE-11 or vergecast@theverge.com.
Learn more about your ad choices. Visit podcastchoices.com/adchoices
Ad Filtering: Enabled (15 ads detected)
Speaker 1:  So old school, right? It's like if you want to go across the office or
Speaker 1:  down the street or to the other side of the building, you have to
Speaker 1:  use your feet like it's the Middle Ages. It's so, it's who has the
Speaker 1:  time, you know what I mean? Well, I have a better way. They're Hoverboards.
Speaker 1:  They're those two wield self-balancing scooters, and they are
Speaker 1:  all the rage from The Verge and Vox Media. This is Version History, a
Speaker 1:  show about the best and worst and strangest and most
Speaker 1:  important products in the history of technology. I'm David Pierce,
Speaker 1:  and today we are going for a ride, a definitely
Speaker 1:  dangerous and potentially explosive ride.
Speaker 1:  O Cain is here. Yeah, band is back together. This is exciting. This is very
Speaker 1:  exciting. First, let's just talk about relative
Speaker 1:  hoverboard expertise. Andy, you have a confession to make, I believe
Speaker 1:  is how should
Speaker 5:  Start. Yes. I I, this is very shameful for me to admit, but I have never
Speaker 5:  actually ridden on a hoverboard
Speaker 1:  At some point. That's a choice. You made
Speaker 5:  It, it was 'cause we had one in the office. Yeah, it was, it was always there.
Speaker 5:  O other, you know, co coworkers were, were blasting around.
Speaker 5:  I was writing about it very frequently, and yet I still have not
Speaker 5:  put my dainty little feet on the platform. So,
Speaker 1:  You know. Any, any regrets?
Speaker 5:  No. None. None at all. It's late
Speaker 1:  Now for sure.
Speaker 5:  Zero regrets about that. I, I, I actually, I, I feel
Speaker 5:  better about it today. Every day that goes by, I feel even better about the
Speaker 5:  decision.
Speaker 6:  Think of how much more complicated your commute to bring your kids to school
Speaker 6:  could have been if you had stuck with the hoverboard.
Speaker 5:  That's
Speaker 1:  Right. My first ever hoverboard experience, I first, I will never forget
Speaker 1:  this moment. I got it on Amazon, took it outta the box, And I was in
Speaker 1:  Oakland in my apartment, And I was like, okay, my, my living room is tiny.
Speaker 1:  I was in like an 800 square foot apartment. I was like, I don't have any
Speaker 1:  room to ride this thing. I'm gonna take it down to the street.
Speaker 5:  First mistake right there. I
Speaker 1:  Was like very early in the hoverboard world at this point. And so I was like,
Speaker 1:  I didn't know how any of this worked. So I take it down to the sidewalk.
Speaker 1:  I went, I don't know, 18 inches into like the
Speaker 1:  line between two of the blocks on the sidewalk and just absolutely launched
Speaker 1:  myself into traffic like, like in the middle of the road,
Speaker 1:  eight seconds after getting a hoverboard. And then I was like, all right,
Speaker 1:  I'm in it now.
Speaker 5:  So we're, we're very lucky to still have you here with us.
Speaker 1:  It's, it's a small miracle. Sean, what about you
Speaker 6:  Have ridden have not stuck with it. Okay. I expertise would be
Speaker 6:  a, a word I wouldn't use.
Speaker 1:  Like would you, would peak Sean on a hoverboard. Would you roll
Speaker 1:  around this set? Oh no. And not feel, and feel comfortable not destroying
Speaker 1:  things
Speaker 6:  Without breaking all of the cameras? No. Okay. No. Okay.
Speaker 6:  Gimme a wide open space. You know, put me on an airport runway. Oh yeah.
Speaker 6:  I could probably cruise a
Speaker 5:  Gymnasium. A
Speaker 6:  Recently paved airport runway. I could probably cruise pretty well. Okay.
Speaker 1:  That's a, I mean, that comes for something. Yeah. So what I'm hearing is
Speaker 1:  I'm the best at Hoverboards. This is a great way to start, but we all covered
Speaker 1:  this pretty aggressively. I was at Wired at the time. You two were both
Speaker 1:  at The Verge during like the entirety of the hoverboard craze. You were both
Speaker 1:  like covering it a lot is my memory of it, right? Like it was, it was
Speaker 1:  a huge story in a way that is I think very easy to forget now 10 years
Speaker 6:  Later. There are so many parts to the story that I hadn't remembered until
Speaker 6:  I was looking back. Like, it's not just about the product, it was about what
Speaker 6:  we called it. It was about who was riding it. It was about this
Speaker 6:  celebrity craze of all of them probably getting paid to ride them
Speaker 6:  or just like thinking they were cool and there were all the, I mean, it
Speaker 6:  was just, there was, to me it's also like a harbinger of what was to
Speaker 6:  come with sort of the trade war stuff that we've been in over the last couple
Speaker 6:  years of sort of rapid production and, and domestic
Speaker 6:  manufacturing in China. And it's, it was a deeper story than I
Speaker 6:  remembered
Speaker 5:  All the safety implications. Yeah. That was sort of where I came into the
Speaker 5:  story was once like they started exploding and catching on fire
Speaker 5:  was when I was like, oh, this is, you know, more than just your average like
Speaker 5:  cheap product out of China that people are really into. It's, there's something
Speaker 5:  else going on here.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I think this was also, I had forgotten kind of the beginning
Speaker 1:  of the like last mile craze. Yes. Where everyone was obsessed
Speaker 1:  with this idea that like, oh yeah, what we're gonna do is not just have Hoverboards,
Speaker 1:  but we're gonna reinvent the way that you move small distances.
Speaker 1:  Which seems insane to think about now, but I was like, I was all in on this
Speaker 1:  idea at the time and there were like, we were doing weird electric
Speaker 1:  skates. There were a bunch of different skateboard ideas. You ended up
Speaker 1:  covering boosted board for a like forever after this. All of that,
Speaker 1:  maybe not starts with this, but kind of starts with this. This was like the
Speaker 1:  beginning of the idea of like, what weird stuff can I put under my feet that
Speaker 1:  are gonna make it fun to move around the office, warehouse, neighborhood,
Speaker 1:  what have you and weird times. Yeah. I still have a bunch of those
Speaker 1:  things at my house.
Speaker 6:  It was, I mean, it was a more optimistic time, right? We were watching Google's
Speaker 6:  little sort of cutesy autonomous vehicle for the first time,
Speaker 6:  navigate some streets. We were thinking about electric aircraft and all this
Speaker 6:  stuff. Everything was in the concept phase. And so these became
Speaker 6:  sort of the first tangible things of like, this is what the future will be
Speaker 6:  like and as far as how you're gonna move around. And I think that was one
Speaker 6:  of the reasons that fueled all that stuff. And it was also, I honestly, I
Speaker 6:  think there's a, an element of the Tesla piece here where
Speaker 6:  there was all this talk at the time about the rapid
Speaker 6:  acceleration of development of electric motors, of battery technology,
Speaker 6:  the miniaturization of that, the lowering of the cost. It's gonna revolutionize
Speaker 6:  the kinds of things you can build because they're no longer cost prohibitive.
Speaker 6:  And so it was just, all of that stuff got swept up into what became
Speaker 6:  this weird thing, this weird thing that we called the boarding. I
Speaker 5:  Think there's also sort of like, there's a germ of like influencer culture
Speaker 5:  that like kind of birthed out of this as well. Like we didn't really have,
Speaker 5:  like, there wasn't like profession, like a professional influencer.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. This thing would've done numbers on TikTok shop seriously.
Speaker 5:  And like, it was like we needed to have the celebrities be the ones to like
Speaker 5:  introduce us to this weird gadget, right. As opposed to just like
Speaker 5:  all of the, the, you know, the eventually what became, you know, like influencers
Speaker 5:  as we know them today. So I, I always thought that was really interesting.
Speaker 5:  Totally.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So this was a weird one because most of the things we talk about on
Speaker 1:  the show sort of start in one obvious place.
Speaker 1:  Hoverboards very much do not, let me just sort of lay out the like two
Speaker 1:  parallel histories here and we can sort of talk through it. So on one
Speaker 1:  parallel history, we have this guy named Shane Chen, who is an inventor,
Speaker 1:  lives in the Pacific Northwest, has been into like ridely things
Speaker 1:  for forever. And in 2013 he files a
Speaker 1:  patent for a thing called the hover tracks with an X at the end. So, you
Speaker 1:  know, it's cool. And he called it a two wheel self-balancing vehicle
Speaker 1:  made with independently movable foot placement sections. And like the thing
Speaker 1:  that made it new and not a segue was that it had essentially two
Speaker 1:  distinct platforms both attached to a wheel and you could move them independently.
Speaker 1:  Right? And so the whole thing was like you, you push them forward and it
Speaker 1:  goes forward. You push them backwards and it goes backwards. You push one
Speaker 1:  and pull one and it turns. And so that, that was like his big
Speaker 1:  technical change. He set up a Kickstarter
Speaker 1:  for this thing he had, he has said since that he had this idiot in 2011 patent
Speaker 1:  said in 2013, does the Kickstarter in 2013
Speaker 1:  raises like a little over $80,000 from I think it was
Speaker 1:  162 backers on Kickstarter, which is
Speaker 1:  fine numbers. Congratulations. Yeah. How you did it, it hit its goal. So
Speaker 5:  You, you get in on the ground floor on Hoverboards, like you're living that
Speaker 5:  billionaire lifestyle these days. You know, that's what you wanna be, you
Speaker 5:  wanna be one of those original seed investors.
Speaker 1:  Well,
Speaker 1:  well our boy Shane Chen might have different feelings than that. But
Speaker 1:  let me just, this is the most like 2013 Kickstarter video ever.
Speaker 1:  So let me just play you a short clip from the Kickstarter.
Speaker 7:  This is my latest dimension. It's called Hover Tracks
Speaker 7:  because it has two wheels. So you can stand still
Speaker 7:  and you put your feet on on here, you lean
Speaker 7:  forward, you move forward, lean back, you come back
Speaker 7:  and you press one foot forward and one
Speaker 7:  foot back you spin
Speaker 7:  or you can make turn when you're moving forward. And
Speaker 7:  this is very convenient and
Speaker 7:  very portable.
Speaker 1:  I love this because he's like, this is the most, like I invented a thing
Speaker 1:  And I have no idea what it's for. Video of all time. Yes. Do you
Speaker 1:  wanna back this on Kickstarter?
Speaker 5:  Take all my money please.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, exactly. So, okay, so all of this is happening.
Speaker 1:  Patents, it starts to ship it out. There were some delays because of
Speaker 1:  port shenanigans, but like shift a bunch of things to
Speaker 1:  actual people in the world and in America
Speaker 1:  that's one version of the history. The other version of the history
Speaker 1:  starts in China with this company called Chic Robotics, which is one of the
Speaker 1:  like big factories in China have a lot of like little tiny house brands.
Speaker 1:  So there's like a million companies inside of this one factory. Chic Robotics
Speaker 1:  is one of them. They start making what they call self-balancing
Speaker 1:  scooters that look a lot like our buddy Shane's
Speaker 1:  hover tracks in August of 2014. And these,
Speaker 1:  I did a story about these a million years ago in which I went back and looked
Speaker 1:  through, went back when this is a thing you could do every YouTube video
Speaker 1:  that had ever been posted about these things all the way back to the beginning.
Speaker 1:  And the very first one I ever found was from August, 2014 of a device
Speaker 1:  called the Smart S one from Chic Robotics. So
Speaker 1:  Chic Robotics makes this device, they take it to the, the largest
Speaker 1:  trade show in China. It's a big hit. One of the stories of these things kind
Speaker 1:  of over and over is that one of the ways they grow is by like
Speaker 1:  taking a bunch to a convention center somewhere and then just like have people
Speaker 1:  ride them around. Sure. And they become this like weird viral phenomenon
Speaker 1:  over and over. I think we all had this experience at CES one year. It was
Speaker 6:  Just one of those things where they just showed up and it was, you know,
Speaker 6:  that was, I think CES is its most fun is when there are people who are sort
Speaker 6:  of at the edges and don't, aren't part of the whole machine of sort of setting
Speaker 6:  up a schedule and like getting people to meet and they just have a fun idea
Speaker 6:  and they're like, and this thing, you know, to your point about it, catching
Speaker 6:  people's eye in spaces like that, there's something so unsettling about
Speaker 6:  seeing the top half of a person moving without bobbing up and
Speaker 6:  down. Yes. And I think that like, honestly I think that's a small part, but
Speaker 6:  an important part of like why this thing caught so many people's eyes. Because
Speaker 6:  if you see someone moving like that, you're like, what is going on? Right.
Speaker 1:  Well and it's like a few inches off the ground. So you're, you're the tallest
Speaker 1:  person in the room all of a sudden and you're just kind of slowly moving
Speaker 1:  towards everyone. Like it's, it is deeply like alarming. You're like on a
Speaker 1:  dolly almost. Yeah. Yeah. So, okay. So Sheik
Speaker 1:  makes this thing and their version of this story is
Speaker 1:  relatively straightforward. Like Sheik makes a thing, finds a bunch of distributors,
Speaker 1:  those distributors put logos and stickers on it and they, you know,
Speaker 1:  change the manufacturing a little bit and they start to ship it all over
Speaker 1:  the world. Those are the two versions of the story. Shane Chen,
Speaker 1:  who we should point out, was out doing this earlier publicly.
Speaker 1:  What he says is that what Sheik did was basically look at his Kickstarter
Speaker 1:  page, take the photos and the video and reverse engineer
Speaker 1:  their product out of it. This is a thing that is very hard to know.
Speaker 1:  It has been litigated endlessly, which will come up over and over
Speaker 1:  again throughout this story. But it, it tracks like that. The place
Speaker 1:  that I've landed is like the thing that we have in the United States looks
Speaker 1:  more like that one from Chic than it does the one, the
Speaker 1:  hover tracks that Shane Chen made the year before. And then whatever happened,
Speaker 1:  everybody else ripped off their intellectual property. Right. So as soon
Speaker 1:  as even this stuff comes out and as soon as these things start to get manufactured,
Speaker 1:  they are just immediately everywhere. And so, like
Speaker 1:  when they first came to the us, which was pretty quick, they came,
Speaker 1:  my recollection at least is not sort of as, as there was not one product
Speaker 1:  that showed up and then a bunch of knockoffs. Right. All it was all knockoffs
Speaker 1:  right. From day one. Yeah. Which was just
Speaker 5:  Weird. And they all had the weirdest names there. It was, it was always like
Speaker 5:  some sort of like bizarre combination of English words that didn't really
Speaker 5:  seem like they made sense together. Like car, wind
Speaker 5:  wheel,
Speaker 6:  Another sort of harbinger of what was to come. I feel like this is a proto
Speaker 6:  version of like the alphabet soup. Oh yeah. Like Amazon Best that we have
Speaker 6:  today of like, ah, I'm gonna buy an electric toothbrush. This one that's
Speaker 6:  called X nine Z two B. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Free looks
Speaker 1:  Good. I will say to the Hoverboards credit, one of them was called Funky
Speaker 1:  Duck with a pH. Oh yeah. And that's very good. So we did, we, we made a,
Speaker 1:  a clip of some of our favorite hoverboard brand names.
Speaker 1:  Lemme just tell you this for you. Yeah. This is a swag wing. This
Speaker 8:  Is the Funky Duck. This is Hover Tracks, this is the Epical Classic. This
Speaker 8:  is the Mono Rover two Carl Lifestyle iHawk, the Hoverboard
Speaker 8:  360.
Speaker 9:  This particular model is called the Lee Ray Self-Balancing scooter.
Speaker 9:  They also call it the the Dream Walker.
Speaker 6:  The Oh Walker. That's ominous. I
Speaker 1:  Say a favorite version. My favorite version of this story is,
Speaker 1:  I believe it was Funky Duck sent one of their scooters
Speaker 1:  to Soulja Boy, which
Speaker 1:  is a very 2015 sentence to say out loud. And then,
Speaker 1:  and then like, like days later, Soulja Boy starts
Speaker 1:  selling. Yeah. A board, I believe it's called the Soulja Board. Yeah. Because
Speaker 6:  Why not? It
Speaker 1:  Is literally, and the picture is just him standing on the board That Funky
Speaker 1:  Duck sent it. Yeah. Which is just, this is just where we were at the time.
Speaker 1:  I love
Speaker 6:  It. Yeah. It was, you know, a Cambrian explosion of the same
Speaker 6:  thing. Just
Speaker 5:  The thing that that always amazed me is that none of these things looked
Speaker 5:  any different from the next one. Yeah. They all looked almost identical.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like you put, you line 'em all up together and you would have a difficulty
Speaker 5:  like applying brand names to any of them because they just all looked the
Speaker 5:  same.
Speaker 1:  And what was funny is every one of the companies would hate that
Speaker 1:  characterization, right? Because they were all like, oh well a, we have big
Speaker 1:  plans for the second one. Get ready for
Speaker 6:  As soon as we know what that is and where we're gonna get the idea from.
Speaker 1:  We're gonna do all kinds of stuff on Funky Duck too. Like you're not even
Speaker 1:  gonna believe it. But then they would all say, you know, everybody else is
Speaker 1:  using shoddy batteries and they're not doing any safety testing and they
Speaker 1:  don't care about, but we are the ones doing a good job. And I mean, down
Speaker 1:  that line of what you're describing, every single one of them would've said
Speaker 1:  that to you. Which is just, which is just delightful. But anyway, so these,
Speaker 1:  these companies start suing each other and and
Speaker 1:  pointing fingers at each other. You have Funky duck And I hawk both of which
Speaker 1:  I guess are distributing chic robotics, which may or may not be knocking
Speaker 1:  off the hover tracks. This is, look, I lose my mind trying to
Speaker 1:  explain hoverboard the layers of this seriously. And
Speaker 1:  so everybody just starts to fight. But meanwhile this thing is everywhere.
Speaker 1:  Like my memory of it is essentially overnight all of a sudden, like this
Speaker 1:  went from being a thing I had never heard of and never cared about to being
Speaker 1:  like front and center in pop culture
Speaker 6:  Because it's also hit right around the same time. I feel like I'm remembering
Speaker 6:  correctly that Instagram really became
Speaker 6:  a place for celebrities to post. That wasn't the case for a while. I remember
Speaker 6:  it was just sort of like, you know, artful of pictures and filtered whatever
Speaker 6:  and your friends, 'cause you were coming, well you weren't coming from Facebook
Speaker 6:  but you know, they bought it eventually. But this idea that we were getting
Speaker 6:  a glimpse of the sort of polished version of a celebrity's home life
Speaker 6:  and all of a sudden into that comes like some of the first product, to your
Speaker 6:  point earlier, just like this was sort of like proto influencer
Speaker 6:  marketing, like celebrity influencer marketing where they were getting these
Speaker 6:  products and dang in front of her face. I remember other ones being like,
Speaker 6:  you know, Lewis Hamilton riding some sort of like electric surfboard. There
Speaker 6:  was a lot of this stuff happening at the time, but this was certainly the
Speaker 6:  most viral.
Speaker 1:  I went back, I did a really, really unnecessary
Speaker 1:  Instagram deep dive to figure out who was the first celebrity to post
Speaker 1:  a hoverboard. Who do you think it was? Oh
Speaker 6:  Gosh.
Speaker 5:  Paul Giamatti. No, that would
Speaker 1:  Be amazing.
Speaker 6:  I yearn for that content
Speaker 1:  In his like full John Adams
Speaker 6:  Garb.
Speaker 5:  Love that. Oh God, I don't know. That's a gree, that's a good one.
Speaker 1:  He's very famous. Oh, And I love his music. Unironically.
Speaker 6:  John Mayer.
Speaker 1:  Justin Bieber. Okay. Oh, okay. Okay. Justin Bieber I
Speaker 1:  think historically speaking kind of gets a lot of credit for like
Speaker 1:  single-handedly making Hoverboards a thing. And the more I research it, the
Speaker 1:  more I think he's right. But here, let me just play you, this is the
Speaker 1:  very first video I could find. This is from May I believe
Speaker 1:  14th of 2015. This is, wow. This is like the,
Speaker 1:  the celebrity birth of Hoverboards
Speaker 6:  And
Speaker 1:  It's just him spinning around ticking one foot off, which fairly
Speaker 1:  advanced.
Speaker 6:  I mean, is it him?
Speaker 5:  Well look at those pants, look at those shorts and then he falls
Speaker 6:  Off. I'm just saying
Speaker 1:  The caption in that video is something like I dyed right after this, which
Speaker 1:  is very good. Sure. I
Speaker 5:  Even though we didn't see his face, I know that that was floppy hair era
Speaker 5:  beaver. It had to have been right without question.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Okay. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I'm, I'm a truther, I'm not lie
Speaker 5:  You don't think
Speaker 6:  It was beeps? No
Speaker 1:  Beeps. Body double did a lot of work in 2015 on a hoverboard.
Speaker 6:  It was Giovanni Ani.
Speaker 1:  But I love that clip. 'cause a to your point, this was like early Instagram
Speaker 1:  video when like no one would be caught dead making that low
Speaker 1:  quality Instagram.
Speaker 6:  It wasn't even a good V anymore, let alone a good
Speaker 5:  Instagram. There was no music. No,
Speaker 1:  It was too long. He spins in a bunch of circles, he falls nothing funny happened.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But that was huge and then it just absolutely took off.
Speaker 1:  So like here's just a, a small percentage of the
Speaker 1:  list of people, Wiz Khalifa, Nick Jonas
Speaker 1:  z Kendall Jenner Jr. R Smith, who, I don't know if you guys remember this,
Speaker 1:  if you're a basketball fans rode one in the tunnel to I believe the NBA
Speaker 1:  finals. And it was like, it, it was like a, like a national news moment.
Speaker 1:  Sure. Millions of people watching JR Smith just like potentially injure
Speaker 1:  himself all the way to the locker room. Nicki Minaj,
Speaker 1:  Nina al the model. David Ortiz. Kareem sma, the soccer
Speaker 1:  player. Skrillex who he came very well known for his
Speaker 5:  Hover boarding. That's the most
Speaker 6:  2015. Yeah. We, that should have been my guess.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And then all of the late night hosts.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  This was like a staple all of late night 19. All the Jimmy all Jimmys,
Speaker 1:  Jimmys and James' and all of them.
Speaker 1:  And so like, this was, this was like a huge thing. And the thing that I had
Speaker 1:  forgotten was how short a period of time that actually was.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Because this is basically, so like Beaver posts in March and
Speaker 1:  then we spend kind of May, June, July, August,
Speaker 1:  culturally obsessed with Harvard Board.
Speaker 5:  Is this 2016?
Speaker 6:  15. 15. 15.
Speaker 1:  Okay. This is literally, this is all, this is, it's this whole story is
Speaker 1:  one year long. It's nuts.
Speaker 5:  I I also remember like, it was either 2015 or 2016 but like whatever
Speaker 5:  year the holidays came around. Yeah. It was
Speaker 5:  insane. Yeah. That like every kid was like, I want one of these
Speaker 5:  so bad. Sure. Like that's the only thing that I want mom and dad. And it
Speaker 5:  was like every like, it was like, you know, rushing to get, you know,
Speaker 5:  wherever you could get one, you know, people fighting over them at Black
Speaker 5:  Friday deals like it was, and
Speaker 6:  There were absolutely no problems with these things sitting under flammable
Speaker 6:  Christmas trees. None at all.
Speaker 5:  None at all.
Speaker 1:  What a good segue that is. So all of this happens and then
Speaker 1:  what do Hoverboards start doing? They start exploding. Which is where
Speaker 1:  Andy comes into the story. Do you, do you remember any of the like early
Speaker 1:  versions of this story? I
Speaker 5:  Remember being very like, you know, panic, panicked, like this is
Speaker 5:  a problem because Yes, they started exploding. They were catching on fire.
Speaker 5:  There was some deaths I think associated with it. Like it was, it was bad.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And it's, it's useful to remember that these things are huge. Yeah. Which
Speaker 1:  is like, it's not like if your, even your phone battery exploded 'cause this
Speaker 1:  is just before
Speaker 6:  The, the notes seven the Galaxy note
Speaker 1:  Shenanigan. Like Yes. It's really like
Speaker 6:  We were actually so prepared for the note seven 'cause of Hoverboards.
Speaker 5:  Right.
Speaker 6:  This is actually Hoverboards are, were learning moments for me in multiple
Speaker 6:  ways. One was, this is where I first learned what UL certification is. Yes.
Speaker 5:  Same important.
Speaker 6:  Because we spent a lot of time trying to figure out whether or not post this
Speaker 6:  sort of fire stuff starting whether or not each
Speaker 6:  individual company had gotten UL certification most of 'em hadn't. And how
Speaker 6:  important that can be. And then and you know that was
Speaker 6:  just a big that was a big one.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah. UL certification is another thing that one
Speaker 1:  of those you're like, why I wish I had never needed to learn about this.
Speaker 1:  But here we are. I'm glad it exists And I hope I never think about it again.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Okay. I have a couple of clips I would like to play for you of
Speaker 1:  hoverboard explosions because what are we here for? It's not
Speaker 1:  hoverboard explosions with the gawk.
Speaker 10:  Hoverboards are red hot in more ways than than one. There has been another
Speaker 10:  reported fire involving the popular self-balancing scooters.
Speaker 11:  I came down the sidewalk not even probably a hundred feet and it
Speaker 11:  exploded. It said boom.
Speaker 5:  But how did they explode? So well simple.
Speaker 12:  We take a battery from a 90 cell phone and make a power of motor designed
Speaker 12:  for a small
Speaker 13:  Car safety officials saying all the Hoverboards sold in the US my God are
Speaker 13:  unsafe strollers
Speaker 14:  Company to continue to sell Hoverboards that they know
Speaker 14:  do not comply with the standard.
Speaker 15:  And since not a single one has been certified as safe, the consumer product
Speaker 15:  safety commission warns consumers risk, serious injury or
Speaker 15:  death if they're self-balancing scooters ignite and burn
Speaker 5:  Well. And as soon as that came came down like
Speaker 5:  everywhere started banning them. Right? Yeah. The MTA
Speaker 5:  the all the airlines banned them.
Speaker 6:  Walmart. Right. Walmart was like pulling 'em off the shelves, pulling
Speaker 5:  'em off the shelves. You couldn't go through TSA security with one if you
Speaker 5:  had it. Like it was just sort of like it was a free for all and then nowhere
Speaker 5:  would allowed them to have them anywhere. Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1:  Like almost immediately. Yeah. There were, it just, it turned
Speaker 6:  God. Just remember that there were like, they took, you remember at the time
Speaker 6:  there were all those MTA sort of helpful hint things on the subway
Speaker 6:  with like the sort of simply drawn figure people
Speaker 5:  Like the cartoon people.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And they had ones for the Hoverboards or it was like, don't bring this
Speaker 6:  on board. I think they're still up there probably in some, yes. And I remember
Speaker 6:  it would, some of them would be animated on some of the video screens and
Speaker 6:  it would be like, you know, big X over like guy trying to bring
Speaker 6:  a like little simply drawn hoverboard onto the subway. Like I,
Speaker 5:  I lived in the city for like, you know, 20 years And I don't think I ever
Speaker 5:  saw anybody. I think I saw, saw some people carrying that, but I've never
Speaker 5:  saw anyone use one on a subway. And I'm just wondering like how the physics
Speaker 5:  of that work, if you're going back and the train is going forward, are you
Speaker 5:  just standing still if you're riding the hoverboard? How does that work?
Speaker 5:  See
Speaker 1:  That I would, I would give somebody a dollar for that on the subway
Speaker 1:  show time. Yeah. It's like mariachi band Showtime.
Speaker 5:  That's your showtime before. That's showtime. Absolutely.
Speaker 1:  Especially if you can like spin up through the bars with the H.
Speaker 5:  We haven't even talked about the ones that have like builtin speakers and
Speaker 5:  lights. Yes.
Speaker 1:  And I like, oh
Speaker 5:  Yeah, I don't wanna get
Speaker 1:  Ahead of ourselves. No, this, this is the right time. 'cause this was like,
Speaker 1:  that was the other thing that it was time
Speaker 6:  For funky dunk too baby.
Speaker 5:  There you go.
Speaker 1:  Well, so there, at this point there were basically one of three things is
Speaker 1:  going to happen. Either this whole thing is gonna die, it's
Speaker 1:  gonna get safer and better or it's just gonna get weirder.
Speaker 1:  And for a minute it just got weirder. To your point. So people, people started
Speaker 1:  moding these things. Companies now that there had been like more time to
Speaker 1:  actually rev the product and ship the stuff and more people were manufacturing
Speaker 1:  it. There were all these weird new ideas about stuff you could put in it
Speaker 1:  like speakers, which I remember being just a full nightmare of a
Speaker 1:  idea
Speaker 6:  Yet somehow like deeply appropriate. Yes. Like this thing is so gar. I mean
Speaker 6:  it already was essentially like a party speaker on wheels. So like making
Speaker 6:  it a party Speaker on Wheels was like Yeah. Yeah. That tracks. Yeah that
Speaker 1:  Tracks. Yeah. And there I, I remember seeing like increasingly crazy light
Speaker 1:  shows coming out of the side of them that lasted
Speaker 1:  for a minute and then the third thing happened, which is it all fell apart.
Speaker 1:  But we need to take a break really quickly and then we're gonna talk about
Speaker 1:  what actually happened to Hoverboards. We'll be right back.
Speaker 17:  Rinse takes your laundry and hand delivers it to your door. Expertly
Speaker 17:  cleaned and folded so you can take the time. All that time
Speaker 17:  once spent on folding and sorting, watching and waiting
Speaker 17:  to finally pursue a whole new version of you. Like
Speaker 17:  Birdhouse building you.
Speaker 16:  Yeah. The birds are gonna love this.
Speaker 17:  Or Dollhouse building you.
Speaker 16:  Yeah. The kids are gonna love this.
Speaker 17:  Or maybe, how is DJ track building to the base
Speaker 17:  drop you.
Speaker 16:  Oh yeah. The kids are gonna love it.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. So end of 2015
Speaker 1:  it all kind of goes sideways. Everything's exploding. Like
Speaker 1:  cover
Speaker 6:  Board was sideways.
Speaker 1:  Yes. The hoverboard, I fell off the hoverboard metaphorically and literally
Speaker 1:  in 2015. But the big thing to your point about
Speaker 1:  holidays from before, the big thing that happened was Amazon stopped selling
Speaker 1:  all of the Hoverboards like all at once. And, and
Speaker 6:  We all know that's the only way to buy anything these days. I mean kind of.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And it was like, it was really interesting 'cause it, I, I went back and
Speaker 1:  was looking at the beginning of the story. There was this run of people buying
Speaker 1:  them on Alibaba and a lot of like drop shipping stuff happening
Speaker 1:  from some of these factories in China. And then all those factories just
Speaker 1:  started selling directly on Amazon. And so that became the place
Speaker 1:  everybody bought Hoverboards like for a long time. And
Speaker 1:  then Amazon just essentially overnight just stopped selling them. And so
Speaker 1:  you just couldn't get them. And this happened like at holiday season so a
Speaker 1:  lot of people had them already, but now they are a safety risk that are,
Speaker 1:  is being broadcast to everyone as a huge safety risk. You literally can't
Speaker 1:  buy one and the whole thing just kind of just poof
Speaker 1:  disappears overnight. There are people trying to
Speaker 1:  make that happen more either more slowly
Speaker 1:  or reverse it. So Razor the scooter company
Speaker 1:  buys that original 2013 patent from Shane Chen in
Speaker 1:  2015 and decides to simultaneously go make safer,
Speaker 1:  more legit versions of the hoverboard. They start to get the the UL certification.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. They start to go like take more care of the batteries and start
Speaker 1:  to actually like build these things in a safe way and they go just sue the
Speaker 1:  pants off of everybody else who is making Hoverboards. Everybody's suing
Speaker 1:  everybody. And then there just becomes this question of like, is any of this
Speaker 1:  different enough to be defensible? Yeah. And as far as I can tell,
Speaker 1:  overwhelmingly the answer became somewhere between No.
Speaker 1:  And nobody cares. And I think that just seemed to be the, the end
Speaker 1:  of the story there is everybody picked these fights forever about these
Speaker 1:  patents and then just kind of decided, eh, it's
Speaker 6:  Too much. Our court system does not move nearly at the speed of sort of
Speaker 6:  viral viral anything, let alone viral like product.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You know, just that that was never going to be something they could
Speaker 6:  sort out in time for this thing, for it to matter for this product.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And it was just always destined to come out of fashion before a
Speaker 6:  judgment came from some district court judge.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, true. Well I found myself wondering like the, I think the thing
Speaker 1:  that there's no coming back from was all the safety stuff, right? Like there
Speaker 1:  was just no, it got so bad and so
Speaker 1:  publicized that I think even now I suspect
Speaker 1:  everyone's first association with Hoverboards is explosions. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Like I And I, there's just no coming back from that. But I do wonder 'cause
Speaker 1:  if you, if you rewind to the beginning of 2015, like again, this whole story
Speaker 1:  takes place in 12 months, which is insanity. But if you
Speaker 1:  rewind back to the beginning of it, there was a real sense.
Speaker 1:  This thing is huge. Everybody's into it.
Speaker 1:  It's, it's a good idea. It's a fun product. People like it, but there is
Speaker 1:  no brand that's gonna work. Yeah. Yeah. And I think it was
Speaker 1:  Joe Bernstein in Buzzfeed that compared it to jet ski where it's like, right,
Speaker 1:  there are, there are lots of ways to move around on the water. There's only
Speaker 1:  one jet ski. And if you could have been the one to come in and be like, okay,
Speaker 1:  screw io Hawks screw funky duck, all these dumb brands we're gonna be the
Speaker 1:  one like the Yeah. The sort of brand name the, the Kleenex
Speaker 1:  of the space that that was going to be massively,
Speaker 1:  massively valuable. And it's sort of sad to me that we didn't get
Speaker 1:  to see that from
Speaker 5:  You. I mean it could have happened that's Yeah. If it didn't explode and
Speaker 5:  they didn't catch on fire and people hadn't died there, we could have gotten
Speaker 5:  to a point where there might have been some sort of incumbent, whether it
Speaker 5:  was, you know, Ile Hawker or Mark Cuban's thing or
Speaker 5:  whatever it was that that could have emerged eventually had there been
Speaker 5:  more time I think. And, but because there was this like hard stop
Speaker 5:  at, you know, explosions, it didn't really get there and, and we're still
Speaker 5:  kind of in a place where there's a million different brands and they are
Speaker 5:  still available and they're a lot safer obviously now than they, than they
Speaker 5:  were before. But I feel because there was that disruption in
Speaker 5:  the mid in like sort of like right in midstream as this thing was getting
Speaker 5:  going, it kind of prevented it from happening.
Speaker 6:  I think that that moment too, it was a reset moment because not
Speaker 6:  only was there a safety threat, even people who didn't really
Speaker 6:  care much about that couldn't really buy them as easily all of a sudden.
Speaker 6:  And I think that that gave people enough space to realize
Speaker 6:  like what really is the utility of this thing. Yeah. You know, you talked
Speaker 6:  earlier about this idea that was sort of really in vogue at the time of like
Speaker 6:  the last mile thing. You know, you're gonna take a, you know, a
Speaker 6:  train somewhere, but you're going to have that last mile to your
Speaker 6:  destination. Should it be an electric bike? An electric scooter? Electric
Speaker 6:  skateboard or something like this. But, but I think people started to realize
Speaker 6:  in that sort of hangover moment of like, does this really actually
Speaker 6:  work like that? I mean you can take these things down like a sidewalk,
Speaker 6:  but like if there's a bump, like you're kind of doomed.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. You know, and it's like it really, you know, we talked earlier about
Speaker 6:  sort of, we were joking about like could we even ride it in this studio space?
Speaker 6:  Like it really is a thing that only works that well on like the shiny
Speaker 6:  floors of Justin Bieber's mansion or Yeah. Or an airport I guess. But
Speaker 6:  like for real, actual transportation, they are not as
Speaker 6:  useful as I think any of those early
Speaker 6:  companies, marketers, whoever would've really wanted people to believe. And
Speaker 6:  there were some attempts at making a changing that a little bit.
Speaker 6:  But it's tricky when you're dealing with self-balancing stuff. Especially
Speaker 6:  any, even if you're the wheels can handle it, you're gonna run into trouble
Speaker 6:  if you're going over sort of uneven surfaces. 'cause it's just gonna naturally
Speaker 6:  gonna throw off the inputs that you're giving into it and it just spirals
Speaker 6:  a bit out of control. And so it's, I think the most competent version of
Speaker 6:  that that we've ever seen is eventually the, the seg nine bot one
Speaker 6:  that really has, it's essentially a shrunk down segue with no stock to like
Speaker 6:  lean on with your hands. And that is like something that actually
Speaker 6:  probably works in those settings but is definitely more cumbersome,
Speaker 6:  not as easy to carry around on the subway or wherever. Like, like these were,
Speaker 6:  what
Speaker 5:  Is the problem that we're solving with this walking?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like
Speaker 5:  I think walking's fine. I don't see walking hot take as a problem. You know?
Speaker 5:  I understand that. Disagree, But no, I mean like if
Speaker 5:  that, if that was, if that was the problem. 'cause otherwise it was just
Speaker 5:  a novelty and it was just for Yeah. It became a punchline eventually where
Speaker 5:  like, you know, characters on tv, if you saw a character on, on a show
Speaker 5:  or TV on a, on a, on a hoverboard, it was like that person's a clown.
Speaker 5:  Right. Like that Yeah. You know, it was like John Ralphio from Parks and
Speaker 5:  Rec or something like that. Like, you know, like that it was, it was meant
Speaker 5:  to send the signal that this is like an unserious person. Yeah. And
Speaker 5:  so that's, and then I think it quickly sort of became associated with less
Speaker 5:  of the utility and more of sort of like the jokey like novel,
Speaker 6:  Which is funny 'cause around that same time, the same sort of aspersions
Speaker 6:  were being cast on people who were using the earliest versions of like the
Speaker 6:  electric kick scooters that we see around a lot of major cities. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  But that has utility to it. Yeah. So now people care less,
Speaker 6:  probably still some, but less about how weird they look if it just gets them
Speaker 6:  somewhere and quickly Yeah. And this was never gonna solve that problem.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean,
Speaker 1:  And again, go back to sort of the, the world at that time. It's like you
Speaker 1:  were talking about, we were like, okay, robo taxis are gonna take me everywhere.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. The the Hyperloop is gonna change my
Speaker 1:  life. Oh God. Like we were in this phase of it's not going to be
Speaker 1:  that long until you don't own a car anymore. Right. It was a thing a lot
Speaker 1:  of people would have you believe at the time. Yeah. And in that world, something
Speaker 1:  like this that is like, I just need to quickly get to the coffee shop. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Makes a lot more sense. And I own more cars than I did in 2015.
Speaker 6:  And it's like
Speaker 5:  Amazing to me that none of the car companies like tried to buy like
Speaker 5:  hover tracks or like, 'cause that's what they did with the scooter companies,
Speaker 5:  right. They like, they saw like Ford and others saw an opportunity, they're
Speaker 5:  like, we have to get a piece of this. This is gonna be huge. Yeah. And I
Speaker 5:  think because there was that, that disruption sort of like mid cycle as this
Speaker 5:  thing was just gaining momentum, like escape velocity. It was getting there.
Speaker 5:  Like you could have had like GM swoop in and like, buy
Speaker 6:  One of these. I'm dying. I'm like dying thinking about like the the 30
Speaker 6:  page slide deck that someone prepared for Mary Barra at GM of
Speaker 6:  like, here's why we should acquire Iowa Hawk. And then they
Speaker 6:  start exploding and she's like, get outs. The future of
Speaker 5:  Transportation is the hover
Speaker 6:  Tracks. I'm gonna invest a billion dollars in cruises instead. Like
Speaker 1:  Yeah, you could argue which one of those went better. I'm just saying. So
Speaker 1:  anyway, okay. So the story here basically ends with, you can still go to
Speaker 1:  a store and buy a hoverboard, which I will be honest is not a thing I knew
Speaker 1:  until I was researching this. I they're pretty cheap by all accounts. They're
Speaker 1:  pretty safe. Yeah. They, they're like, they're just out there. They're mostly
Speaker 1:  now called Hover tracks. The the whole thing is owned by
Speaker 1:  Razor. But I think Shane Chen kind of got his, got his piece. He, he won
Speaker 1:  in the end. Nice. He sold the patent. They're still called Hover tracks.
Speaker 1:  They're still out there. I wanna talk about two more things before we get
Speaker 1:  to the Version History questions. One is, during all of this
Speaker 1:  you, Sean had an actual experience with an actual hoverboard.
Speaker 6:  Yes. That's one of the crazy things too. I feel like this was
Speaker 6:  a thing that we, we set aside because it was such a weird moment.
Speaker 6:  But I think another element of why these things took off was because
Speaker 6:  it was just like hoverboard mania for a few years because there
Speaker 6:  were all these other companies at the time trying to do,
Speaker 6:  I, we were coming up on 2015 was what? The 30th anniversary
Speaker 6:  of Back to the Future. The date In fact of the future.
Speaker 6:  So, you know, there were all these people who were like gearing themselves
Speaker 6:  up to be like all retrospective about Back to the Future and the hoverboard
Speaker 6:  and, and, and so I think people
Speaker 6:  were just ready for it. And all these other companies, there was this company
Speaker 6:  called Hendo. There was, or Arcs pacs I think was the one that was actually
Speaker 6:  behind that. And there were, there were all these, they were coming up with
Speaker 6:  weird ways to try to make all air
Speaker 6:  quotes here, make Hoverboards that worked.
Speaker 6:  And it was like, you know, they would be okay this one hovers
Speaker 6:  with like magnetics over like non Ferris metal surfaces.
Speaker 6:  Okay, cool. Like and they remember they
Speaker 1:  They were science projects. Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 6:  They cool,
Speaker 5:  They're essential. You could just take it anywhere that they're
Speaker 6:  Yeah, yeah. There, there was one for a while. Oh man, the name escapes me.
Speaker 6:  But there was one where it was actually from a, a, a space company.
Speaker 6:  I think their name was ACA Space. And, and they were trying to do almost
Speaker 6:  like Aducted fan one that had like 40 or 50
Speaker 6:  or even more like little ducted fans, which looked
Speaker 6:  like a nightmare ride because like you're basically balancing on like an
Speaker 6:  air, like a small airboat. And so there were all these things and then I,
Speaker 6:  the big one that I remember was there was this sort of
Speaker 6:  hoaxy video that Tony Hawk did where it was digitally edited to make it
Speaker 6:  look like he was actually writing a hoverboard. And it had been created and
Speaker 6:  here it is. And it was just some viral stump for something else. And it was
Speaker 6:  like, that was the moment where that was happening. Like alongside all of
Speaker 6:  this stuff, just sort of fueling the mania. And then the, the
Speaker 6:  craziest one of all of 'em was like all of a sudden we got a call one day
Speaker 6:  from a a a, a pr PR rep who worked for
Speaker 6:  Lexus and, And I pick up the phone 'cause I, I'm one of those crazy people
Speaker 6:  that picks up every phone call that I get, even if it looks like it's gonna
Speaker 6:  be spam. 'cause you never know. And they were like, Hey,
Speaker 6:  like we we're doing this thing in Spain and
Speaker 6:  we want to know if you're interested. And they were describing it and it
Speaker 6:  was this whole thing about doing a real hoverboard. And we weren't really
Speaker 6:  sure of all the specifics, but it looked like we were looking at some of
Speaker 6:  the stuff that they were showing us and it was like, this looks like legit.
Speaker 6:  And I remember just like on, still on the phone, like scouring
Speaker 6:  the office looking around like, where is Sam Scheffer? We need to get into
Speaker 6:  Spain. And it was like right around 4th of July too. So I remember it
Speaker 6:  just being like, I'm sorry if I'm blowing up your holiday, but like, you
Speaker 6:  should go to Spain. Like, like you're welcome.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. There are worst
Speaker 1:  Things to be told. Over the
Speaker 6:  4th of July he went and it was like, you know, again, it was another one
Speaker 6:  of these things where it was very science experimented. They basically just
Speaker 6:  built an entire skate park that had
Speaker 6:  magnetic rails underneath most of the park.
Speaker 6:  And it was, you know, it was similar to if you've ever seen those things
Speaker 6:  where there's like a super cool piece of some material and it kind
Speaker 6:  of like, you know, hovers over a base of some other material.
Speaker 6:  It was essentially that. But they had balanced it out well and they had worked
Speaker 6:  with some skateboarders and they, they went through all the work to make
Speaker 6:  it a really work but it within its
Speaker 6:  own limits. And it was, I remember he had so much trouble
Speaker 6:  getting it to work because it's in Spain, it's very hot. It was the summer,
Speaker 6:  the materials they were using had to be cooled to a certain temperature.
Speaker 6:  If it went above it. They had to swap out the board. But you know, he was
Speaker 6:  able to, you know, even all those constraints like set those aside, he was
Speaker 6:  able to ride a skateboard on a skate park that hovered. And it was like a
Speaker 6:  really cool moment. Like we filmed a really good video about it and it was
Speaker 6:  like such a fun, weird thing. Again, it was just a stunt, but
Speaker 6:  it was like all that was happening at the same time that all this stuff was
Speaker 6:  happening, which was like fueling the mania of this product,
Speaker 6:  but also even just the idea of calling them a hoverboard in the first place.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And this one actually hovered, let me, I I have a clip of that video,
Speaker 1:  which if memory serves was one of the verges most
Speaker 1:  successful and viewed videos
Speaker 6:  Still, still to this day, day I
Speaker 1:  Think almost. Yeah. It's truly wild here It is. It
Speaker 19:  Hovers off the ground like a proper hoverboard. But as I'm sure you've
Speaker 19:  guessed, there are some big caveats like the track it needs to run on, which
Speaker 19:  is crucial to how the thing works at all. The board, I mean,
Speaker 6:  It looks cool because it's designed well, but it looks like all the
Speaker 6:  liquid nitrogen coming off, it just like makes it look
Speaker 1:  The magnetic. Nothing about this is real, but it's sick
Speaker 19:  Vertically with the center of the board. So it's, I mean it
Speaker 6:  Looks like it's on
Speaker 19:  The ground around tightrope. And
Speaker 6:  If your balance there does is perfectly
Speaker 19:  Distributed on this thing, you end up scraping the ground with the undersides
Speaker 19:  of the board. It took me like
Speaker 1:  15 minutes just to glide
Speaker 5:  A few feet. Oh yeah. You can kind of see that's a good angle.
Speaker 6:  That was where the heat was working against them too, where it was like the
Speaker 6:  hotter it was the, the less whatever the force was was working.
Speaker 6:  So I remember him telling me that he was struggling with that part of it
Speaker 6:  and it was, it took them a minute to really get one with just the right
Speaker 6:  amount of like the liquid nitrogen or whatever it was to, to get it to hover
Speaker 6:  in a frame to really try and ride it.
Speaker 5:  IIII rode one of the ones on the metal surface Oh yeah. At, at a
Speaker 5:  Hyperloop event. Sure. As it were. Yeah. In
Speaker 5:  Texas, a SpaceX had this big hyperloop competition
Speaker 5:  at Texas eight M University. And like one of the vendors that was there showing
Speaker 5:  off like their products was one of the, I, I forget which one it was. I think
Speaker 5:  it was
Speaker 6:  The Hendo
Speaker 5:  One. It might have been the Hendo one, but the, I remember the funny thing
Speaker 5:  about that was they, they made you hold hands with somebody Yeah. While you
Speaker 5:  were on it. So I'm like, this is the most like yeah. Nursery school
Speaker 5:  demo I've ever done in my entire life. I'm holding hands with this man as
Speaker 5:  I write on a, I actual, I
Speaker 6:  Like that you wrote a hoverboard, but you've never ridden a hoverboard board
Speaker 6:  on the
Speaker 5:  Hoverboard. Yes. I know. That's the, that's one of the weird things about
Speaker 5:  me. I
Speaker 1:  Also like that that's like what the future of the hyperloop should have been.
Speaker 1:  Yes. Like just put up rails and let us all hoverboard from San
Speaker 5:  Francisco to LA while holding. Well they're all about magnetic levitation.
Speaker 5:  Right at at Hyperloop Inc. That's
Speaker 1:  Exactly right. So, okay. And then the last thing we have to talk about, which
Speaker 1:  is the only thing that matters in this entire thing, all of this has been
Speaker 1:  a waste except for one important question, which is
Speaker 1:  why the hell are these things called Hoverboards? They don't hover. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Fair point taken.
Speaker 1:  But they are Hoverboards and they, they, they just are Hoverboards.
Speaker 6:  There was never any other good name. Yeah. To call them,
Speaker 6:  you know, like we, we ran through a few of them already, like
Speaker 6:  self-balancing scooter, you know, just nothing that like really rolled off
Speaker 6:  the tongue. And then, you know, I I where that comes from, I don't even really
Speaker 6:  remember again this, there was this sort of cultural thing
Speaker 6:  happening, like I said at the same time where Hoverboards were in our
Speaker 6:  mind in a way that they hadn't been in years prior. And so, you know,
Speaker 6:  I think it just, it became a good shorthand for it. And again, like to the
Speaker 6:  what, like I said earlier, if you're not looking at what somebody's doing
Speaker 6:  and you're just seeing there like torso and Ed coming at you, it looks
Speaker 6:  like you're hovering. It looks like you are floating at me as a specter
Speaker 6:  about to like, you know, it's just Yeah. I get it.
Speaker 1:  So I want to see if we can rename this thing very quickly
Speaker 1:  knowing what we know now. Is there a better name for this thing?
Speaker 1:  I
Speaker 5:  Mean, I kind of agree with Sean that you can't, you can't really beat hoverboard
Speaker 5:  in terms of like the cultural,
Speaker 1:  But it doesn't
Speaker 5:  Hover Ations that it has rolly
Speaker 6:  Board roll board. No bad ideas. Go ly.
Speaker 5:  Board Glide. Glide Ride. Glide Ride. Can
Speaker 1:  We just call it a
Speaker 6:  Scooter Spin Doctor?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, there you go. Glide Ride
Speaker 1:  Is actually very good. It's nothing but it's very good.
Speaker 5:  It's nothing
Speaker 5:  Spin Doctor's good. I like Spin Doctor. I can
Speaker 6:  See somebody selling it as the Spin Doctor. Yeah. The company's called something
Speaker 6:  else.
Speaker 5:  Brand
Speaker 1:  Name. Yeah, for
Speaker 6:  Sure.
Speaker 5:  Tilt O World Tilt World.
Speaker 1:  This is all making me like hoverboard more
Speaker 5:  Ass blaster. I said you followed your ass.
Speaker 6:  Zoom, scooter
Speaker 6:  Foot. There's probably something with Foot, right? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Foot,
Speaker 6:  Foot Wheel Foot. Mobile. Mobile.
Speaker 5:  That's gonna get a whole other demographic. Yeah. Interested
Speaker 6:  In it. Hey listen.
Speaker 5:  The foot demographic.
Speaker 1:  All right, fine. It's Hoverboards. This sucks. This didn't go at all how
Speaker 1:  I was hoping it was going
Speaker 5:  To. They're called Icarus
Speaker 6:  Wings. Unironically Touch the
Speaker 6:  Sun.
Speaker 5:  I stand by Glide Ride. I feel good about that.
Speaker 1:  Glide Ride's pretty good. Glide is like, I think we just came up with a bunch
Speaker 1:  of good company names. Like when we're gonna bring the hoverboard
Speaker 1:  back, we're gonna call it the
Speaker 5:  Glide Rides. Well here's the thing that's gonna stick. You noted that the,
Speaker 5:  the Hoverboards still around. I was at my children's talent show
Speaker 5:  earlier this year in amidst all of the terrible renditions of
Speaker 5:  frozen songs and Pink Pony Club and all the other things that
Speaker 5:  were going on. Two kids came out on Hoverboards and did a
Speaker 5:  hoverboard dance to some song I'd never heard before. I think it was like
Speaker 5:  a Minecraft song or so like that. This was recently, this was, this was like
Speaker 5:  a couple months ago and they were wearing like glittery spandex like
Speaker 5:  outfits and they killed it. Shout out to Nico
Speaker 5:  and Brooks. Those kids
Speaker 6:  We're sure you're listening
Speaker 5:  Were amazing And I, it gave me some songs. 'cause this is not
Speaker 5:  Gen Z or millennials or anyone. This is like Jet Alpha, right? Yeah. These
Speaker 5:  are the kids are still are into 'em. They're still
Speaker 1:  Have, we have, we come all the way back around so that they're vintage. It's
Speaker 1:  like eighties glam cringe cover boards.
Speaker 5:  Millennial cringe is back. Right? It's,
Speaker 6:  Well,
Speaker 1:  We're all a thousand years old is the main takeaway from this episode of
Speaker 1:  Version History. Alright, let's oh, one coda to this story.
Speaker 1:  Before we get to the Version History questions, can I share with you what
Speaker 1:  our good friend Shane Chen has been working on recently? Oh,
Speaker 5:  Please. Yes.
Speaker 1:  I have a clip that I would very much like to share with you. So this
Speaker 1:  is a product, it is simply called Shane.
Speaker 20:  Shane. A revolutionary new car embraces the laws of physics
Speaker 20:  in an unexpected Oh right invented way. Yes. Large
Speaker 20:  parallel wheels automatically shift relative to the car's body to keep
Speaker 20:  Shane in perfect balance during acceleration and braking, making it
Speaker 20:  stable and safe even at high speeds, a capability not
Speaker 20:  previously possible. Suspended motors and regenerative shocks are
Speaker 20:  housed in the wheels, maneuverability and parking are easy
Speaker 20:  thanks to two wheel differential speed control, which eliminates the
Speaker 20:  complicated steering system of today's cars. Pure electronic steering
Speaker 20:  makes it a better self-driving car. Shane is practical and
Speaker 20:  efficient for everyday urban and highway driving.
Speaker 1:  The only way I can describe this to you is as hoverboard
Speaker 1:  but spaceship. Yes. It looks
Speaker 6:  It's like a frog car.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  A better self-driving car.
Speaker 5:  Why is there so much parking in the desert? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  My question is like, well one of my questions is,
Speaker 6:  is this something he's been like building towards or is it a new idea? Like
Speaker 6:  is it, is it is the dream to always make a car
Speaker 6:  with two wheels named after himself? I mean, I
Speaker 1:  Do sort of like the idea that you can, you can go all the way back to all
Speaker 1:  of his inventions. Yeah. And they just get bigger and more expensive and
Speaker 1:  then they end up being a spaceship on self-balancing wheels. Like
Speaker 5:  Are reading an SUV version of this at some 0.3
Speaker 1:  Row Shane.
Speaker 5:  I do like that he was like two wheels. That's it. Oh yeah.
Speaker 5:  For the, that's all we need for everything in our lives is
Speaker 5:  just two wheels. This four wheel stuff. That's bullshit.
Speaker 5:  We need to just narrow it down to two.
Speaker 1:  Did you see how easy it was to park? I mean, come on. That's in's a dream.
Speaker 1:  All right, Shane, I'm glad you did it. Congratulations.
Speaker 5:  Dream is alive. You won.
Speaker 6:  You send me the Kickstarter link. I wanna back.
Speaker 1:  I think so. Yeah. We'll, we'll do that with this episode. All right. We need
Speaker 1:  to take one more break and then we're gonna come back and do the Version
Speaker 1:  History questions. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. It's time as always, for the eight questions we ask
Speaker 1:  about every product we cover on this show. Question number one,
Speaker 1:  weirdly tricky. In this case, what was the best thing
Speaker 1:  about Hoverboards?
Speaker 6:  Oh,
Speaker 1:  Man. Sean, you go first.
Speaker 6:  I like the content, like you just, like all the celebrity
Speaker 6:  Bs and like, you know, people, you know, unboxing videos at
Speaker 6:  Christmas. I feel like there was just such a, a moment that we've talked
Speaker 6:  about of like this becoming like
Speaker 6:  something you could read about or watch for days on end and, and that it
Speaker 6:  got to like local news, you know, you've got local news
Speaker 6:  penetration where you're just like, you know, someone in like Peoria, Illinois's
Speaker 6:  local station talking about Hoverboards. It was just,
Speaker 1:  I do think hoverboard probably got to like a hundred percent brand awareness.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. At some point. It's like Coca-Cola, iPhones,
Speaker 1:  Hoverboards, like that was, it was right up there for a while. Yeah. I, not
Speaker 1:  for good reasons, but it was there. That's a good answer. I like that. Andy,
Speaker 1:  what do you think? I, I think
Speaker 5:  It's like how they didn't overstay their welcome that they, I mean, like
Speaker 5:  for, not, not by choice, like they flamed out literally, but I feel
Speaker 5:  like it, it, it, they didn't, they didn't stick around and like, we didn't
Speaker 5:  have to go through like, multiple cycles of, you know, the boom and bust
Speaker 5:  of it all. They just came, they, they made, you know, sort of made their
Speaker 5:  case for themselves and then they started exploding and then that was the
Speaker 5:  end of it. And yeah, they're still around and you know, but they're not as
Speaker 5:  big as they were. I, I, I think that that's more products should be like,
Speaker 5:  sort of like the original office where you just like three seasons and you're
Speaker 5:  done and that's it. Like end on a high note,
Speaker 1:  High-ish, you
Speaker 6:  Know,
Speaker 1:  It ended on a note,
Speaker 6:  End on a note.
Speaker 5:  I'm not defending this take at all. It's just a take.
Speaker 1:  It's a good take. I like it. I think for me, the, the underrated thing about
Speaker 1:  these things is I think they got the size of the thing
Speaker 1:  kind of right? Like the, one of my problem with all of these, like last
Speaker 1:  Miley things, we, we've, you know, the electric bikes, the electric scooters,
Speaker 1:  all these, they're just enormous. And they're like, I had one of the nine
Speaker 1:  bot scooters for a while and the thing weighed like 45 pounds,
Speaker 1:  like, you know, three feet long, really annoying to carry around. And there
Speaker 1:  was something about like, you could just kind of pick up a hoverboard and
Speaker 1:  carry it with you. And it was, it was too heavy in a way that I
Speaker 1:  actually think, like the year three of Hoverboards, they would've figured
Speaker 1:  out how to make it lighter and it would've been more compelling for it. But
Speaker 1:  like there was something about just the basic shape of the thing that I was
Speaker 1:  like, all right, if we're gonna do the last mile thing, this is about the
Speaker 1:  shape of it that feels right to me. Mm. Alright. Question number two is gonna
Speaker 1:  be much easier because the answer is explosions. What was the worst thing
Speaker 1:  about Hoverboards
Speaker 6:  The content?
Speaker 6:  This was sort of more of the wild West days of like influencer marketing
Speaker 6:  and we didn't really know, you know, Kendall General wasn't posting
Speaker 6:  hashtag ad under her posts yet. You know, like that kind of stuff. And it
Speaker 6:  was like, there was more than just the Hoverboards or all these like
Speaker 6:  electric surfboards and stuff, and it just, it was such a weird time of like,
Speaker 6:  you know, how much of the truth are you telling us
Speaker 6:  here? And, and you know, like I just, that part
Speaker 6:  of it always felt really weird to me.
Speaker 1:  Okay. If I, if I give you 51% of
Speaker 1:  the celebrity hoverboard content was bought and paid for in some way, are
Speaker 1:  you, are you going over or over?
Speaker 6:  Oh, over you think? Yeah. I mean, oh, that's so sad. Even if I, I, I say
Speaker 6:  over, but like with the caveat of like, including, there were
Speaker 6:  probably instances where people were getting them for free, but they were
Speaker 6:  probably expecting something in return at some point, you know, like Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Like Justin Bieber probably did not buy his iHawk on Amazon. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Clear. Yeah, definitely not. So yeah, I would definitely over, yeah, I don't
Speaker 5:  Know if they were cashing big checks. No. You know, from, from any of these
Speaker 5:  companies necessarily, but yeah, they definitely were. There was something
Speaker 5:  going on.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. What about you? What was the worst?
Speaker 5:  I mean, aside from the human toll and the destroyed property
Speaker 5:  and, you know, all of that. I probably the name, I guess
Speaker 5:  it's like, you know, 'cause we did, we, you know, we, there could have been,
Speaker 5:  we did have Hoverboards and then this sort of supplanted that, and now we
Speaker 5:  can't talk about the concept of Hoverboards without thinking of these things
Speaker 5:  first as opposed to the much,
Speaker 6:  And even your children's, you know, that, that whole That's right. Era is
Speaker 6:  tainted now too. Won't
Speaker 5:  They won't even, they, they, they'll grow up in a world never knowing the
Speaker 5:  joys of back to the future.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. They're gonna watch back to the future too and be like, that's not
Speaker 1:  a hoverboard. That's exactly. And you're just gonna die inside. Exactly.
Speaker 1:  It's right there
Speaker 5:  In front of them. That will be the, the day that I, I turn into the guy from
Speaker 5:  the end of last crusade. The Andy's
Speaker 6:  Answer is the Indy generational intergenerational trauma.
Speaker 5:  Yes. That's
Speaker 1:  Good. All right. Well, it's the explosions. You're both wrong. Question number
Speaker 1:  three, would it have been a bigger hit if Apple had made it?
Speaker 1:  Could Apple have made Hoverboards work?
Speaker 5:  Apple would've done a secret project Titan like project
Speaker 5:  to develop their own hoverboard for 15 years and then
Speaker 5:  abandoned it after spending $8 billion and
Speaker 5:  deciding, like,
Speaker 1:  Would you be be surprised if you learned that there was a hoverboard just
Speaker 1:  embedded into the trunk of the Apple car? That like the timing
Speaker 1:  kind of works, but
Speaker 6:  There was like a space Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Specifically where you plug it in. Like,
Speaker 1:  Like I'm, I'm sure there was a
Speaker 6:  Meeting, right? The question is, could Apple have made it successful? Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Oh man. No.
Speaker 1:  Okay.
Speaker 6:  Because Johnny, ive would've made it like a single plank of wood
Speaker 6:  and it wouldn't have worked,
Speaker 5:  You know, and it would've come preloaded with just you two. The
Speaker 6:  Yeah. It would be about blasting out the, the party speakers on the side.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. No,
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I think I'm also saying, no, I think there's like, it would've been
Speaker 1:  safer if Apple had made it. Yeah. I have a lot of faith in Apple's ability
Speaker 1:  to make
Speaker 6:  Batteries that don't, well, safer on the battery side, maybe not on the riding
Speaker 6:  side. Well, right. And industrial design probably. Sure. Better. But still,
Speaker 6:  I
Speaker 5:  Think, yeah, it would've been white and depending
Speaker 6:  Also if it would've been, did,
Speaker 1:  It would've been like five grand and it would've not sold like the, the vision
Speaker 1:  pro of
Speaker 6:  For your feet cover boards. Yeah. Here's the tagline,
Speaker 1:  Not what we're about, I don't think.
Speaker 1:  Question number four. If you could go back and make it yourself, what would
Speaker 1:  you do differently? You're, you're going back, we're the three of us just
Speaker 1:  became hoverboard distributors. It's April of 2015.
Speaker 5:  I, I would put a stock on it And I would call it a segue.
Speaker 5:  I don't know what I would've done differently. I think maybe I would've started
Speaker 5:  with the party speaker, speaker angle. Like that would've been like the first
Speaker 5:  thing like this. It's not alone, it's not enough. It needs to be like more
Speaker 5:  than what it is.
Speaker 1:  I would've tried to make it like rugged and sporty in
Speaker 1:  some way. Mm. Yeah. Because like you mentioned, the, they started doing the
Speaker 1:  ones with like the bigger wheels, a little easier to maneuver. I think
Speaker 1:  especially at the beginning. You never experienced this 'cause you're a coward
Speaker 1:  and never tried it. But the first most
Speaker 1:  people had a bad first experience Yeah. On a hoverboard. Of course. And,
Speaker 1:  and the question was if you were willing to try it like three or four or
Speaker 1:  five times to kind of get the hang of it. But there's like researching this
Speaker 1:  episode, I saw the same clip so many times of you, the people who stand
Speaker 1:  on the thing and then their legs start wobbling. Yep. Yeah. Because it, it
Speaker 1:  takes a minute for your brain to realize, okay, it's, I actually don't move
Speaker 1:  my legs. Right. The whole point of this is that I don't move my legs. It's
Speaker 1:  all like, it's an upper body thing most of the time, but they get on and
Speaker 1:  you just sort of wobble back and forth and then fall off and hurt yourself
Speaker 1:  spectacularly. But they had started to do things with like bigger, wider
Speaker 1:  wheels, slightly more sort of stable things and try to make
Speaker 1:  it like more outdoorsy. Yeah. And I just
Speaker 1:  would've gone straight to that. Be like, this is not a commuter tool. This
Speaker 1:  is like Pure fun to do like
Speaker 6:  Shocks, like having some sort of like shocks on it to absorb the bumps. What
Speaker 1:  If it could go on the sidewalk and not try to throw you off every time?
Speaker 1:  Like I would've just started there.
Speaker 6:  I would've probably given it more than two wheels. Mm. And
Speaker 6:  maybe take out the motors. Call it Shane right now. Skateboard. Shane. Shane
Speaker 6:  is crying. He heard he's hearing motors.
Speaker 1:  I was imagining three wheels and it's like a triangle that you stand on now
Speaker 6:  We're talking, now we're talking. I like this.
Speaker 6:  Or
Speaker 1:  We call it the pyramid and it just, it just takes you along everywhere you're
Speaker 1:  going.
Speaker 6:  Or you know what, eight wheels. Whoa, fuck it. You know,
Speaker 6:  fuck it. We're doing eight wheels.
Speaker 1:  Are we going longer or just more wheels?
Speaker 6:  No, I think, you know, like in, in octagonal shape. Okay. And you can go
Speaker 6:  omnidirectional.
Speaker 1:  So like a stop sign with wheel.
Speaker 6:  Like a true platform. Yes. Like a sign, like a class eight. Like a true like
Speaker 6:  platform that you're on and you know, instead of just leaning forward back
Speaker 6:  where you can kind of go into,
Speaker 1:  Did you have those things in elementary school? That's
Speaker 6:  What I'm thinking of
Speaker 1:  With the, yeah, they had the wheels and you would sit on them and hold the
Speaker 1:  handles and like launch yourself around the gym. Yeah. You're talking about
Speaker 1:  one of those kind of, but you
Speaker 6:  Stand on it, but double the wheels.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 6:  And you stand on it.
Speaker 1:  That's the best idea I've heard all day. I love it. Amen. We just, we fixed
Speaker 1:  it. Chris job
Speaker 6:  Bust.
Speaker 1:  Mark Cuban, get at us.
Speaker 1:  What thing about Hoverboards, the experience of riding them or
Speaker 1:  the things themselves would you still
Speaker 1:  want to have today? What last Miley Gadget would you make out of a
Speaker 1:  hoverboard?
Speaker 6:  Oh, I see. I mean, I wrote a lot of electric skateboards
Speaker 6:  And I mean, honestly, a lot of those were trash too. But the booster board
Speaker 6:  was really good. There was this thing called Z board for a while. Z board
Speaker 6:  was really good. And that was, that one actually is maybe the closest analog
Speaker 6:  to this because the Z board,
Speaker 6:  unlike boosted and a lot of the other ones didn't use a remote. It had foot
Speaker 6:  pressure pads on the front interest of the skateboard.
Speaker 1:  Oh, interesting. Okay. I don't think I ever tried that one.
Speaker 6:  I mean, the first version of it was very heavy. I don't know that I ever
Speaker 6:  actually rode the second one outside of maybe a quick demo at CES, but the,
Speaker 6:  the first one I had for a while while I lived in Queens and like rode around.
Speaker 6:  That was great. I actually really loved that. It was like, was it self balancing?
Speaker 6:  It wasn't bal I mean, it was just a skateboard. It was like a pretty heavy,
Speaker 6:  like big wood deck, like longboard with the motors and stuff underneath.
Speaker 6:  But you would, you would speed up and slow down by applying pressure to the
Speaker 6:  pads on either side. And it was the closest that that form factor ever got
Speaker 6:  to something like this. I,
Speaker 1:  That's cool. That's what I was gonna say too is I don't, I don't know about
Speaker 1:  the self-balancing, but the, the sort of lean to go and lean back to stop
Speaker 1:  thing I actually think is pretty intuitive.
Speaker 6:  It was really fun
Speaker 1:  And, and works pretty well.
Speaker 5:  I mean that's, I think that that's key, like essential to like the delight
Speaker 5:  of the product, why so many people were attracted to it because they were,
Speaker 5:  they felt like they were doing something right. Like the, like the, the machine
Speaker 5:  was kind of doing it for them, but they were like balancing on this in like
Speaker 5:  a way that like was unexpected.
Speaker 1:  And that's so much about that sort of simple movement of your body
Speaker 1:  that I think is very cool. Alright, question number six. Is there an
Speaker 1:  alternate timeline in which this thing was more or even more successful?
Speaker 5:  I mean, yeah, if they didn't explode, I think they would've probably
Speaker 5:  continued. I think they would've like petered out and like leveled out at
Speaker 5:  a certain point. But yeah, I think minus the explosions you could have, like,
Speaker 5:  you could very well see like a lot of, you know, even
Speaker 5:  more mainstream of adoption around
Speaker 1:  This. Do you think there's any world in which they get up to like
Speaker 1:  electric bike level speed? No. Like, oh, penetration.
Speaker 6:  Oh, adoption. Yeah. Like
Speaker 1:  If I'm, do
Speaker 5:  I mean, I would argue that Hoverboards had more penetration than E-bikes
Speaker 5:  did in some
Speaker 1:  Respects for 10 minutes. For 10. Yeah. Yeah. No, you're right. But you're
Speaker 1:  right. But I think what I'm thinking of is like, there, there is an age that
Speaker 1:  every kid gets to right? Where they're like, I want a bike. Yeah. And I think
Speaker 1:  is there ever a world in which Hoverboards ascend
Speaker 1:  to something like that
Speaker 6:  Level? I mean, you'll like this No, not in the United States. Like
Speaker 6:  if, if this country or any of its cities were really oriented around
Speaker 6:  pedestrians versus cars, then actually I think this
Speaker 6:  thing would've had a pretty good crack at it. But like the infrastructure
Speaker 6:  is just not there. Like I said, it's like a pebble on the sidewalk is
Speaker 6:  just gonna throw you off of this thing. And if, if there were more
Speaker 6:  spaces where you could take these kind of like personal mobility things
Speaker 6:  than, you know, on smoother surfaces to get rounded actual
Speaker 6:  city, then maybe there really would be. But that, that's just not
Speaker 6:  how this country's built.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I think I agree with that, that there is, if, if a lot of
Speaker 1:  like the alternate timeline would start in like the 18 hundreds
Speaker 6:  In order for this thing to, or even further or like back to the future, like
Speaker 6:  even further into the future from now where it's like the, the
Speaker 6:  sort of, you know, that that meme of like, this is the future we could have
Speaker 6:  if only for X, you know? Yeah. And it's like the glossy city with like all
Speaker 6:  this stuff. Yeah. Like it would have to be something like that. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. We're riding through the hyperloop tubes on our Exactly. On our Hoverboards,
Speaker 6:  Our last mile off the hyperloop tubes to,
Speaker 6:  to go to work at the AI training facility. Yes.
Speaker 1:  If the, the futures we've lost.
Speaker 1:  All right. Question number seven. Could you make Hoverboards a thing again
Speaker 1:  now?
Speaker 5:  I, I, I think so because like yeah, I think that we are in that era where
Speaker 5:  like there's like, there's no boundary in, in terms of like how, like how
Speaker 5:  much time has needed to pass before you can feel nostalgic about something.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like everything has just collapsed. Yeah. And it's like, you can feel
Speaker 5:  nostalgic for 2016. You can feel nostalgic for 2020
Speaker 5:  if you want to. Like, it does feel like they, people can reach back and take
Speaker 5:  what they want and sort of cherry pick and like cobble together their own
Speaker 5:  kind of like, you know, memories about what the past was and how it
Speaker 5:  was better. So I, I do think that there could be some, you know, like you
Speaker 5:  give it to Benson Boone or whomever and he does a back flip off a piano onto
Speaker 5:  a hoverboard Ooh. At the Oscars or something like that. You,
Speaker 1:  You, you are making me remember there was a run of
Speaker 1:  hoverboard dance craze during all of this that was like people doing
Speaker 1:  wild synchronized hoverboard dancing. Sure, yeah.
Speaker 5:  Child's,
Speaker 1:  We could absolutely bring that back
Speaker 5:  School at their, that's talent show. Yes. We
Speaker 1:  Could absolutely bring that back. I think with without a lot of trouble.
Speaker 1:  We could bring that back. We could make that happen again. All we need to
Speaker 1:  do is get one, like, it's, it's probably Benson Boone now. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  I, we call
Speaker 1:  Taylor Swift on a hoverboard. Like it's done. We get it.
Speaker 6:  I say we call Soulja Boy. I'm sure he's still got some stock can now
Speaker 6:  he's got some stock back in a warehouse somewhere. Oh yes.
Speaker 5:  He's got a closet full just stacked to, to
Speaker 6:  The ceiling. Nothing but sold Unop
Speaker 5:  Boxes. Yes.
Speaker 6:  That's what we should call him is just so, I mean, soldier Board nailed it
Speaker 6:  out the gate. Yes, he did, he did. Soldier board. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And he would, he would easily get into business with us on this, I'm sure.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. So that's great. Okay. We're good. This is
Speaker 5:  All right. New.
Speaker 1:  We made a lot of money for the, this, this is great news. Last question,
Speaker 1:  do Hoverboards belong in the Version History Hall of Fame? The rules for
Speaker 1:  the Hall of Fame are nebulous and vibe-y as all hall of fames are,
Speaker 1:  but I think the, the rubric to the extent that it exists is just,
Speaker 1:  did this thing matter? Like in the, in the anals of
Speaker 1:  technology history, were the Hoverboards
Speaker 1:  sort of capital I important enough to belong in the Hall of Fame?
Speaker 5:  I do think that there was, you know, like I, there's a universe at which
Speaker 5:  like, you didn't have Hoverboards, maybe you didn't have e-bikes or
Speaker 5:  e scooters or e skateboards and all the other sort of mobility devices that
Speaker 5:  have like, been way more successful than
Speaker 5:  the hoverboard ever was. Like, you needed to have this kind of like kitschy
Speaker 5:  toy product to come first and also show us,
Speaker 5:  you know, sort of like the capacity that China has in terms of
Speaker 5:  manufacturing products and seized upon things that
Speaker 5:  have become popular in other countries and just like flooding the
Speaker 5:  zone with this kind of stuff. So
Speaker 6:  Then changing their factories the next week to make like e-cigarettes or
Speaker 6:  whatever,
Speaker 5:  Like Right, exactly. On a dime. Yeah. So, yeah, I I do feel like that there
Speaker 5:  is like a version like, you know, like the hover, we needed to have like
Speaker 5:  the boondoggle of the hoverboard in order to get like these much more
Speaker 5:  utilitarian e mobility devices that are actually
Speaker 5:  last mile devices that are worthwhile and
Speaker 5:  should, but it all, it also, it's frustrating because we learned
Speaker 5:  nothing from the hoverboard as well. Correct. Because those products all
Speaker 5:  exploded, inflamed out and did horrible things to people. And we didn't learn
Speaker 5:  from the hoverboard that we need to make these things safer and there need
Speaker 5:  to be safer safety standards around the construction of these batteries,
Speaker 5:  especially. And I wish that we had
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I like part of that explanation makes me think that no,
Speaker 1:  it doesn't belong. It's like saying the, the pitcher who taught the other
Speaker 1:  pitcher how to be better than him belongs in the Hall of Fame. And it's like,
Speaker 1:  I'm not sure that's right. But I do think everything you just said is true.
Speaker 1:  And also it was such a moment and it burned so
Speaker 1:  bright like that, that was the thing that really came back to me in, in prepping
Speaker 1:  for this was it was so huge. Hillary Clinton.
Speaker 5:  Clinton was supposed to be the president. Let's just keep that in mind. At
Speaker 5:  that year, that's what all of us were thinking as the hoverboard was gaining
Speaker 5:  traction. Real different world President Hoverboard. Nope. That's not
Speaker 5:  the world we live. All
Speaker 1:  Right. I think we're gonna put it in the Hall of Fame, just because Shane
Speaker 1:  Chan needs a win. We're doing it for Shane.
Speaker 5:  You don't wanna put the Shane in there. Well, so
Speaker 1:  Here's the question though is are we putting the Chic Robotics S one? Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Which one? Or are we putting the hover tracks?
Speaker 6:  We're putting
Speaker 6:  a vague recreation of a patent application in there,
Speaker 1:  But like the cartoon version of a hoverboard Yeah. Goes in,
Speaker 1:  goes in the Hall of Fame. I think so. All right. I like it. I feel good about
Speaker 1:  it. All right. That is it. That's it for the show. Thank you both for being
Speaker 1:  here. Thank you. This was very fun. We're gonna go Red Hoverboards and see
Speaker 1:  who gets injured first has ever. You can watch all of our
Speaker 1:  episodes on YouTube. You can listen to 'em wherever you get podcasts. And
Speaker 1:  the best way to support all of this and everything we do is to subscribe
Speaker 1:  to The Verge dot com. That's it. Thank you so much for being here. See you
Speaker 1:  next time.
Speaker 2:  Version
Speaker 1:  History is produced by Victoria Barrios, river Branson, Owen Grove, Brandon
Speaker 1:  Kiefer, Travis Uck, Eric Gomez, Andrew Marino, and Alex Parkin.
Speaker 1:  Studio support from Chris Shirtliff. Our theme music is composed by
Speaker 1:  Brandon McFarland. Be sure to subscribe to the new Version History podcast
Speaker 1:  feed to get all of our new episodes as soon as they arrive.