# Transcript
ID: 76ddbe5d-842b-4825-b3cc-4a10b101a15b
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/-1827136009249556856/-1609564094464774717/s93290-US-6263s-1738318961.mp3
Description: Nilay and David dig into the week's biggest story: the new Intel-powered Surface Pro. Kidding! They talk about DeepSeek, the out-of-nowhere AI company that sent both Silicon Valley and the stock market into uproar this week. Then, after the hosts debate what the real killer app for AI is — and whether we've even found one yet — we follow up on our question from last week about how people are actually using AI. We got so many good answers, and we talk through what to make of them all. Finally, in the lightning round, we talk about Brendan Carr being a dummy, the return of the Pebble, the continued rise of Bluesky and Threads, and Meta's $25 million check to Trump.
Speaker 1:  Hello and welcome to our chest, the flagship podcast Stealing
Speaker 1:  stuff. Sam Altman has already stolen.
Speaker 1:  You're on notice, Sam, you steal a car. I'm coming to steal that car. Look,
Speaker 1:  I haven't been a lawyer in a long time. Isn't that double jeopardy? Like
Speaker 1:  if somebody else has done a crime and then you do the crime to them,
Speaker 1:  you're
Speaker 5:  Good. Yeah, if it's additive crime, I think it it is fine.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I don't look, I passed the bar exam a long time ago.
Speaker 1:  I've drank a lot since then. Just in the past five days of the Trump
Speaker 1:  administration, I've drank away one full bar exam. But I do believe, and
Speaker 1:  you correct and correct me if I'm wrong, that if someone does a crime and
Speaker 1:  then you do that same crime to them, the court's like, you're good.
Speaker 5:  Listen, if we've learned anything in the last two weeks, it's that you can
Speaker 5:  in fact just say things
Speaker 1:  Whenever you want. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And sometimes those things turn out to have huge weight
Speaker 5:  over how America works. So yeah, here we are.
Speaker 1:  We're fully in the, I declare bankruptcy stage as the American experiment,
Speaker 1:  as, as I believe George Washington prophesied in his
Speaker 1:  first inaugural. He is like, one day people are just gonna start saying stuff
Speaker 1:  and you should row a boat away from Harris as fast as you can. Those are
Speaker 1:  all the things I know about George Washington. All right. It's about right.
Speaker 1:  There's a lot going on this week. I'm actually very excited about our second
Speaker 1:  segment this week. Last week we asked a bunch of you to tell us
Speaker 1:  what you were using AI for because there's a big gap, right? In
Speaker 1:  how people feel about it, what the companies say about it, the amount of
Speaker 1:  money we're spending on it, and then how people are actually using it. And
Speaker 1:  it turns out a lot of you are using ai.
Speaker 5:  We got so much feed, like, so much feedback, including from a bunch
Speaker 5:  of people who like, were outraged at the idea that
Speaker 5:  not everyone uses AI for everything all the time. And I really actually appreciate
Speaker 5:  that. It was, it was very cool to go through and be like, oh, these are like
Speaker 5:  real people who use it in their real lives and not just like
Speaker 5:  somebody trying to convince me to give them billions of dollars.
Speaker 1:  Are you sure that Sam Altman wasn't outraged and not everybody's
Speaker 5:  Using ai? Do I think Sam Altman has a lot of burners and is in our inbox
Speaker 5:  on occasion? I I do think that, yeah,
Speaker 1:  He does have access to chat. Bt I'll say that. Sweet. We're gonna go
Speaker 1:  through all those. I think that's gonna be really fun. We got a lightning
Speaker 1:  round, but we gotta start, I think with the, the tech news.
Speaker 1:  It's the tech news and it's obviously that Microsoft is continuing to launch
Speaker 1:  Intel powered surface devices.
Speaker 1:  No, David?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. For 500 more dollars, you can have a surface
Speaker 5:  that has more words in the name and a chip you don't really want
Speaker 1:  And worse battery
Speaker 5:  Line. Congratulations. You did it.
Speaker 1:  There's something there. They, they did announce they're gonna do this. They
Speaker 1:  also announced that Microsoft is running DeepSeek now on copilot PCs
Speaker 1:  that run Qualcomm chips. We're gonna talk about DeepSeek in a second, but
Speaker 1:  it's just interesting that there's still,
Speaker 1:  Microsoft has to still carry Intel in this specific way because that
Speaker 1:  partnership is so long and so important to everyone. But it's like,
Speaker 1:  everything about Microsoft releasing new service devices has changed
Speaker 1:  in the past 18 months. Yeah. To where two years
Speaker 1:  ago they're like, here's some service devices with arm chips. I think the
Speaker 1:  reaction would be, eh, and now it's, here's some service devices
Speaker 1:  with Intel chips and it's like, oh man, you're still doing this. And that's
Speaker 1:  a big change.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it, it really did happen a really fast and B,
Speaker 5:  almost without anybody noticing, like, I feel like every step along the way
Speaker 5:  was also kind of meh, right? Like when that first round of
Speaker 5:  copilot p copilot plus PCs, still the worst name in
Speaker 5:  laptops came out. They they were
Speaker 5:  fine, right? Yeah. Like the overwhelming response was like, Qualcomm did
Speaker 5:  pretty good work here, but the emulation stuff is still pretty bad. The
Speaker 5:  performance isn't what we, it's like, it's just not, it's, it's fine.
Speaker 5:  And then somehow between there and here, we've flipped
Speaker 5:  all the way to, like you said, I see Intel Surface Pros and go, that's
Speaker 5:  not what anybody wants. Like, it's crazy,
Speaker 1:  But I don't, and I, to be clear, I don't think the arm powered chips are
Speaker 1:  doing everything yet. There's a, a reason to sell Intel powered laptops.
Speaker 1:  Lots of people are still buying Intel powered Windows PCs obviously. But
Speaker 1:  it's just interesting to see where the bleeding edge has gone to.
Speaker 1:  Like, it's obvious that that thing has runway and intel and you know,
Speaker 1:  along the way they did fire their CEO,
Speaker 5:  They did do
Speaker 1:  That. So maybe it's just vibes all the way down. That's not actually the
Speaker 1:  biggest news. That was a joke. A joke. And we ended up talking about it because
Speaker 1:  it's forecast. The big news is DeepSeek. Yeah. It has turned
Speaker 1:  the tech world upside down in just a very, the only way to describe, it's
Speaker 1:  a very bubbly way. Like everyone was over invested and
Speaker 1:  overhyping AI and then everyone overreacted to another AI tool.
Speaker 1:  What do you think, David?
Speaker 5:  So I actually think that's the right frame for it, because the more I've
Speaker 5:  learned about this, and the more I've talked to people about it, the more
Speaker 5:  I've come to believe there are sort of three
Speaker 5:  simultaneous things going on. On the one hand, there's the
Speaker 5:  stock market freak out, which is just a stock market freak out a bunch
Speaker 5:  of people, I would say like half correctly
Speaker 5:  understood what DeepSeek is and made a bunch of
Speaker 5:  weird semi thoughtful bets
Speaker 5:  against Nvidia as a result. And there's been some really interesting
Speaker 5:  reporting over the last few days that a big part of the selloff was triggered
Speaker 5:  by this one super deep, super thoughtful
Speaker 5:  blog post about somebody who was shorting Nvidia. And he, he like writes
Speaker 5:  this big thing and lands on short Nvidia, it has no moat.
Speaker 5:  This thing is not, this thing is massively overvalued,
Speaker 5:  got shared by a bunch of people in tech and in you can kind of argue that
Speaker 5:  that's what caused a lot of that. So on the one hand, there is just a
Speaker 5:  lot of money was lost very quickly. So a lot
Speaker 5:  of people got in a like CNBC tizzy about that, right? So that's like one
Speaker 5:  thing happening over here. The other thing is
Speaker 5:  very much a story about technology and, and
Speaker 5:  the actual questions of like, okay, how do we think about
Speaker 5:  what DeepSeek did here that is interesting and unique and how do we
Speaker 5:  think about open source AI being really at the bleeding edge? A lot of this
Speaker 5:  stuff and what did DeepSeek do that is interesting, that's gonna roll back
Speaker 5:  to some of these companies and what does it mean for OpenAI? That's all interesting
Speaker 5:  and I think we should spend most of our time talking about that. And then
Speaker 5:  there's a third thing, which is just China. It's just the China of it all.
Speaker 5:  And I think everybody sort of twists themselves
Speaker 5:  in knots about everything to do with China in part, for good reasons and
Speaker 5:  in part for bad reasons. But like coming off of all this stuff with
Speaker 5:  TikTok and Red Note and the, the ideas about
Speaker 5:  what these companies are collecting about us and what it means that there
Speaker 5:  is like technical leadership happening in those countries and like
Speaker 5:  everybody is just really spun up to have feelings about China.
Speaker 5:  And so there was a lot of feelings about China in their altogether.
Speaker 5:  So it just became this like perfect storm of, I think under
Speaker 5:  a couple of really small changes, this would've been like an
Speaker 5:  interesting story and not like the only thing anyone in my group chats cared
Speaker 5:  about all week. But because it was those three things together,
Speaker 5:  it became everything. Like my high school friends are talking about DeepSeek,
Speaker 5:  this has just been happening this week.
Speaker 1:  Well, once you turn the entire economy into gambling, which is
Speaker 1:  what we're doing, yeah. Everyone cares a lot about the gambling and to,
Speaker 1:  to like whatever you mentioned the CNBC of it all. Like most
Speaker 1:  people's retirement savings are like in big index funds. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Which are all just big tech stocks, right? And so it's like eight
Speaker 5:  Companies now,
Speaker 1:  Right? So when Nvidia goes down or Apple goes down or meta goes down, like
Speaker 1:  actually the whole economy kind of goes with them, which is not great. There's
Speaker 1:  a, there's a lot of reading and reporting you can do about that. That's not
Speaker 1:  what we care about here at The Verge, but it's just notable that that's why
Speaker 1:  it breaks through so often now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Oh, I agree. And I think in, in, in NVIDIA's case, I mean the, the
Speaker 5:  like, what people have been saying about Nvidia for months is that it has
Speaker 5:  essentially propped up the stock market on its own for a very long time now.
Speaker 5:  And it has gone through the roof. Like it's, it's grown like crazy. And so
Speaker 5:  yeah, everybody has been saying there is a bubble and just pointing
Speaker 5:  it Nvidia. By the way, total side note, one of the funniest things about
Speaker 5:  every time Nvidia is in the news is the number of different ways people pronounce
Speaker 5:  the name of that company. Yes. There's a lot of Nvidia happening like
Speaker 5:  Nvidia. Yes. Which I like. There's a lot of, we gotta
Speaker 1:  Got if VERGE has, listen, if you're paying attention to The Verge, there's
Speaker 1:  some of that floating around the bir lately. Listen, we're we're gonna fix
Speaker 1:  it.
Speaker 5:  The thing is, I'm not sure anybody's wrong, you know, who knows? It's, it's
Speaker 5:  nuclear and nuclear like, you know. No,
Speaker 1:  It's the, there's wait, hold on. But there's a, we we can't slide this far.
Speaker 1:  There's an answer. We're gonna, we're gonna clean it up. That's all I'm saying.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So it's like we agree that you, you would pronounce it like Nvidia,
Speaker 5:  like there's a sort of silent, there's an I at the beginning, right? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like a, like a gentle I
Speaker 1:  Nvidia has, their name is so stupid that they have pronunciation
Speaker 1:  guidelines online. Do
Speaker 5:  They really?
Speaker 1:  Yeah, they have for years. Years and years and years. It doesn't matter because
Speaker 1:  like the CNBC people will just say in Nvidia,
Speaker 5:  But also Nvidia might be the company that most violates my theory that you
Speaker 5:  can't overcome a stupid company name. Mm. And it's a stupid company name.
Speaker 5:  It's hard to pronounce. It doesn't mean anything. It has nothing. It's just,
Speaker 5:  it's, it's just like an Amazon brand of letters that they happen
Speaker 5:  to turn into. Oh that's,
Speaker 1:  That's one of the biggest companies on our Oh, that's rough. But it's good.
Speaker 1:  That's a rough chuckle. That's really good. I bought this Nvidia battery
Speaker 1:  bank. That's what I'm saying, $39 with a 10% coupon code.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like in a parallel universe, you green makes all of the GPUs that people
Speaker 5:  buy in the world. And this is where we are. But yeah, so the the,
Speaker 5:  the money of it is, is real. And I think to the extent that it's also tied
Speaker 5:  up in all of this other stuff, it, it's, that's important. But to me that
Speaker 5:  is actually like, that is the thing people got most sort of
Speaker 5:  bent outta shape about and took it to mean that there is all this other
Speaker 5:  equally important stuff happening in these other ways like with the tech
Speaker 5:  itself. And the more I learn about it, the less I feel like that's actually
Speaker 5:  the case.
Speaker 1:  So I keep making that comparison to Bluetooth with ai. It's
Speaker 1:  just, it's just my go-to. You know, you've
Speaker 5:  Been doing that a lot recently. Every, you compare a lot of things to Bluetooth
Speaker 1:  Recently. Everything is Bluetooth,
Speaker 1:  right? Like we had to, you don't remember this when we
Speaker 5:  Do it first cast coffee table book, by the way, that's the title, just throwing
Speaker 5:  that
Speaker 1:  Everything is Bluetooth. Everything is Bluetooth. When, when Bluetooth first
Speaker 1:  hit the scene, they were so proud of themselves and they're like,
Speaker 1:  we, everything is gonna be Bluetooth, Bluetooth is gonna change the economy.
Speaker 1:  They were, they, they were out here talking about personal area networks
Speaker 1:  or pans. Oh yeah, I, I wrote a lot of blog posts in gadget about
Speaker 1:  personal area networks. How's your pan doing? This is awesome dude.
Speaker 1:  It's my Apple watch and my hair fox.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 1:  My pants crush. This is a real thing that was gonna happen, right? Like the,
Speaker 1:  we were gonna blow up the world with Bluetooth and then the
Speaker 1:  actual in products didn't ma match the investment for years.
Speaker 1:  And so like, it's a, just a good comparison. FI 5G actually is
Speaker 1:  another great comparison. We were in a race for that you will recall.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Just to what? To what finish line. No one knew the
Speaker 1:  answer. Robot surgery
Speaker 1:  seems unlikely. Autonomous cars there, there's some of 'em driving
Speaker 1:  around. Sure, sure. But like that was the big imp
Speaker 1:  and you will also, with 5G you'll call, we had to beat China because
Speaker 1:  if China got 5G networks, first America
Speaker 1:  was done. Right? You can't, can't have it.
Speaker 5:  Which is very much what people are saying about AI right now.
Speaker 1:  Right? It all just tracks like the, the, these things rhyme, right?
Speaker 1:  The difference is when at and t and Verizon spent
Speaker 1:  billions of dollars to build 5G networks against whatever hype
Speaker 1:  and whatever graft, they at least knew they were gonna sell people cell
Speaker 1:  phones and cell service true at numbers that people
Speaker 1:  were willing to pay, right? And the people who put Bluetooth everywhere,
Speaker 1:  they didn't know that there would be AirPods, but they could imagine
Speaker 1:  AirPods and they were like, one day there will be AirPods and then
Speaker 1:  eventually Apple invented AirPods. But they had
Speaker 5:  This, yeah, you could get all the things with wires and be like, what if
Speaker 5:  no wires and like that, that worked, right? You could, you could see how
Speaker 5:  you'd get there.
Speaker 1:  But with AI we just keep, we're like, what if it bangs you?
Speaker 1:  Is that worth $5 billion? For some people the answer is
Speaker 1:  decidedly yes. We're like, what if it's agents and it does some clicking
Speaker 1:  around the web for you? What if the rabbit R one is great? What if the humane
Speaker 1:  pin is great to quote David Pierce, is this a thing? And there's not
Speaker 1:  the, there's not the finish line, right? Right. Where everyone's gonna pay
Speaker 1:  all of the money for the products that justifies all of the investment.
Speaker 1:  And I think my version of the DeepSeek story is like,
Speaker 1:  it just showed that all of this big upfront investment
Speaker 1:  maybe isn't necessary.
Speaker 1:  And so meta doing dick measuring by
Speaker 1:  how many Nvidia GPUs it was buying kind of is like are, wait, are you
Speaker 1:  just wasting money? Like is there, is there an end result
Speaker 1:  to this or can or can you just do it much more cheaply now? And I don't
Speaker 1:  like, I don't know the answer to that, the, these questions because I don't
Speaker 1:  think anybody has really delivered a product
Speaker 1:  that is gonna pay it all back
Speaker 5:  In the context of DeepSeek. That conversation has been super interesting
Speaker 5:  this week because like the, the,
Speaker 5:  for all of this being good news for the, the
Speaker 5:  Mark Zuckerberg, you know, talking about the size of his data center
Speaker 5:  of the world is, okay, I lemme see if I can explain
Speaker 5:  how the theory goes. The theory goes like this, If you make
Speaker 5:  AI cheaper to make two things will happen. One,
Speaker 5:  you'll be able to make better AI for the same price. So you get the, the
Speaker 5:  performance scale goes up, right? I can now make something
Speaker 5:  50% better for the same price as I was planning to do it before. So
Speaker 5:  thus good ai then all the stuff that I've already been doing
Speaker 5:  gets cheaper. So it becomes more accessible to more people who use it
Speaker 5:  for more things, thus also better. So it's like thi this flywheel of,
Speaker 5:  of scaling is what everybody is very excited. Dario Amay, the CEO of
Speaker 5:  Anthropic made essentially that argument, right? That now, because all
Speaker 5:  this stuff is getting cheaper, and this has been happening for a while. Like
Speaker 5:  DeepSeek didn't invent making AI cheaper to run like this has been happening
Speaker 5:  for a while.
Speaker 1:  One of the very first Google iOS in this whole AI tumult like two years
Speaker 1:  ago, literally Sindar Phai was saying the thing that we're best
Speaker 1:  at is making things cheaper,
Speaker 5:  Right? And so, so now what you're thinking is like, okay, if you're Sam Altman,
Speaker 5:  instead of spending $10 billion to do
Speaker 5:  this thing, I can spend $10 billion to do the next thing. Right?
Speaker 5:  I can, I can make the thing that I'm working on with all this money, 50%
Speaker 5:  better. But what
Speaker 1:  Is he making?
Speaker 5:  This is what I'm saying. So all I I actually buy that theory, right? Like
Speaker 5:  the, the, it, it all makes sense, but the question continues to be what are
Speaker 5:  we laddering all of this up to? What is the pot of gold at the end of this
Speaker 5:  rainbow? And the, my favorite thing that happened this week was did you read
Speaker 5:  Reid Hoffman's New York Times opinion essay that everybody
Speaker 5:  was dunking on all week? Yes. Can I just read out loud two paragraphs from
Speaker 5:  it please. He says, imagine AI models that are trained on comprehensive
Speaker 5:  collections of your own digital activities and behaviors. This kind of AI
Speaker 5:  could possess total recall of your Venmo transactions and Instagram likes
Speaker 5:  and Google calendar appointments. The more you choose to share, the more
Speaker 5:  this AI would be able to identify patterns in your life and surface insights
Speaker 5:  that you may find useful decades from now. As you try to remember exactly
Speaker 5:  what sequence of events and life circumstances made you finally decide to
Speaker 5:  go all in on Bitcoin. Your AI could develop an informed hypothesis based
Speaker 5:  on a detailed record of your status updates, invites dms and other potentially
Speaker 5:  enduring ephemera that we're often barely aware of as we create them much
Speaker 5:  less days, months, or years after the fact. This is Reid Hoffman writing
Speaker 5:  about how AI is going to make humanity better. And the best use case
Speaker 5:  can dream about is it's gonna tell you
Speaker 5:  which DM made you wanna buy into Bitcoin. Like
Speaker 5:  what, what's the plan here? Like, and, and now, and
Speaker 5:  I I I've been thinking about this a lot with the questions of like, okay,
Speaker 5:  well then if all these companies don't need this much money, why are they
Speaker 5:  raising all this much money? And it's like, well, 'cause money's good to
Speaker 5:  have and you should, If you can raise it, you might as well. And so Sam
Speaker 5:  Altman is out there raising unheard of amounts of money and there are reports
Speaker 5:  that they're about to raise anywhere from 15 to 25 billion more dollars
Speaker 5:  now. Like Sam Altman is as
Speaker 5:  good a fundraiser as we have ever had in this industry. And so he's gonna
Speaker 5:  go out and raise money. But it turns out I'm not sure anyone knows
Speaker 5:  what we're building towards anymore. And I'm less and less sure every day
Speaker 5:  that people know what the answer is to what problem they are solving with
Speaker 5:  ai. So we're in this place where like DeepSeek is very interesting in
Speaker 5:  that it is going to make, it is going to help make a lot of this stuff easier
Speaker 5:  and cheaper to make. The fact that it's open source I actually think is on
Speaker 5:  balance. Very cool. There are scary things
Speaker 5:  about open source ai, but whatever, I think by and large, I this stuff should
Speaker 5:  be in the open and not in the hands of three companies.
Speaker 5:  It's going to change the way that this stuff gets developed. People are going
Speaker 5:  to like take the things that DeepSeek did, bring it in, make it
Speaker 5:  better, the whole industry will get better. And to what end has not become
Speaker 5:  any clearer at all.
Speaker 1:  You know, it's funny, the Reid Hoffen thing, I read that too in, you
Speaker 1:  know, like you do in Trump administrations, I I spend a, I've been spending
Speaker 1:  a lot of time think about the inner lives of rich, rich men.
Speaker 1:  Sure. Like very rich men. What do they, what do they want from me?
Speaker 1:  Because they seem to be in charge of everything. And it's just like dude
Speaker 1:  wants a friend. Like I don't, I think a lot of these guys don't have
Speaker 1:  all their relationships are just people who want things from that, right?
Speaker 1:  And so when they're like, what, what could this robot be for me? They just
Speaker 1:  imagine just a friend who's known them since kindergarten.
Speaker 5:  But then do you think there's also a little part of them that's like, wants
Speaker 5:  their AI friend to know how rich they are? Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Oh
Speaker 5:  Absolutely. They're like, why don't you think my ideas are good? I don't,
Speaker 5:  I don't want your ideas Ai I want you to like my ideas.
Speaker 1:  I just think I, if I have a piece of life advice for everybody listening,
Speaker 1:  it's like you should have some non-transactional relationships in your life
Speaker 1:  with people who just like, like you and you like them and that's it. Like
Speaker 1:  you're not trying to buy and sell That's right. Everything, yeah. All the
Speaker 1:  time. That might be good for humanity. I always think about Steve Jobs,
Speaker 1:  you know, he would end all the keynotes with like apples at the intersection
Speaker 1:  of liberal arts and technology and like, these dudes are like,
Speaker 1:  fuck the liberal arts.
Speaker 1:  It's like, no, that's the the important thing. Like that's why that, that's
Speaker 1:  why that company is important. 'cause they, they like care about culture.
Speaker 1:  They're like the the computers are to make art with,
Speaker 5:  That's why they can't make AI for shit though.
Speaker 1:  But that's, that's so funny. Like I, I dunno what Steve Jobs thought about
Speaker 1:  ai, but it's like, you look at the output and it's like, it's
Speaker 1:  pretty bad and it's like, is this good? Like is this, do you wanna
Speaker 1:  make more stuff with this? Right? I will say DeepSeek,
Speaker 1:  there's some copy going around that it had written about like the nature
Speaker 1:  of tools, which is a very VERGE thing to write about. Dieter made an entire
Speaker 1:  video about whether or not computers or tools or instruments once amount
Speaker 1:  of time. It was like pretty good, you know, it's like not great,
Speaker 1:  but that it had some bangers in there, you know,
Speaker 5:  It, it didn't sound like chat GPT, which I mean is a compliment right there.
Speaker 5:  Is this like, yeah, I think we're all kind of learning how to
Speaker 5:  sense when something is written by ai and it didn't sound like that.
Speaker 5:  It was weird and kind of overdone and overwrought and it was very much
Speaker 5:  like a overly pretentious college sophomore writing a paper
Speaker 5:  for their English class. But like that's a lot better than chat gt
Speaker 5:  so I'll take it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's not like a, a receptionist who's kind of annoyed that you're there,
Speaker 1:  which is chat GT's default tone. Like I'll be so corporate that you will
Speaker 1:  go away is kind of how Chad p writes. But I just think that's like
Speaker 1:  very fascinating. Like what are these, what is this tool for? And the first
Speaker 1:  answer with the image generators was art, right? And then the
Speaker 1:  second answer was the chat bots will write me 10 more episodes of
Speaker 1:  Seinfeld and then it was like, they'll kill Hollywood. And then we just kind
Speaker 1:  of like brought it all the way down to like, it'll be a friend that'll, that'll
Speaker 1:  book an Uber for you and maybe buy a sandwich. And it's like, this is a
Speaker 1:  really small vision at the end of the day, just as we're talking,
Speaker 1:  I think you, you just kind of mentioned it, David, open eyes like in talks
Speaker 1:  to raise more money at a $340 billion
Speaker 1:  valuation. This is right on top of them announcing
Speaker 1:  $500 billion to do Stargate, which is not real,
Speaker 1:  right? That's the most like Trump talk about Trump administration staying
Speaker 1:  in the White House announcing a project that you're not gonna build as like
Speaker 1:  the heart of the Trump administration experience.
Speaker 5:  It's a giant novelty check. Like it really is. Yeah. That, that whole thing
Speaker 5:  was a giant novelty check for $500 billion. Like sure,
Speaker 1:  But the reality check on this whole industry right now is you're spending
Speaker 1:  all this money 'cause no one was stopping you, everyone wanted
Speaker 1:  crypto to be it and crypto wasn't it? So then maybe I'll be it. And
Speaker 1:  because it can do something as opposed to crypto,
Speaker 1:  like all the big companies are like, look at this new thing our our phones
Speaker 1:  can do. It's Apple intelligence. Like, great,
Speaker 1:  but it hasn't done enough yet. And then Deepsea
Speaker 1:  comes along and they're doing it for way cheaper and
Speaker 1:  I still don't think it's good enough, but it's so much cheaper that it's
Speaker 1:  like wiping out this like investment thesis that you need all of the
Speaker 1:  money to make a friend,
Speaker 5:  Right? And again, it goes back to the thing of you have to start to
Speaker 5:  explain to people what you're making. And I think like the this,
Speaker 5:  this, this we are making God thing isn't
Speaker 5:  gonna work forever. It's already starting to come unwound. Like a thing I've
Speaker 5:  really noticed is
Speaker 5:  as Sam Altman and others have started to pull back on
Speaker 5:  what they claim a GI is this idea that
Speaker 5:  we are like marching towards a singularity where these things are going to
Speaker 5:  be as good as humans at everything is like
Speaker 5:  getting more nebulous and weird. And so like if
Speaker 5:  anything, the goal posts are getting fuzzier for these companies,
Speaker 5:  not more clear. And so it's, it's wild that
Speaker 5:  it continues to be this frothy when it feels
Speaker 5:  less and less like anybody has any idea what they're going towards here
Speaker 5:  except it will reinvent the economy.
Speaker 5:  And that's what you have to say because that's the only way to raise 25 billion
Speaker 5:  more dollars is to claim you are going to change the way that people live
Speaker 5:  their lives. And like that's how Adam Neuman convinced
Speaker 5:  Masa Stone to give him a lot of money. And that went super great for WeWork
Speaker 5:  and we're just, we're just doing it again at even more scale now.
Speaker 1:  It is notable that SoftBank is investing into at large
Speaker 1:  valuations. It's also notable that, you know, Sam Altman is, you know, making
Speaker 1:  videos where he is saying AI will require us to renegotiate a social
Speaker 1:  contract. And Mark Andreessen is like, absolutely not. And then in the next
Speaker 1:  breath, mark Andreessen is tweeting, like imagine a world in which wages
Speaker 1:  go to zero and everything is free. And it's like, well that's renegotiating
Speaker 1:  the social contract mark. Yeah. I don't what are you talking like that you're
Speaker 5:  Also, none of that is going to, I cannot say clearly enough. None of that
Speaker 5:  is going to happen. It's just not like some if,
Speaker 5:  if, if that does happen, play this clip for me and I will be suitably
Speaker 5:  embarrassed as I sit on the yacht that I got for free because of ai. Like,
Speaker 5:  this is not going to happen. And so, and until then it's like, okay,
Speaker 5:  sure, let's work backwards from reshape the way humans live our lives.
Speaker 5:  What's the, what's the first killer app that you're
Speaker 5:  gonna, like, what are you gonna make for me that is great that I like and
Speaker 5:  use all the time.
Speaker 1:  It's, it's Apple intelligence too. God, you can, you can summarize
Speaker 1:  any email you want at the click of a button.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 1:  I saw a a, an unnamed big tech executive and
Speaker 1:  I just said the words Apple intelligence and we just started laughing.
Speaker 5:  I think that's right.
Speaker 1:  That was basically where, where they were at with it. There are two other
Speaker 1:  funny parts of the DeepSeek story. Interesting, but funny
Speaker 1:  one is that DeepSeek is the result of,
Speaker 1:  you know, Biden administration policies to restrict chips in China.
Speaker 1:  And so it really feels like a, a bunch of US AI researchers
Speaker 1:  got lazy and they were not optimizing their code enough.
Speaker 1:  And the Chinese researchers with H 800 chips, which
Speaker 1:  are nerfed H one hundreds over-optimize
Speaker 1:  those chips to get better results than the H one hundreds, which is
Speaker 1:  just a like a classic of computers story, right?
Speaker 1:  Yes. Like you start out with 64 kilobytes of Ram and you just like worked
Speaker 1:  your way up from there and then the old head programmers are like, these
Speaker 1:  kids today are wasted cycles on animations. Like it's all,
Speaker 1:  it's it's just there. It it's the same story.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I don't know if it's laziness. I think, I mean there's, there's certainly
Speaker 5:  some laziness they were
Speaker 1:  Counting on an infinite supply of processing power. Right? Right.
Speaker 5:  But that's like, it's, it's, you know, what is it? Constraints breed creativity.
Speaker 5:  Like yeah, there is something to that. But I also think, I don't know that
Speaker 5:  they were sitting around being like, well we don't have to try hard because
Speaker 5:  the chips will do it for us. Actually, now that I say that I do, I I know
Speaker 5:  for sure they were kind of doing that. See what I'm saying? Yeah, no, you're
Speaker 5:  right. Once
Speaker 1:  You worked it all way out, you're like, oh, they didn't, they were just like,
Speaker 1:  we'll just buy more chips like Sam, get more money and buy more chips. Right.
Speaker 1:  There
Speaker 5:  Was, there was a brute forcing to this problem that everyone
Speaker 5:  just assumed was going to be how we get better was that like, and
Speaker 5:  they've been making changes to the foundational technology and like transformers
Speaker 5:  are better than they were in 20, 20 17 when people started talking about
Speaker 5:  this stuff. Like they're doing that, but nobody
Speaker 5:  at these companies spent a lot of time thinking about how do I do this on
Speaker 5:  worse chips because they just had the good chips.
Speaker 1:  Right. That's true. And you know, the, you know, a month ago we were talking
Speaker 1:  about scaling laws. I'm like, can you just throw more horsepower and more
Speaker 1:  data at this problem to make the models more efficient? And the answer was
Speaker 1:  like, kind of no. Right. And that might have been when the bottom should
Speaker 1:  have fallen out of all these stock prices. Yeah. 'cause that answer was no
Speaker 1:  then this moment was coming inevitably. Well,
Speaker 5:  But then what they all did in response was say, okay, well we're, we're running
Speaker 5:  into walls with our, you know, frontier models at these
Speaker 5:  unbelievably huge things. GPT five is reportedly not
Speaker 5:  what OpenAI wanted it to be. Like, nobody can find kind of the next
Speaker 5:  huge turn. And then they were like, but if we do even
Speaker 5:  bigger data centers,
Speaker 1:  And
Speaker 5:  It's, it's the same thing to your point. It wasn't like, let's go back down
Speaker 5:  to the metal here and figure out like from first
Speaker 5:  principles how to do this. It was what if we throw even more chips at it?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Which is how you get Nvidia.
Speaker 1:  Which is, and, and, and very much like in, you know, and in Liz and I have
Speaker 1:  been talking about parts of the Nvidia story for a while now. I think she's
Speaker 1:  even written it up. Like there are startups that are financing their
Speaker 1:  purchase of Nvidia chips with the Nvidia chips is the collateral on the loan.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Because their assumption is that there will be so much demand for usage,
Speaker 1:  they'll be able to just like make it work. And it's like, that's a little,
Speaker 1:  that's got some NFT vibes to it. You know what I'm seriously?
Speaker 1:  And you just see, okay, well they didn't, the Biden administration
Speaker 1:  put restrictions on the chips we could sell in China. And the
Speaker 1:  Chinese researchers at DeepSeek were able to
Speaker 1:  ultra optimize those chips in a way that US engineers
Speaker 1:  and researchers had no incentive to do. And then this is so that's funny,
Speaker 1:  right? That's like a unintended consequence of a restriction.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. That like fine, like it's funny
Speaker 1:  in the sense that like trying to Nerf the Chinese AI market
Speaker 1:  ended up tanking the US stock market. Weird. It's pretty good.
Speaker 1:  That's not what you want there. And then the second extremely funny
Speaker 1:  part is this idea of distillation
Speaker 1:  where part of DeepSeek was trained by just like ripping off open AI models
Speaker 1:  in various ways. That's pretty cool. And like, you know, Sam Alman is like
Speaker 1:  a little bit outraged by it and it's like, Sam, you stole the entire internet.
Speaker 1:  Everyone's so mad at you. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I mean DeepSeek is, is apparently was built on top of
Speaker 5:  llama meta's model and used vast quantities
Speaker 5:  of output from chat GPT to train itself, which
Speaker 5:  is just, it's just perfect. Like, it's just if every single stereotype you
Speaker 5:  wanna believe about the AI industry, every single stereotype you wanna believe
Speaker 5:  about China, like it's all right there. It's great. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And at least meta to its credit is like, yeah, we made the model open source.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like that's what it's here for. Yeah. Like, you know, open,
Speaker 1:  but the open eye making noises that like they have evidence that this was
Speaker 1:  and it's like, yeah, who cares?
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Like, don't know they broke your terms of service.
Speaker 1:  How awful. Lot of evidence about you my friends. Like, you know, what else
Speaker 1:  should take the bottom out of the AI industry losing the number of copier
Speaker 1:  lawsuits that you are currently engaged in. Yep. I feel like I need to disclose
Speaker 1:  at this time that Fox Media has signed some kind of licensing deal with
Speaker 1:  open AI to make our stuff show up, show up and search GPT. And
Speaker 1:  honestly no one uses it, so it's fine. It
Speaker 5:  Seems right.
Speaker 1:  That's way above our heads. But there it is. There's a disclosure.
Speaker 5:  They just turned Gemini on for our Google workspace. That's a thing that
Speaker 5:  happened this week. Disclosure,
Speaker 1:  We had to have a meeting trying to turn it off and keeping our data
Speaker 1:  inside our own house, even that Right. We're gonna take a big bite outta
Speaker 1:  the search market and knock Google off it like it hasn't played out.
Speaker 1:  And that's the biggest identifiable market so far. Right? You
Speaker 1:  will ask the robot questions and it'll deliver you answers. Right. We're
Speaker 1:  gonna make Google dance all of that to I that doesn't seem to have
Speaker 1:  played out.
Speaker 5:  No, and I think that's, it's why everybody's betting so big on agents, right?
Speaker 5:  It's like, okay, somewhere between we're gonna take a cut of
Speaker 5:  your DoorDash order and we are going to be the payments
Speaker 5:  processor is like, that's the idea. Everybody has had like, I think
Speaker 5:  it was you that said to me at one point on the show that everybody's business
Speaker 5:  model ultimately is just payments processing. Like it's really, it's really
Speaker 5:  extremely true. Yeah. Everybody is just desperately trying to do payments
Speaker 5:  processing, including now x this week, which we can talk about. But
Speaker 5:  the, the, these ideas just aren't working like it is true. And we're gonna
Speaker 5:  talk about a lot of the stuff that people are doing with these tools.
Speaker 5:  It is true that people like using these tools and that that is a meaningful
Speaker 5:  thing. But the question of what are they
Speaker 5:  for? And maybe even more importantly, what is the business here?
Speaker 5:  Super duper unknown. Like it's, it's important to keep reminding you that
Speaker 5:  the bigger open AI gets, the more money it loses and that
Speaker 5:  continues to be true. And like there was like the Uber thing
Speaker 5:  that was like, you know, when when we win we will, we'll take over and we'll
Speaker 5:  raise our prices. And like they, they did win, they did raise their prices.
Speaker 5:  They had to retrench in like a huge way and now they're making
Speaker 5:  this much money. Yeah. That's not coming for any of these AI companies
Speaker 5:  Anytime soon, no matter how many billions of dollars you raise, it's just
Speaker 5:  not coming.
Speaker 1:  Right. 'cause they, their product isn't as useful as when you push a button
Speaker 1:  a Toyota Highlander shows up. Right?
Speaker 5:  Right. And it's, it's being commoditized even faster than that.
Speaker 5:  Like the, the thing everybody was worried about, about Uber 12 years ago
Speaker 5:  was robo taxis are gonna come and just end, just throw all this into chaos
Speaker 5:  that's happening in the AI world. Like all this stuff, whatever you build
Speaker 5:  as an AI model company is going to be copied
Speaker 5:  and bested like immediately by six other companies.
Speaker 5:  And this is, this is just what we're seeing.
Speaker 1:  So let me ask you this.
Speaker 1:  Microsoft had earnings this week. They're, they're doing, they're doing fine.
Speaker 1:  But you know, it seems like the Microsoft Open AI relationship has, has been
Speaker 1:  rocky for a minute. Yep. You know, they were like part of the Stargate announcement,
Speaker 1:  not really part of the Stargate announcement that was mostly funded by Oracle
Speaker 1:  and SoftBank, Nadela was asked about
Speaker 1:  $500 billion and he is like, we've already committed $80 billion to Azure
Speaker 1:  build outs and I'm good for my 80 billion. And we just like wouldn't talk
Speaker 1:  about Stargate. Yep. And then this week, Altman and Nadella, they Altman
Speaker 1:  post a selfie of the two of them. So the next chapter of this relationship
Speaker 1:  is gonna be great. But, but then they, the companies had also announced that
Speaker 1:  like Microsoft's deal basically goes until 2030.
Speaker 1:  I can't tell what's going on with these two companies right now. And especially
Speaker 1:  he posted that after DeepSeek and after Nadella is trying to
Speaker 1:  calm down the market by talking about Jevons Paradox, which is what you're
Speaker 1:  describing where you make the thing cheaper so people use it more.
Speaker 1:  What is going on with these two companies?
Speaker 5:  I I think it's as simple as they are.
Speaker 5:  It it they're sort of in a mutually assured destruction thing where like
Speaker 5:  Microsoft benefits so much from open AI being
Speaker 5:  a huge success because it has these agreements for the all the
Speaker 5:  cloud stuff that's happening because it's such a huge investor in the company.
Speaker 5:  Like as OpenAI gets bigger, it uses more Azure,
Speaker 5:  which is more money for Microsoft. Like Microsoft literally wins coming and
Speaker 5:  going when it comes to open ai. So if I'm Satya Nadella,
Speaker 5:  it makes sense to be doing both of these things. You both want to shore
Speaker 5:  this stuff up in house in case this company implodes in some
Speaker 5:  meaningful way, which a, it has already done once and B
Speaker 5:  could just happen again. Like I, the the people
Speaker 5:  a lot this week have been talking about the fact that most of open AI's
Speaker 5:  co-founders aren't there anymore. There are many litigious people circling
Speaker 5:  around this company. There are lawsuits circling like OpenAI is both
Speaker 5:  absolutely chockfull of money and like pretty fragile in a lot of ways. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So I think if you're Sacie Nadella, you're like, okay, I I need to
Speaker 5:  not be fully reliant on it, but I also am going to make so much
Speaker 5:  money from OpenAI if it hits that it's,
Speaker 5:  it's worth a selfie and like a nice tweet a couple of times a year. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Like that's a pretty low risk way to at least keep the peace enough
Speaker 5:  that open. Nobody gets super nervous about open
Speaker 1:  Like so one selfie. Yeah. Like he's got a chart in his office. It's like
Speaker 1:  options one selfie. Right. Invest
Speaker 1:  $200 billion. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Leak phone call to Sam. Like Yeah. Be caught
Speaker 5:  Having lunch with Sam at Sweet Green is like
Speaker 5:  $200 billion. Like it's, I I really, I think, I think these companies hate
Speaker 5:  each other and I think they know it's better to be stuck
Speaker 5:  together for a while. Yeah. And to root for each other because it will be
Speaker 5:  successful for everybody. But I think they will be in, in they,
Speaker 5:  I think Sam and Satya both go home at the end of day and like throw
Speaker 5:  darts at a, at a the other person's
Speaker 1:  Face. The really interesting thing is, you know, Microsoft's core
Speaker 1:  business is Azure, like in the realist way.
Speaker 1:  Azure's doing great, you know, their earnings are out. There are
Speaker 1:  parts of the Azure business that are like different than the others. Like
Speaker 1:  their new customers are not signing up for ai, they're just signing up to
Speaker 1:  be cloud customers. And they kind of announced during the earning call like,
Speaker 1:  yeah, we, we stopped trying to do that. Like we're we're back to just trying
Speaker 1:  to get cloud customers. Yeah. I mean
Speaker 5:  That's what that, that has happened in a real way like that that's actually
Speaker 5:  been a big moment that both Microsoft and Google were like, okay, we're gonna
Speaker 5:  charge $20 a month extra on top of the normal like
Speaker 5:  workspace or office subscription and you're gonna get all the AI stuff
Speaker 5:  and people didn't like $20 per month per person for
Speaker 5:  nebulous AI features. Turned out to be an awful lot to ask. And
Speaker 5:  these companies, like you said, they need more cloud customers and they need
Speaker 5:  people to use the AI in order for the AI to get any good. And so they
Speaker 5:  have just walked it all the way back and what they want is they
Speaker 5:  want you to use their tools that make them money and then they wanna
Speaker 5:  shove AI at you so that you use it and maybe someday we'll pay for it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. We'll see how that goes. But that's like a really
Speaker 1:  interesting piece that Microsoft is at least reselling whatever capability
Speaker 1:  it has. Google's reselling it, Amazon is reselling it in Nvidia
Speaker 1:  sells the chips and then they, you know, like Jensen Flash on the world on
Speaker 1:  is jet made of money. Meta is really interesting in here. 'cause they're
Speaker 1:  the only ones who don't resell the capacity. They're, they are buying all
Speaker 1:  the GPUs. They're building the huge data center the size of Manhattan like
Speaker 1:  crazy. But they sell none of it. It's all for meta
Speaker 1:  and either that's a lot of risk, right. They have to get the value out of
Speaker 1:  it or they figured it out and in their
Speaker 1:  earnings,
Speaker 1:  this isn't great, I don't love it, but they're like, we are, we've increased
Speaker 1:  ad targeting yield by sorting through all of the ads. We can show
Speaker 1:  people faster and that's what the GPUs are for. And it's like,
Speaker 1:  oh they actually figured it out. They know why they're spending
Speaker 1:  the money. They're not just trying to resell capacity to somebody who's gonna
Speaker 1:  make a killer app or
Speaker 1:  assuming that they can make Digital co Yeah. They're like, oh, there's a
Speaker 1:  thing we do with this that actually goes faster because we're doing it.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I mean the killer app for AI might be ad targeting.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Which is terrifying. Like, I, I wanna be clear. That sucks. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And, and Meta would love for you to not think about that and instead think
Speaker 5:  about smart glasses. But like Meta is building those data
Speaker 5:  centers to serve you better ads, not to
Speaker 5:  like let you wear glasses on your face if they can do all that
Speaker 5:  stuff. Terrific. But the business case for that Manhattan sized data
Speaker 5:  center is advertising. Yeah. And I think that's, that's what is happening
Speaker 5:  across the board. It's true for Google, it's true for a lot of these companies.
Speaker 5:  Like ads are going to be how a lot of
Speaker 5:  these things support themselves in a way that I think people are not yet
Speaker 5:  ready for
Speaker 1:  In and in the case of Meta and Google specifically, they have already started
Speaker 1:  down this road where the end result is you're
Speaker 1:  some advertiser and you just type in who you want to
Speaker 1:  reach and you put in the first version of your ad and then
Speaker 1:  it makes infinite variations of that ad targeted at
Speaker 1:  specific people. So everyone is seeing their own ad. Right. And that's what
Speaker 1:  the generative AI is for. And this is either good or bad, you know, like
Speaker 1:  it's bad, but,
Speaker 1:  but like, you know, from those company's perspective, they're,
Speaker 1:  they might spend less money in advertising but meta might make more because
Speaker 1:  they're showing more ads that convert more clicks and purchases. And you
Speaker 1:  can just see how you get to this is all good. And then you can also see how
Speaker 1:  the user experience of the platforms will go to hell
Speaker 1:  because they're gonna be just choked to death with AI slop.
Speaker 1:  Yep. And extremely weird AI ads and it's already happening. Like
Speaker 1:  I don't want to pretend, I don't wanna be like, this is some
Speaker 1:  like vaporware idea. Like TikTok has some of this capability in their
Speaker 1:  adec today. Meta and Google are already
Speaker 1:  saying to creators, let people chat with AI avatars of yourself. Yep. Like
Speaker 1:  they are training the user base to see AI
Speaker 1:  content and think of it as the regular part of the user experience. And then
Speaker 1:  it's just, it's just one turn to Hey Ford, give us
Speaker 1:  a bunch of money and we'll have infinite ad for
Speaker 1:  explorers that like we know everything about this person and
Speaker 1:  we'll be like, Hey, we saw that you bought a lot of stuff at the store today
Speaker 1:  that would fit better in a Ford Explorer. Like down to that level of
Speaker 1:  targeting.
Speaker 5:  Or it'll show me the color of Ford Explorer that I'm most likely
Speaker 5:  to like in the setting that is most likely to make me wanna buy it because
Speaker 5:  that is data that these companies have. Like Yeah. It's, it's gonna get
Speaker 5:  really weird. And I think the, the like uncanny value of
Speaker 5:  targeted advertising is about to be explored in a really fascinating way.
Speaker 5:  I will say one of the funniest things about this is that it is going to make
Speaker 5:  Amazon look even stupider because Amazon still does the ad where
Speaker 5:  you're like, I buy a hat on Amazon and then for six months Amazon's ads are
Speaker 5:  just like, do you wanna buy that exact hat that you already bought? Yeah.
Speaker 5:  How about a hat? Do you like hats? Here's a hat. And I'm like,
Speaker 5:  and it's just like Amazon. If, if AI can fix that,
Speaker 5:  I'm in Gimme ai
Speaker 1:  Just boil, just stop with the boil the ocean. Yeah. Take this hat away from
Speaker 1:  me. I it's weird. Look, okay. We've done enough negativity around
Speaker 1:  ai. I do think that this thing is a bubble and it has popped
Speaker 1:  to some extent and it might bubble again, but
Speaker 1:  there's just, I don't, it's not just DeepSeek,
Speaker 1:  it's the products. It's I'll I'm gonna compare it to, to
Speaker 1:  cell networks again. 'cause it, this is just, this is just the world I was
Speaker 1:  raised in. The money we spent on LTE was
Speaker 1:  good. Like If you, If you, we have a lot of newer
Speaker 1:  listeners, but If you are with here with us from the beginning, you'll
Speaker 1:  remember that the iPhone getting LTE was a big deal. Yeah. Right. And
Speaker 1:  the iPhone launching without 3G was like a, a legitimate criticism
Speaker 1:  of the product at that time. It had edge, it had two g networking, it was
Speaker 1:  too slow and putting wifi in it was the big, like the big
Speaker 1:  innovation. This is all impossible to think about right now. Yeah. But the,
Speaker 1:  when the iPhone got 3G, that was a big, big deal
Speaker 1:  because it meant that it could access the internet faster and was usable
Speaker 1:  on the go as an internet device when it got LTE that meant it
Speaker 1:  could do video and that's when a bunch of mobile video like took off
Speaker 1:  and like became a thing when it got 5G
Speaker 1:  everyone was like, that's gonna happen again. Right. And it
Speaker 5:  Just didn't, it didn't,
Speaker 1:  It super didn't.
Speaker 5:  What is this for is a question people should ask much more often
Speaker 5:  about technology. I will say, I just wanna say one
Speaker 5:  nice thing about DeepSeek and then we should take a break and talk about
Speaker 5:  cool things people do with ai.
Speaker 5:  Learning about DeepSeek sent me down a deep rabbit hole on
Speaker 5:  chain of thought reasoning. Yeah. Which is one of the technologies that,
Speaker 5:  that DeepSeek did a really good job with. Basically like these reasoning
Speaker 5:  models, all these companies are coming out with that kind of show you the
Speaker 5:  way that they think. Truthfully I thought of that as kind of a gimmick that
Speaker 5:  was like less doing something different and more just like
Speaker 5:  play pretending to be human so that you trust it more. But what it actually
Speaker 5:  is is DeepSeek and other companies have found ways to
Speaker 5:  basically, instead of generating one token that is like the answer to your
Speaker 5:  question, it's able to generate a bunch at a time and actually go step
Speaker 5:  by step and try to think through a problem. And what DeepSeek figured out
Speaker 5:  how to do is how to use a technique called reinforcement learning, which
Speaker 5:  basically rewards and punishes a model when it does things right and wrong
Speaker 5:  and teach it how to do that kind of step by step
Speaker 5:  reasoning inside of the model. And so there's a, there's a great moment in
Speaker 5:  one of the technical papers where the model starts to
Speaker 5:  answer a question, goes step by step, gets it wrong, realizes that
Speaker 5:  it is going down the wrong road and is going to make a mistake backtracks
Speaker 5:  and starts over. And that is like a powerful moment in
Speaker 5:  the history of ai. 'cause all this stuff is like If you just think about
Speaker 5:  it as like it's generating the next word every time, it doesn't actually
Speaker 5:  have the capability to go back and be like, wait, where did I go off track?
Speaker 5:  It just keeps going off track. And with something like this, like
Speaker 5:  this is the kind of thing you will start to see in every other model very
Speaker 5:  quickly. I think because the, the reasoning model is a, they have there,
Speaker 5:  there are pretty strong studies to suggest that it's vastly
Speaker 5:  more accurate when you ask these things to go step by step. Because instead
Speaker 5:  of trying to answer the question all at once, it answers it step by step,
Speaker 5:  which is like the correct way to do things. But that also,
Speaker 5:  the more you let the model do that, like
Speaker 5:  the, the longer you let it take and the more steps you let it take and the
Speaker 5:  more you let it think and try and poke around and do stuff, the more accurate
Speaker 5:  it actually is. So there, there is a path toward we can do this
Speaker 5:  better. And it looks like these reasoning models and there
Speaker 5:  are huge compute challenges there. There are huge latency problems there.
Speaker 5:  Like that stuff is gonna be hard to do in a way that is like good user experience.
Speaker 5:  But the idea
Speaker 1:  All right, so last week
Speaker 1:  we pointed out a gap that I, I think we see in all of our AI coverage. So
Speaker 1:  you might have even felt in the last segment that there's how people
Speaker 1:  feel about ai, which in our comments is bad
Speaker 1:  straightforwardly. There is a real like
Speaker 5:  Principled stance against it. Yeah. As a whole that
Speaker 1:  A lot of people, it's antiar on machine and maybe it is, like I said the
Speaker 1:  other, the other leg of the stool that could get kicked out is the New York
Speaker 1:  Times winning its copyright case against Open Act or Sarah
Speaker 1:  Silverman or any of these other people. Wasn't
Speaker 5:  It Mark Andreesen, who was like, If you don't let us steal from the whole
Speaker 5:  internet, this all falls apart.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. He wrote it in a letter to the copyright office. Perfect. Where he
Speaker 1:  was like, I need you to, I need you to do me a favor. Then he brought the
Speaker 1:  government. So we'll see what happens. Yeah. There's that by the copyright
Speaker 1:  office. This week announced a clarification of its rules saying If you make
Speaker 1:  art with AI, that gets copyrightable. But art made entirely by AI is not
Speaker 1:  no gray area there that won't be confusing. Ten one. Super, super straightforward.
Speaker 1:  Anyhow, there's a gap. The, the gap that I'm saying is people are mad about
Speaker 1:  it, especially in our comments across the internet and various social media
Speaker 1:  platforms. You, you, it's movie studio puts up a poster with ai, they get
Speaker 1:  bullied right off the internet. Then there's what the companies tell us,
Speaker 1:  which is people are using the stuff like crazy. DeepSeek is at the top of
Speaker 1:  the app store chat, GPT most popular app by growth
Speaker 1:  in the history of all applications. I think it's a little bit less than that,
Speaker 1:  but you get what I'm saying. And then there's just the stats that we hear
Speaker 1:  from the companies themselves that are sort of like less invested in the
Speaker 1:  hype. Like the one I always call out, I call out last week Adobe
Speaker 1:  Chanti new Ryan told me on decoder that people use Generat to fill at the
Speaker 1:  same rate as layers in Photoshop, which means they just have opened Photoshop,
Speaker 1:  right? Like that's just an identity. Yeah. There's this big gap
Speaker 1:  in how people are saying they feel about ai, the hype
Speaker 1:  we're gonna make digital God, and then the sort of like mundane reality of
Speaker 1:  a lot of people are just using this stuff and a lot of people like it, but
Speaker 1:  they don't perceive themselves as like using ai. So we asked
Speaker 1:  listeners, send us what you're doing. And David, it sounds like
Speaker 1:  everybody responded. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  We got a lot. We heard from a bunch of folks on social. We got a, like
Speaker 5:  dozens of calls to The Vergecast hotline. We got a whole bunch of
Speaker 5:  emails. Everybody it turns out,
Speaker 5:  uses AI and there are at least and a lot of people out there
Speaker 5:  who, who had a use case that they wanted to share. So I figured
Speaker 5:  we should just go through a bunch of 'em. And I think I tried to pull ones
Speaker 5:  that are
Speaker 5:  re reflective of trends that we saw in the responses.
Speaker 5:  So if, if you're down, I'm gonna read you some emails and I'm gonna play
Speaker 5:  you some hotlines and we're just gonna talk about it. 'cause they all made
Speaker 5:  me feel a lot of feelings and we need to sort through them together.
Speaker 1:  What is the show? But sorting through feelings today, that's, that's
Speaker 5:  We're here for, so I'm gonna not say the emailers names
Speaker 5:  because some of this stuff is very personal. And also most people in their
Speaker 5:  emails don't explicitly give us instructions whether to say their
Speaker 5:  names. I think a few of the folks on the hotline say their names, but I feel
Speaker 5:  like If you say it into the voicemail knowing we're gonna play it on the
Speaker 5:  show. That's fair game. So I'm so sorry if I'm outing you here on the first
Speaker 5:  cast.
Speaker 1:  This first email is from Sam A
Speaker 5:  All right, let's start with
Speaker 1:  Ilya S has a note for us about how good AI is.
Speaker 5:  So here's one email we got. It says, I was recently diagnosed with
Speaker 5:  a stomach issue. So it's been difficult for me to find and know things that
Speaker 5:  trigger and don't trigger a flare up. So when it's really acting up, it's
Speaker 5:  super easy for me to just take a picture of a menu at a restaurant or bar
Speaker 5:  and just ask what, what can I have? And from what I've told chat GBT from
Speaker 5:  the doctors, it can just tell me what's safest to eat and drink. Even telling
Speaker 5:  me the exact ingredients that are safe in those dishes. That's awesome.
Speaker 5:  Like unambiguously cool use case in my,
Speaker 1:  That's a great use case. It's just like I, again, I'm just being negative.
Speaker 1:  I don't know how the restaurant actually made the food. I don't know if the
Speaker 1:  things hallucinate like that. It's just, this is what I mean. Like I'm
Speaker 1:  just prone to see the risk. And I think that's an email where
Speaker 1:  people see the benefit.
Speaker 5:  So this is, you just brought up the exact thing that is going to come
Speaker 5:  up an awful lot in these, which is you are
Speaker 5:  going to see a trend in which there is a question of
Speaker 5:  how much should I trust this? And one of the things that
Speaker 5:  consistently surprised me is a lot of people saying it doesn't really matter.
Speaker 5:  That like, I understand it has flaws. It might not be perfect. It's something
Speaker 5:  like, here, let me, let me read you one. I've often felt intimidated by
Speaker 5:  the professional and technical demands of public service. However, chat GBT
Speaker 5:  has given me the ability to communicate more effectively, present my ideas
Speaker 5:  professionally and quickly understand complex topics from rebuilding water
Speaker 5:  treatment facilities and developing billing systems to ensuring compliance
Speaker 5:  with the Environmental protection Agency regulations. I've been able to handle
Speaker 5:  responsibilities I never imagined I could take on again. Very
Speaker 5:  cool. To me, I immediately read that and go, how many of
Speaker 5:  the EPA regulations do you think chat GPT just flatly it's wrong. Like
Speaker 5:  yeah, just, just fully hallucinates some made
Speaker 5:  up thing. And I feel a, with a lot of these things I keep coming
Speaker 5:  back to like, it, it's gonna work for you until it blows up spectacularly
Speaker 5:  in your face. Right? And it's like, it's the same with the eating in the
Speaker 5:  restaurant. Like as long as it's right, and let's say it's right
Speaker 5:  80% of the time, which is probably kind to
Speaker 5:  most of these systems. But let's say it's you take a picture of your food
Speaker 5:  or you, you upload a PDF of a regulatory document,
Speaker 5:  ask it questions, it's often gonna be right. But when it's wrong,
Speaker 5:  If you trust it, really bad things can happen. And so
Speaker 5:  I, I feel like where I fall on the like, but what if
Speaker 5:  it doesn't work? Scale might just be different than some
Speaker 5:  other people. But that just is the thing I keep thinking about with all of
Speaker 5:  these.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I, my, I don't trust computers. I have a weird job
Speaker 1:  in that regard, but like, as David knows, when I record this podcast at home,
Speaker 1:  I insist on recording locally into another
Speaker 1:  recorder. Yeah. And not letting my Mac do the recording. 'cause I just don't
Speaker 1:  trust the Mac, which is weird because I should,
Speaker 5:  But I will say on the, on the flip side,
Speaker 1:  But like, that's the, but I just like, that's the frame that I'm in. Right.
Speaker 1:  Whereas it's like what I hear that email is
Speaker 1:  not about trust. It's about
Speaker 1:  I worked out this idea so that I would have the confidence to go have, like,
Speaker 1:  have the idea. And that's really different and interesting.
Speaker 5:  How, how So say more about that.
Speaker 1:  I mean, I, that person sounds like they have a very complicated job. They,
Speaker 1:  they know, they have to know how to do everything and they're like designing
Speaker 1:  a water plant, right? Yeah,
Speaker 1:  I hear that. And I think, well you already, you already did know how, right?
Speaker 1:  Like you had the capability of doing it and what you needed
Speaker 1:  was a conversation or a more easily
Speaker 1:  adjusted reference material or whatever to get you over the hump.
Speaker 1:  Like you just solved your imposter syndrome. You,
Speaker 1:  the, the AI didn't do it for you, right. You just, it just helped
Speaker 1:  you get to where you were inevitably gonna be.
Speaker 5:  I, I think there's something to that, and I think there's also a, a recurring
Speaker 5:  theme in a lot of these that is basically like, I
Speaker 5:  just needed something, I didn't have a tool
Speaker 5:  to do this thing and now I have a tool to do this thing. And even if it doesn't
Speaker 5:  necessarily do it well, the fact that it does it at all is
Speaker 5:  something right. And it's like I I I think that I started with the food one
Speaker 5:  because that is one that there isn't a clean other answer to,
Speaker 5:  right? Like I see on Reddit all the time, the people who go to a restaurant
Speaker 5:  with like those huge placards of like, here's all the food I can't eat. And
Speaker 5:  I hand them to the chef and then the chef posted it on Reddit being like,
Speaker 5:  this asshole came to my restaurant. And to have something that is like,
Speaker 5:  I can take a picture of this and it is going to give me even, even reasonably
Speaker 5:  reliable information about what this is and whether I can safely eat it
Speaker 5:  reasonably reliable and easy is probably a huge step up from the
Speaker 5:  alternative. Yeah. In this case. And I think that's, that's something really
Speaker 5:  meaningful. And so there's this sense that like, something is better than
Speaker 5:  nothing is, is so pervasive through a lot of this. And I think is really
Speaker 5:  interesting in a way that I didn't give it credit for. All right. Let me,
Speaker 5:  let me play you a couple of voicemails. We got,
Speaker 7:  Hi, this is Alex. And I wanted to call in to talk about how I
Speaker 7:  use LLMs in my daily life. I use chat
Speaker 7:  EBT as an on demand advisor of
Speaker 7:  sorts. You know, how can I improve this recipe? How much
Speaker 7:  cat lit should I have, be using per month? What are some good ways to save
Speaker 7:  time at the gym if these are my priorities?
Speaker 7:  A lot of these things are things I could use Google for,
Speaker 7:  but it's just quicker to ask chat GBT. Another
Speaker 7:  thing I use it for is as a way to
Speaker 7:  organize my thoughts. So if I'm ruminating about something,
Speaker 7:  I'll just talk to chat GBT It's no
Speaker 7:  replacement for my therapist, but it helps reorient my thinking
Speaker 7:  when I need it to. I know I could also get this from
Speaker 7:  my friends and sometimes I do, but Chatt PP is nearly
Speaker 7:  always available instantly.
Speaker 5:  I find that very compelling, I have to say.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I mean, again, it's, it's hard to tell anyone
Speaker 1:  they're like doing it wrong. Yeah. Like, that's that's great. I'm like very
Speaker 1:  happy that that's working in that way. I, the thing that grabs me at that
Speaker 1:  one in particular is it is the thing
Speaker 1:  that Google is afraid of, right? But it's also the thing
Speaker 1:  that these products have shown themselves to be the worst at.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Like how much cat litter should my, my cat use every month is,
Speaker 1:  well, first of all it depends on the cat, but second of all, it's like that's
Speaker 1:  the one where it's like, I you should, you should feed your cat rocks. Like,
Speaker 1:  it's like that's what will
Speaker 5:  Happen. Put glue in the cat litter. It's like it's just sitting there. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And that I think this is just really eyeopening for me in that
Speaker 1:  you're to your point, it's just good enough. Yeah. It's just something. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And we, and we and as we have covered exhaustively typing that sort of thing
Speaker 1:  into Google right now is like getting mugged in an alley.
Speaker 5:  Seriously. Yeah. No, I, there there is a real
Speaker 5:  thing that I I I keep hearing in a bunch of these that is just how
Speaker 5:  aggressively Google fumbled the bag of search that like
Speaker 5:  what people want is better Google not chat
Speaker 5:  GPT and Google just threw all of that away. But I think
Speaker 5:  one of the things that you say all the time is that the internet is about
Speaker 5:  to be flooded with c plus stuff. And I think what we might be under
Speaker 5:  rating is how valuable a c plus can be sometimes. Like maybe a
Speaker 5:  c plus delivered to me easily and quickly at all times is
Speaker 5:  actually something
Speaker 5:  Hmm. Is that bleak as hell? Probably, but it's something.
Speaker 5:  All right, lemme keep, lemme keep going.
Speaker 1:  That's like the, that's like how they, why they invented legacy admissions
Speaker 1:  at Harvard. Like that's what you're describing. Like what if we can just
Speaker 1:  accept a flood of c plus applicants.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And that goes fine. What talking about, alright, here's the next one.
Speaker 5:  Hey,
Speaker 8:  This is Jake. I've listening to your recent podcast where you've mentioned
Speaker 8:  how you want people to call in and say what they use Chad GBT for in the
Speaker 8:  real world. I use it weekly to make my shopping list. I ask
Speaker 8:  you to make recipes based off of what I have in my house and what I'm going
Speaker 8:  to buy. Try to make it where I can get it as macro friendly as
Speaker 8:  possible. One of the features that I've started using Mo more recently
Speaker 8:  is whenever I make a shopping list, I ask it to make an optimized
Speaker 8:  shopping pattern for a standard location of where I'm going. So I can go
Speaker 8:  into Costco or Aldi, I can make sure that I'm shopping the most sufficient
Speaker 8:  and then I ask it to find substitutes to make for recipes, top
Speaker 8:  values. Use it for pretty much anything that it comes to
Speaker 8:  for like vacations, trips you for planning. That's
Speaker 8:  the, those are some of the main use cases that I use it for outside of
Speaker 8:  all of my work.
Speaker 1:  All right, so first of all, I just, I that's all great. I,
Speaker 1:  me Google blew it. You just described everything Google has ever demoed at
Speaker 1:  Google io right? I know, but you're doing it in Chachi. I know.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, yeah. Like there, there's a, there are a hundred Google Keep features
Speaker 5:  that you just described. No one uses.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, no, I, this to me was the one that I was like the most
Speaker 5:  sort of down the middle simple use case is like, I'm gonna write
Speaker 5:  a list of stuff that I have in my fridge. You're gonna spit back some recipes
Speaker 5:  and then I'm gonna say, can you optimize this list to go to Costco? Like
Speaker 5:  ta GPT is great at that. Do it. Love it. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And then the next turn is go on Instacart with operator
Speaker 1:  and order it for me. Right. Like you can see how you connect all those
Speaker 5:  Dots. Next time I go to Costco, I'm going to tell Chad Gt
Speaker 5:  to give me directions around Costco and I'm only going to follow Chad
Speaker 5:  GBT. We're gonna see how it goes.
Speaker 1:  This is actually the part where he said that I'm dying to know more here.
Speaker 1:  It really implies that Chad GT knows how Costco's are
Speaker 1:  organized and just based on my Costco in
Speaker 1:  it's a war zone, I sure
Speaker 5:  Costco knows how Costco
Speaker 1:  Is organized. That's what I mean. It's like I've asked Costco employees where
Speaker 1:  things are and they're like, no, no, no, no, no. Good luck to you sir.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it's a secret you're not allowed to know. But yeah, that kind
Speaker 5:  of thing. Like I I, I am always talking to people about like what I, what
Speaker 5:  do I think are good use cases for chat GBT And the one I always come up with
Speaker 5:  is movie recommendations. 'cause it's like super low stakes, but actually
Speaker 5:  a thing AI is unusually able to be good at. Where I'm like, I like these
Speaker 5:  three movies, what else should I watch? And it's like, that's a thing LLMs
Speaker 5:  do very well. And this kind of like, recipe remixing
Speaker 5:  is another good example of that. So I just thought that one was great. All
Speaker 5:  right. Let me read you another email. Real tone shift here. You ready for
Speaker 5:  this? Yeah. We got an email from somebody who's going through a divorce
Speaker 5:  and said, Chad GBT has been a surprising source of support. Let me
Speaker 5:  be clear, I don't use it as a talk therapist parentheses gross, but rather
Speaker 5:  as a tool to help me communicate effectively and with kindness, my wife is
Speaker 5:  very sensitive to perceived criticism. So I draft emails to her and then
Speaker 5:  use Chad GBT to help me soften the tone, make them warmer and remove anything
Speaker 5:  that could be interpreted as critical while still ensuring my requests and
Speaker 5:  boundaries are not diluted. Filtering emails this way has made a difficult
Speaker 5:  process a little less hard. It's also helped me curb any instincts to be
Speaker 5:  petty, sarcastic or passive aggressive. It helps me keep my side of the street
Speaker 5:  clean.
Speaker 1:  Wow.
Speaker 5:  Right.
Speaker 1:  So I'm, I'm married to a divorce lawyer. I have heard about
Speaker 1:  an infinite variety of passive aggressive emails between partners for
Speaker 1:  the past several years. I feel like I should just go tell her about this.
Speaker 5:  It's really interesting, right? Yeah. I, this one I was like, I don't know
Speaker 5:  how to feel on the one hand, it, it, it, there's like a piece of this that
Speaker 5:  kinda makes me sad that it's like, it's a bummer that there is a, a web app
Speaker 5:  that has to be your tool for this. But on the other hand, like again,
Speaker 5:  what's your alternative? Where else would someone go to do something like
Speaker 5:  this?
Speaker 1:  If you took this out of the bigger context of AI and all of
Speaker 1:  the noise and all of the hype and you were like, there's a new
Speaker 1:  feature in Grammarly, right. Five years ago. Yeah. Or
Speaker 1:  you're like, Google Docs has a new feature that just helps you, like
Speaker 1:  de passive aggressive in email. I don't know that anyone would have any
Speaker 1:  reaction to this other than that's actually pretty good. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I think that's right.
Speaker 1:  And it's only in the context of all the AI hype and you know, that horrible
Speaker 1:  Apple commercial where it's just like bad employee sends professional email.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And like this is what Apple intelligence is for
Speaker 1:  there, there this is maybe the most human of the notes
Speaker 1:  that we've gotten. Yeah. Right. And that, I mean, not to say everyone else
Speaker 1:  isn't human, but like, this is a very emotional task that is being
Speaker 1:  performed. Totally. And I I I really do think If you took this one out of
Speaker 1:  the AI bubble in all of the baggage that comes with it,
Speaker 1:  you put this in any other product five years ago and everyone's like, oh,
Speaker 1:  this rules.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Yeah. I mean, and I think it, it goes to show that
Speaker 5:  a, our, our vocabulary about AI is still so primitive. Like we call
Speaker 5:  everything ai and actually AI has lots of wildly
Speaker 5:  different things and we need to get to the point where we're better at talking
Speaker 5:  about them as different things.
Speaker 5:  But it also to some extent goes to show how versatile something like chat
Speaker 5:  GPT is, like all this stuff is happening in the same text box.
Speaker 5:  Right? Like it's a pretty remarkable thing.
Speaker 1:  Also very notable. Everyone has said Chacha Bt
Speaker 5:  Every single person. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  We haven't gotten one Dolly. We haven't got one Gemini. Nope. No,
Speaker 1:  no. Apple intelligence mix. A little bit of claw
Speaker 5:  Love in a, in a few of
Speaker 1:  These. Oh, it's common. Okay. Okay. A little bit
Speaker 5:  Of Claude love. I don't think I pulled any of the ones that people use Claude,
Speaker 5:  but you're
Speaker 1:  Just, just, sorry, calling
Speaker 5:  It out. Sorry Claude users. But it was, Claude was mentioned. I don't think
Speaker 5:  Gemini came up one time in the emails that we got brutal. But Claude
Speaker 5:  there people were like, oh, I mostly use chat GPT and like some Claude.
Speaker 5:  There was a lot of some Claude.
Speaker 5:  All right, lemme play you another voicemail. Here's a, again, we're just
Speaker 5:  gonna tone shift all over the place here 'cause that's what AI does. Here
Speaker 5:  we go.
Speaker 9:  Hey, this is Leo from Atlanta, Georgia. Neil, I asked what
Speaker 9:  everyone's using their AI assistance for and I
Speaker 9:  use mine almost exclusively to solve hard questions
Speaker 9:  in the word puzzle game word salad. Also to note,
Speaker 9:  I recently discovered that something about David's voice makes me super tired
Speaker 9:  and helps lull me to sleep. So I want to give a quick shout out and thank
Speaker 9:  you to Mr. David Pierce for improving my sleep
Speaker 9:  quality and helping fight my insomnia. Thanks guys. Love the show.
Speaker 1:  Som David's voice makes me super tired.
Speaker 5:  First question, was that a compliment or an insult?
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that's really, that's a tough one. You make me sleepy. It's like
Speaker 1:  a really
Speaker 5:  Yeah, he said thanks. I don't think he meant it, but that one
Speaker 5:  like another in the line of like movie recommendations, right? Like pretty
Speaker 5:  low stakes, pretty straightforward. This thing has a lot of information and
Speaker 5:  it can, it can spit some information back at me. Yeah, it works.
Speaker 1:  You're cheating, but it works.
Speaker 5:  You are cheating to be so clear. You are cheating. It's okay. I've
Speaker 5:  Googled, what's the word I'll answer before, like it's fine. It's
Speaker 1:  Bedtime for you, sir.
Speaker 5:  We all have bad days. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Okay, let me, let me find the next one.
Speaker 5:  I've been fascinated by my mom's usage of ai. She's 49 and while she uses
Speaker 5:  it a lot for her small business writing posts, et cetera, I've noticed that
Speaker 5:  over the past year, she's also started to use it as a general Google replacement
Speaker 5:  in her personal life as well. She wants to know a fact. She asked chat GPT,
Speaker 5:  she has to write a WhatsApp message that requires minimum thinking. She asked
Speaker 5:  chat GPT last week. She found out one of her close friends is struggling
Speaker 5:  with her mental health and having suicidal ideations. And I shit you not,
Speaker 5:  she asked chat GPT what are the best ways to support someone who's depressed?
Speaker 5:  Again,
Speaker 5:  just Google fumbled the bag. Like people want better Google.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, but this is the one, again, I, these are real people.
Speaker 1:  Everyone use a computer however you want. I'm, I'm happy it's working,
Speaker 1:  but this is the one that's the, the blinking red danger sign,
Speaker 1:  right? It's like, oh, everyone just needs a friend. Like
Speaker 5:  Sure.
Speaker 1:  Right. There's, there's just an element here where this
Speaker 1:  is to me like this is where the robots hallucinate
Speaker 1:  all day long. And what you're getting is better Google
Speaker 1:  with worse results presumably, but in a better interface
Speaker 1:  or more reactive or just someone to talk to you and in a way that's natural.
Speaker 1:  And it's like,
Speaker 1:  this is the one where it's like, If you tell me this is the use case, I will
Speaker 1:  confidently tell you this does not support $500 billion data center built
Speaker 1:  out. Oh,
Speaker 5:  A hundred percent.
Speaker 1:  Because it, it, it doesn't scale like the thing
Speaker 1:  will happen that happened to Alexa in Siri, which is you'll do this
Speaker 1:  until it fails you and then you will stop thinking it can do anything more
Speaker 1:  than this. Right? Like you're like, Siri, tell me a joke.
Speaker 1:  And it's like, I don't, I give up. Right? You're like fine timers of music.
Speaker 1:  It is, and I'm not saying the ceiling is, the ceiling for Chacha piece
Speaker 1:  is so much higher, obviously, but there's still a ceiling. And the ceiling
Speaker 1:  is when it lies to you. Right? When it makes something up when
Speaker 1:  you ask it for movies and it gives you three real movies and one fake one.
Speaker 1:  And then people are literally showing up at public libraries asking for books
Speaker 1:  that don't exist. Yep. And that, that's what I mean. It's like when lawyers
Speaker 1:  show up in court citing cases that aren't real and they get disciplined by
Speaker 1:  the bar association. That's the pro, like, they
Speaker 1:  can't overcome. They don't know how to overcome that. And so, like this one
Speaker 1:  to me is like, yeah, I I I every experience is valid.
Speaker 1:  Like great. And that's really interesting to see how different people are
Speaker 1:  approaching it. But this is the one that hits the wall the fastest.
Speaker 5:  Interesting. Yeah. I mean I think I agree, but I also think there is a, a
Speaker 5:  more charitable way to look at that, that says
Speaker 5:  the human is still kind of in charge here, right? Like, I think it's, it's
Speaker 5:  one thing to
Speaker 5:  have these things do things on your behalf, right? And this is where I think
Speaker 5:  things like operator get really messy. Like, would you let
Speaker 5:  chat GPT text your wife for you? Like e
Speaker 5:  even something relatively inno obvious again,
Speaker 1:  David, I don't, I i I don't think I've made this clear enough. I am married
Speaker 1:  to a divorce lawyer.
Speaker 5:  No, but even something very simple where you're like,
Speaker 1:  That woman can have chat g bt divorce me. It's just a macro on her computer.
Speaker 1:  It's a work issued windowed laptop with a button that says D and then my
Speaker 1:  life is over. Fair.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But like, okay, fine.
Speaker 5:  Helen Hala, our boss, our boss. Would you, would you like
Speaker 5:  voice mode chat GBT and be like, Hey, will you text Helen and tell her I'm
Speaker 5:  running late, but I'll be like 10 minutes late to the meeting. Why wouldn't
Speaker 1:  I just text
Speaker 5:  Her that? No, no. But, but just go thought, experiment with me here for a
Speaker 5:  second. Okay. Would you let it take that act like do
Speaker 5:  that on your behalf. Not say here's a message you might send, but be like,
Speaker 5:  send this message for me, chat. GBT, would you have it do that?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Abstractly.
Speaker 5:  Yes. Really. See, I wouldn't, I like just the, there, there is a certain
Speaker 5:  thing where I'm like, okay, If you wanna write the text and then I'll look
Speaker 5:  at it and send it. That's something. Yeah, I guess
Speaker 1:  That's what I'm imagining. 'cause that's how I use Siri in the car.
Speaker 5:  No, I even get freaked out in the car because you say it and it reads it
Speaker 5:  back to you and I'm like, what if it like put weird punctuation and a period
Speaker 5:  at the end and wife is gonna think
Speaker 1:  I'm, there's middle emojis between every word and you just don't know. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I'm
Speaker 5:  With you. And I still like, I I truly get nervous about doing a text that
Speaker 5:  I can't look at the words before I send them. Yeah. And I think that's where
Speaker 5:  all of this age agentic stuff gets really messy for me because I'm so, I'm
Speaker 5:  expecting you to do things. But again, just to finish this thought, in this
Speaker 5:  case, the idea that like I'm asking chat GBT to
Speaker 5:  give me ideas about how to support a friend, I think is
Speaker 5:  less terrifying than the idea of like, send my friend a supportive text message,
Speaker 5:  which
Speaker 1:  Would be
Speaker 5:  Horrifying. I
Speaker 1:  Scrolled down and I'm reading the rest of the same email Sure. About the
Speaker 1:  mom
Speaker 1:  and the second part of the email is the most important part of the email.
Speaker 1:  Okay, here's a quote. Most people I'm friends with or that listen
Speaker 1:  to the show are probably concerned with accuracy, environmental impact, development
Speaker 1:  of critical thinking, et cetera. She, the mom could frankly
Speaker 1:  not give less of a shit.
Speaker 1:  And I suspect people are like her are likely to be in the majority, not because
Speaker 1:  she's dumb, she's brilliant in other ways because she's just not wired that
Speaker 1:  way. And this is your point about good enough. Yeah. Right. It's just
Speaker 1:  the computer's talking to you and it sounds fine
Speaker 1:  and that's good enough. And I,
Speaker 1:  I'm just very convinced that we live in an age where just being confident
Speaker 1:  is like all you need, like just bluing through
Speaker 1:  it is very effective in a variety of domains. And maybe
Speaker 1:  that collapses on itself. We'll find out. But
Speaker 1:  that's like the whole population is primed to just be like confident
Speaker 1:  talking. That must be right. Totally.
Speaker 5:  Wired ran a headline the other day, something to the effect of the less people
Speaker 5:  know about AI the more they like it.
Speaker 5:  And I'm there based on a study that I think it was like a marketing firm
Speaker 5:  did, basically defined that the, If you don't understand
Speaker 5:  what's happening, AI seems great. Yeah. And that makes perfect sense to me.
Speaker 5:  That feels exactly right. And I think most people don't understand what's
Speaker 5:  happening. And maybe that's terrifying. But I think that's what's coming
Speaker 5:  based
Speaker 1:  On this. And that second piece, which is super interesting to me.
Speaker 1:  I understand why a bunch of companies are so excited about this because
Speaker 1:  it is the first time using a computer has felt different for people,
Speaker 1:  right? The, the jump from the command line to the graphical user
Speaker 1:  interface felt different. And you built an entire paradigm of computing
Speaker 1:  around it. And then the jump from desktop computers to touchscreen
Speaker 1:  mobile phones was an entire paradigm shift. And obviously phones could go
Speaker 1:  with you and all, all the other stuff, but that created an entire economy
Speaker 1:  and they've been searching for something else that makes computers feel different
Speaker 1:  to people. Are they gonna fold? You know, like
Speaker 1:  what's something, it's gotta be something. And this feels different to people
Speaker 1:  'cause they're just talking to them, but there's not an application layer
Speaker 1:  behind that that builds the whole economy or supports all this. Like, and
Speaker 1:  also I just come back to this here example. Like, eventually mom's gonna
Speaker 1:  hit a wall, right? It's gonna lie to her. She's gonna make a mistake, it
Speaker 1:  will embarrass her in some way, and then, and then we'll stop
Speaker 1:  because she can't trust it. And that trust once it's gone is gone.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I, I definitely agree with that. And I think the question of a,
Speaker 5:  when that happens and B, what the stakes are is the stuff that makes me really
Speaker 5:  nervous about all of this.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And either I'm just a chicken or everyone else should be more afraid
Speaker 5:  or both. I don't know. All right, let's do one more and then, then we'll,
Speaker 5:  we'll get outta here. Yeah. Here's one more.
Speaker 10:  Hey, The Verge and or the Slack channel. My name's Florian. I'm calling
Speaker 10:  from New Jersey. Taking up your request on what I use chat GBT for.
Speaker 10:  I would say primarily I use it as a, a
Speaker 10:  more reliable resource than Google searches for informed decisions.
Speaker 10:  So whether that's in depth settings, menus, I can find Bluetooth.
Speaker 10:  But you know the other ones, I'm a recent college grad, so I've
Speaker 10:  used a lot to help friends with their career growth or updating resumes.
Speaker 10:  Kind of like the bad code, good code argument.
Speaker 10:  I come back for practical advice, namely curious
Speaker 10:  topics or other things like that to gain some
Speaker 10:  information on very quickly. But I would say primarily
Speaker 10:  it's for things like when I can't find the answer on AV forums for how to
Speaker 10:  set up the Blu ray player through a RC with the
Speaker 10:  soundbar and making sure that Dolby true HD plays from
Speaker 10:  my disc. Neil, I for you, but I love you.
Speaker 10:  Thanks for the great pod and hopefully someone in the slack see this, have
Speaker 10:  a great day.
Speaker 1:  I love you. I love this man. First of all, just call me, you know, you how
Speaker 1:  talk to the robot I'm around.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. This is why the verb cast exists. We will solve these problems for
Speaker 5:  you.
Speaker 1:  That's great. The, the in-depth technical problem. The issue that I've always
Speaker 1:  run into with that is the answer is buried in some forum posts from six
Speaker 1:  years ago and it's just been muddled. And I
Speaker 1:  actually wanna find the old forum post where the person actually has the
Speaker 1:  answer, not the, do you know what I mean? Yeah. Like not the, not the
Speaker 1:  synthesis over time. This is
Speaker 5:  Where I think like Reddit answers the, the Reddit AI search is, is
Speaker 5:  actually super exciting because it is geared toward that exact thing. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That is like, what if we just did a smarter job of searching this
Speaker 5:  stuff, but we're still interested in finding actual people's actual
Speaker 5:  answers. It's like that's a, that's a cool mix if we can figure out how to
Speaker 5:  do it right. I lied. I have one more to play for you and then we should go
Speaker 5:  to break. But let's just wait.
Speaker 1:  I just wanna say to, to my guy, you're my best friend.
Speaker 1:  We don't know each other, but we we're in it now together.
Speaker 5:  You are one of us. Now we're family. Welcome to The Verge. All right, I got
Speaker 5:  one more
Speaker 1:  True HD for life.
Speaker 9:  This is Matt from Springfield, Missouri. I was just answering your question
Speaker 9:  about using AI daily. All these tools came out when I started
Speaker 9:  dating and I used it to help write my profile and
Speaker 9:  also compose my messages. 'cause I'm a machinist, I'm
Speaker 9:  have good ideas, but I'm not good at words. And AI helped me fill that gap.
Speaker 9:  It must have worked because now I'm in a relationship. I'm gonna have a
Speaker 9:  son this year and I still use AI today to compose
Speaker 9:  crack thoughtful messages to send to her throughout the week.
Speaker 1:  Oh, this is great.
Speaker 5:  AI is good. Neli,
Speaker 1:  I gotta say, I mean that's, we just got it there. We should shut down The
Speaker 1:  Verge Negative. Nancy is good outta here. That's fast. Yeah, that one made
Speaker 5:  Me
Speaker 1:  Really happy. Cha We only hit two years ago. We went from zero to sun.
Speaker 1:  Killing it. Pretty good. Yeah, pretty good. Pretty good.
Speaker 1:  You know, most people move in together for, I'm just saying anyway.
Speaker 5:  Not anymore. This is an AI world we live in. No time
Speaker 1:  For that. Okay. I'll give you, I'll give mine. And we, and it's very different
Speaker 1:  than that, but it's in the same zone. I recently sold something on
Speaker 1:  eBay and I let eBay's AI just write the description for me. Really just gave
Speaker 1:  it, it was so dumb. It was like we, we bought a new stove
Speaker 1:  and we bought different color handles for the stove. So I sold the old ones
Speaker 1:  and I, I just took a picture and I figured out what it was and I'm like,
Speaker 1:  do you wanna write a description? And it's like, this is the lowest stake
Speaker 1:  shit in the world. Like anybody who's searching for replacement stove handles
Speaker 1:  and sees a picture of this like they know. Yeah. Like it, you don't have
Speaker 1:  to describe them very much. And I was like, fine, here's some copy. And it
Speaker 1:  did it. Poshmark today actually announced that they're letting
Speaker 1:  people do AI descriptions. I think there's this world in which like weird
Speaker 1:  low stakes fields get filled in. Yeah. Obviously dating is a higher
Speaker 1:  stakes field, but I can, I can see why it's very tempting to
Speaker 1:  people. Yeah, it's good stuff. And by the way, that's a great story. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Matt, congrats. We're very happy for
Speaker 1:  It. I hope you name your son Al. Think about it.
Speaker 1:  All right. We should take a break. And we got a lightning round. That was
Speaker 1:  great. Send us more of those.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Thank you to everybody who, who wrote in It was super fun. I learned
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Unsponsored lightning round. That's how you know
Speaker 1:  it's wild.
Speaker 5:  It's crazy. Times out
Speaker 1:  There Unfiltered, uncensored. The First
Speaker 1:  Amendment's back people. And by back we mean Trump
Speaker 1:  will arrest you If you
Speaker 13:  Criticize it.
Speaker 1:  All right. There's actually a lot this lightning round. Let's start with
Speaker 1:  some very exciting, very niche Vergecast News.
Speaker 1:  Google is open sourcing the Pebble Source code, this original
Speaker 1:  smartwatch. And Eric Midkowski, the founder of Pebble, is gonna make
Speaker 1:  another watch. David, you like talk to him. What's going on here?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, so I saw Eric at CES, we had lunch and he
Speaker 5:  had a pebble on his wrist and I said, we were just talking
Speaker 5:  about, you know, life and the future and gadgets. And I was like, I was like,
Speaker 5:  so you, you've left automatic, he sold his company beeper the messaging app
Speaker 5:  that we talked about a bunch to automatic last year. He left the company
Speaker 5:  looking for something to do. I was like, so are you gonna, are you gonna
Speaker 5:  just like do Pebble again? Are you gonna re Pebble? And little
Speaker 5:  did I know, he asked me again. We talked this past week and he was like,
Speaker 5:  did did you know? And I was like, what are you talking about? And he was
Speaker 5:  like, we're calling it re Pebble. How? Like what? Why did you say So I, I'm
Speaker 5:  feeling very proud of myself except that I completely let him off the hook
Speaker 5:  and just moved on to something else. But anyway, so Eric,
Speaker 5:  I guess over the last year has been working with Google to open
Speaker 5:  source all of Pebble Os. So Pebble sold to Fitbit, which sold to Google and
Speaker 5:  a lot of the like Pebble ideas sort of percolated around those two
Speaker 5:  companies. And you can see some DNA in like the Pixel watch, but the
Speaker 5:  Pebble software itself was just not being used. And so
Speaker 5:  Google to its credit, I cannot report that
Speaker 5:  Dieter Bone was involved. But I also believe in my heart that Dieter Bone
Speaker 5:  was involved.
Speaker 5:  Dieter famous Pebble fan was just works
Speaker 5:  for Google. Now you know there, there's just sometimes there are pieces there.
Speaker 5:  But anyway,
Speaker 1:  Look, we don't do conspiracy theories here except for that
Speaker 5:  One. Except for that one. And Google
Speaker 5:  agreed to do it. So Google open sourced all of Pebble s which is
Speaker 5:  not everything. There are like third party drivers and stuff that
Speaker 5:  are occasionally complicated to open source. The name Pebble still belongs
Speaker 5:  to Google. But functionally all of the software is now available. And
Speaker 5:  so Eric is starting a company that will not be called Pebble, but the goal
Speaker 5:  is just to make Pebbles again. He's like, we got it right. His pebbles now
Speaker 5:  still work. He said he had to replace the battery on all of them, but they
Speaker 5:  still work and they still do the things he wanted. And so he's like, I'm
Speaker 5:  gonna keep making these like long lasting e ink
Speaker 5:  gadgety gadgets to put on people's wrists. And the plan is
Speaker 5:  hopefully to start making stuff quickly. Like even this year.
Speaker 5:  And there are a lot of pebble nerds out there who are very excited about
Speaker 5:  this. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  So the Pebble story as I recall it is that they just
Speaker 1:  ran into API problems with the iPhone. 'cause the
Speaker 1:  original Pebble could get notifications, right? Like Apple supported sending
Speaker 1:  notifications out that way. But you couldn't reply to a message like it.
Speaker 1:  They were just limited like in very real ways. You could just like look at
Speaker 1:  a text message but you gotta get your phone. Apple's never gonna open that
Speaker 1:  up. No. So probably Android phones, the Pebble app on the
Speaker 1:  Android phones, they could do some of that stuff more. It
Speaker 5:  Was, it always much better. Yeah, there's more to do on Android, but also
Speaker 5:  I think for Eric in particular, I think the idea of
Speaker 5:  it being like a messaging machine is, seems to be less compelling. He's
Speaker 5:  like, he's very into it as like it's an easy way to get kind of
Speaker 5:  glanceable information, but it's also like simple. And the battery lasts
Speaker 5:  a long time and it has buttons for music controls, like buttons for music
Speaker 5:  controls is one of the specific things he named as like a core
Speaker 5:  competency of Pebble. And it is like, love it. It does not have to be a messaging
Speaker 5:  system, which I actually kind of agree with. Like I, I, I
Speaker 5:  would like lots of features to exist but I find that I only
Speaker 5:  use a very small number of them on my wrist and I would trade a lot of them
Speaker 5:  for like five day battery life. And yeah. And I think it, it's gonna be interesting
Speaker 5:  to see what they do this time.
Speaker 1:  I'm excited. I love a good open source hardware hacky project.
Speaker 5:  It's gonna be cool. 'cause there there's like, there's been a pretty big
Speaker 5:  community of people keeping this stuff alive for a long time. And
Speaker 5:  the fact that now they have honest to God software to play with instead
Speaker 5:  of like hacking around the edges of existing pebbles. I think we're
Speaker 5:  gonna see some pretty interesting stuff here like that that community is,
Speaker 5:  is really engaged and I think is gonna get up to some stuff.
Speaker 1:  Okay, so that's Pebble next one. Oracle
Speaker 1:  and Microsoft reportedly and talks to take over TikTok.
Speaker 5:  This story makes me so tired.
Speaker 1:  Although Trump denied Oracle right in some press con, but he doesn't know.
Speaker 1:  I mean like when I say he doesn't know, I don't, I just mean be dismissive.
Speaker 1:  I mean literally he gave them a 75 day illegal
Speaker 1:  extension, which Apple and Google do not trust enough to put TikTok back
Speaker 1:  in the store. And then at a press conference he said Congress
Speaker 1:  has given me 90 days, which is 15 more days than he gave himself.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Congress has not given him 90 days.
Speaker 5:  Congress didn't give anybody anything.
Speaker 1:  The time's up like what he gave TikTok was a 75
Speaker 1:  day pause on enforcement of breaking the law. Right. Which
Speaker 1:  again, apple and Google did not trust. 'cause that's billions of dollars.
Speaker 5:  Right.
Speaker 1:  Anyway, so I'm just saying like the facts are confusing on the ground. Like
Speaker 1:  what does Trump even believe is going on here? Because he's just saying different
Speaker 1:  numbers and then, but he did say I don't think Oracle was involved, which
Speaker 1:  is weird. But Microsoft was a bid the first time
Speaker 1:  Nadella famously said it was like the weirdest deal he is ever been a part
Speaker 1:  of.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. A bidder might give
Speaker 5:  Microsoft too much agency in that. It seems a lot like Microsoft was like
Speaker 5:  dragged into a room and yelled at about buying TikTok for a while.
Speaker 1:  No one knows what's gonna happen. Yeah. Like truly no one knows what's gonna
Speaker 1:  happen. And then this other plan that Trump keeps
Speaker 1:  floating where someone does a joint venture and they give 50% of it
Speaker 1:  to the United States.
Speaker 1:  Our own big tech companies are extremely nervous
Speaker 1:  about that plan.
Speaker 5:  Oh, interesting.
Speaker 1:  'cause If you just think about it, that means India could shut down
Speaker 1:  YouTube and demand it get sold and 50%
Speaker 1:  of YouTube be given to Indi. Like that's a precedent you do not want
Speaker 1:  to play with.
Speaker 5:  Right. Interesting. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Because all their governments are way less skittish about
Speaker 1:  nationalizing companies or doing speech regulations and
Speaker 1:  everyone's like, don't play this game. Right.
Speaker 5:  We'll see if any is actually a particularly interesting one in that it is
Speaker 5:  a government that I think would be excited to do that kind of thing. And
Speaker 5:  is such a crucial market as a growth engine for
Speaker 5:  so many of these companies. Oh
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I picked it. India has banned TikTok. Yeah. Like straight up and it
Speaker 1:  is very reliant on YouTube, but it has very draconian speech policies. The
Speaker 1:  Modi government does not enjoy descent in very specific ways.
Speaker 1:  You, you could Brazil and other country like that. Russia exists. Yeah. You
Speaker 1:  know like there's a million countries that would play these games.
Speaker 1:  And so like our own big tech companies are like, do not, you do not wanna
Speaker 1:  open this door. Mm. Like you're already in 50 different trade wars. Like
Speaker 1:  don't do this.
Speaker 5:  Is it possible that the door is opened now that just someone has set it out
Speaker 5:  loud? Like do you wonder if there are a bunch of people sitting around
Speaker 5:  in like government boardrooms being like, how did we never think of this?
Speaker 1:  Like they do, but like If you wanna roll up on the United States that way
Speaker 1:  the United States would be like No. Fair.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  But then the United States starts doing it and they're like, okay, tit for
Speaker 1:  ta. Like here we go. Like we're off the races. Like we, the norm has been
Speaker 1:  shattered and like we're, because we're doing trade wars, you, you don't
Speaker 1:  already see it. You can see people be like, we dunno what's gonna happen.
Speaker 1:  But don't don't do that one. We'll see if any of that goes through. We'll
Speaker 1:  see if there's a buyer. We'll see what happens at 75 days. Like 75 days is
Speaker 1:  not a long time to close a deal of this magnitude. No.
Speaker 5:  Even If you had agreed on it already, it would be a short amount of time.
Speaker 1:  Right. And as far, so far as, you know, there's no lead buyer. And then there's
Speaker 1:  the big question of are you selling TikTok US
Speaker 1:  or are you selling by dance? And there's a lot of chatter that
Speaker 1:  the answer is they're gonna sell by dance.
Speaker 5:  Hmm.
Speaker 1:  And so that's a much bigger deal, right. With a much
Speaker 1:  different set of investors. One of whom is Jeff Ya Trump
Speaker 1:  donor, you know, like a lot of his money is set up in by dance not
Speaker 1:  TikTok us. And then there's the question of like, what
Speaker 1:  does control mean? Because the law specifies it can't be under the control
Speaker 1:  of a foreign adversary power and then Trump is supposed to run an
Speaker 1:  inter-agency process to blah blah blah blah blah. Yeah. Okay. Is he
Speaker 1:  gonna, is he gonna do that? So there's just, I don't know man. I think
Speaker 1:  we're, I think we're gonna run to the end of that seven, five days and then
Speaker 1:  we're all just gonna look at each other and it's, who knows
Speaker 5:  It, it really does seem like at the end of day 74 we're
Speaker 5:  still gonna look around and everybody's gonna be like, what happens now?
Speaker 5:  And yeah, no one is going to know like that. It feels like that's where we're
Speaker 5:  headed
Speaker 1:  And that is gonna, you know, not, not that Trump isn't running into
Speaker 1:  the separation of power's problem every single day, but you get to day 74
Speaker 1:  and he is like, I'm extending it again.
Speaker 1:  Bunch of Republican senators are gonna say, no, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 1:  Right. Tom Cotton is gonna be like, no, here's what we're gonna do. We're
Speaker 1:  gonna shoot TikTok in the street. Right. That's where he's already at. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  And so I, yeah, we're just barreling towards
Speaker 1:  a full sale of bite tents, which is nuts to
Speaker 1:  contemplate with the permission of the Chinese government.
Speaker 5:  Byan probably either the first, second or third most valuable
Speaker 5:  startup on earth right now. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Way up there by April. Yeah. And by the time you're listening to to this,
Speaker 1:  it will be very close to February. Like this is just not gonna happen.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 1:  It's crazy to me.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I I really like, we were, we were on the show for a couple of weeks
Speaker 5:  trying to like handicap possibilities and I have given up even trying to
Speaker 5:  guess like I, I couldn't possibly begin to make an
Speaker 5:  educated guess about what's gonna happen here, which is so interesting and
Speaker 5:  also so insane.
Speaker 1:  I do think there's some reasonable likelihood that Microsoft actually goes
Speaker 1:  through with this and tries to do it. They have the money to do it.
Speaker 1:  They have the ability to run the infrastructure. They have Azure, they
Speaker 1:  have consumer market with Xbox users.
Speaker 1:  Like they have a thesis for why they would run it. They have an
Speaker 1:  advertising business. It's fine, not great. Like sure. Meta
Speaker 1:  can't do it for sure. Can't do it for other reasons. We can talk about,
Speaker 1:  but like, you know, the FT C is still pursuing a breakup in that like they're
Speaker 1:  not gonna do it.
Speaker 5:  Would buying by dance be the biggest acquisition in history companies
Speaker 5:  worth, like upwards of $300 billion is the number that keeps being floated
Speaker 1:  Around. I know what the number is,
Speaker 5:  But then I, I've heard numbers for TikTok that are higher than $300 billion.
Speaker 5:  So like by dance by the way, also kind of in the
Speaker 5:  DeepSeek race of putting out much cheaper AI models that can be like,
Speaker 5:  there's a lot happening in that company.
Speaker 1:  There's a lot happening in that company. Also, just the, the
Speaker 1:  chatter that I've heard is the number changes based on who buys it. Mm.
Speaker 1:  Right. So like if Meta or Google
Speaker 1:  buys it, for example, they have gigantic
Speaker 1:  monetization engines that are really, really good. So they
Speaker 1:  don't have to spend any money like getting their money back out.
Speaker 1:  Sure. Right. They just have to deliver ads inside of TikTok and they already
Speaker 1:  have the clients and they already have the tech and they already have the
Speaker 1:  ai like whatever it is that you think they need, they've already, they already
Speaker 1:  have it.
Speaker 5:  It's just really expensive scale essentially. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  They just bought more scale. If you are Amazon even, you gotta
Speaker 1:  go build an entire monetization system, right. So you're gonna pay a lower
Speaker 1:  price 'cause you gotta allocate some money to that stuff. So like how much
Speaker 1:  you're willing to pay, how much it's worth is all based on what you can do
Speaker 1:  with it. And there's only so many companies like, and the two companies that
Speaker 1:  could do the most of it, pay the most are not gonna do it because the government's
Speaker 1:  trying to break 'em up. Yeah. So like literally they're trying to break up
Speaker 1:  Google.
Speaker 5:  Google has to sell Chrome but can have TikTok. Yeah. It's like a
Speaker 5:  very funny outcome.
Speaker 1:  It's nuts. Yeah. Alright, onto the next one. This is a new segment that you're
Speaker 1:  gonna have to get used to in a virtual cast for the next four years. I'm
Speaker 1:  just calling it Brendan Carr is a dummy. Ooh.
Speaker 5:  It's a podcast within a podcast.
Speaker 1:  He's a moron. He is. He is a total
Speaker 1:  political hack job with no conviction and no morals. That's my
Speaker 1:  belief. Brendan, if you're listening you can come on to coder and you can
Speaker 1:  try to prove me wrong, but good luck buddy. He
Speaker 5:  Doesn't even have a cool mug. Like if you're gonna be terrible at this job,
Speaker 5:  at least like have a funny mug. You know what I
Speaker 1:  Mean? You know Ajit Pi, he was a guy. We,
Speaker 1:  he was also a character in the first Trump administration. He had
Speaker 1:  a governor. Like he, there was a line of depravity
Speaker 1:  that he would not cross
Speaker 5:  Fair.
Speaker 1:  Like you could be like, I disagree with this irritatingly
Speaker 1:  Verizon captured conservative Republican commissioner.
Speaker 1:  Brendan is just a political animal. Yeah. Here of two
Speaker 1:  examples this week. And they're just gonna happen every week. 'cause the
Speaker 1:  man loves attention.
Speaker 1:  He is rolling back a rule that allowed people who
Speaker 1:  live in apartment buildings to go get their own internet service.
Speaker 1:  So like a lot of apartment buildings, your landlord would be like,
Speaker 1:  I'm just gonna sign everybody up for whatever ISP, Verizon
Speaker 1:  at t Comcast, whatever. And all of you have to use it and you can't go get
Speaker 1:  your own. And because I have collected this all up together, I'm gonna
Speaker 1:  get a deal. Right. We have, we have some scale English in the
Speaker 1:  ISPs and if you've experienced this, you're like, I don't what
Speaker 1:  like it's just the same number as everything else. Right, right. You're
Speaker 1:  not getting a deal, you're just being lazy or you're getting a kickback from
Speaker 1:  the ISP and you're not passing any of that on like, th this was my
Speaker 1:  experience in an apartment in Chicago was my experience in an apartment in
Speaker 1:  New York. Like same. Yeah. Several. A lot of people have had this experience.
Speaker 1:  Yep. Biden, FCC passes rule says
Speaker 1:  you cannot do bulk billing. You have to increase competition and let
Speaker 1:  people sign up for their own ISPs and apartments. Brendan Carr
Speaker 1:  has revoked this rule and his argument is this will lower prices,
Speaker 5:  Which just on its face doesn't make any sense. It's one of those things that
Speaker 5:  like, I, I can't even make the bad faith
Speaker 5:  argument that that makes sense. You know what I mean? Yeah.
Speaker 1:  Here's a quote. I have ended the F c's consideration of a bride and error
Speaker 1:  proposal that would, could have increased costs by 50% the price that some
Speaker 1:  Americans living in apartments pay for internet service. This is regulatory
Speaker 1:  overreach and it would've artificially raised the cost of our service. There
Speaker 1:  is not a world in which letting people choose their service provider
Speaker 1:  raises a surprise. There's a, I might choose world, world mean expensive.
Speaker 1:  One world in which you live in an apartment, that building that's so big.
Speaker 1:  Then you have a landlord that's so good that maybe they were
Speaker 1:  negotiating a terrific rate. I don't know anybody who lives in
Speaker 1:  an apartment. Yeah, no,
Speaker 5:  There's there's one of those in America and that's the one Brina car is
Speaker 5:  talking about.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I just, I'm like, what this do you mean by a political animal? Like
Speaker 1:  he's straight up saying, reducing your experience of broadband
Speaker 1:  competition will lower prices.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's ridiculous. Alright. What was the other one you said? There were
Speaker 5:  two pure
Speaker 1:  Doublespeak. All right, well there's two actually there's two other ones.
Speaker 1:  The, the second one is he's reopened investigations
Speaker 1:  into N-B-C-A-B-C and CBS's broadcast license. It was very
Speaker 1:  complicated 'cause the stations have them, not the networks but Socos
Speaker 1:  and in particular he opened up the NBC one because he says they
Speaker 1:  violated the equal time rule by having Kamala Harris on and Tim Kane
Speaker 1:  on Saturday Night Live.
Speaker 5:  Oh right.
Speaker 1:  Do you remember this whole
Speaker 5:  Thing? This was like last fall that he got all fussy about it. Yep.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And so on her way out the door, Biden's FCC chair Jessica
Speaker 1:  Rosenworcel just like wipes out these investigations. She's like, these are
Speaker 1:  stupid. I know they're politically motivated. We're not doing this. He's
Speaker 1:  reopened them,
Speaker 1:  whatever you could say, whatever. About two of them, they're, they're dumb,
Speaker 1:  but in particular the NBC one, he knows
Speaker 1:  that NBC complied with the rule because he has emailed people
Speaker 1:  and said that they have, this is such a brazen
Speaker 1:  lie. Yeah. Right. He's like, they had her
Speaker 1:  on, they complied with the rule, here's their notice. And then immediately
Speaker 1:  had Trump on a NASCAR race the next day because they gave the proper notice
Speaker 1:  and the campaign took adv advantage of it. He know, I
Speaker 1:  know he knows it. 'cause I've seen the email and he is reopened it to be
Speaker 1:  like I'm investigate. Like this is just total political theater for an audience
Speaker 5:  Of one. It's just, yeah.
Speaker 1:  And like this is dangerous First Amendment territory. I don't like this
Speaker 1:  speech, so I will cost you money is not what you want any government,
Speaker 1:  it doesn't matter If you like Kamala Harris, you love Donald Trump, you hate
Speaker 1:  one, you love, it doesn't matter. Unelected bureaucrat saying, I will cost
Speaker 1:  this money, I will make this painful because I don't like your
Speaker 1:  political speech is red flashing warning
Speaker 1:  light of free speech problems. Yeah. And then on top of that,
Speaker 1:  just as we sat down to record, Carr announced investigations into
Speaker 1:  NPR and PBS. Okay. 'cause he says they are illegally
Speaker 1:  advertising and what he specifically means is that they do fundraisers.
Speaker 1:  And so there his line is taxpayer should not pay
Speaker 1:  for commercial activity. And then, you know, the usual
Speaker 1:  garbage about woke Sesame Street. Right. Or woke NPR,
Speaker 1:  he's attacking NPR in particular because the CEO of NPR is
Speaker 1:  Katherine Maher who used to run Wikipedia and the conservatives
Speaker 1:  hate Wikipedia right now. And so this is just Brendan Carr
Speaker 1:  trying to chill speech. Right. He's like, I will defund
Speaker 1:  PBS and NPR because they, because I've constructed a legal reality in
Speaker 1:  which them doing fundraising drives or saying we're supported by viewers
Speaker 1:  like you call us to give us money, is advertising for an agenda.
Speaker 5:  Right. With, and all of that is transparently not since, but it maybe it
Speaker 5:  doesn't matter because he's in charge of
Speaker 1:  The ffc. It doesn't matter in, in like the alternate reality of x where this
Speaker 1:  man is trying to build a profile. And I'm tell like if he, Brendan,
Speaker 1:  I know you pay attention to us, you have for years, you wanna come on decoder
Speaker 1:  and explain this like craven political bullshit when
Speaker 1:  you are playing with the absolute fire of the First amendment and claiming
Speaker 1:  you'll do it. Come on, I'll talk to you. But it's not gonna,
Speaker 1:  it's not gonna be easy. 'cause I think this stuff is incredibly transparent.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I also, this is not important in the scheme of things, but like
Speaker 5:  If you find yourself against Sesame Street, like in any way business
Speaker 5:  politics, like if you're canceling Sesame Street or you're mad
Speaker 5:  at like you've done something wrong, like just,
Speaker 5:  it's not good. You shouldn't be against Sesame Street. That's, that's it.
Speaker 5:  That's all I have to say. Sesame Street is great.
Speaker 1:  It's pretty straightforward.
Speaker 5:  Leave Sesame Street alone.
Speaker 1:  I'll stop. It's lightning ground. We gotta move on.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Oh, but I have another super fun, deeply craven
Speaker 5:  political speech thing. Oh good. Do you wanna talk about it real fast? Love
Speaker 1:  It. My favorite
Speaker 5:  Meta agreed to pay $25 million to settle
Speaker 5:  the, the Trump suit over suspending his account after January 6th,
Speaker 5:  which is just like in a sea of Mark
Speaker 5:  Zuckerberg nakedly sucking up to Trump for business reasons. This is the
Speaker 5:  simplest one yet. Yeah. Like, here's a bunch of money, please be nice. And
Speaker 5:  then there was some reporting that Trump was basically like,
Speaker 5:  I think what he said is like, we have to settle this lawsuit before I can
Speaker 5:  like bring you into the, into the fold. I think he called it the nest. Into
Speaker 5:  the nest.
Speaker 5:  And it's just like this, this was the price of admission, right? Like this
Speaker 5:  is what happened at the inauguration. They all spent a bunch of money to
Speaker 5:  hang out with him and go to parties and he would say nice things and, and
Speaker 5:  now meta is just spending another $25 million to make Donald Trump
Speaker 5:  like them, because that is worth it.
Speaker 1:  Can I just say why this one is like particularly galling to me? Meta
Speaker 1:  would've definitely won, right? The theory of this
Speaker 1:  case Yeah. Is that meta
Speaker 1:  when it banned Donald Trump was somehow the government and that
Speaker 1:  violated Trump's first amendment rights. Right. And I would Which is nonsense.
Speaker 1:  Which is nonsense for the very simple reason that the
Speaker 1:  president at the time met Aban Trump from its platform was
Speaker 1:  Trump.
Speaker 5:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  He was the government at that it turns out. Yeah. He
Speaker 1:  Was super, the gov like, you don't even have to get to the like pedantic
Speaker 1:  forum stuff of like the First Amendment is about the government not slash
Speaker 1:  like I can do that all day. I I was, I was raised in that
Speaker 1:  fire. I'm just saying this one is particularly stupid
Speaker 1:  because you're like meta acting on orders from the government who was
Speaker 1:  me illegally abandoning. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  It's so stupid. He's lost other versions of this case.
Speaker 1:  But this, this is everyone is doing, there's other cases that he would've
Speaker 1:  A, B, C settled one, Disney, A, B, C, settled one. They're just trying to
Speaker 1:  get out of the line of fire. 'cause he controls the regulatory agencies.
Speaker 5:  Right. All these companies have decided it's worth the money. And the thing
Speaker 5:  is, they're, they're right. Right. Like I would say pretty transparently.
Speaker 5:  You, you can make the case that this is just a good use of
Speaker 5:  $25 million for meta, which is,
Speaker 1:  Yeah, this is a sneeze
Speaker 5:  Has a lot of complicated cases going on. There are antitrust questions about
Speaker 5:  meta. Trump has threatened to throw Mark Zuckerberg in jail a bunch of times.
Speaker 5:  Like I can see why you write this check. It just sucks.
Speaker 5:  Like it just sucks so much that this is the state of things
Speaker 5:  right now. I
Speaker 1:  Mean, yeah. The FTC is gonna try that. Their antitrust case to break up Metas
Speaker 1:  coming the various teen health cases about
Speaker 1:  Instagram causing mental health crises across the country.
Speaker 1:  They're all coming up. You can, If you have an angry
Speaker 1:  Trump who's like, break him up and you can get outta that for
Speaker 1:  $25 million. Yeah. Yes. Done. There's a ruthless cynicism here. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  But man, we are, I'm, we are just playing with fire with the First Amendment
Speaker 1:  right now. Like left and right. Yep. We're, we are doing weird
Speaker 1:  speech regulations and claiming to do them in the name of free speech.
Speaker 1:  Weird. Super weird. Yeah. All right. We gotta end with a happy one.
Speaker 5:  Blue sky.
Speaker 1:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I'm happy Blue Sky's working. I have, I'm all in on Blue Sky. I was was
Speaker 5:  wait.
Speaker 1:  Just the concept of Blue Sky. Last Blue sky.
Speaker 5:  Happy Sky has 30 million years there. You,
Speaker 1:  I was like, there's news, right? Not just knowledge, like I logged into Blue
Speaker 1:  Sky.
Speaker 5:  It's growing. Yeah. Threads is much bigger. Threads
Speaker 5:  massively bigger. Continues to add a million people a day. It has
Speaker 5:  320 million is the number Mark Zuckerberg gave on the earnings call this
Speaker 5:  week. That's a gigantic number.
Speaker 5:  But Blue sky blue Sky's the fun one now I think we can say pretty,
Speaker 1:  Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Certainly that like Blue Sky has replaced Twitter as the
Speaker 5:  place that is fun to hang out. And it is true. It's a bunch of like liberals
Speaker 5:  being annoying to each other. Super annoying. But in addition to that, this
Speaker 5:  is a group of
Speaker 1:  People. It's also a lot of that does not love jokes. No.
Speaker 5:  Like
Speaker 1:  Yeah. That's, at least that's why it's Experie. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  But like a, I'm psyched that there are multiple versions of this thing
Speaker 5:  that are succeeding. I think it would've been a bummer if we had just replaced
Speaker 5:  Twitter with one thing. The fact that there are a few different cuts at this
Speaker 5:  that are gonna work is really exciting. Mark Zuckerberg also made noise about
Speaker 5:  wanting to make the OG Facebook experience come back,
Speaker 5:  which that's not gonna happen. Like, sorry Mark, you ruined
Speaker 5:  that 15 years ago. But like Blue sky man,
Speaker 5:  blue sky I think has hit like, escape velocity in that this thing is gonna
Speaker 5:  work and it's here. People are building stuff on the protocol. People are
Speaker 5:  using the app. Are they? It's coming. Yeah. I don't
Speaker 5:  remember what, but they're doing it.
Speaker 1:  I would say I've, I, I'm a blue sky person. My harshest criticism Blue sky
Speaker 1:  is for all the promises of that protocol and how open it is.
Speaker 1:  There's not one other server.
Speaker 5:  No there's not. But there are people just gimme there. But people building,
Speaker 5:  somebody built a cool blue Sky EE app that just looks like Instagram
Speaker 5:  and it just takes photo posts. Like that's cool. That's the fedi verse baby.
Speaker 5:  Gimme weird ideas about how to look at Blue Sky. I'm in.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. But that's all just like API front end views. Listen,
Speaker 5:  I want
Speaker 1:  One other place to log
Speaker 5:  In one thing at a time.
Speaker 1:  Man. I wanna post. Maybe that's gonna be the ver
Speaker 5:  You said good news. Let's end on good news.
Speaker 1:  Okay. Good news. We're happy the Fedi verse is
Speaker 1:  around.
Speaker 1:  Here we go. I like it. I do like it. I do love an open source weird
Speaker 1:  pebble hack. And I do love a weird band of misfit,
Speaker 1:  decentralized social media hackers. That's the good stuff. Hell
Speaker 1:  yeah. That's the rebel stuff. Well, you know, the bad thing happens. That's
Speaker 1:  what we want. Send us more. This is your, send us more weird
Speaker 1:  rebel technology. Right. That stuff. That's your, that's your
Speaker 1:  homework for this week. And we, we'll
Speaker 6:  Play the voicemails next week. Love it. All right. That's it. We got, we're
Speaker 6:  way over time. That's The Vergecast. Bye Carl.
Speaker 6:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 6:  you. Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one.
Speaker 6:  The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network.
Speaker 6:  Our show is produced by Will Por, Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer. And
Speaker 6:  that's it. We'll see you next week.