# Transcript
ID: 37d896f9-6620-4623-a781-6b594c0fa47f
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/7218256074197170703/5989486234300082894/s93290-US-6469s-1745573315.mp3
Description: Some weeks, it just feels like everything is up in the air all at the same time. Nilay and David are joined by The Verge’s Jake Kastrenakes to talk about all the unrest, starting with the ever-changing tariff rules that are making gadgets hard to price, hard to find, and hard to bet on going forward. (Maybe that’s why it seems everyone on Earth tried to pre-order a Switch 2 this week.) After that, the hosts catch up on the Meta and Google antitrust trials happening this week, and try to figure out who might be interested in the internet’s most popular browser. Finally, in the lightning round, we talk Brendan Carr (who is a dummy), the wood-backed Motorola Razr Ultra, and the 20th anniversary of YouTube.
Speaker 5:  Hello and welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast, winning the Levy
Speaker 5:  Awards. David, tell 'em, tell 'em what we've won. We are the
Speaker 6:  Flagship podcast of the Webby Awards. I think that's what they told us. Yeah.
Speaker 6:  Thank you to everybody who voted. We won two Webby Awards, which are the
Speaker 6:  same award, but different awards for best
Speaker 6:  technology podcast. Basically there's like the Judges' award and there's
Speaker 6:  the People's Choice Award. We care a lot more about the People's Choice Award,
Speaker 6:  but it's like, you know what, if, if there's an award, you might as well
Speaker 6:  win it. You know what I mean? Yeah. And we did, we won them both. It was
Speaker 6:  very exciting. We're gonna get another one of those cool springy
Speaker 6:  statues. I'm very excited about that. Thank you to everybody who voted. I
Speaker 6:  know everybody like tolerated us begging for votes for several weeks. So
Speaker 6:  I I, I appreciate everybody who voted and we're very excited that we won
Speaker 6:  and
Speaker 5:  Shouts to everyone else in the category. We appreciate our fellow nominees.
Speaker 5:  We defeated you.
Speaker 6:  I will say there are some like, sincerely very good podcasts in that group.
Speaker 6:  The EFF has had a podcast that was, I think came in second to us. It's very
Speaker 6:  good, but was resoundingly defeated by The Verge cast as were
Speaker 6:  all of our, we're
Speaker 5:  Trying so hard be gracious winners and we're
Speaker 1:  Not.
Speaker 6:  And I will say the number one piece of feedback that we got was that the
Speaker 6:  Webbys needs a new award for best podcast within a podcast, and we are going
Speaker 6:  to win it next year. But we'll get to that later.
Speaker 5:  That's how, you know, I, we had the, the president of the Grammys on decoder,
Speaker 5:  like just before Grammy nominees were announced. And I was like, do you just
Speaker 5:  keep inventing categories so Beyonce can win them? And he was like,
Speaker 6:  Yes,
Speaker 5:  I'm open to it. I'm just, I'm putting, you gotta put the energy in the world
Speaker 5:  to collect it in return. You know what I'm saying? Yeah. Anyway, I'm a friend
Speaker 5:  Eli. That's David Pierce. J Kakis is here.
Speaker 6:  Hey, good to be here.
Speaker 5:  A lot going on this week. We, we, we should try to unpack what happened
Speaker 5:  with Nintendo Switch to pre-orders. Gadgets are appearing and
Speaker 5:  disappearing and prices are vanishing. We're not being announced
Speaker 5:  'cause of tariffs. We have to make a list of who might be able to buy Chrome
Speaker 5:  because Google is on trial. So is meta
Speaker 5:  just a lot going on in our nation's courthouse? Literally the same courthouse,
Speaker 5:  both trials in the same courthouse.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Like down the hall from each other, essentially. Yeah. It's very funny.
Speaker 6:  Our,
Speaker 5:  Our boy Brendan continues to speak or not speak that's
Speaker 5:  coming up and then there's a a, a found made of what
Speaker 5:  That's true. Just a lot, just a lot in this episode of, but I wanna start
Speaker 5:  with listener feedback and, and what I would
Speaker 5:  consider an investigation, like a crowdsourced listener
Speaker 5:  investigation. So there's evidence, as you all know, that
Speaker 5:  the party speaker market is hot. And the only evidence that
Speaker 5:  we have of this is that these companies keep making
Speaker 5:  them
Speaker 5:  like we're five generations into party speakers. They keep getting bigger.
Speaker 5:  People add more lights to them, more models are put out
Speaker 5:  buttons to make them make more and less base or added and removed at
Speaker 5:  random times. There's something happening here to justify all this
Speaker 5:  investment. And we are the locus
Speaker 5:  of, I think, the single most important body of analytics
Speaker 5:  information about the part party speaker market in the tech industry today.
Speaker 5:  Because everyone keeps sending us pictures of party speakers when
Speaker 6:  I see them.
Speaker 7:  This investigation is going to win us the next webby.
Speaker 6:  A hundred
Speaker 5:  Percent. It is remarkable that no one has one, but everyone sees them everywhere
Speaker 5:  and then sends us photos of them. So we, we've got two this week one
Speaker 5:  we are gonna ask for more information about, if you know about this, I think
Speaker 5:  this is directly related to our nation's war fighting capability, but
Speaker 5:  Sam emails to say, I know a huge target
Speaker 5:  for the party speaker market. It is the US military and the
Speaker 5:  US militaries in all capital letters. I'm in the Navy and the ship has at
Speaker 5:  least a dozen party speakers that they loan out on deployments
Speaker 5:  and such one dozen speakers per ship rules.
Speaker 6:  This is rules, this is perfect. You have a bunch of, you know,
Speaker 6:  strapping gentlemen who can, who can carry enormous
Speaker 6:  speakers. So that helps. And,
Speaker 6:  and you
Speaker 5:  Know, that's not, there's not like SEAL team six with party speaker.
Speaker 6:  There's just one person in every platoon who just carries the party speaker.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And they're out in the world. They're doing
Speaker 6:  stuff, they're busy, they can't be tied down by short
Speaker 5:  America's greatest sex sport is our culture and our nation's military is
Speaker 5:  just playing bangers on beaches around the world. If you're in the
Speaker 5:  military. Sam, tell us more. Sam offered to tell us more. So I'm asking,
Speaker 5:  tell, tell us more. Are there fights? Is there a line to get the one dozen
Speaker 5:  speakers? Are there one dozen speakers per boat?
Speaker 5:  Ooh, are there more on aircraft carriers? Fewer on, I don't know, other
Speaker 5:  kinds of boats.
Speaker 6:  This suggests that there, somewhere in the Pentagon there is a budget line
Speaker 6:  for party speakers
Speaker 5:  And it hasn't been cut by Doge.
Speaker 6:  Right.
Speaker 5:  See what I'm saying? Like Elon looked at it and was like
Speaker 5:  up number go up
Speaker 6:  Just sounds right. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Two dozen per boat. Okay, so that's one you're dying to know more.
Speaker 5:  If you can send me a picture of a party speaker on an aircraft carrier with
Speaker 5:  a jet going off in the background, I think we might be done here. That might
Speaker 5:  be the end of our
Speaker 6:  Goals.
Speaker 5:  That's fix three. Okay. So that's one second. Matthew
Speaker 5:  sent a photo of a giant Sony party speaker in the wild
Speaker 5:  in the rain at a soccer clinic. And he says, I've
Speaker 5:  included my five-year-old daughter for size comparison. He grinds his permission
Speaker 5:  on the photo, we're gonna put smiley face over the face face.
Speaker 5:  He, he goes on to say this thing sounded like shit intermittent Bluetooth
Speaker 5:  connection maybe, but I enjoyed its very existence.
Speaker 6:  It's fabulous. It
Speaker 5:  Is true that the speaker is almost as big as the 5-year-old. Five year olds.
Speaker 5:  Very cute as well, by the way. And
Speaker 6:  To my previous point, it looks photoshopped like, we'll we'll show this on
Speaker 6:  YouTube if, if you're watching this, but I still
Speaker 6:  have not seen a picture in which the party speaker does not look like it
Speaker 6:  was photoshopped in after the fact. And It is like a preposterously large
Speaker 6:  alien from outer space that has just been inserted into this photo.
Speaker 5:  Send me photos, send me photos of frat house basements of car dealerships,
Speaker 5:  soccer tournaments. Again, aircraft carriers. Extremely welcome.
Speaker 5:  We're just gonna keep talking about this. The mainstream media won't talk
Speaker 5:  about this, they're all about ai. But I'm saying look at the amount of
Speaker 5:  investment and effort that has gone into giant party speakers over the
Speaker 5:  past five years.
Speaker 6:  And this isn't VC funding, this is just pure capitalism. Yeah. This is like
Speaker 6:  the Sony party speaker is at the end of the hype cycle. Yeah. Which means
Speaker 6:  It is only sustainable based on pure
Speaker 6:  unadulterated success.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. This is the, the, the robots aren't trying to bang Kevin Rus on the
Speaker 5:  front page of the New York Times. This is us saying on the ground, the real
Speaker 5:  people are demanding speakers the size of their children and the market is
Speaker 5:  providing it to them.
Speaker 5:  Look at it. Don't look away.
Speaker 5:  Alright. Seriously, if you see one said it's delightful every time It is,
Speaker 5:  it's very good. Some of you send photos of things that are not party speakers,
Speaker 5:  they're just speakers, which I also appreciate that people see speakers in
Speaker 5:  the world and they think of me. I lo I love you.
Speaker 5:  Thank you. But we, you know, you know what we want Exercise
Speaker 5:  and judgment.
Speaker 5:  Alright, let's talk about the switch two. It David, you were
Speaker 5:  saying just before we, we started recording, everyone knew this would happen
Speaker 5:  and it happened, but it also felt like chaos.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. This feels like it, it's sort of inevitable, right? I think
Speaker 6:  it, it's been clear for a long time that the switch to is, is a
Speaker 6:  giant hit that a lot of people are gonna want very badly. Right. And then
Speaker 6:  they were supposed to go on pre-order two weeks ago and then that got delayed
Speaker 6:  for a bunch of Taree reasons, but they finally went on
Speaker 6:  sale or on pre-order what, Wednesday night into Thursday.
Speaker 6:  And it was midnight East coast. Like an alarming
Speaker 6:  amount of our staff is, is just useless today because they
Speaker 6:  were up late last night trying to order a Switch to,
Speaker 6:  and it was on sale at a bunch of places. We had folks checking at Target,
Speaker 6:  we had folks checking at Best Buy at Walmart. It was GameStop
Speaker 6:  I think like did it, but was coming later. And it was, it was at first
Speaker 6:  just a huge gigantic mess right There were like, there were, we
Speaker 6:  had people on our team who were like in a line to get in the line, you know,
Speaker 6:  the thing they do with like concert tickets now where they're like, here's
Speaker 6:  the, here's the queue before we put you in the queue to buy tickets. Oh yeah.
Speaker 6:  And they did that, but then they, it would just punt you back to the beginning
Speaker 6:  of the line when you got to the end of, it's like total mess. But then
Speaker 6:  it seemed like somewhere between like 45 and 60 minutes
Speaker 6:  in, so like right around 1:00 AM Eastern, all the systems just
Speaker 6:  sort of turned on. And at least on our team, I think everybody who
Speaker 6:  wanted one got one. And so it just, it it was a mess
Speaker 6:  and then it worked.
Speaker 5:  Sure. I mean that's, that's better than what, what usually happens, which
Speaker 5:  is it's a mess and then a spate of apologies are issued
Speaker 5:  and then no one gets one.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Yeah. Jake, did you try, you didn't try to get one, did you?
Speaker 7:  I, I did and I think I am the only person in the United States
Speaker 7:  who had a good experience. I I was like, really? I know I normally go to
Speaker 7:  bed like around midnight, so I'm like, yeah, whatever. We'll see what happens.
Speaker 7:  So a minute rolls around, I open up Target, hit the button all good.
Speaker 7:  I signed in the next morning and everything's on fire and everybody's just
Speaker 7:  like, like it took it outta my cart. They canceled my order later.
Speaker 7:  Yeah. It, it seems like it was a disaster for everybody except for me. And
Speaker 7:  so I'm so sorry. I don't even wanna play Mario Kart. I I
Speaker 7:  feel like I don't deserve to have had that experience, but
Speaker 7:  yeah, I, it seems to me that there is just like maybe fundamentally no
Speaker 7:  way to open a webpage and have like
Speaker 7:  10 million people hit it at once and just like execute it. Well it like
Speaker 7:  this every single time this happens and it never goes well. And I don't know
Speaker 7:  that there's a solution for it. There
Speaker 6:  Is some really complicated infrastructural thing going on that I would love
Speaker 6:  to know the answer to because like, one of the things that a bunch of folks
Speaker 6:  on our team found was, I believe it was Antonio de Benedetto, his wife
Speaker 6:  just opened up the target app and bought one just, just like nothing. Totally
Speaker 6:  fine. Yeah. Everybody else is like melting servers across America and she
Speaker 6:  just sort of like haphazardly wandered her way into a switch too. Do you
Speaker 5:  Think it's, if you look like a bot, the bot honeypots trap you. And so
Speaker 5:  like, Jake doesn't look like a bot. 'cause he wasn't like try, he
Speaker 5:  didn't have like eight webpages open already. And Antonio's wife
Speaker 5:  didn't look like a bot. She just like opened Target and was there and it
Speaker 5:  was like, oh, you're not a bot. Like, come on in. Meanwhile,
Speaker 6:  Shy and Hollister shared a screenshot of him with like every store on the
Speaker 6:  internet
Speaker 5:  Open at the same time. You see what what I'm saying, it's like you look more
Speaker 5:  like a bot than not. Like let's see how committed you are. 'cause that's
Speaker 5:  the, that's the real root of all the problem, right? Is they all wanna stop
Speaker 5:  bot farms and scalpers. And it sounds like, Jake, you're gonna become a
Speaker 5:  flipper now.
Speaker 7:  Oh yeah. I I, how dare you. Like I could take it or leave it, you
Speaker 5:  Know, but like that even in ticketing, like this is the problem.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. That you, you wanna stop all these bad actors from automating their
Speaker 5:  way into buying all the inventory and reselling it. And so I, it feels like
Speaker 5:  that was happening with a switch too.
Speaker 5:  But it also feels like now the people are starting to look like bots
Speaker 5:  and getting sent into like bot hell.
Speaker 7:  I mean, people are acting like bots, right? Because everybody knows that
Speaker 7:  they're up against the bots. And so like everybody has a hundred tabs open
Speaker 7:  and there's just like, what is the solution to that? The solution to that
Speaker 7:  is like, I, I mean you build competent ticketing,
Speaker 7:  like line weighting infrastructure. You have like a, I don't know, a randomized
Speaker 7:  lottery system ahead of time, which
Speaker 6:  Didn't work. Nintendo was like, we'll, issue invites. And then right before
Speaker 6:  pre-order start Nintendo was like, oh, just kidding. We might invite you
Speaker 6:  like a long time from now.
Speaker 7:  Well, and did you see the numbers in Japan? It is incredible.
Speaker 7:  So I think this is from Dom's article,
Speaker 7:  I believe that in, what was it, eight years ago when the
Speaker 7:  original switch came out, it was something like, they sold
Speaker 7:  360,000 switch units in Japan within the first month.
Speaker 7:  And so, you know, I, who knows how they estimated how
Speaker 7:  many they would need in Japan this time around, but they put out this press
Speaker 7:  release saying, Hey, we might not have enough for
Speaker 7:  the lottery that we announced because 2.2 million
Speaker 7:  people have applied Whoa. Which I will say is a lot more switches
Speaker 7:  than last time. So Yeah. I I like no wonder they're having a hard time.
Speaker 5:  There's also just the additional pent up demand of
Speaker 5:  I better lock in this price now before tariffs arrive.
Speaker 7:  Oh, big time. Yeah. Yeah. Because like I, I believe Nintendo like
Speaker 7:  a, a week ago or something like that, when they finally said, Hey, we're
Speaker 7:  gonna start up pre-orders again that they have like a line in
Speaker 7:  their press release. So they're just like, this is the price for now. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  And it's like, yeah. Like I, I don't blame them. I I appreciate the like
Speaker 7:  limited transparency there just, they have no idea what's gonna happen. Right.
Speaker 6:  And I think it's, there's a chance that not only is the price gonna go up,
Speaker 6:  but it might be much harder to get this thing at. Yeah. At some point in
Speaker 6:  the relative near future. Like there is the, the sort of shock of the supply
Speaker 6:  chain that is coming if and when all this tariff stuff becomes real
Speaker 6:  rightly makes everybody nervous. And we're already starting to see the fallout
Speaker 6:  of some of that stuff.
Speaker 5:  It's interesting that the things that went up, like major appliance purchases,
Speaker 5:  skyrocketed, car purchases have skyrocketed. We have a story about
Speaker 5:  that and it, and then there was like Nintendo Switch to panic buying
Speaker 5:  occurred, like all, all at the same time. David, it appears you
Speaker 5:  bought a Mac and for some reason
Speaker 6:  I did. I I went and panic bot is a little
Speaker 6:  strong, but like it's a thing I was gonna need to do in a year and instead
Speaker 6:  I just did it today I bought a new MacBook Air that already I have not even
Speaker 6:  turned it on and it has fingerprints all over it. Perfect. So that's good
Speaker 6:  stuff. But yeah, there is, there is a real, there is a
Speaker 6:  real sort of lingering sense of like, many things have not
Speaker 6:  changed yet, but the confusion just
Speaker 6:  continues to get so much more confusing that like, folks I talk to all the
Speaker 6:  time are like, look, the only responsible thing we can tell you to do is
Speaker 6:  if you want something just go get it. Yeah. Like, it, It is, it might be
Speaker 6:  fine.
Speaker 5:  That's not advice I need to hear. I I wanna
Speaker 6:  Be clear about this, but it like, it, it, there is like a better than 50%
Speaker 6:  chance that it will be fine, but it's not like a lot better than 50. Do
Speaker 6:  you know what I mean? And so it's like, okay, if you're at a point where
Speaker 6:  you need something where it's sort of a coin flip of like, is It,
Speaker 6:  is it just gonna be sitting on the shelf at this price for you in six months?
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I bought a Mac studio as I've been threatening to do for did weeks on this
Speaker 5:  show. Yeah. I bought a base model Mac studio and I upgraded the storage in
Speaker 5:  it, which made it a custom order. And I watched that thing
Speaker 5:  sit at the, at the dock in China. Oh wow. Going through customs
Speaker 5:  waiting to see Oof. I watched the DHL shipping page.
Speaker 5:  It, it's here. It's, it's, it's a delight. It's so much more computer than
Speaker 5:  I need. Like every time I push it and the fan comes on, I'm like, I don't
Speaker 5:  deserve this.
Speaker 7:  How many local AI models do you run?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, just all, it's just talking to me all day long just to
Speaker 7:  Distract. I I'm actually neli vibe coded me. I'm, I'm not here.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's, it's vastly more computer than a, and the old iMac is sitting
Speaker 5:  here and I am gonna in fact peel out the guts and try to make it a display.
Speaker 5:  It's, I'm gonna break It is what I'm gonna do, but it's, it's, but I didn't
Speaker 5:  need to buy it like you David. I was like, at some point I'm gonna do this
Speaker 5:  and then all this happened and I don't know, I just, I didn't, I didn't need
Speaker 5:  a lot of push. It sounds like you didn't need a lot of push either.
Speaker 6:  No, I needed exactly zero push. I needed a reason to be out
Speaker 6:  of my house this morning is what I needed. My, it worked out great,
Speaker 6:  but there, but It is a real thing. It's like I, I have a laptop that is kind
Speaker 6:  of on its last legs and would like to know that
Speaker 6:  the laptop I need is the right thing. I mean, it's like, I used to make fun
Speaker 6:  of Walt Mossberg years ago because he bought I think
Speaker 6:  like at least two, but maybe even several of the last
Speaker 6:  MacBook Air before they put in the butterfly keyboard. Yep. And his
Speaker 6:  excuse is always like, I might need another laptop and I don't wanna have
Speaker 6:  a crappy one. And I sort of feel that way now too. Like, yeah, I don't need
Speaker 6:  this thing today, but I will need it eventually and I would like it to
Speaker 6:  be here.
Speaker 7:  Well the other thing is like, you know, the reason you wait is you think,
Speaker 7:  okay, I'm gonna, like, the price is gonna go down and, and, and at the very
Speaker 7:  least we know that is not going to happen. So if, if, if you're okay with
Speaker 7:  suffering whatever the standard price is and you're just going to buy it
Speaker 7:  like six months from now or a year from now, it's like Hmm. The, the gamble
Speaker 7:  becomes a lot more appealing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And we're, again, we're seeing this all over the place and then we're
Speaker 5:  also seeing just some companies opting out,
Speaker 5:  right? Amber Brunick, which makes a bunch of Game Boy clones, which are ably
Speaker 5:  legal anyway. They're like, we can't do this anymore. Like they, they just
Speaker 5:  halted all shipments. There's another one called A A YN,
Speaker 5:  they're pausing their shipments of basically Game Boy clones.
Speaker 5:  Those companies were always under threat. Like we, we've been talking and
Speaker 5:  writing about those companies, like they're in a very gray area legally where
Speaker 5:  it feels like the addition of tariffs to their existing risk.
Speaker 5:  It is like, just makes that not a good business to be in. And so like why
Speaker 5:  wouldn't they just stop and so like get some certainty. We have a big story
Speaker 5:  about just general confusion in the auto industry
Speaker 5:  about what parts of cars are gonna get,
Speaker 5:  what tariffs from China. The Trump administration is pausing and un pausing
Speaker 5:  tariffs. They've announced that they're in talks and then the Chinese government
Speaker 5:  said they're not in talks. You can watch the stock market just go up and
Speaker 5:  down just begging. Like literally the stock market is
Speaker 5:  just begging for someone to tell them some, some good news. I keep joking
Speaker 5:  that all of CNBC right now is just a long podcast about a shitty chart.
Speaker 5:  And like, I like literal and It is great. It's the most compelling television
Speaker 5:  you can watch because every day someone's like, do you know what's going
Speaker 5:  on this chart? And or else Sarkin is like, I don't know. And like that's
Speaker 5:  the whole, it's eight hours of CNBC. Elizabeth Warren
Speaker 5:  is basically asking Apple if they finagled a tariff exception
Speaker 5:  because that is corruption like pretty straightforwardly
Speaker 5:  I would say. We have some reporting, it's not totally locked down that a
Speaker 5:  lot of tech companies are asking for tariff exceptions. And this isn't just
Speaker 5:  Tim Cook being special, we're trying to nail it down. But
Speaker 5:  that's just happening, right? Like different companies are getting different
Speaker 5:  messages about what will get tariffed and what won't get tariffed. The major
Speaker 5:  retailers, like, I think it's Walmart and Target and Best Buy all went
Speaker 5:  to the White House and said our our shells will be empty and the the tariffs
Speaker 5:  have pulled back. There's just a lot going on here that seems to
Speaker 5:  indicate like you're saying David, that come a few months from now, there
Speaker 5:  might not be stuff Yeah. Because no one is shipping things to the United States
Speaker 5:  right now.
Speaker 6:  Right. I think it was it, it was DHL right? That just stopped taking deliveries
Speaker 6:  to the US over $800 because it, again, everybody's just at this point where
Speaker 6:  it's like this, we don't know what's happening. We don't
Speaker 6:  know the rules, we don't know what it's gonna be like tomorrow. And so
Speaker 6:  the, the risk of literally putting something on a boat from
Speaker 6:  China is too high because we don't know what the situation's going to be
Speaker 6:  like when it gets there. Like It is. It's that simple and
Speaker 6:  crazy. And I will say it's worth pointing out over and over again that this
Speaker 6:  is precisely the point, right? Like this is the thing that President
Speaker 6:  Trump keeps saying is that this is all about leverage. He wants them to come
Speaker 6:  to him and try to make a deal the, the, the flying to Mar-a-Lago to
Speaker 6:  beg him to make a tariff exemption so that he feels powerful and special.
Speaker 6:  That's the whole point. And the, the confusion and the chaos is
Speaker 6:  the thing that they are doing here on purpose. But what we're seeing
Speaker 6:  is it has just absolutely frozen everybody.
Speaker 6:  Like I, I got a Bowers and Wilkins launched new headphones
Speaker 6:  today and I got an email from a comms person just like, you know,
Speaker 6:  sending along the press release and a picture being like, Hey, we launched
Speaker 6:  a new thing. And it just says, due to the uncertainty at the tariff situation,
Speaker 6:  pricing and availability are not available at this time. However, a notify
Speaker 6:  me button will be placed on the Bowers and Wilkins website for customers
Speaker 6:  who wish to purchase the product. So literally the best you can do for a
Speaker 6:  pair of headphones you want that a lot of people are gonna like and are gonna
Speaker 6:  be very good is click a button that says, tell me when you know how much
Speaker 6:  this thing is gonna cost. Like that's, that's where we are and we're starting
Speaker 6:  to see that a lot of places that like over and over
Speaker 6:  we're just going to get things that that companies have made but
Speaker 6:  literally don't know if or how to sell them to you. Yeah. And
Speaker 6:  that's wild.
Speaker 7:  I think we're gonna see a lot of companies waiting till the absolute last
Speaker 7:  second to declare what their pricing is.
Speaker 7:  'cause again, like you, you don't even know if the
Speaker 7:  day you announced your pricing things are gonna change.
Speaker 6:  Right. That was the Nintendo thing, right? They they launched it in what,
Speaker 6:  April? They
Speaker 7:  Launched it the day the tariffs were announced.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And for a product that's coming out in two months and, and like I I
Speaker 6:  bet they regret that decision.
Speaker 7:  Oh yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So Ryan Peterson is the CEO of Flexport, which is a soft well
Speaker 5:  shipping software company that a lot of people use them to manage how things
Speaker 5:  get across the world. He was just on decoder. His Twitter feed is totally
Speaker 5:  spicy. He's
Speaker 6:  Become everybody's like WTF tariff guy because he's
Speaker 5:  Very, he's very spicy. He's very good. It's a, it's a fun episode. He is
Speaker 5:  a fun Listen, he is everywhere all the time now. 'cause he has all this data.
Speaker 5:  So he tweeted yesterday in the three weeks
Speaker 5:  since the tariff took effect, ocean container bookings from China, the
Speaker 5:  United States are down over 60% industrywide. Wow. And then just today he
Speaker 5:  tweeted the number of container ships sitting idle at the ports of Shanghai
Speaker 5:  and NBO and China are double what they were a month ago. And then
Speaker 5:  I think that is starting to spook people because there's reporting
Speaker 5:  and no one really knows what's eman jers from CNBC. It is pretty reliable.
Speaker 5:  Says treasury secretary Scott Cent said the next step was
Speaker 5:  China are, no one thinks the current status quo is sustainable. 145 and
Speaker 5:  125%. There will be a deescalation and
Speaker 5:  that should give you a sigh of relief. If you look at the number of
Speaker 5:  container bookings between the United States and China, it's down 64%.
Speaker 5:  The goal is not to decouple the United States from China. It's to deescalate.
Speaker 5:  So it's like, oh, they're just caving like nothing happened. Yeah. And they're
Speaker 5:  just like walking it back. But that means no one knows how much anything
Speaker 5:  will cost. And we're just seeing it across the whole industry.
Speaker 5:  Products are being announced without pricing. People are rushing to buy things
Speaker 5:  before tariffs hit. And all these companies are showing up at the White House
Speaker 5:  basically asking for exemptions. Right. And we don't know how those will
Speaker 5:  be applied or not. It does seem like I should buy a car. Is that the next
Speaker 5:  thing I should do? I do like reasons to buy.
Speaker 5:  I dunno what car
Speaker 6:  We're gonna buy. We're just at a point now where it's, it's hard to know
Speaker 6:  anything. Right. And I think like the, the funny thing about this Tim Cook
Speaker 6:  news is that there is this overwhelming sense in the industry that Tim Cook
Speaker 6:  is the only one. He's like the fixer who for
Speaker 6:  say what you want about apple's, you know, creativity and it's product
Speaker 6:  development. Like my guy knows how to get things shipped. Like
Speaker 6:  that's, that's a thing Tim Cook is, is like historically great at,
Speaker 6:  and it, it's just very funny that all of this stuff is happening and
Speaker 6:  everybody's like, well, okay, there's a, there was an exemption for like
Speaker 6:  chips and smartphones and computers like Hmm, who makes all of those?
Speaker 6:  And you could just sort of see like there's, there's a real, like, you know,
Speaker 6:  the silhouette of Tim Cook like walking out of the West Wing in a suit and
Speaker 6:  he just like accomplished all of his goals.
Speaker 6:  I have no idea if Tim Cook did that, but yeah,
Speaker 5:  No one knows. And there, there, there are a lot of confusion and the, and
Speaker 5:  the first term, the way he accomplished that was by convincing Trump
Speaker 5:  that if you put these tariffs on somehow Samsung would beat Apple.
Speaker 5:  And that you can't have that. Right. Who, who knows
Speaker 5:  what the mechanism there would've been.
Speaker 6:  It was Bixby. If
Speaker 5:  It was Bixby, it was Samsung, it was Saturday Samsung. They're
Speaker 5:  gonna give you a free TV with every TV you buy and somehow that will defeat
Speaker 5:  Apple. But that was his argument and you Trump said it many times in his
Speaker 5:  first term that I, I eased some of these tariffs back. 'cause they didn't
Speaker 5:  want Apple to get defeated by Samsung. I'm not sure what anyone is saying
Speaker 5:  now. The tariffs are across the board, like literally across the
Speaker 5:  board to every country. And we don't know what's gonna happen in these markets.
Speaker 5:  So I think we're seeing a lot of, a lot of rush to buy things.
Speaker 5:  We, we've seen all those stories everywhere. And all that means is somewhere
Speaker 5:  at the end of this, just like Covid, there will be a giant fall.
Speaker 6:  Yep.
Speaker 5:  People will have the stuff, they will not need the stuff and the industry
Speaker 5:  will not be even at like, there will not be even demand across the year
Speaker 5:  or across years. It will be, oh, we bought everything in April of
Speaker 5:  2025 and so a year from now, no one will need anything.
Speaker 5:  And that is, that's always Rocky.
Speaker 6:  It's so funny you mentioned that I was thinking about this with Peloton just
Speaker 6:  today. That like, Jake, to your point about the, the gigantic
Speaker 6:  numbers in Japan, like if I am Nintendo,
Speaker 6:  do you look at this and say, okay, awesome, this is going to be a
Speaker 6:  monstrous hit on proportions we had not even imagined.
Speaker 6:  Let's go make a ton more of these things because, because this is,
Speaker 6:  this is going to take over the world and we have won and we have to go chase
Speaker 6:  that. Or are we gonna do the thing that Peloton did, which is
Speaker 6:  look at a bunch of people who bought a thing all at once for mostly cultural
Speaker 6:  reasons. As it turned out, this was like the beginning of the pandemic and
Speaker 6:  every person on earth who had ever thought maybe I should buy a Peloton bought
Speaker 6:  one all at the same time. They all did. And Peloton took that to mean, oh,
Speaker 6:  sick, we're so much cooler than we thought we were. This growth will go on
Speaker 6:  forever. And then what happens is you make a bunch of stuff, it's very
Speaker 6:  expensive to store all that stuff. You don't sell it that very fast and it
Speaker 6:  destroys your business. Like it's wait,
Speaker 5:  Wait. Peloton made an even bigger mistake. They bought Precore. They
Speaker 5:  they bought another company for its manufacturing
Speaker 5:  capabilities. That's
Speaker 6:  Right. I forgot they did that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And then they were like, shit, we own Precore. Right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Which
Speaker 5:  Like, we, we own these factories to make treadmills that no one wants. Right.
Speaker 5:  They have a since recover. They're like two CEOs since then. Yeah. Pelotons
Speaker 6:  Doing fine. But I, but I do think, and it's, It is, I actually feel for
Speaker 6:  companies in a moment like this, because It is so hard to know, and you have
Speaker 6:  to make so many of these decisions with such long lead times and things are
Speaker 6:  changing so quickly that like God help anyone who has to make like,
Speaker 6:  you know, multimillion dollar inventory decisions about 20, 27 right now,
Speaker 6:  which like people have to do. That's a thing that's happening. Yeah. And
Speaker 6:  It is, it, it just all seems impossible.
Speaker 7:  I'll say for the Switch, I think it's like maybe a little bit different just
Speaker 7:  because of the timeline of that product. Right. Nintendo is selling
Speaker 7:  effectively the exact same product they made eight years ago. Yeah. For
Speaker 7:  the exact same price. They like changed the chip once, but it's
Speaker 7:  fundamentally the same thing
Speaker 6:  And it's doing fine still for
Speaker 7:  Them. Like, I don't know, like it's, It is gonna be a little bumpy, but like
Speaker 7:  they'll be whatever. They can just put out some more switch one games like
Speaker 7:  that, that's where all the money is for them.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. No, I, I think you're probably right. Nintendo is probably as immune
Speaker 6:  to this as just about anybody.
Speaker 7:  But I do think in general like this idea of like, oh man, all these
Speaker 7:  companies have no idea how to plan for the future. Oh yeah. It's gonna be
Speaker 7:  really tricky. I I have no idea what this's gonna look like a
Speaker 7:  year from now when people are,
Speaker 7:  you know, have already bought everything or we just don't have any products.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Do you know what the all time number one we
Speaker 5:  thought the pandemic would be forever. Mistake was,
Speaker 5:  Ooh,
Speaker 7:  I, I'm Can I, I'm guessing I'm gonna guess you're going with
Speaker 7:  Verizon BlueJean.
Speaker 6:  That's a good one.
Speaker 5:  The CEO of Verizon Wireless was on, he was like, yeah, it was a rounding
Speaker 5:  error. So no, but the good one.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Okay. Is it fancy webcams?
Speaker 5:  Nope.
Speaker 6:  Damn.
Speaker 5:  What is it? No, no, no. It's so bad. It's so bad. It's so big. I it's it's
Speaker 5:  so big you can't see it.
Speaker 5:  Facebook renamed itself meta. No.
Speaker 7:  Oh
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's, they were like, we're gonna live, we're gonna do cartoons. No legs,
Speaker 5:  no
Speaker 6:  One ever outside. We're
Speaker 5:  All day
Speaker 7:  Long. You know what though? I think that's worked out for them. Everyone
Speaker 7:  has, everyone has forgotten that they're, they're furious with Facebook.
Speaker 7:  They've forgotten why was renamed Meta because no one ever
Speaker 7:  used Meta Horizon. Like it, nobody's like,
Speaker 7:  man, that thing we sure stopped using that. Yeah. Like Zoom, everybody's
Speaker 7:  like, boy that really like went in the bucket afterwards. Horizon,
Speaker 7:  horizon Worlds, whatever is doing just as well as it ever was.
Speaker 5:  That's certain. What was the one concert in Fortnite that at just
Speaker 5:  ev it confused everyone. Do you know what I'm
Speaker 6:  Talking about? Was it was Travis Scott? It
Speaker 5:  Was Travis Scott. That's what it was. Yeah. They did as old and Fortnite.
Speaker 5:  Yep. And I mean, just that day, like Mark
Speaker 5:  Zuckerberg is like, we are, everyone's gonna be at home Oh yeah. In headsets
Speaker 5:  forever. And it's like, no, the kids really
Speaker 5:  want to go outside. Like they want Yeah. They want to look at
Speaker 5:  a Travis Hunt concert at the concert.
Speaker 6:  So just to give people some, some inside baseball here, when you're a reporter,
Speaker 6:  one of the things that happens is anytime there is like a big moment
Speaker 6:  of some sort product launch sort of cultural event, whatever, one
Speaker 6:  of the things that happens to every reporter is a million people flood into
Speaker 6:  their inbox offering some kind of quote about that thing.
Speaker 6:  Like, my CEO would love to talk about how this affects B2B ad sales
Speaker 6:  or like, whatever. That was one of those days that I, I distinctly
Speaker 6:  remember the, the, the Travis Scott concert in Fortnite happens
Speaker 6:  and I had a hundred emails the next day from people who were like, let me
Speaker 6:  tell you why this just changed everything about how society is going
Speaker 6:  to work. Yeah. And it was like, you're totally right. It was like, this is
Speaker 6:  a moment and the world will never be the same afterwards. And it was,
Speaker 6:  it went right back.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. But that's this, I mean, what's what's staggering about
Speaker 5:  all of that is Covid was an external crisis. Like it happened
Speaker 5:  and everyone reacted to it. And then however you experienced covid,
Speaker 5:  like a, a number of behaviors changed. A really
Speaker 5:  interesting one, for example, is we started decoder before Covid
Speaker 5:  and no one wanted to be on video. And now everyone's assumption is that they
Speaker 5:  will be on Google meet calls. Yep. Weird. That's just a totally a pandemic
Speaker 5:  change that happened. Tariffs are a totally self
Speaker 5:  created mess. Like, they woke up one day, they asked Cha
Speaker 5:  PD how to ruin the world economy. And like, here we are. But the same
Speaker 5:  kind of like ripple effects are happening. You can just see it and, but
Speaker 5:  no one, there's no behavior change around it. It's
Speaker 5:  like on balance, it's, it's a little bit easier to convince David to buy
Speaker 5:  a MacBook Air that that's where we're right now. And that is, but
Speaker 5:  that's on a permanent change. It, it's not like a, everyone
Speaker 5:  got used to video conferencing over these two years. Right. But you can see
Speaker 5:  that companies are having to deal with it in, in kind of the same ways.
Speaker 5:  I don't know, like there's just something I wish I could, if I could go back
Speaker 5:  before Covid and predict what would've happened that you maybe
Speaker 5:  would've predicted. Everyone gets more comfortable with video calls and working
Speaker 5:  from home, but there's this one, I I'm just not sure what the change
Speaker 5:  is other than everyone's kind of mad that they can't get a switch to,
Speaker 6:  Right. Yeah. I mean there's gonna be like a long, long road of
Speaker 6:  here's what happens when everything gets more expensive and harder to find.
Speaker 6:  But in terms of this sort of,
Speaker 6:  you know, one day to the next culture change,
Speaker 6:  like here's hoping we never go through that again. Right? Like that was,
Speaker 6:  that was such
Speaker 5:  All right, we're back. Which trial should we start with? Should we start
Speaker 5:  with Google? Should we start with meta?
Speaker 6:  They're both so good. Let's do Google first just because I'm like, I need
Speaker 6:  to warm up to how much fun I found Kevin Strom at the meta trial. Yeah, so
Speaker 6:  let's, let's do Google first.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, Google's a little simpler there. There's a game to be played here right
Speaker 5:  now. Google is in the remedies phase on the search
Speaker 5:  trial. It has lost the ad tech trial. If you want nitty
Speaker 5:  gritty on what those trials were, what those cases claimed,
Speaker 5:  how they were constructed. Jonathan Cantor who led the DOJs antitrust division
Speaker 5:  was just un decoder. We went through them in detail, so we'll hold off on
Speaker 5:  the detail. But the remedies phase of the search trial. Google was found
Speaker 5:  to have an illegal monopoly in Search par, partially because they pay
Speaker 5:  a bunch of money to Apple and other companies for defaults in Safari and
Speaker 5:  other places. Now we're onto, what are we gonna do about it?
Speaker 5:  The government says, and David, you were there for this part of the trial,
Speaker 5:  so I wanna hear what this was like in person. The government says you gotta
Speaker 5:  sell Chrome and you gotta make search interoperable. And this
Speaker 5:  is happening literally in the same courthouse in which
Speaker 5:  meta is on trial to have to sell
Speaker 5:  Instagram and WhatsApp and Lauren finder's like running between the courtrooms,
Speaker 5:  which is hilarious to me. Yeah. Let's talk about the Google piece. You
Speaker 5:  were in the courtroom and the government sort of like made this big claim.
Speaker 5:  What, what are the vibes?
Speaker 6:  So I was there for opening arguments on Monday and
Speaker 6:  one of the funniest parts about it to me was how much of opening arguments
Speaker 6:  were just the lawyers reminding the judge of
Speaker 6:  what laws are. It's like, 'cause there's a real sense of like, it,
Speaker 6:  it becomes, I I discovered this in the, in the course of like talking to
Speaker 6:  people about this and being there that like reminding everyone
Speaker 6:  at the beginning of a remedies phase that Google is a monopolist and it lost
Speaker 6:  and it has been convicted and that that is no longer the question that is
Speaker 6:  the starting point was, was so important for the government, right? Because
Speaker 6:  they're setting up this thing where it's not a question of whether Google
Speaker 6:  did the wrong thing. Google is gonna appeal that and we will be litigating
Speaker 6:  that for forever. But for the purposes of right now, Google
Speaker 6:  is a convicted monopolist that is, that is no longer in question.
Speaker 6:  And so David Dahlquist, who did the opening arguments for
Speaker 6:  the DOJ said that like over and over and over again, he's like
Speaker 6:  every, every two sentence, he was like, well, because Google is a monopolist.
Speaker 6:  But it, it was really interesting and I think these two sides have had a
Speaker 6:  long time to talk to each other and do
Speaker 6:  discovery and figure things out and try to like understand what they
Speaker 6:  want. And if anything, it feels like they're getting further apart from each
Speaker 6:  other.
Speaker 5:  Well you're about as far as you can get right now.
Speaker 6:  I mean, yes, but the, the do j's argument, I I would, I would actually put
Speaker 6:  it into three buckets. One is you have to sell Chrome. One
Speaker 6:  is no more distribution deals of any kind. You, you cannot, you cannot
Speaker 6:  give Apple $20 billion to make you the default search engine engine in Safari.
Speaker 6:  They would just like to get rid of those deals entirely. And then number
Speaker 6:  three is, is what you said about interoperable. They want Google to essentially
Speaker 6:  white label Google search for anyone who wants it.
Speaker 6:  Google doesn't like any of those surprise, what Google wants
Speaker 6:  essentially is to stop making
Speaker 6:  exclusive deals. It would essentially like to take the word exclusive
Speaker 6:  out of all of its contracts. And so the
Speaker 6:  idea is, well now anyone can play the games that we are playing. If you
Speaker 6:  wanna give Apple $20 billion, you're welcome to.
Speaker 6:  I would argue that is preposterous. That is also what the government argues.
Speaker 6:  But the thing that I found most interesting is that it seems very
Speaker 6:  clear to me that the, the one of those three things that Google is most
Speaker 6:  nervous about is the white labeling of Google.
Speaker 6:  I think the, the Chrome thing is really interesting and I wanna talk about
Speaker 6:  who might buy Chrome, but essentially what is being
Speaker 6:  asked of Google, if the DOJ gets its way is to take all of its data. So
Speaker 6:  it's it's search index, it's query data, which is like what people are actually
Speaker 6:  sending even it's like ranking algorithms and systems
Speaker 6:  and just package that up and give to any other search engine that
Speaker 6:  wants it for, I believe the phrase is a marginal cost. What is that cost?
Speaker 6:  No one knows. It's up to some committee that will get appointed and Google
Speaker 6:  would like a lot more clarification about that. But Google's argument is
Speaker 6:  essentially we have spent 25 years building this and
Speaker 6:  now you just want us to hand it to anybody with $10 and
Speaker 6:  a designer and they can just have Google and the DOJ is like, yes, that
Speaker 6:  is exactly precisely what we are trying to do. David,
Speaker 7:  Do you think that, is that the like we're gonna ask for too much and then
Speaker 7:  get a step back? Or do you think they like legitimately are like, no, this
Speaker 7:  is, this is the thing we want and this is the thing we should have happen.
Speaker 6:  So I think I still think Chrome is the ask for too much
Speaker 6:  move. Oh, interesting. I think, I think Chrome is more
Speaker 6:  like the DOJI think is more serious about selling Chrome than I expected.
Speaker 6:  But I think if, if the DOJ was gonna give one of these up, it would be that
Speaker 6:  one. But I think the, the argument that the government makes
Speaker 6:  is essentially that if you just level the playing field
Speaker 6:  starting now and you say, okay, everyone starting today has to play by the
Speaker 6:  same rules. Google is so far ahead that it doesn't
Speaker 6:  matter, right? Like you're, you're starting a marathon and you're saying
Speaker 6:  you're both running a marathon, but Google gets to start 25 and a half miles
Speaker 6:  ahead, but you can both run as fast as you want. Now it's like that's not
Speaker 6:  a fair race. And so what what Google is saying is, well, okay,
Speaker 6:  you're actually, you're giving all of our competitors a giant leg up
Speaker 6:  just because we're a monopoly. And, and the DOJ is saying
Speaker 6:  yes, that is the only way to rectify this thing that we're doing. So I, I
Speaker 6:  wondered if it was one of the things that the DOJ would be willing to get
Speaker 6:  rid of, but listening to them talk about it, they're like, no, this is not
Speaker 6:  just about stopping the monopoly, it's about rectifying the monopoly. Like
Speaker 6:  we have to, they kept using the, the phrase antitrust antifreeze,
Speaker 6:  which I hate and it's a bad metaphor. And like they should stop. They were
Speaker 6:  like, they like
Speaker 7:  Print on
Speaker 6:  T-shirts. It is, it's awful. They're like, it's what does that mean? So the
Speaker 6:  idea is Google's conduct froze all of its competitors and, and
Speaker 6:  basically like put a freeze on the search engine market. And they were like,
Speaker 6:  I I think it was David Alquist who was like, we wanna, we don't want to just,
Speaker 6:  you know, put the block of ice out to thaw. We wanna light a fire under it.
Speaker 6:  And then somebody else came up and he was like, antitrust antifreeze. And
Speaker 6:  I was like, guys, this isn't it. Like this isn't, this isn't doing
Speaker 5:  What you can is I don't wanna, I don't wanna, I mean I'm this person and
Speaker 5:  this is our audience, I'm just gonna go for it. That's not how melting and
Speaker 5:  freezing things work.
Speaker 5:  Like you don't pour anti-freeze on ice to make it not
Speaker 5:  No, you you, you actually, you just whatever. Okay, good job government.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, you're doing great. But
Speaker 6:  Anyway, so all of this is to say, I think that that
Speaker 6:  piece of it and, and what I left the courthouse wondering and I'm, I'm
Speaker 6:  curious what y'all think of this is if there is a middle ground in that one,
Speaker 6:  if there is a way to like give some of its competitors
Speaker 6:  a leg up so that they can compete without just making Google handover
Speaker 6:  25 years of trade secrets in order to
Speaker 6:  prop up anyone who wants to build a search engine. Because like literally
Speaker 6:  the way the DOJ is framing this is that like the three of us
Speaker 6:  could design a front end with a search box
Speaker 6:  and then just like pipe in a Google API and be and and and we would have
Speaker 6:  Google like that. It's, it's not all the way that, but It is
Speaker 6:  pretty damn close to that.
Speaker 5:  Well their, their idea is that we would pay Google some fee
Speaker 6:  Right?
Speaker 5:  For that service and then we would have to then figure out a business model
Speaker 5:  that made us paying that fee to Google worth it. Right? Like what they want
Speaker 5:  is competition on that layer. Like there should be competition search engines
Speaker 5:  and there can't be right now because no one has the clickstream from
Speaker 5:  Google. No one has the raw volume of search data.
Speaker 5:  So you gotta get that somehow Google can give it to you and then you can
Speaker 5:  have con like then KA can be better or whatever. Right? Right. Like that
Speaker 5:  feels hard for a variety of reasons. 'cause no one knows the other
Speaker 5:  business model is, the thing that gets me is, and you,
Speaker 5:  you hear this now from a lot of antitrust people on both sides of the aisle
Speaker 5:  and it's fascinating that this is the Trump DOJ basically
Speaker 5:  saying the same things Jonathan Cantor was saying, we can't just
Speaker 5:  fix the problem now we have to change it so it doesn't happen again. We have
Speaker 5:  to go back in time and unwind some of this. I think they call it a flywheel,
Speaker 5:  right? You have Chrome, you collect all the click data from Chrome that feeds
Speaker 5:  into search, you get better search, you know, click data from search, you
Speaker 5:  direct traffic to webs. Like that's the problem. It's very hard for any
Speaker 5:  external company to just like replace one part of that. So you gotta break
Speaker 5:  the whole thing up, right? But the real issue, and you just hear this a lot,
Speaker 5:  is the complicated. You have to
Speaker 5:  behave this way and we're gonna watch you to make sure you, you act better
Speaker 5:  is really hard, especially for the government. 'cause presidents come and
Speaker 5:  go, people come and go like it's
Speaker 5:  private companies, especially huge private companies are very clever and
Speaker 5:  motivated in finding ways out of the compliance rules that they were put
Speaker 5:  in front of. And so breaking up the company, the
Speaker 5:  quote structural remedy is just simpler.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And now the argument that I, I've heard like
Speaker 5:  FTC commissioners who are coming on decoder next week, the argument they're
Speaker 5:  making is it's actually more democratic. It, it takes the government outta
Speaker 5:  your business. We just send Chrome off into the woods or
Speaker 5:  you'd sell Instagram and then that's a different company and we're done
Speaker 5:  like the government's outta your hair as opposed to we're gonna watch your
Speaker 5:  every move, which you kind of like the Trump administration is like, what
Speaker 5:  if we watched your every move? Right? Like they, they have an in, they have
Speaker 5:  an in inclination to be like up in your business. And so you, there's a little
Speaker 5:  bit of a flip there, but I don't know if make the
Speaker 5:  API interoperable make search interoperable
Speaker 5:  will play because Google will just preference itself again, they'll find
Speaker 5:  a way to do it. They'll come to some settlement agreement and say, okay,
Speaker 5:  our Google search experience is still slightly better than the one we sell
Speaker 5:  to Microsoft.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Which I think one of the, one of the other things that DOJ really
Speaker 6:  wants is that the, the sort of cloud
Speaker 6:  they get to put over Google's head if they don't comply with all of these
Speaker 6:  things and all and like live under the remedies correctly, is to have to
Speaker 6:  sell Android. Like that's that's the, that's the
Speaker 6:  thing for non-compliance,
Speaker 5:  That's like in case of emergency.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And, and so I came to realize over the course of this that like they
Speaker 6:  picked the biggest possible hammer that they could
Speaker 6:  in order to say, okay, if, if we don't think, and again, it's all very
Speaker 6:  nebulous. It's like if a, if just a bunch of people who have not yet been
Speaker 6:  named decide that you're not doing a good enough job and Google is like,
Speaker 6:  we have questions about all of that, but they, they're like,
Speaker 6:  their compliance rule is Android and, and that is the, that is the real wow.
Speaker 6:  Huge hammer hanging over Google if it goes through
Speaker 5:  My hottest take here is that in 36 months, Google as we know, it does not
Speaker 5:  exist.
Speaker 6:  It sure seems like it.
Speaker 5:  Like whether it's the government that does it, whether Google reconfigures
Speaker 5:  itself somehow, whether the thing that sort of happened to Microsoft
Speaker 5:  in the nineties happens, like Microsoft had all these cases and
Speaker 5:  all these, but they, Microsoft ended with a big consent decree. They were
Speaker 5:  going to break up Microsoft into, I think they called it Apco and,
Speaker 5:  and Osco, which is horrible names Apco is the one that it
Speaker 5:  was like on the cover of time, like what's apco? It's like very silly.
Speaker 5:  And then the, you know, George Bush got elected,
Speaker 5:  the Clinton DOJ went away and they settled the case with this big consent
Speaker 5:  decree. And that said, Microsoft had to
Speaker 5:  not preference its own apps and stuff on Windows. And that just led to like
Speaker 5:  years of headaches that allowed like Google to exist and Apple to make this
Speaker 5:  like roaring comeback on the strength of the open web, which is the only
Speaker 5:  reason the iMac is any good. Like Apple came back because the web browser
Speaker 5:  supplanted windows as an app platform.
Speaker 5:  Now we have Apple, but if that hadn't happened, why would you buy an iMac?
Speaker 5:  Right? So all of that happened because Microsoft was kind of distracted and
Speaker 5:  then Bill Gates will tell you that's why they missed mobile. Although I don't
Speaker 5:  think that's the case at all. I saw their mobile phones, you know,
Speaker 5:  I'm just wondering like 36 months from now, three years from now, what will
Speaker 5:  have Google been distracted by Google is not like a monster of execution
Speaker 5:  right now. Yeah. So the government breaks it up, Google breaks itself up,
Speaker 5:  Larry Page shows back up and is like, I don't know, spin off YouTube like
Speaker 5:  something is happening that changes this company as we know it in the next
Speaker 5:  few years.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I think it's, it's possible that the big tech companies
Speaker 6:  now just have like a different level of resources than any of
Speaker 6:  those companies did back then. That they're so entrenched and so much bigger
Speaker 6:  and have so much more money that they can, they can, you know, walk and chew
Speaker 6:  gum at the same time in that respect. But it also, I mean to your point,
Speaker 6:  we we're seeing it now, right? Like Google is already not
Speaker 6:  operating at full capacity because it has been fighting these fights
Speaker 6:  and, and you see, you see leadership is changing and moving around
Speaker 6:  in this company is like relentlessly trying to figure out what kind of company
Speaker 6:  it's supposed to be, which is a lot as all of
Speaker 6:  this is happening. And of course Google's argument is that AI is that thing,
Speaker 6:  right? Like what, what the web and what mobile were to Microsoft then
Speaker 6:  AI is now and
Speaker 5:  They're running the same playbook. Yeah. It says in the trial it was revealed
Speaker 5:  that Google is paying Samsung an enormous sum to Preinstall
Speaker 5:  Gemini. Yep. Like they're just doing what they do.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. And, and so the DOJ is like, no, we have to stop Google
Speaker 6:  from doing this so that it doesn't do it again. And Google is like, well,
Speaker 6:  Chatt PT is doing just fine. And so that,
Speaker 6:  that isn't a real problem. Like this is the fastest growing
Speaker 6:  consumer technology in history and Google is not getting
Speaker 6:  in its way. So I think where, where that shakes out in this trial is gonna
Speaker 6:  be really fascinating. But there's been a lot more AI already in court
Speaker 6:  than we expected. Like the very first witness after opening arguments was
Speaker 6:  an AI expert who literally just spent like an hour and a half explaining
Speaker 6:  terms about AI to the court, which I thought was so interesting. I
Speaker 7:  Might be jumping ahead a little bit here, but the AI thing is really fascinating
Speaker 7:  when it comes to Chrome because the big companies to be like, oh, I buy Chrome.
Speaker 7:  They're AI companies. They're all looking for a
Speaker 7:  gateway in, and those gateways are, they're Google
Speaker 7:  products, right? It is Chrome. It is Google's search index.
Speaker 7:  They would leap at this opportunity because Google is
Speaker 7:  still the gatekeeper. They're still the biggest surface.
Speaker 7:  They're winning because they keep putting their own stuff on that surface.
Speaker 7:  And I think these AI companies know no matter how good their product is,
Speaker 7:  you just cannot replace that.
Speaker 5:  Well, it's true. You said that the big AI companies, I just want to peel
Speaker 5:  that apart a little bit. One, one, OpenAI said they would buy Chrome,
Speaker 5:  and they said that in court, right? David? Or they filed a, the document
Speaker 5:  saying they would do it and then Perplexity, which is just a very different
Speaker 5:  scale than OpenAI was like, yeah, we'll do it too. But they perplexity is
Speaker 5:  also like, we'll buy TikTok. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Perplexity is is a SPAC
Speaker 6:  With an AI arm attached. Like they, they, they will buy Peloton
Speaker 6:  if it comes up for sale.
Speaker 5:  So look, I don't know if Plexy can afford it. I don't know if Plexy can afford
Speaker 5:  TikTok. They do have some revenue. I tweet any revenue. It is a joke. They
Speaker 5:  do have some revenue that's growing, but open eyes, the the big dog. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Right. They, Sam Altman's like, what if I had a trillion dollars? And a lot
Speaker 5:  of people are like, what if you did amazing?
Speaker 5:  What they would get is distribution, which is the thing they all
Speaker 5:  need, Right? If you're up against Apple on the iPhone
Speaker 5:  and Apple can just be like, you're gonna use Siri until we make it good,
Speaker 5:  you're kind of stuck, right? But if you're in Chrome literally
Speaker 5:  looking at all of the webpage that people are using and all of the
Speaker 5:  things they are typing into all of the text boxes across the internet,
Speaker 5:  well, you have a lot of power, right? That's, that's huge. And then you
Speaker 5:  can put the AI system or the chatbot right in front of all the users all
Speaker 5:  the time, which is stuff other browser makers afraid. Like that's basically
Speaker 5:  what the ARC browser is going to become, right? Yeah. Who else could buy
Speaker 5:  Chrome?
Speaker 6:  Well, it, it was really interesting listening to the lawyers
Speaker 6:  in opening arguments, try and make the case that Chrome is a really good
Speaker 6:  business. Because the thing Google says, and the thing I've heard a bunch
Speaker 6:  is the browser business as a standalone business
Speaker 6:  actually really sucks that a browser has lots of value
Speaker 6:  and is hugely useful. And the, like you said, the distribution is ridiculous.
Speaker 6:  The, the do j's estimation was that Chrome has four and a half billion users,
Speaker 6:  which is, would make it the biggest platform on the
Speaker 6:  internet by like a pretty wide margin.
Speaker 6:  But people don't pay for browsers. They
Speaker 6:  put up a thing where they were like, here's how you monetize. And the first
Speaker 6:  thing they came up with was ads, like the, the Mozilla Firefox
Speaker 6:  ads that you see. And I'm just sitting there in, in listening to this being
Speaker 6:  like, yeah, and how's that going from Mozilla, which gets all of its money
Speaker 6:  from a Google default search deal. Like it's just,
Speaker 6:  that is very hard to pull off. And then they came around to,
Speaker 6:  well, what if a, what if an AI company just took
Speaker 6:  out the Google search box and put in their chat bot? And that
Speaker 6:  is the answer. It's, it's the only way, right? Like it becomes the thing
Speaker 6:  that I use to interact with chat GPT that I spend
Speaker 6:  $20 for, right? It's, it's, it's different than
Speaker 6:  It is for Google because it doesn't, like you, there's nowhere that you pay
Speaker 6:  money. Google's flywheel just exists sort of next to Chrome, and you access
Speaker 6:  it by constantly typing searches into the Chrome bar, which is why it's a
Speaker 6:  perfect and unbeatable business. But that
Speaker 6:  is the whole pitch as far as I can tell, is, is it gives you
Speaker 6:  massive distribution. It puts you in front of most of the
Speaker 6:  population of the Earth already. Even if it doesn't grow, it's like
Speaker 6:  It is an unparalleled thing to just be able to put your
Speaker 6:  stuff in front of it does, it gets you browsing data, it gets you all kinds
Speaker 6:  of stuff. But it, it, it will have to be in service of something else. And
Speaker 6:  even the DOJ is like, this is not going to be a business by
Speaker 6:  itself. You're not just gonna be able to start charging $10 a month for Chrome,
Speaker 6:  and that's gonna work. Like they understand that it, it has to be
Speaker 6:  in service of another thing in order to work. And I found that really fascinating.
Speaker 6:  Wait,
Speaker 5:  It was just like, it's funny, we, you can do the TikTok exercise, you can
Speaker 5:  come up with this list of potential acquirers for TikTok
Speaker 5:  that It is pretty vast, right? I think I, I keep putting Walmart on that
Speaker 5:  list. Like Walmart should buy TikTok and then the TikTok shop won't
Speaker 5:  feel quite like being mugged and the way that it does today. Like, have you
Speaker 5:  heard of Vivo? Or you will now, like there's something happening there that's
Speaker 5:  just dark. Yeah. And maybe Walmart can just like take it and run it and have
Speaker 5:  a young audience and compete with Amazon. Like you can build a pretty wide
Speaker 5:  aperture for TikTok. I don't who buys Chrome?
Speaker 5:  Is this just OpenAI and perplexity? Look, why would Apple buy
Speaker 5:  Chrome?
Speaker 7:  I think Apple should buy Chrome. Hear me out. Really? Okay. Yeah. Safari
Speaker 7:  is a garbage browser. Chrome is the probably the most used software on
Speaker 7:  Mac, and It is the worst running piece of software on Mac. They fixed that.
Speaker 7:  They've just doubled the battery life on MacBooks and who needs a
Speaker 7:  surface for when they eventually have a good AI application? Apple?
Speaker 5:  Wait, they have the biggest surface in history. They have the iPhone.
Speaker 7:  Yeah, but you put it on, put it on Chrome too. Now it's everywhere.
Speaker 6:  You know what more people use than use iPhones? Neli.
Speaker 5:  Is It, is it Chrome? Well, right, but Apple doesn't care. They're not, can
Speaker 5:  you imagine whoever is Craig Feder being like, we gotta work on Windows
Speaker 5:  Chrome, you guys, like, that's your job.
Speaker 6:  The very funniest outcome here would be that Apple buys Chrome just
Speaker 6:  to shut it down. And they claim it's in the ex in the interest of the user
Speaker 6:  experience on the Mac, they're like, we don't want people using bad browsers
Speaker 6:  on Apple devices, so we're just gonna kill Chrome.
Speaker 5:  Like Yeah. Apple does not want the web to be a great application platform.
Speaker 5:  'cause they want iOS to be their application platform. Yeah. Like they,
Speaker 5:  that there's a, there's something happening with Safari that is often
Speaker 5:  overlooked, but it's like Safari just has a wall of
Speaker 5:  capabilities that prevents web apps from competing with iOS apps. It's like,
Speaker 5:  again, I I hear you. I I, I bought a a, a Mac
Speaker 5:  studio just to run Chrome 10 years from now, it'll still be running
Speaker 5:  Chrome, but not well. Yep.
Speaker 7:  And listen, they're gonna need to build a search engine once those search
Speaker 7:  deal exclusivity, that exclusivity cash stops coming through
Speaker 7:  Chrome.
Speaker 5:  So, but that may, that's a, that's an argument to license Google.
Speaker 5:  If you're Apple, you can quickly, and all this goes through, you can
Speaker 5:  quickly build a, a better, more interesting search product
Speaker 5:  into Spotlight or Siri or whatever because you have the backend of
Speaker 5:  Google to support it in a way that has to be interoperable. It doesn't mean
Speaker 5:  you have to buy Chrome.
Speaker 7:  I'm not saying this is all let's wise decision.
Speaker 5:  Okay. So that, but that's the argument, Jake, that's, that's
Speaker 7:  The
Speaker 5:  Ly made the argument, which was increase the better left on MacBook. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  Mi Microsoft
Speaker 6:  Wouldn't work the, I mean, they, they even said in court,
Speaker 6:  Microsoft meta, Amazon basically
Speaker 6:  out for antitrust reasons.
Speaker 5:  Who can buy What is, I don't understand this. I,
Speaker 6:  It literally, the, the longer I think about this, the more it might literally
Speaker 6:  just be open ai. Like you, there's a really interesting
Speaker 6:  case to
Speaker 5:  Be made. Like I'm just like naming big companies Exxon. Like
Speaker 5:  what, what It
Speaker 6:  Becomes the rivian ex
Speaker 5:  Exclusive
Speaker 6:  Browser. No, I think there's a, there's an interesting case to be made that
Speaker 6:  if all of this goes against Google, the single company that stands to benefit
Speaker 6:  the most is OpenAI. And it, it, it
Speaker 6:  has the cash to do it. It doesn't have the antitrust worries to do
Speaker 6:  it,
Speaker 6:  it, it can raise money infinitely. Clearly.
Speaker 6:  It would hugely benefit from access to Google's search data.
Speaker 6:  One of the things that one an OpenAI person said in
Speaker 6:  deposition was basically it's, you can get to
Speaker 6:  80% of Google's search quality pretty easily, and the last
Speaker 6:  20% is virtually impossible and
Speaker 6:  just absolutely impossibly expensive. And this is the thing I've heard from
Speaker 6:  anyone who wants to build search. You can build a pretty good search engine
Speaker 6:  by yourself, but to the difference between a pretty good and a
Speaker 6:  Google level search engine is many years and hundreds of
Speaker 6:  billions of dollars or Google is forced to give it to you, right? Yeah. And
Speaker 6:  so OpenAI immediately starts to solve that
Speaker 6:  quality gap, maybe gets a browser out of it and suddenly
Speaker 6:  goes from having, not distribution problems, but like it has to win
Speaker 6:  its distribution to suddenly just having it and like,
Speaker 6:  it, it, it would be in a very funny way, raising one competitor
Speaker 6:  in particular out of all of this. Like up to Google's level.
Speaker 5:  It's just funny that like literally at TikTok, I can make an argument for
Speaker 5:  almost any company to buy tiktoks. Yeah. Sun Kiss should buy TikTok.
Speaker 5:  Like, fine, give me enough time. I'll get there. And the Orange company should
Speaker 5:  buy TikTok. It's hard to make an argument for any company to buy Chrome
Speaker 5:  because the business model doesn't make a lot of sense. You
Speaker 6:  Can sort of make a like browsing data argument that
Speaker 6:  is interesting, but not at the price it would cost to
Speaker 6:  get it, right? Like having access to everyone's browsing data
Speaker 6:  is very valuable and would be to lots of people. But I think
Speaker 6:  buying and running Chrome is probably not the most efficient way to get
Speaker 6:  there,
Speaker 5:  Or at least the way that Google runs Chrome, which to its credit is in a
Speaker 5:  like, reasonably open way. Like I
Speaker 5:  think people think of web browsers, like document viewers, but they're actually
Speaker 5:  application platforms. They're little operating systems now, right? They
Speaker 5:  have different memory between tabs. Your apps are literally running them
Speaker 5:  and obviously in the cloud as well. Like that's where apps run on desktop
Speaker 5:  computers for most people. And Google has to manage that.
Speaker 5:  They have a commitment to the web being open, which is good.
Speaker 5:  If you buy Chrome, you don't have to do any of that. You
Speaker 5:  can just say your app will run even better in Chrome if you pay us some money.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And like, there's all these other things you could do to make that
Speaker 5:  money, which seemed bad.
Speaker 6:  And in addition to offloading Chrome, the government wants Google
Speaker 6:  to offload the Chromium project, which is, it's, it's
Speaker 6:  like ostensibly but not really open source
Speaker 6:  browser project that it oversees and funds and
Speaker 6:  also powers every other browser that you probably use at this point. Like
Speaker 6:  Edge is chromium, arc is chromium, brave is
Speaker 6:  like, they're everything on the web at this point except
Speaker 6:  for Safari and kind of Firefox
Speaker 6:  is chromium. And so you end up at this point where like we're, we would be
Speaker 6:  changing the way that like the underlying infrastructure of how people use
Speaker 6:  the internet belongs to somebody else. And like, maybe there's a devil,
Speaker 6:  you know, devil you don't thing going on here, but like for all of its
Speaker 6:  flaws, Google has been a pretty good steward of browsers
Speaker 6:  over the years. Yeah. We, we give Chrome a lot of crap. But like
Speaker 6:  the reason web chat is very good and video
Speaker 6:  looks really great in your browser is in large part thanks to work that Google
Speaker 6:  did and then gave to the ecosystem. Like that stuff is, that stuff matters.
Speaker 5:  It's funny 'cause they, the reason they did that was to ensure
Speaker 5:  Google search could see everyone's data. Well, sure. Right? Like Yeah. I
Speaker 5:  mean that this idea, I mean like they're, they were always aligned. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  The alignment was good for the most part. Like let's build open web platforms
Speaker 5:  for everything and make sure everything is standards compliant also, that
Speaker 5:  will ensure that our systems can crawl everything and see everything. Right?
Speaker 5:  Great. And now we're just like, if you break that apart, maybe, maybe
Speaker 5:  there's not so, so much incentive for things to be happen. I have no idea
Speaker 5:  what's gonna happen here. I just think it's fascinating that, I mean, I don't
Speaker 5:  know what's gonna happen with TikTok either. It's just really interesting
Speaker 5:  that you should buy and run TikTok seems like a simpler problem than you
Speaker 5:  should run Chrome, which does not have like content
Speaker 5:  moderation issues or like the Chinese government hating
Speaker 5:  Donald Trump issue. Like, but it's like, oh, that's way harder. Like we should
Speaker 5:  buy TikTok.
Speaker 7:  Is this because like TikTok, there's like a clear business model Chrome.
Speaker 7:  The business has to be something else, right? Like, unless you're just going
Speaker 7:  to have a bunch of popups on every single new tab screen, like
Speaker 7:  you fundamentally need to have another business that you are boosting with
Speaker 7:  Chrome, which means you just need to have a pretty good business
Speaker 7:  already that could use that distribution and you have to have a bunch of
Speaker 7:  extra cash. And that's just a really weird situation to be in. Maybe it's
Speaker 7:  Walmart. Every new tab screen is just a bunch of recommended products
Speaker 6:  To buy
Speaker 5:  Walmart at the end. Walmart buys,
Speaker 7:  Wait, wait, hear me out, tabula.
Speaker 6:  Oh God.
Speaker 5:  Oh, well that's the end of, that's the end of the internet, everybody. Okay.
Speaker 5:  So that's one trial. We, we know what's gonna happen that's ongoing. We're
Speaker 5:  gonna cover, keep covering that one really deeply, simultaneously
Speaker 5:  in the same building meta's on trial. And that might
Speaker 5:  result in the breakup of Instagram and WhatsApp. I would say that one started
Speaker 5:  out sleepy. I I got a note today from an executive in
Speaker 5:  the industry says we, we complain too much about market definitions of Alex
Speaker 5:  eat last week. That it doesn't matter as much. The judges is gonna
Speaker 5:  decide whatever. And that it's the emails and Kevin
Speaker 5:  Strom on stage saying, meta tried to choke Instagram after it acquired it.
Speaker 5:  That will win the day.
Speaker 6:  I have done a 180 on this trial in the span of seven days.
Speaker 5:  Okay, tell me why
Speaker 6:  I left last week. Basically being like, the government
Speaker 6:  doesn't know how, how to categorize meta and it's gonna tank
Speaker 6:  its case, right? Like meta is very deliberately all things to all people.
Speaker 6:  And that is a very hard thing to put a market definition on. And if you can't
Speaker 6:  have a good market definition, you can't call it a monopoly. And
Speaker 6:  meta is not a monopoly on the internet. And so it's like that there was just
Speaker 6:  that fundamental disconnect that it was like, maybe, maybe the case
Speaker 6:  against Meta is going to hinge on wrapping its arms around meta. And that's
Speaker 6:  gonna be very hard to do. But then Kevin Strom gets on
Speaker 6:  the stand and just spends a day just
Speaker 6:  throwing darts at every other executive at Meta. Mark
Speaker 6:  Zuckerberg in particular,
Speaker 5:  Kevin Strom, famously the founder of Instagram, one of the co-founders of
Speaker 5:  Instagram.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Sold Instagram to Facebook, then called Facebook for a billion dollars.
Speaker 6:  Obviously Instagram is Instagram and
Speaker 6:  Mark Zuckerberg's argument before Kevin Sichem took the stand is essentially
Speaker 6:  that Instagram is only Instagram because of this company that we,
Speaker 6:  we have the resources, we poured fuel on the fire. It grew because of us,
Speaker 6:  like on and on and on. And we talked last week about it's actually hard to
Speaker 6:  prove otherwise. And then Kevin Sichem came and sat on the stand and said
Speaker 6:  otherwise over and over and over again, that actually what happened was Instagram
Speaker 6:  came aboard and was starved for resources that Mark Zuckerberg
Speaker 6:  saw Instagram as a threat. And so took stuff away from it in order to prevent
Speaker 6:  it from growing and killing Facebook. And, and this is a thing
Speaker 6:  we've heard kind of intermittently over the years is that like Mark Zuckerberg
Speaker 6:  runs a big company, but like Facebook is his special baby. And anything
Speaker 6:  that threatens the Facebook platform
Speaker 6:  cannot be allowed to do that. Like that that tracks with what we know of
Speaker 6:  his personality and history. That Facebook, the thing is more
Speaker 6:  important to him than anything else in his empire. And
Speaker 6:  so rum just gets up there and basically for like a whole day was just
Speaker 6:  like Instagram was killing it. And then we continued to kill it more or
Speaker 6:  less in spite of the company that acquired us, which by the way got an
Speaker 6:  unbelievably great deal in doing so.
Speaker 5:  Do you think Mark Zuckerberg uses Facebook? No.
Speaker 6:  I mean, he posts on Facebook, but what is, what is there for him to use?
Speaker 6:  Like is he looking at all the AI generated memes? Like, because he's on
Speaker 5:  Marketplace. I've heard this thing that he loves Facebook and, and I'm sure
Speaker 5:  he loves the charts and graphs that say he's rich. You know,
Speaker 5:  like Facebook makes so much money that when they think they're gonna have
Speaker 5:  a bad quarter, like PMs can just like turn knobs
Speaker 5:  to make the revenue targets. Like it's nuts. It it the scale and the
Speaker 5:  power of Facebook. But if you say to someone, I
Speaker 5:  heard someone say this today on the train, he sounds like
Speaker 5:  he reads a lot of Facebook. He sounds like he spends a lot of time on Facebook.
Speaker 5:  And I was like, I know exactly what that means and it's bad. Yeah, it's not
Speaker 5:  right, it's not good. And it's like, do you think Mark Berg is
Speaker 5:  just like Facebook brained? Like that would be horrible and that
Speaker 5:  it's whatever Instagram is, whatever it's becoming now
Speaker 5:  full of ai slap for a minute. It was cool,
Speaker 5:  right? And it still, it it still has a place in the culture. It's very
Speaker 5:  important. Yeah. In a way that Facebook, the only reason I use It is 'cause
Speaker 5:  like the parents group at the school is on Facebook.
Speaker 6:  Okay. But if I'm, if I'm gonna psychoanalyze Mark Zuckerberg here
Speaker 5:  For minute, also, sometimes I take I type Mustang in a marketplace and I
Speaker 5:  just think about the lives I could lead. That's it.
Speaker 6:  I've been shopping for patio furniture on marketplace and It is
Speaker 6:  not a great time.
Speaker 5:  I'm just saying if you wanna buy like a, a mid two thousands Terminator cobra,
Speaker 5:  you can find one on Facebook marketplace
Speaker 5:  continue.
Speaker 6:  But okay, so if, if I'm gonna psychoanalyze Mark Zuckerberg for a second,
Speaker 6:  which feels dangerous. I think
Speaker 6:  what is true of Facebook and meta at large
Speaker 6:  is that the, the wrap on the company is that all meta has ever done is,
Speaker 6:  is copy. That It is a very successful and ruthless fast follower,
Speaker 6:  right? That what It is in many ways is a collection of other
Speaker 6:  people's good ideas executed on at larger scale except
Speaker 6:  Facebook. Mark Zuckerberg did Facebook. Right? Like that is, that is a real
Speaker 6:  thing that he holds onto. And I think if you're Mark Zuckerberg and you are
Speaker 6:  this like business tycoon who is sort of
Speaker 6:  known for being a monster, as much as you are like a
Speaker 6:  great coder,
Speaker 6:  Facebook is the thing that you did. And I think that is forever really
Speaker 6:  meaningful to someone. Like he doesn't sure, he doesn't get credit for Instagram
Speaker 6:  the same way he doesn't deserve credit for Instagram the same way, same with
Speaker 6:  WhatsApp. Like those are part of his business empire, but they're not like
Speaker 6:  things that he did. And I think the the world sees it that way.
Speaker 6:  And I I would, I would bet that he sees it that way too. But
Speaker 5:  Like in the context of this, they also launched Threads, right?
Speaker 5:  And Threads is was a copy of Twitter. It now is a weird parallel
Speaker 5:  ecosystem of just like, it's still creators doing prompts all
Speaker 5:  day long. Yeah. But like the prompts are getting darker and weirder. Like,
Speaker 5:  tell me five people you hate something like what is happening on
Speaker 5:  Threads? And they adversary just launched
Speaker 5:  their cap cut clone Edits, like Instagram is getting ready for TikTok to
Speaker 5:  go away. Yes. And they're doing it by cloning all the rest of tiktoks
Speaker 5:  features. They're doing it by turning threads into more of a posting
Speaker 5:  platform for like, they're building a creator marketing
Speaker 5:  platform that still has nothing to do with Facebook as far as I can tell.
Speaker 5:  Like, all of the interesting things that are happening at Meta are happening
Speaker 5:  and the threads Instagram zone,
Speaker 5:  but nothing is happening on, on It is like, if you care about it the most,
Speaker 5:  like why don't you have any ideas for it?
Speaker 6:  Well, there's that, I mean, I think, I think to some extent that's
Speaker 6:  a view that is easy to hold for people of a certain age in the United States,
Speaker 6:  right? Which are like Facebook's least engaged demographic right now.
Speaker 6:  But It is true that you go lots of pla other places around the world and
Speaker 6:  Facebook is much more like central to culture and it's very important. But
Speaker 6:  also to your previous point, Facebook is now so big
Speaker 6:  that I think you can't mess with it. And, and like we, we've even
Speaker 6:  seen in the trial last week, Zuckerberg had used to have all these wild ideas.
Speaker 6:  What if we reset everybody's friend count every year and made them
Speaker 6:  rebuild it from scratch? Which the more I think about It is an idea that
Speaker 6:  I love. And I think all of social media should maybe adopt this like on January 1st,
Speaker 6:  every year you just start from a clean slate and have to do it again. Amazing.
Speaker 6:  Should do that. But like
Speaker 6:  increasingly It is like, it's both sort of too big to fail and also too
Speaker 6:  big to do anything with. So it's just kind of left over here.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. By itself. Kevin
Speaker 5:  Citro showing up in saying I could have done this. No problem. I think is
Speaker 5:  to your point, devastating to, to meta in this case.
Speaker 6:  Yes. Because
Speaker 5:  He's, he, he's very confident that he could have succeeded here.
Speaker 7:  But David, you were saying that like market definition is not going to be
Speaker 7:  important. But it sounds like you're saying that actually what matters
Speaker 7:  in the end is people just don't like Facebook. Right? And, and like, is that
Speaker 7:  enough to get a judge to agree that It is a monopoly? Like I still just
Speaker 7:  fundamentally, right? Instagram could have been great on its own. Sure,
Speaker 7:  sure, that's fine. But that doesn't make meta a monopoly
Speaker 7:  today, does it? But
Speaker 5:  It's not today. It's not today. This is actually a, as I've done more
Speaker 5:  reporting on this and talked to more people, the
Speaker 5:  the thing that the government is, is trying to argue as clearly as it can
Speaker 5:  is the bad thing that happened is Mark Zuckerberg's saw upstart competitors
Speaker 5:  and tried to kill them. And here now are the founders of
Speaker 5:  those competitors showing up and saying, we got bought, they
Speaker 5:  paid the money. And this argument that they supercharged
Speaker 5:  our growth is just fiction, right? Because actually what there was was
Speaker 5:  jealousy and a reduction in resources. And we could would've raised money
Speaker 5:  or grown on our own or been more innovative. But instead I fought these political
Speaker 5:  battles,
Speaker 6:  Which is a tricky argument because like scoreboard, right? Yeah. Like look
Speaker 6:  at Instagram, you, you can't argue that Instagram has not been a huge success.
Speaker 6:  That's just, that doesn't work. But, but Citro got up there and
Speaker 6:  was basically like we succeeded against the wishes of our
Speaker 6:  acquirer. Which I think to your point Eli, is if that
Speaker 6:  argument is successful, that's the argument that wins this case. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  So by the way, meta, you know, Andy Stone from Meta is out there being like,
Speaker 5:  look at all this nice stuff Kevin SRAM has said in the public in the past.
Speaker 5:  And it's like, well dude, he wasn't on in court under oath.
Speaker 5:  Like totally free to say whatever he wants. Like he worked for you. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  of course. He said nice things when he worked for you.
Speaker 6:  He's also got his fuck you money now in like a very real way.
Speaker 5:  I mean, that's the dream, right? Yeah. Is to sell the company for a billion
Speaker 5:  dollars and then like years later show up and be like, you were a dick.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  That's again, that one's very clean. I can see it, I can see how Instagram
Speaker 5:  survives as a business all on its own. I can't quite see how WhatsApp
Speaker 5:  survives as a business all its own. But the most interesting thing about
Speaker 5:  that conversation is the founders of WhatsApp had no
Speaker 5:  intention of being a big business. And Zuckerberg was like shocked
Speaker 5:  by, I think he said they they lacked ambition.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. They just were happy doing their thing and they, they were like a small
Speaker 6:  team that was massively successful. They probably would
Speaker 6:  never have been a, whatever it was, $21 billion business that they ended
Speaker 6:  up selling for.
Speaker 6:  But yeah, they were fine with that. And, and in a really funny way that
Speaker 6:  gave them tons of leverage. Yeah. It also turns out that
Speaker 6:  this is the other thing that came up in, in court was that absolutely everyone
Speaker 6:  wanted to buy WhatsApp. Like we, we kind of knew that at the time,
Speaker 6:  but Google kicked the tires. I think Twitter at the time kicked
Speaker 6:  the tires. Like it was, it was very clear that this was going to be
Speaker 6:  a thing. And it, it gave, it gave
Speaker 6:  WhatsApp a lot of leverage and credibility, but it also put meta in a position
Speaker 6:  of being like, oh, this thing is a huge threat to us as being validated.
Speaker 6:  We have to go get it right now. Wow.
Speaker 5:  I dunno what's gonna happen in this one. I i, the, the, the, the, the twists
Speaker 5:  and turns day by day in this trial. You know, there's this a very old
Speaker 5:  cliche in like lawyer world, that if you don't have the law on your side,
Speaker 5:  you argue the facts and you don't have the facts, you argue the law. If you
Speaker 5:  don't have either, you pound the table. This is like a joke that, oh, that's
Speaker 5:  good all and it feels like meta doesn't have the facts. So they're really
Speaker 5:  focused on these very hyper-technical legal arguments. And
Speaker 5:  then it's also just like the Trump FTC is in charge of this trial and I Mark
Speaker 5:  Zuckerberg's in the Oval Office, like throwing money around, like no idea
Speaker 5:  what's gonna happen here. But it does seem like my prediction
Speaker 5:  with Google is 36 months, totally different company one way or
Speaker 5:  another, 36 months from now, 36 months from now. What do you think meta looks
Speaker 5:  like?
Speaker 6:  Jake, what do you think?
Speaker 7:  I I think they're gonna walk out of this. I think they're gonna be fine.
Speaker 7:  It it, it's, it's a confusing technical trial and
Speaker 7:  I, I don't know how much the Trump White House has committed to this thing.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I keep saying it's the most legible one. It's very hard to explain
Speaker 5:  Google Ad Tech to people.
Speaker 7:  But I I that it's so funny 'cause I I still feel like this trial
Speaker 7:  is, we don't like meta Yeah. We don't like Mark Zuckerberg.
Speaker 7:  That is is valid. Very legible. That is very, very, very, very real.
Speaker 7:  But it, I, I don't know, is is it against the law? Like,
Speaker 5:  Ugh, you're so unlikeable. It's illegal.
Speaker 7:  That's tough
Speaker 5:  Right now in the American legal system, like edging closer to a viable,
Speaker 5:  it's close. We'll see, we'll see. David, what's your prediction?
Speaker 6:  IIII think what meta should do
Speaker 6:  and genuinely might, is just spin off Instagram of its own volition.
Speaker 6:  I think that solves this problem. You can't spin out WhatsApp in the same
Speaker 6:  way, but I think it, it, it agrees to a
Speaker 6:  settlement where it spins off Instagram and actually wins
Speaker 6:  just as much because Instagram would be fabulously successful on its own.
Speaker 6:  Do
Speaker 5:  You think there's like a move in inside Meta that's like, let Messer Cook?
Speaker 6:  Yeah, I kind of, I mean, Moser's been cooking, right? Like it's,
Speaker 6:  it's not nothing that he has been out in front of this company for a
Speaker 6:  pretty long time now and keep pioneered the chain. Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 6:  So another thing that Mark Fast followed,
Speaker 5:  I mean, I I've been saying this for months on this show, that these companies
Speaker 5:  should break themselves up before the government does it for them. And I,
Speaker 5:  I could buy that, but I I I, they're too proud of a company to, to do that.
Speaker 6:  Can I just say real quick, I just wanna shout out to people before we get
Speaker 6:  off this topic. One is Lauren Finer, who has been in court,
Speaker 6:  it's multiple courtrooms at a time all week and has been doing awesome work
Speaker 6:  for us all over the website. The other person is Dirk Stoop,
Speaker 6:  who was a former product manager on the Facebook camera team
Speaker 6:  who was called up to testify in this trial and was basically asked
Speaker 6:  a series of questions that amounted to why was Facebook camera so bad that
Speaker 6:  they had to buy Instagram. And that's tough. And I that's, I just wanna
Speaker 6:  say to Dirk that you you did, you did your best and I'm very sorry you
Speaker 6:  did those three
Speaker 5:  Best socks. Big shout out to Lauren, by the way. We would've had her on the
Speaker 5:  show, but she's in court right now. Yeah,
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Literally the next time Lauren comes out of the DC Circuit Courthouse,
Speaker 6:  we will have her on this show.
Speaker 5:  Yeah, but she, yeah, she's killing it. All right. We gotta take a break
Speaker 5:  and rest up for the lighting round. You let us know. You tell me
Speaker 5:  what you think. Email us 36 months around, what do these companies look like?
Speaker 5:  I'm dying to All right, we gotta take a break. We'll be right back
Speaker 5:  We are back. It's time for the lightning round. Unsponsored for flavor.
Speaker 6:  We've gotten some t-shirt designs. I'm pretty excited about them
Speaker 5:  Today. I I, I had a meeting with a platform executive and
Speaker 5:  he was asked me some business questions and I was like, I don't know. I talked
Speaker 5:  to our publisher Allen, she's very smart, and he was like, you don't get
Speaker 5:  involved in your business. And I was like, no, what I sell is our ethics
Speaker 5:  policy. He goes, oh, that's very royal. And it was a real interaction I had
Speaker 5:  and I was like, It is very royal. That's what we sell here, because it,
Speaker 5:  you know, it's like high and mighty. That's what he meant. Oh,
Speaker 6:  Not like of the Royals. I was like, no, he
Speaker 5:  Didn't mean that like me and Meghan Markle have anything in common. He meant
Speaker 5:  that you sound like a pompous jerk. And I was like, I am in fact
Speaker 5:  very, very precious about the fact that you can't pay me to say anything
Speaker 5:  unless you new sponsor the lightning round. In which case, let's talk.
Speaker 6:  It's time for our new segment in the lightning round. Neli versus Meghan
Speaker 6:  Markle,
Speaker 6:  who wore best.
Speaker 5:  It's time to get some clicks on YouTube, my friends.
Speaker 5:  Let's do it. We're going straight into celebrity coverage. All the latest
Speaker 5:  in Celebrity Defamation. I don't know anything about that.
Speaker 6:  She does have a podcast. I think so. Technically she is our enemy now. So
Speaker 5:  Did she win the Webby for Best Technology podcast? I'm saying she did not.
Speaker 5:  Duchess. Yeah. All right. I don't
Speaker 6:  Sign
Speaker 7:  US BBC takes. Were just, they're outta left field did not make any sense.
Speaker 7:  I know the, the people weren't buying it,
Speaker 5:  But wait, but I think the audience knows. I think Suits is a horrible show.
Speaker 5:  All right, we have to stop talking about Meghan
Speaker 6:  Markle.
Speaker 5:  Ooh. All right, David. Is it time?
Speaker 6:  It's time. It is time once again for
Speaker 6:  the 2026 Webby winning podcast. Within a podcast.
Speaker 6:  We're gonna win so hard. We create a category just so we can win it.
Speaker 6:  Brendan Carr is a dummy. Neli what he got,
Speaker 5:  Brendan had a, he had a quiet week. He did, he had a quiet week.
Speaker 5:  He went to a satellite company in Texas with Ted Cruz
Speaker 5:  and said he was bringing American innovation back in a way that required
Speaker 5:  him to say Ted Cruz is like cool and smart
Speaker 5:  again. I think Brendan's a dummy. So he got hoodwinked by Ted Cruz and having
Speaker 5:  to say, Ted Cruz is cool and smart. So that happened. The really interesting
Speaker 5:  things that happened with Brendan this week. Amount to who he
Speaker 5:  will talk to and who he will not talk to. Okay. The thesis
Speaker 5:  of the Trump administration this time around is what if corruption
Speaker 5:  was cool, right? You can see it all over the place. Like what if
Speaker 5:  Mark Zuckerberg gives Trump a million dollars? Is that enough to settle a
Speaker 5:  lawsuit? The answer is no. So we're gonna find out if it's $2 million. Like
Speaker 5:  there's just a lot of what if corruption was cool happening in this
Speaker 5:  administration? So the first one is just so
Speaker 5:  funny. Who is, who is Brenda meeting with? Well, he's meeting with his old
Speaker 5:  boss, a Jeep Pie, who is in the White House and at the FCC this week in his
Speaker 5:  new role is president of the CTIA, which is the wireless industry's
Speaker 5:  number one lobbying group. And they're posting selfies together. So
Speaker 5:  here's the head of the FCC posting selfies with his old boss
Speaker 5:  who is now the top lobbyist for the wireless companies that Brendan
Speaker 5:  regulates just openly corrupt. Like, it's just like hilariously corrupt,
Speaker 5:  right? Like these guys are supposed to
Speaker 5:  be on opposite sides of the fence and there's always a weirdness, right?
Speaker 5:  With, with the regulator and the companies they regulate. 'cause the regulator
Speaker 5:  wants the companies to be successful. We all want the wireless companies
Speaker 5:  to like have good networks and charge reasonable rates and all this stuff.
Speaker 5:  And you're like, no, that's a gpi. Like he, he's the one who was
Speaker 5:  like, you know what we should do? We should create Dish Network. Like, it
Speaker 5:  doesn't make any sense at all. None of this makes any sense. Like what if
Speaker 5:  we went from having lots of competitors to three and then a
Speaker 5:  fake network that ran something called Open ran that doesn't work
Speaker 5:  every day. The CEO of Verizon wakes up thinking about Dish Network. Like
Speaker 5:  it's just a fake, it's a totally fake situation. Yeah. But he's in the office,
Speaker 5:  a Jeep Pie taking Softies together. You know who he's not meeting with
Speaker 5:  David Ellison, who wants to buy Paramount and CBS
Speaker 6:  Reporting
Speaker 5:  In puck this week. Brendan who has threatened CBS Trump
Speaker 5:  has threatened CBS over 60 minutes. News distortion, all the censorship he
Speaker 5:  wants to do, saying I wanna have investigations into CBS and how it works.
Speaker 5:  Well, the potential acquirer of Paramount in C Bs, David
Speaker 5:  Ellison, whose father is Larry Ellison, notable Trump donor
Speaker 5:  can't get Brandon on the phone.
Speaker 6:  Interesting. That's a weird one because I mean, the other news this week
Speaker 6:  was Bill Owens, the, the, the executive producer
Speaker 6:  of 60 Minutes quit basically because he was like, I, I
Speaker 6:  have become a corporate problem. And because of all
Speaker 6:  the like journalistic shenanigans of the parent company,
Speaker 6:  he was like, I, I can't, I can't be here anymore. And all of this is being
Speaker 6:  done in this incredibly crappy, shady, anti
Speaker 6:  journalistic way so that Brendan Carr will take David Ellison's phone calls.
Speaker 6:  That's the whole point of all of this, is we are going to write giant
Speaker 6:  settlement checks so that they let the deal go through. Yep.
Speaker 6:  And it's just, it's just not happening.
Speaker 5:  What if corruption worked, right? It's, and the answer is the check isn't
Speaker 5:  big enough. The capitulation hasn't been big enough. There's a Bill Owens
Speaker 5:  a 60 minutes producer said, I can't produce a show in an independent way
Speaker 5:  anymore. I've gotta go. The corporate pressure on the news division is too
Speaker 5:  high and it's still not enough. And so the thesis is, and
Speaker 5:  this is in the, in the puck article, we'll, we'll put it in the, the show
Speaker 5:  notes is legally this is all bad.
Speaker 5:  These are clear violations of the First Amendment for the FCC to, to
Speaker 5:  say, we'll launch an investigation in 60 minutes for Donald Trump to say,
Speaker 5:  last week, I think Brendan Carr should pull CBS's broadcast license 'cause
Speaker 5:  they didn't like the coverage. You take that to court, you're gonna win.
Speaker 5:  Right? That, that's just violations of the First Amendment straightforwardly.
Speaker 5:  News distortion does not mean I don't like it. Like there's,
Speaker 5:  there's a real standard there, there's a jurisprudence. These cases aren't
Speaker 5:  brought very often because they're incredibly hard for the government to
Speaker 5:  win, for good reason because the First Amendment exists. But they
Speaker 6:  Have no intention of winning it. They have an in, they have every intention
Speaker 6:  of of getting a check and an apology.
Speaker 5:  What they want is power. So you don't take the call and you make the person
Speaker 5:  do more and more stuff to bend to your will to get what you
Speaker 5:  want. And this is the thesis now. He will meet with a jet in his office,
Speaker 5:  take selfies together to give the wireless companies more spectrum because
Speaker 5:  they spend a lot of money on lobbying, but he won't meet with David
Speaker 5:  Ellison, whose deal he's blocking on totally specious grounds. So
Speaker 5:  that CBS will put even more pressure on its new division that is just
Speaker 5:  censorship stuff. That is just Brendan trying to
Speaker 5:  shift what is acceptable public debate in his role as a government
Speaker 5:  regulator speech. As always, this is a disaster for the First
Speaker 5:  Amendment for American civil liberties. And you can see at some
Speaker 5:  point the rich people who wanna buy CBS who own the networks should start
Speaker 5:  fighting back. 'cause when they're fighting back in other parts of the government,
Speaker 5:  when Harvard fights back against Trump administration, they start to cave.
Speaker 5:  But no one's really pushed back on Brendan yet, at least from the
Speaker 5:  industry. But the thing that's starting to happen that I think is fascinating
Speaker 5:  is the other commissioners of the FCC former commissioners of the FCC
Speaker 5:  are starting to push back very loudly. So Anna Gomez,
Speaker 5:  who is a democratic commissioner of the SEC, is going on tour. She's
Speaker 5:  actually, I think she's starting today as we record, she's going on tour
Speaker 5:  to protect the First Amendment.
Speaker 5:  It's called the First Amendment Tour to
Speaker 6:  Challenge. What a cool thing to say, by the way, I'm going on tour to protect
Speaker 6:  the First Amendment.
Speaker 5:  The tour is called the First Amendment tour to challenge government censorship
Speaker 5:  and control. So she announced today she's having events all over the country.
Speaker 5:  She says the FCC is being weaponized under Brendan Carr to
Speaker 5:  attack freedom of speech in the media and telecommunication sector instead
Speaker 5:  of focusing on its core mission, connecting the public, protecting consumers
Speaker 5:  and supporting competition. I
Speaker 6:  Feel like we can't say clearly enough that that is from another FCC
Speaker 6:  commissioner
Speaker 5:  From another FCC commissioner, his colleague,
Speaker 5:  weird. They go to the same office, they, they park their cars next to each
Speaker 5:  other and she's like, Hey, you're a weird threat to America. I mean, they
Speaker 6:  Actively work together closely.
Speaker 5:  I it's unclear under
Speaker 6:  Normal circumstances,
Speaker 5:  It's unclear. Look, the FCC, I've covered the FCC for a long time until Brendan
Speaker 5:  got there. This was never a bunch of fire breathers,
Speaker 5:  a bunch of gray suit government lawyers being like, we need to allocate the
Speaker 5:  spectrum efficient. Like that's, and now they're like a censorship machine.
Speaker 5:  And you can see it took a while
Speaker 5:  for everyone else to be like, oh, this is really bad. They had to shake off
Speaker 5:  the character they were supposed to play and adopt these new characters.
Speaker 5:  Anna Gomez. Silencing, dissenting voices is not a show of strength. It's
Speaker 5:  a sign of fear. We must continue to speak out against the growing campaign
Speaker 5:  of censorship and control before this dangerous new normal becomes the status
Speaker 5:  quo. That's her talking about nominally her boss. Yeah. Weird.
Speaker 5:  Yeah,
Speaker 6:  But good. This is like, if you ever discovered the podcast I have where I
Speaker 6:  just say mean things about you the whole time that's like that,
Speaker 5:  Then I think you will see some signs of fear data.
Speaker 5:  Crazy, right? Like this is happening in the government right now,
Speaker 5:  sitting commissioners of the FCC who might be illegally fired by Trump. He's
Speaker 5:  already illegal fired, legally fired commissioners at the Federal Trade Commission.
Speaker 5:  He's threatened to illegally fire Powell at the, at the Fed. She's speaking
Speaker 5:  out. Good for her. She's welcome. If you wanna on tour, you wanna stop with
Speaker 5:  us and the coder, we'd love to have you commissioner, former commissioner
Speaker 5:  Tom Wheeler is out with peace and law this week saying
Speaker 5:  Brendan Carr is moving to break foundational principles of
Speaker 5:  American government and democracy. I've met Tom Wheeler. Tom
Speaker 5:  Wheeler has been on VERGE shows before. Go back and just look at a
Speaker 5:  picture of Tom Wheeler, like, look at him, watch his
Speaker 5:  interactions with me as I push him on things. He is not a,
Speaker 5:  you're gonna break foundational principles of American government and democracy.
Speaker 5:  Editorial writer. He is not a bomb thrower. He is, he was a government
Speaker 5:  regulator of spectrum. He famously, he came from the industry. People
Speaker 5:  criticized Obama for revolving door hiring wheels. And
Speaker 5:  here he is saying, cars actions marking unprecedented
Speaker 5:  expansion of government intrusion in his free speech and a direct assault
Speaker 5:  on those engaged in promoting equal opportunity. They undermine the constitutional
Speaker 5:  balance of power by bypassing co-equal branches of government to enlarge
Speaker 5:  presidential authority through self-serving presidential decree
Speaker 6:  For a high level bureaucrat that is like screaming swears as
Speaker 6:  loudly as you possibly can. Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Again, I've known, I've known Wheeler for a long time. Just listen
Speaker 5:  to him, talk to me about anything in the past,
Speaker 5:  gaze upon him perceived on Wheeler. And he is like, yeah, you're doing some
Speaker 5:  dictator stuff, man. It's not normal. So there's some
Speaker 5:  pushback against Carr this week. He, again, he was in Texas having to pretend
Speaker 5:  that Ted Cruz is hip and cool. But I'm, I'm,
Speaker 5:  I'm happy to see Commissioner Gomez and now former Chairman Wheeler
Speaker 5:  really push back very loudly. And you can see it, it's, it's starting
Speaker 5:  to percolate throughout the media ecosystem again. There's a big puck article.
Speaker 5:  So yeah, the podcast within a podcast continues, but the, the
Speaker 5:  battle is joined. As always, Brendan,
Speaker 5:  you're welcome to to join us here on America's favorite podcast. Within a
Speaker 5:  podcast. If you have, if you are as cool as you think you are, you will join
Speaker 5:  a podcast called Brendan Carr is a dummy, right? If, if you have
Speaker 5:  it, you have the juice, you would be on the show.
Speaker 5:  You're also welcome on decoder, during which I'm much more polite.
Speaker 6:  Mm. That seems less fun.
Speaker 5:  I mean, look, dude, the CEO of Verizon Wireless was just on decoder. He did
Speaker 5:  not have to come on that show, but he's a fan had the best answer to the
Speaker 5:  decision making question I've ever heard one of the worst answers to Why
Speaker 5:  did you kill that neutrality you've ever heard? But that's life. So look,
Speaker 5:  it's equal opportunity.
Speaker 6:  It's a really great process for making really bad decisions. I love that.
Speaker 5:  It was good. It's a good episode. I highly recommend it. We got into it.
Speaker 5:  He's a listener. He is a virgin nerd. It was cool to talk to him. We
Speaker 5:  disagree about That's fine Brendan. You're welcome. It will maybe
Speaker 5:  be less cool. Oh, also, by the way, in that podcast article, Brendan's wife
Speaker 5:  McKayla, she is the top policy person at Palantir.
Speaker 5:  The, the MAGA universe. The MAGA extended universe
Speaker 5:  continues to grow. There
Speaker 6:  Are only like four companies in, in this entire world. It,
Speaker 6:  it turns out
Speaker 5:  All right, Brandon, you're welcome again. I, I think you're a coward, so
Speaker 5:  you won't show up and dummy. And so if you do, I think you'll lose. But you
Speaker 5:  should come on. It'll be fun. We'll have a good time. Bring
Speaker 6:  Ted Cruz. We'll have a great time.
Speaker 5:  I've been dying to debate Ted cr Ted Cruz. I, this is like one of those things
Speaker 5:  like what, what, what would you throw it all away for? And it's like yelling
Speaker 5:  at Ted Cruz. All right. We need a palate cleanser. David,
Speaker 6:  Can I just you in a wood smartphone? Is that, is that a good palate
Speaker 6:  cleanser
Speaker 6:  Jeep, I think is bringing back the wood. Jeeps wood is back, man. This is,
Speaker 6:  we're we're doing it here. Yeah. Because
Speaker 5:  We can't import anything else, right?
Speaker 6:  It's gonna cut down
Speaker 5:  More trees have to cut down America forests.
Speaker 6:  It's great.
Speaker 6:  Motorola came out with some new phones. I am torn on these.
Speaker 6:  So it's, it's three different flip phones like the, the
Speaker 6:  thing Motorola has been doing at the Razor. But the most interesting one
Speaker 6:  is the Razor Ultra, which I, I would say essentially
Speaker 6:  makes the same set of changes that the other new razors do, which is like,
Speaker 6:  you know, it's a little, a little faster. It has slightly better,
Speaker 6:  like build quality essentially. Like that's the thing Motorola sort of consistently
Speaker 6:  is trying to get better at. It's just like how to make these things nice.
Speaker 6:  But the ultra has a wood back. It's $1,300.
Speaker 6:  It is preposterous and I love it so much.
Speaker 5:  There's a really fun thing to do whenever this comes up, which is look at
Speaker 5:  our own links of our own coverage about Motorola making wooden
Speaker 5:  phones. And I'm just pointing out that in 2014,
Speaker 5:  January 29th, 2014, David Pierce wrote a story about the
Speaker 5:  Moto X called the New Retro, how Motorola brought wood back.
Speaker 5:  Literally. And it's about the wooden back of the Moto X and the first line,
Speaker 5:  the lead. That's terrible. I don't know how you and I chose this 'cause I
Speaker 5:  remember editing this story, but the lead of this story,
Speaker 5:  the first sentence not so long ago, wood was everywhere
Speaker 5:  in the world of consumer electronics
Speaker 6:  Was this is fact. And by not so long
Speaker 6:  ago, I mean the mid 1970s,
Speaker 5:  It's like, okay, look on website, it's like a time capsule into like,
Speaker 5:  what were we thinking?
Speaker 6:  Jake, what do you think about this phone? Be with me on this, Jake. Well,
Speaker 6:  there's a, there's a, a key
Speaker 7:  Feature that you failed to mention
Speaker 5:  By the way. The, the Motorola executive editor in 2014 was Rick Oslo, who
Speaker 5:  now on,
Speaker 6:  So I was writing, so was he Fontan? Yeah.
Speaker 7:  Key feature you forgot to mention. Exclusive to the ultra
Speaker 7:  big upgrade possibility here. AI button on the side.
Speaker 6:  Oh.
Speaker 7:  So what,
Speaker 6:  What kind of button are we talking about? I missed this. I need to look at
Speaker 6:  pictures of this now.
Speaker 7:  It is like your standard flavor button. It's, it, it
Speaker 7:  opens up some AI menu where you can maybe
Speaker 7:  th there's, there's been a lot of noise this week about how perplexity is
Speaker 7:  gonna come pre-installed on this thing.
Speaker 7:  I think perplexity was, was probably hoping everyone would,
Speaker 7:  you know, thi think this is a, a more serious integration.
Speaker 7:  Not just
Speaker 6:  The care is the world
Speaker 7:  Is on the second screen when you open it up.
Speaker 7:  You know, much potential there. I would say in another world where Gemini
Speaker 7:  didn't exist.
Speaker 7:  But listen, I'm all for it. I love it. They also have an
Speaker 7:  alcantara, I dunno if I'm saying that right version. Yeah. So really it's
Speaker 7:  hot, greatest hits Surface line. Gave that up.
Speaker 7:  You know, we're due for some fun phone textures. I feel like the razor line
Speaker 7:  in its way is sort of all about throwback stuff. This is
Speaker 7:  fun. It's cool. I love it. It's unfortunate that It is exclusive to
Speaker 7:  the ultra version, which is the most expensive version. And I think you're
Speaker 7:  stuck with, you know, the plain old options on the like
Speaker 7:  standard model that I think most people probably go for. But,
Speaker 7:  but even
Speaker 6:  The standard ones, I will say have, they're, they're doing a fun sort of
Speaker 6:  two-tone color thing where the bottom half is one color. Mm. And the top
Speaker 6:  half is another color. It's just nice, right? Like we're in, we're in this
Speaker 6:  moment where like the best you can hope for is like a gentle blue on your
Speaker 6:  smartphone. Mm. I bought my phone just to get the blue and
Speaker 6:  that's, this is what excitement looks like in smartphones now. And
Speaker 6:  like genuinely kudos to Motorola for a
Speaker 6:  continuing to go with the only thing it ever did that anyone cares about,
Speaker 6:  which is the razor. Yeah. Like truly, I, I mean that sincerely.
Speaker 5:  And also apparently wooden phones, which you cared about a lot in 2014. Listen,
Speaker 5:  this story is very long.
Speaker 6:  The Moto X was sick.
Speaker 7:  There's two things and they, this just combines them.
Speaker 5:  That's exactly, can I continue to read you quotes from Rick Oslow to David Pierce
Speaker 5:  from the story from 2014? Sure. The ex phone team started
Speaker 5:  to show the wooden models to focus groups and the response was overwhelming
Speaker 5:  quote. People were immediately like, whoa, that's different from anything
Speaker 5:  I've seen before. People couldn't believe that it was actually real.
Speaker 6:  That's a bad quote. That's my bad. I should have cut that one out.
Speaker 5:  Wait. And then he goes on to say there's no supply chain for wood. Oster
Speaker 5:  says
Speaker 6:  There's your headline.
Speaker 5:  Wood is typically used for furniture and stuff. It's a totally
Speaker 5:  group of people from the people we normally do business with.
Speaker 6:  Wood is typically used for furniture and stuff. That's the insight you come
Speaker 6:  to The Verge for.
Speaker 5:  That's like we were, we just didn't, we did we, it was a long time ago. We
Speaker 5:  didn't really know what we were doing yet. Yeah. We're Rick, Rick rolled
Speaker 5:  us. Rick rolled David Pierce in particular with Here's how hard it was to
Speaker 5:  make a wooden phone.
Speaker 6:  All I'm saying is 11 years later we're back at it. So they must have
Speaker 6:  been on to something. Finding
Speaker 5:  Wood that won't wa warp, splinter or crack is hard.
Speaker 5:  Another, I think that was a pull quote actually. Is this one
Speaker 5:  wood or is it bamboo as well? The, the Moto X was bamboo, I believe
Speaker 6:  Alison who wrote about this and saw it. Her piece calls it a wood grain back
Speaker 6:  panel.
Speaker 5:  Oh boy. It's like a sticker.
Speaker 6:  Dunno what to make of the Yeah, it's, it's either like a sticker or
Speaker 6:  it's like wood in the way that Ikea furniture is wood.
Speaker 6:  It's like, it, it does make me slightly nervous. But all of this is like,
Speaker 6:  there's some interesting like, you know, material stuff going on, but it
Speaker 6:  just looks great and there's something to these things just being
Speaker 6:  more than a giant slab of glass that I think should be
Speaker 6:  explored a lot more than it has been recently. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And once we break up every single company, many more companies will be able
Speaker 5:  to build a wood supply chain. Perfect. I wanna end with
Speaker 5:  It is a big, think
Speaker 5:  YouTube turned 20 this week. We, we ran a piece about the
Speaker 5:  first videos and YouTube famously it was like my day at the zoo or whatever
Speaker 5:  it's called. And David, you wrote about YouTube itself. And then
Speaker 5:  YouTube TV is getting some changes and it's all kind of the same story. Like
Speaker 5:  there's still just random clips of stuff, but it did eventually
Speaker 5:  eat tv.
Speaker 6:  It really did eat tv. So that was the, the where I started with the story
Speaker 6:  was essentially trying to figure out like what is YouTube now? 'cause the
Speaker 6:  big change that happened at YouTube or really over the last
Speaker 6:  two or three years is that it became mostly a TV platform. Like
Speaker 6:  It is still viewed everywhere. It's still very popular, but It is like, it,
Speaker 6:  It is both in terms of how people watch YouTube and
Speaker 6:  how YouTube conceives of itself. It is mostly a TV
Speaker 6:  platform now. And I just think that's fascinating. So I talked to a bunch
Speaker 6:  of people across the company about like YouTube's conception of itself and
Speaker 6:  tried to understand just sort of like what makes this thing go
Speaker 6:  and landed on, essentially, this is a, not a reference
Speaker 6:  anyone is ever gonna remember, but there's this very famous Matt Taibbi story
Speaker 6:  in Rolling Stone about Goldman Sachs, where he described Goldman Sachs as
Speaker 6:  I'm paraphrasing, but a, a vampire squid that jumps on the
Speaker 6:  face of anything that smells like money and that's YouTube, but for content
Speaker 6:  and in a much less like society destroying way.
Speaker 6:  But this company's fascinating. Like I talked to the people there who do
Speaker 6:  the TV stuff and the people who do the gaming stuff and the people who do
Speaker 6:  the creator stuff. And overwhelmingly like, if you just think of YouTube
Speaker 6:  as like an insatiable content machine
Speaker 6:  that just, it will take anything that is content, however broadly you wanna
Speaker 6:  define that and it will put it into an algorithm that is very good at figuring
Speaker 6:  out what somebody is going to want and then stick it in front of you. That
Speaker 6:  is like, like you talk about Google Flywheels. That is Google's best
Speaker 6:  flywheel right now. Yeah, It is. It is unstoppable and It is working
Speaker 6:  way beyond anything I realized.
Speaker 7:  I think it's so interesting to be talking about this right after we discussed
Speaker 7:  the meta trial. 'cause meta they turned, or Facebook turned 20 last year,
Speaker 7:  YouTube turns 20 this week. And if you just look at the, the, the
Speaker 7:  cultural trajectory of those two platforms, they could not be more different.
Speaker 7:  That's so true. YouTube, I I I don't know that you'd necessarily call YouTube
Speaker 7:  a social platform Exactly. But I I think It is
Speaker 7:  probably at at a stronger place than it's ever been in many ways. And
Speaker 7:  Facebook, you just could not say the same thing by any stretch.
Speaker 7:  And IIII couldn't tell you exactly why, but maybe this is because they
Speaker 7:  have looked at it much more as a platform for other people's content and
Speaker 7:  they've just embraced that rather than I think trying to do
Speaker 7:  all those different social plays.
Speaker 5:  I kind of disagree and like a very small way. Not a, not a big way. Jake.
Speaker 5:  I think, I think you, you've got the shape of it, right? YouTube is a social
Speaker 5:  platform in that you as a user are meant to be in the
Speaker 5:  comment section. Hmm. You are not meant to be in the video box. There was
Speaker 5:  a weird period where they thought you were, everyone was supposed to be uploading
Speaker 5:  videos to YouTube, right? Like you can go, you like search
Speaker 5:  file names from a specific period of time and you get everybody's iPhone
Speaker 5:  videos. 'cause they thought it was just a general sharing platform that's
Speaker 5:  gone. They, they, they pivoted outta that really fast. Right? They invented
Speaker 5:  the YouTube creator Taylor Lawrence has a great history of where that
Speaker 5:  word came from. It came from the advertising industry actually, and MCNs,
Speaker 5:  like multichannel networks. They invented the YouTube creator who is
Speaker 5:  this like semi-professional and now very professional,
Speaker 5:  dominant culture maker. That's not regular people. Regular
Speaker 5:  people are doing social stuff on YouTube, right? They're, they're hitting
Speaker 5:  like, they're trying to get t series above PewDiePie. Like that's all
Speaker 5:  happening. Like it's very interactive in social, but it's, it's, it's not
Speaker 5:  in the main box. The main box is like for pros now
Speaker 5:  or people who wanna be pros. Whereas Instagram is still just everything all
Speaker 5:  at once. I think that's, that's the thing that keeps getting meta into trouble.
Speaker 5:  They have never built the thing that lets you, like my daughter just like
Speaker 5:  discovered that YouTuber is a job and now I have to stop that from now.
Speaker 6:  Oh, no,
Speaker 7:  I'm really sorry.
Speaker 5:  Right. But like, Instagram creator is like not really a job. TikTok is, is
Speaker 5:  a job. Like it's, It is just meta is in this weird space where it
Speaker 5:  never delineated all of those things.
Speaker 6:  Well, yeah, and I think, like, I remember when Threads was first launching,
Speaker 6:  Adam Aria was talking about, you know, there's something in the design of
Speaker 6:  the app where like the, the reply and the original post look the same. And
Speaker 6:  that's actually really important in an app like Threads or Twitter.
Speaker 6:  And to your point, Neil, YouTube never, ever, ever tried to do that. It always
Speaker 6:  had such a clear hierarchy of who you are and where you are on the platform.
Speaker 6:  And I think the, the thing that has made TikTok
Speaker 6:  interesting is that it has found the middle ground there that actually works
Speaker 6:  for people, right? Like the, the duets and the stitches. And they have really
Speaker 6:  forced YouTube to be reactive to that. But like, Jake, to
Speaker 6:  your point, what most people want, the vast majority of people want
Speaker 6:  is to mostly consume and like maybe
Speaker 6:  very lightly participate. And, and YouTube hit that formula early
Speaker 6:  on and then never ran away from it. Yeah. And like, even, even at times when
Speaker 6:  it looked like, like it maybe should have when like Facebook was ascendant
Speaker 6:  and all of a sudden it was like, oh, we, we need to make this stuff more
Speaker 6:  interactive and do different kinds of feeds and all this stuff. YouTube just
Speaker 6:  like kept being YouTube and like history just proved it right over
Speaker 6:  and over and over again.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And it's funny 'cause the content got to move up, right? The, the product
Speaker 5:  didn't, the product always had that delineation and the stuff
Speaker 5:  in the video box got more and more and more premium and now it's eating tv.
Speaker 6:  Yeah.
Speaker 5:  And I, I think it's just fascinating. It's also why I think Google should
Speaker 5:  break itself up before the government shows up and distracts that whole company
Speaker 5:  away from whatever YouTube is or is becoming because it's,
Speaker 5:  I think YouTube looks more like Google's future than anything. And I think
Speaker 5:  Google kinds of, kind of knows it too, but it's just tied to this mess.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, no, I, I, I would agree with that. I think there's a, there's a strong
Speaker 6:  case to be made and people make this case. You see it from analysts and stuff
Speaker 6:  every once in a while, that YouTube is a substantially more valuable business
Speaker 6:  alone than It is inside of Google. Huh.
Speaker 5:  I wonder if one of the most fascinating things about Google and other people
Speaker 5:  have made this point for years now
Speaker 5:  is that no one pays attention to It is a platform
Speaker 5:  everyone is constantly paying attention to. Like tiktoks moderation rules.
Speaker 5:  Everyone is constantly paying attention to threads or X or whatever is
Speaker 5:  moderation rules. We all pay a lot of attention to Mark Zuckerberg and how
Speaker 5:  he feels about racism today.
Speaker 5:  Surprisingly more open to it than the day before. 'cause his company's on
Speaker 5:  trial. And what if corruption was good? Who knows? No one talks about YouTube
Speaker 5:  moderation. It just doesn't come up. We sometimes talk about YouTube radicalization,
Speaker 5:  what all the stuff, but the day-to-day YouTube stuff, even though
Speaker 5:  creators there, you know, my joke is that a creator gets their wings when
Speaker 5:  they make their first video about how they're mad at YouTube. Yeah. No one
Speaker 5:  talks about it. It's, it's, and I think that is part of the benefit of being
Speaker 5:  part of Google.
Speaker 5:  You just can't yell at YouTube like it's Google.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I also think It is, it's a big platform that feels
Speaker 6:  big in a way that, like TikTok is a really big platform that feels small,
Speaker 6:  right? And so I think it, it's very funny talking to people about their TikTok
Speaker 6:  feeds because you, you slowly discover over the course of a conversation
Speaker 6:  that, oh, my TikTok and your TikTok have nothing to do with each other. But
Speaker 6:  we both sort of open the app and use it in the same way. So I feel like I'm
Speaker 6:  getting some kind of universal experience. YouTube is just, it just feels
Speaker 6:  giant in a way that I feel like no one thinks they understand YouTube, which
Speaker 6:  really works to YouTube's benefit.
Speaker 7:  I think people engage with YouTube very differently too. Right? For, for
Speaker 7:  Facebook, for Instagram, even for Absolutely for TikTok, you go
Speaker 7:  specifically to those apps, YouTube comes to you. Yeah.
Speaker 7:  That's not, not true for everybody, right? You still open it up on your tv,
Speaker 7:  you still open up on the, on, on the website and browse, but you're gonna
Speaker 7:  find videos embedded. You're going to be sent a link. Right? When
Speaker 7:  was the last time somebody sent you a link to a piece of content on Facebook?
Speaker 7:  Like that wasn't a spammer. Like,
Speaker 5:  I mean, I send people spaghetti Jesus all day long. Whatcha talking
Speaker 6:  About? Dude, it's so funny. I asked you, I asked a bunch of people at YouTube
Speaker 6:  about that because I, I, I posed to one of their engineering people
Speaker 6:  that, like, my, my theory of the case for YouTube is that It is a very good
Speaker 6:  video player that is easily embedded across the internet. And for some reason,
Speaker 6:  no one else has figured out how to do that. And the guy kind of hemmed and
Speaker 6:  hawed and he gave, he gave me a, a good explanation for why that's not
Speaker 6:  the whole answer. And a lot of his answer is actually in the piece.
Speaker 6:  But then I was like, but, but explain to me why no one has done a good enough.
Speaker 6:  Like why aren't embeds as good as YouTube's? And he was kind of like, I don't
Speaker 6:  know. It's weird.
Speaker 6:  It's like you can't do it with music. Like there are no music embeds anywhere
Speaker 6:  on the internet that are as good as YouTube music videos, which is hugely
Speaker 6:  powerful for YouTube. And you, you just poke at that across everything. And
Speaker 6:  it's like the fact that none of these other platforms have invested in,
Speaker 6:  like you said, Jake, that sort of experience I have somewhere else that I
Speaker 6:  interact with. This content is just weird to me. And YouTube is ubiquitous
Speaker 6:  that way,
Speaker 5:  But you know, it's still connected to all the Google stuff. 'cause YouTube
Speaker 5:  is part of Google, which wants the web to be good, which invests in big web
Speaker 5:  containers Fair. Yeah. That its crawlers can see that are interoperable
Speaker 5:  across different browsers, all the web stuff fed into YouTube. Whereas I
Speaker 5:  think if they didn't have that pressure, they might be more closed. Like
Speaker 5:  all the other embeds.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, that's a fair's a fair point. Yeah.
Speaker 5:  I will say, I think it was either TikTok or Instagram that after we launched
Speaker 5:  a redesign, they made their embeds behave better. I was like, these embeds
Speaker 5:  are too tall for our design. And they were like, I don't remember which one
Speaker 5:  it was. They were like, I, I think it was Instagram. They're like, oh, that's
Speaker 5:  bad. But no one uses these embeds, so we never got this feedback.
Speaker 5:  Weird. All right. That's it. Tell me, tell I, I feel like
Speaker 5:  I've asked for a lot of emails from people. Send us your party speakers.
Speaker 5:  Tell me if you would buy Chrome and how much you've spent on it, and then
Speaker 5:  tell me about YouTube. I'm, I'm just sort of dying to know, like everyone
Speaker 5:  has a different YouTube, right? We're 20 years in. I have friends who only
Speaker 5:  watch YouTube, don't have streaming services. They just watch YouTube.
Speaker 6:  Okay. Real quick, before we go, let's, let's just do this. If you were to
Speaker 6:  go to youtube.com right now, what would it show you? Jake, you go first.
Speaker 6:  Oh,
Speaker 7:  It's all chess videos and Bon Appetit cooking content.
Speaker 6:  Oh, okay. Like chess tutorials or like Magnus Carlson. Like
Speaker 6:  being cool.
Speaker 7:  Oh, it's b Both. Both, yeah. It's like, It is like play
Speaker 7:  byplay. It's hugely embarrassing. I'm so sorry.
Speaker 6:  I love this for you. Neela, what's yours? Oh,
Speaker 5:  I've turned off all the tracking. It doesn't show me anything. It just begs
Speaker 5:  me to turn the tracking back on.
Speaker 6:  Get That's smart. Wow. You get just, it's like the, the one, no,
Speaker 5:  The line of text. They, they started, I think they've realized that this
Speaker 5:  was working too well. So they, they started flashing recommendations and
Speaker 5:  they take them away and say, your tracking is off.
Speaker 5:  And it's like, yeah, I know.
Speaker 6:  It's like, I'd love to show you this video. But what
Speaker 5:  I had the tracking, it was a lot of it was in the Covid era before I turned
Speaker 5:  the tracking off. It was a lot of, I don't remember the channel, a
Speaker 5:  guy who restores things, but he would like take an old drill and like
Speaker 5:  sandblast it and repaint it. And I found this very calming. I was like, I
Speaker 5:  just, I need projects to come to a conclusion because nothing in Covid felt
Speaker 5:  like a conclusion. So I would just watch this guy, he is like, I fixed this
Speaker 5:  hand mixer. I'm like, you did it. It is very good.
Speaker 6:  That is really good. Mine, I just went to youtube.com and mine is,
Speaker 6:  I would say a mix of female singer songwriter music videos,
Speaker 6:  which there's a lot of right now soccer highlights and
Speaker 6:  parks and rec competition. Oh, very good. Solid. That's my, that's my YouTube
Speaker 6:  right now.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I watched in embarrassing for our videos on YouTube. I'll
Speaker 5:  say it's very, it's very fun. Alright, that's it. That's for
Speaker 5:  chat. Send us notes. Want your feedback. If you see a party speaker, think
Speaker 5:  to yourself, is this enough? And then email it to me. That's it. That's for
Speaker 5:  cha roll.
Speaker 1:  That's,
Speaker 15:  And that's it for The Vergecast this week. And hey, we'd love to hear from
Speaker 15:  you. Give us a call at eight six six VERGE one one.
Speaker 15:  The Vergecast is a production of The Verge and the Vox Media Podcast network.
Speaker 15:  Our show is produced by Will Por, Eric Gomez and Brandon Keefer. And
Speaker 15:  that's it. We'll see you next week.