# Transcript
ID: 07cfd1d3-4910-484d-b4bb-22b93e78d52e
Status: Done
Stage: Done
Audio URL: https://jfe93e.s3.amazonaws.com/8437266010590801236/-4458498130052189700/s93290-US-5184s-1758505817.mp3
Description: It's been a busy week for The Verge's product reviewers! We've got three new phones, three new watches, and a set of earbuds on the docket, and the team is ready to talk about (almost) all of it. First, Allison Johnson and Jake Kastrenakes join to talk about their experiences with the iPhone Air, iPhone 17, and iPhone 17 Pro. One is fabulous with some compromises, one is just a down-the-middle excellent phone, and the other is for camera nerds. After that, Victoria Song talks about the AirPods Pro 3, which are also a stellar upgrade, and then helps us make sense of the new lineup of Apple Watches. There's the SE 3, the Series 11, and the Ultra 3, but there's only one clear winner for most people. Finally, we answer a question from the Vergecast Hotline (call 866-VERGE11 or email vergecast@theverge.com!) about Apple's up-and-down focus on AI
Speaker 1:  Welcome to The Vergecast, the flagship podcast of phones that look like
Speaker 1:  Phones. I'm your friend David Pierce, And I am decluttering
Speaker 1:  starting to anyway, so it looks like my wife And I are gonna be moving at
Speaker 1:  the end of October, which means that I have now six weeks
Speaker 1:  to get most of the things out of my house. And I would say like, I'm
Speaker 1:  not a pack rat or like a hoarder person in general, but I
Speaker 1:  do accumulate things. Part of that is just the nature of this job.
Speaker 1:  There's a lot of like iPad boxes and random
Speaker 1:  accessories lying around in the basement near me. And a lot of that needs
Speaker 1:  to get shipped and a lot of that needs to get thrown away. But I just,
Speaker 1:  I need a moment, like a few times a year to just really be like, okay,
Speaker 1:  time to get rid of most of the things that I own. It's a very productive
Speaker 1:  moment. It's a moment I actually really enjoy. I should probably do it more
Speaker 1:  often. So I have six weeks now to essentially declutter,
Speaker 1:  pack up and move sometime in the near future. I
Speaker 1:  suspect I'm gonna be doing this podcast from an entirely new place, But that
Speaker 1:  is not what we're here to talk about today or any of the days. For the next
Speaker 1:  six weeks, we're here to talk about Apple. So it's Apple
Speaker 1:  Review season. We have lots of new devices. Our team has been testing the
Speaker 1:  new devices and this is one of the most interesting gadget moments of
Speaker 1:  the year. Not necessarily because the Apple products themselves are so interesting,
Speaker 1:  but because this is a moment to kind of take stock of the whole gadget
Speaker 1:  world, this isn't the end of gadget season. We're about to have Meta Connect,
Speaker 1:  we're about to have some interesting Amazon hardware news I suspect in a
Speaker 1:  couple of weeks. There's a lot of stuff left to come, but this is
Speaker 1:  kind of the end of phone season in a certain way. It's also a good
Speaker 1:  time to just take stock of where we are, how Apple is doing,
Speaker 1:  and whether or not any of these gadgets are still moving forward in an
Speaker 1:  interesting way. So that's what we're gonna talk about. We're gonna have
Speaker 1:  Alison Johnson vs. Song and Jake Cast is on. They've been reviewing the devices,
Speaker 1:  they have lots of thoughts. I don't know anything about how they feel about
Speaker 1:  these devices yet, so hopefully we're gonna get some fireworks. All of that
Speaker 1:  is coming up in just a second, but first I just saw like 12 more things that
Speaker 1:  I need to throw away and post for free on Nextdoor. By the way, posting stuff
Speaker 1:  for free on Nextdoor incredible. This is The Vergecast, we'll be
Speaker 1:  right back.
Speaker 1:  Jake Kakis is here. Hi Jake. Hey there, Jake, in two weeks
Speaker 1:  you have debuted as an Apple Live blogger and you have debuted, I believe,
Speaker 1:  as an iPhone reviewer.
Speaker 6:  I'm trying my best, this is
Speaker 1:  Huge for you.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, no, this is great. What
Speaker 1:  A glow up for Jake this year.
Speaker 6:  They, I know, it's fun. It's, you know, due to
Speaker 6:  everyone else being unavailable, a lot of people thought really hard
Speaker 6:  and said, I, I guess, I guess Jake is available. And
Speaker 6:  that's how I got The Vergecast hosting gig. That's how I got The iPhone reviewing
Speaker 6:  gig.
Speaker 1:  I mean, honestly, this is, this is the life. So if I have this right, Jake,
Speaker 1:  you reviewed the base iPhone 17. Yes. And
Speaker 1:  Allison, you have some or all of the phones, but you've mostly
Speaker 1:  been doing The iPhone air review, right? Yeah,
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Okay. That's been my main gig.
Speaker 1:  Okay. So this is good because I actually think, and, and
Speaker 1:  you should both feel free to tell me I'm wrong and correct me, I think you
Speaker 1:  have the two most interesting phones of the year
Speaker 1:  by a mile, but for wildly different reasons and we should just get into it.
Speaker 1:  So I think we have to start with the air, which I think is probably the
Speaker 1:  phone about which I have the most questions, if that makes sense. Like it
Speaker 1:  is, it is the wildest of the wild cards of these
Speaker 1:  phones so far. So Alison, you've been using the thing, you've reviewed the
Speaker 1:  thing,
Speaker 1:  hit me with it. How do you feel? How's the, how's The iPhone air experience
Speaker 1:  been?
Speaker 5:  Oh boy. I feel, I feel pretty much
Speaker 5:  like I anticipated I would, so I should say that I reviewed
Speaker 5:  the Samsung Galaxy S 25 Edge earlier this year. It's kind
Speaker 5:  of the same idea. It's a phone except thin.
Speaker 5:  And the experience of using that and The iPhone air
Speaker 5:  is, you're sort of wowed right at the beginning.
Speaker 5:  You're like, oh my God, this is so thin, it's so light, I feel like I'm gonna
Speaker 5:  break it. You get used to that. You carry it around and
Speaker 5:  the thing that kind of sticks with you is the weight. Like
Speaker 5:  it'll fit into pockets and little nooks and crannies of the
Speaker 5:  bags. I carry that. Normally I'm like trying to jam a phone into,
Speaker 5:  and every time it does that, I'm like, oh, that was nice.
Speaker 5:  But, but the thing that kind of sticks with me is just sitting
Speaker 5:  and holding it and scrolling and my hand doesn't get as tired
Speaker 5:  And I don't have such a great weight resting on my
Speaker 5:  pinky. You know, it's, it's, it's the little things. It's hard
Speaker 5:  to describe it and convey it without someone picking it up and holding
Speaker 5:  it. If, if you can do that, I encourage you to, but that's
Speaker 5:  my big takeaway.
Speaker 1:  This is one of the challenges of this phone, right? Is I think like you,
Speaker 1:  you look at the specs and like, yeah, it's thinner and yeah, it's
Speaker 1:  lighter, but the numbers are relatively small
Speaker 1:  to the extent it's not like, you know, the, the regular iPhone weighs six
Speaker 1:  pounds and this is suddenly much smaller. Like it's just a
Speaker 1:  slightly smaller iPhone. But you're saying it, the, the difference is there
Speaker 1:  do add up to something meaningful.
Speaker 5:  They do. And I, I went through the same thing. You look at the numbers, you're
Speaker 5:  like, is this really gonna be that big of a difference? And you pick it up
Speaker 5:  and hold it, you're like, oh, it really is. And I think it
Speaker 5:  just comes down to, we are so attuned to like every gram
Speaker 5:  that a phone weighs. 'cause we carry them and use them all the time.
Speaker 5:  And there's just sort of a, we've settled on like, this is roughly how much
Speaker 5:  a phone weighs and you pick this one up and you're like, oh,
Speaker 5:  it's, I don't know. Okay. I do know you have had this
Speaker 5:  experience of like picking up a toddler like day after day
Speaker 5:  and you're like so used to how heavy they are. Then you pick up a newborn,
Speaker 5:  you're like, oh my God, I'm gonna like
Speaker 5:  toss this child into the air. Same deal. It's like
Speaker 5:  toddlers.
Speaker 1:  Interesting. So this really pours cold water on a theory I've had for a long
Speaker 1:  time, which is that actually what I want apple to do is make a bigger phone
Speaker 1:  with like bruising battery life. And that is
Speaker 1:  completely indestructible. And actually what you're making me think is maybe
Speaker 1:  the lesson learned here is that that actually isn't a good idea because we're
Speaker 1:  so attuned to it that if you made it bigger, it would, it
Speaker 1:  wouldn't just feel not better. It would feel like actively worse.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. And I will add to that. So, you know,
Speaker 5:  spoiler alert, battery life is not super great on the air. We sort of
Speaker 5:  anticipated that
Speaker 5:  it's not a disaster, but there's the, the MagSafe
Speaker 5:  battery pack that apple kind of reintroduced, like specifically
Speaker 5:  for the air.
Speaker 1:  Jake was very excited about this on the podcast last week. Oh yeah. Jake
Speaker 1:  loves a battery pack. Yeah, I love it.
Speaker 6:  Love, love making a phone bigger with more accessories.
Speaker 5:  Well, that's the thing, it's like, you can think of it as a modular phone
Speaker 5:  where you're like, this is kind of how it is by itself. But then
Speaker 5:  you slap a battery pack on it. But the, the thing
Speaker 5:  is it, the battery pack itself, it light and thin. You put it on the
Speaker 5:  phone and you use it for a minute and I'm like, this is too heavy. Like this
Speaker 5:  is heavier than a pro. Interesting. It doesn't feel good And I just wanna
Speaker 5:  leave it here until it's charged and then take this thing off of it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. There, there's definitely a real, like, we keep telling people go like,
Speaker 1:  touch it and try it and pick it up. And part of me is like, that might actually
Speaker 1:  be terrible advice because like, maybe you shouldn't know how much
Speaker 1:  thinner and lighter your phone could be unless you're prepared to spend the
Speaker 1:  money on the thinner and lighter phone.
Speaker 5:  You know, the reaction I've gotten, it's kind of a negative one at first,
Speaker 5:  I think from people who are not really expecting, like my husband, he's like,
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna break this. I don't like that. Like, I heard that a couple of times
Speaker 5:  and then after you've used it a little bit, you're like, okay, okay, I feel
Speaker 5:  better with this. This is, this is nice.
Speaker 1:  Does it feel fragile at all?
Speaker 5:  I wouldn't say it does. Like, it, it feels solid. I,
Speaker 5:  I did have it like sitting on the ground and my
Speaker 5:  4-year-old was like stomping around the room And I had to like,
Speaker 5:  ooh, I hope he doesn't stomp right in the middle of his phone. Like,
Speaker 5:  I would not normally think that of a, of a
Speaker 5:  normal phone. But it's, it's something that sort of crossed
Speaker 5:  my mind more often using this. But at
Speaker 5:  no point was I like, thi this feels so fragile,
Speaker 5:  I'm gonna break it.
Speaker 1:  Okay, that's good news. I'm, I'm glad to hear that. 'cause I think, yeah,
Speaker 1:  one of my worries would be that I would end up treating this thing like a
Speaker 1:  precious object because they kind of want you to think it is a precious object
Speaker 1:  and that's just not the right relationship to have with your
Speaker 1:  phone. I think like these things are so utilitarian and so ubiquitous
Speaker 1:  that having something you have to baby is actually really annoying
Speaker 1:  in my humble opinion. But you mentioned battery life And I think the, the
Speaker 1:  two trade-offs we expected coming into this, were going to be battery life
Speaker 1:  and camera question mark, because there's only one
Speaker 1:  and we have a lot of thoughts about it. Let's start with battery life. What's
Speaker 1:  the, what's the actual situation like
Speaker 5:  Battery life? Where I've landed is, and
Speaker 5:  I've only used a thing for a week, but it seems to
Speaker 5:  me it's in, if there's a spectrum of like spectrum acceptable
Speaker 5:  battery life on a brand new phone, it's in that
Speaker 5:  spectrum. It's on the low end. Okay. So depending
Speaker 5:  on the phone you're, you're trading in. Wait,
Speaker 1:  Can I just pause you? Actually this is, this is, can we just do a little
Speaker 1:  exercise right now? Okay. I want all three of us to just say out
Speaker 1:  loud what you think minimum acceptable battery life
Speaker 1:  is for a smartphone. Like how often do you need to charge your phone
Speaker 1:  in order for it to be fine?
Speaker 1:  Jake, you go first.
Speaker 6:  So my current phone that I, that I use day to day is a pixel eight. Okay.
Speaker 6:  And if it hits 20%, it goes into low power mode
Speaker 6:  and it drives me crazy 'cause it turns the high refresh rate screen off.
Speaker 6:  Everything goes into dark mode. Everything gets chugged, you know, starts
Speaker 6:  slowing down.
Speaker 6:  If it hits 20% and I'm in my day to day,
Speaker 6:  that's when it's too low. Mm. So I, I think bare
Speaker 6:  minimum is a phone that is above 20% power
Speaker 6:  when I go to bed.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I like that. Alison, what's, what do you feel like your number is?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, about the same. Like, I, I need to get through my day
Speaker 5:  and if I see that 20%, you know, it turns red,
Speaker 5:  it gives you a a mean notifications. Like
Speaker 1:  Yeah. The iPhone really gets really alarming about it when you get 20%
Speaker 5:  And every time I look at the phone, you know, you see the, the percentage
Speaker 5:  go down and it's still angry at you. So Yeah. I, I agree with
Speaker 5:  that.
Speaker 1:  Okay. It's, it's funny, I actually think we're all almost in exactly the
Speaker 1:  same place, which is really helpful. So I, the reason I ask is because I've
Speaker 1:  been using the iOS 26 betas all summer and like beta software is
Speaker 1:  famously just crushing to phones. So like, I don't hold it against the
Speaker 1:  betas when they crush my phone's battery, but they have, and so
Speaker 1:  I've gotten to the point where now I'm getting to 20% at like
Speaker 1:  four o'clock in the afternoon. Mm. And like the difference
Speaker 1:  that that makes in like my psyche is so much more
Speaker 1:  substantial than I am willing to talk about like that that
Speaker 1:  feeling of like, okay, I ha I am, I have to run out to do an errand
Speaker 1:  and there's like an actual non-zero chance my phone battery is going to be
Speaker 1:  dead before I get home because I have to use CarPlay to get there. I have
Speaker 1:  my grocery list on my phone And I need to get back. So I'm gonna like use
Speaker 1:  this device. It's four 30 in the afternoon And I feel like my phone might
Speaker 1:  be dead before I get home. It's like, that is, that is unacceptable.
Speaker 1:  And so I think I, I like the, like I, I should
Speaker 1:  be able to charge it every night and never hit low power mode, I think is
Speaker 1:  a really good, a really good way of, of thinking about it. So does,
Speaker 1:  does The iPhone error hit that? Does it at least hit that threshold?
Speaker 5:  It mostly does. So the, the days
Speaker 1:  When I, that was a sigh at the beginning of that sentence that I don't like
Speaker 1:  at all.
Speaker 5:  It's just testing a battery. There's so many factors
Speaker 5:  and so many things. That's true. And especially in a period where you're
Speaker 5:  setting up a phone from scratch and using it the first two days are
Speaker 5:  just kind of a nightmare. So the days where
Speaker 5:  I went really hard on the battery had like a ton of, you know, more than
Speaker 5:  five hours of screen on time. I was in the back of an Uber for an
Speaker 5:  hour, all this stuff. Like I was getting to
Speaker 5:  that 20% by dinner time and that was stressing me
Speaker 5:  out. And I was like, do I put the battery pack? Do I charge it? Do I leave
Speaker 5:  the battery pack on while I'm making a phone call?
Speaker 5:  I didn't like that when I've had, and that was a lot more
Speaker 5:  out and about and travel when I've been at home on wifi and I'm
Speaker 5:  just kind of doing normal stuff and it's more like of a three hours
Speaker 5:  of screen on time day.
Speaker 5:  It's been much more acceptable where it's in the
Speaker 5:  thirties by bedtime,
Speaker 5:  so didn't see the low power mode. I breathe the sigh of
Speaker 5:  relief. But, but for a brand new phone
Speaker 5:  that does not feel great, you know? Yeah. That, and that's the kind of thing
Speaker 5:  that's like, this is the best this battery's gonna be. It is not gonna ever
Speaker 5:  be any better. And a year from now, what's
Speaker 5:  that gonna look like? You know?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Jake, that description of the battery sounds like it does not hit my
Speaker 1:  threshold. Does it hit yours? No,
Speaker 6:  I agree with you. Okay. 'cause that, that's exactly where my 2-year-old phone
Speaker 6:  is. Right. If I push it hard, I'm gonna see lower power mode on a normal
Speaker 6:  day it's winding down, but it's fine. But that's fine. It's two years
Speaker 6:  old. You gotta worry. I, that, that makes me concerned about
Speaker 6:  how that's gonna be in the long term.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, yeah. Yeah. And this is like, if, if you're not gonna hold
Speaker 1:  and look at your phone, the hell's the point of buying the fancy one. You
Speaker 1:  know what I mean? I don't think, like, I just don't think The iPhone air
Speaker 1:  is like the, the gentle user's iPhone to begin with.
Speaker 1:  So I think it's, it's a tricky, like the, the self-selecting group of people
Speaker 1:  who is going to buy this phone are going to be be the people who maybe are
Speaker 1:  hit the hardest by the battery limitations. But to some
Speaker 1:  extent that's physics, right? Like it is what it is. I don't, I don't know
Speaker 1:  how much there actually is to do to solve it. Like
Speaker 1:  there's only so much space inside of the phone. The camera is the other one.
Speaker 1:  What's, what's been your verdict on the camera?
Speaker 5:  The camera. I'm a little more okay with, with the
Speaker 5:  asterisk that you know, it, it is a single 48
Speaker 5:  megapixel camera. Very capable in good
Speaker 5:  light. You know, it's hard to buy a phone with a bad camera these days.
Speaker 5:  You do get like a two times crop zoom
Speaker 5:  mode. You get the new selfie camera on the front.
Speaker 5:  Very. Which is very cool and nice. Does that
Speaker 1:  Work by the way? Just random digression Does it, does the, the thing where
Speaker 1:  it, it'll do the landscape selfies. It'll do the crop selfies 'cause it has
Speaker 1:  the square sensor. Like does that all work as advertised?
Speaker 5:  It does. You need, the thing we learned is that you need
Speaker 5:  at least four people in the frame, like moving into the frame and
Speaker 5:  looking at the camera to trigger it where it's gonna go.
Speaker 5:  Landscape mode,
Speaker 5:  which makes me take
Speaker 1:  Selfies with that many people.
Speaker 5:  I don't know. I'm
Speaker 1:  Like, I don't have that many friends. What
Speaker 5:  Are we doing? I don't have many friends. Like what? Yeah. Kind of rude of
Speaker 5:  Apple. Seriously. But it is cool. It does some cool stuff,
Speaker 5:  but the, the thing I miss on the air is the Ultra wide,
Speaker 5:  you know, the Samsung Edge has and Ultra wide it is
Speaker 5:  a little bit thicker and bigger, but that's
Speaker 5:  just one of those things you can't, like computational photography,
Speaker 5:  you're way out of like, if I can't back up in a room, that's it.
Speaker 5:  Right? You're just doing one of these where you're like leaning all the way
Speaker 5:  back. So there's a few situations you get into where
Speaker 5:  I'm like, this is, this is a thousand dollars phone And I can't do this.
Speaker 5:  This doesn't feel quite right.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah. And, and those, those trade offs are always easier to stomach
Speaker 1:  when you're paying less money. This is like what we talked about last week
Speaker 1:  with the, the folding and flipping phones. It's like, it's one thing to be
Speaker 1:  like, oh, you get fewer cameras for fewer dollars, that makes sense. But
Speaker 1:  here is the expensive one, it does less stuff. And you're like, well that
Speaker 1:  doesn't compute quite the same way in round. Yeah. Jake, you've,
Speaker 1:  you've also gotten to use the selfie camera and you as everyone knows, are
Speaker 1:  the most prone selfie taker at The Verge. I would say
Speaker 6:  Nonstop. Nonstop.
Speaker 1:  If you put, if you were like, who is taking the pictures of themselves the
Speaker 1:  most often it's Jake And I, it's not close. What?
Speaker 6:  I have a ring light set up in every room just in case I need to take some
Speaker 6:  photos.
Speaker 1:  You just have one attached, like with a chest strap at all times.
Speaker 6:  I'm constantly slacking you these photos when I'm cooking dinner. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  How have, have you found the, the new selfie camp? Because it's the same
Speaker 1:  one across all the models, right?
Speaker 6:  Yeah. Yeah. So it, it's interesting. I I did side by sides with the 17
Speaker 6:  and the 16 and quality wise, the,
Speaker 6:  the selfies look identical, right? Like, I, I don't think a lot has changed
Speaker 6:  in the character of the selfies. It really just is this trick
Speaker 6:  where it just goes sideways automatically for you. You don't have to it.
Speaker 6:  I, I'm a little torn, like on one hand, I, I did not personally
Speaker 6:  find turning my phone sideways to take a landscape selfie, all that difficult.
Speaker 6:  On the other hand, selfies by
Speaker 6:  far are shot in portrait, right? People are holding their phone
Speaker 6:  upright and Apple has now made it easier to get everybody in the
Speaker 6:  frame while you're doing that. They have fully dummy proofed the selfie and
Speaker 6:  you know what? It works. So I, I don't think this is
Speaker 6:  going to be necessarily like revolutionary for everybody. I don't think your
Speaker 6:  selfies are gonna look better. Is it gonna make it slightly easier for a
Speaker 6:  lot of people to take selfies? Absolutely. Yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 1:  I think dummy proof is like the story of the iPhones camera
Speaker 1:  as we've, you know, talked about many times. It is, their whole thing is
Speaker 1:  basically how do we make it harder to take bad pictures? Which I think is
Speaker 1:  a good and noble goal, but is maybe not the only goal that a camera manufacturer
Speaker 1:  should have.
Speaker 6:  Yeah. I mean, if, if you're a person who wants to take creative photos or,
Speaker 6:  or you know, quote unquote great photos, it's, you know, maybe it's not what
Speaker 6:  you want. But I, I do think, you know,
Speaker 6:  we've been doing selfie cameras for little over a decade now and this is
Speaker 6:  the first time I can really think of a, a major phone being like, Hey, maybe
Speaker 6:  we should optimize for the main way that people shoot selfies.
Speaker 6:  You know what? That makes a lot of sense. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  I buy it. So Alison, just to cover off on the, on the air here, where, where
Speaker 1:  do you land in terms of like, I'm just a person,
Speaker 1:  I have an, I don't know, I have an iPhone 13 that is like on its last legs,
Speaker 1:  it's time for me to upgrade and I'm just earnestly
Speaker 1:  trying to decide which iPhone to buy. I'm not like coming to it with any
Speaker 1:  preconceived notions. Who is the heir the right phone
Speaker 1:  for,
Speaker 5:  This is a, a weird one. So if you have an iPhone
Speaker 5:  13, I would infer about you that you like
Speaker 5:  to hold onto your phone. You don't wanna be going into an Apple store
Speaker 5:  every two years and be like, I'll take the new iPhone please.
Speaker 5:  The iPhone here is not for that person. I think the battery is
Speaker 5:  gonna run down faster.
Speaker 5:  I I think you're just gonna run up against the limits
Speaker 5:  of what it can do sooner, I think, than
Speaker 5:  a pro or maybe even the regular.
Speaker 5:  So this doesn't feel like a phone for a person who wants to kind of
Speaker 5:  set it and forget it.
Speaker 5:  The way I've come around to thinking about it is that it's a
Speaker 5:  little bit of a statement. It's sort of for a person who's like,
Speaker 5:  you know what, phones are huge. I don't need all that. I don't like all that.
Speaker 5:  I would just rather exist with a smaller, lighter phone.
Speaker 5:  I'm fine having this battery pack on me all
Speaker 5:  the time. Or I am always near a power
Speaker 5:  outlet and it's not a problem to just, you know, top off the battery
Speaker 5:  throughout the day.
Speaker 5:  It's kind of a, a leisurely comfortable
Speaker 5:  way to live with your phone. I think there
Speaker 1:  Is a cohort of iPhone mini loving people who are
Speaker 1:  screaming at their headphones right now saying, you just described the
Speaker 1:  reason they should have kept making the mini. I know. And to all of those
Speaker 1:  people just know that I agree
Speaker 5:  With you. I know. And he, to to my iPhone mini
Speaker 5:  friends. This is not a small phone. It is
Speaker 5:  a big phone with small phone energy. It is still like, oh, I like that
Speaker 5:  you still have to reach across the screen. It's lighter, it feels nicer in
Speaker 5:  that way. I can fit it in the front pocket of my jeans, which is how I
Speaker 5:  carry my iPhone mini. But it's just, it's not a small phone.
Speaker 5:  So I'm sorry for everybody.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, that's fair. Big phone with small phone energy is is actually I think
Speaker 1:  a very good way to think about it. But yeah, I I think it's going to be interesting
Speaker 1:  to see how many people are willing to make
Speaker 1:  the particular sacrifices you have to make. I think especially on battery
Speaker 1:  life in order to get the size and shape of the thing. And
Speaker 1:  I have not yet bought an iPhone this year. There's, there's always still
Speaker 1:  time, but I need, I need to hold the air before I make a
Speaker 1:  decision on whether it's time to get rid of the 16 and move up.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. Alright, so
Speaker 1:  Now let's, let's switch gears to you, Jake, because I think
Speaker 1:  this year, for the first time in a while, my
Speaker 1:  sense coming out of the event was that the base
Speaker 1:  iPhone was going to be the right iPhone for most people. In, in that
Speaker 1:  same, like, I'm just looking to upgrade my phone. I have no preconceived
Speaker 1:  notions, I just want a good iPhone. The 17 looked
Speaker 1:  coming out like it had all the right upgrades. The price was good. It seemed
Speaker 1:  like it, it was, it was closer to being the one than it has been in a while.
Speaker 1:  How does it feel after testing? Is that, is that still where you land?
Speaker 6:  Oh yeah. I, I tried living with The iPhone 16 for a week
Speaker 6:  before I reviewed the 17 and it was driving
Speaker 6:  me crazy. Right? The, the always on
Speaker 6:  screen is such a dramatic essential
Speaker 6:  upgrade. So it, it's such a critical part of a phone that it, it's kind
Speaker 6:  of bamboozling that it has not been part of the standard
Speaker 6:  iPhone for so long. Right. It debuted on the pro in
Speaker 6:  2022. And you know, it, the reason it's remained a
Speaker 6:  pro exclusive until now is 'cause it's, it's a major selling point. And I
Speaker 6:  think it's so major that the past several years, I, I would've told anybody
Speaker 6:  like, yeah, like the pro is, that's so important.
Speaker 6:  You should spend money in the pro now there's a $300 price gap
Speaker 6:  and you're getting the best features. You're getting the always on display
Speaker 6:  and it's a high refresh rate screen. It feels like a completely different
Speaker 6:  phone than iPhone 16. Yeah. It
Speaker 1:  Feels like in terms of sort of obviously great things,
Speaker 1:  it doesn't do,
Speaker 1:  the only real thing I can think of is the camera, right? Like are there,
Speaker 1:  are there sort of big things you feel like it's still missing?
Speaker 6:  I think that's the story here, right? It it's, there's always been like a
Speaker 6:  pretty big gulf between the two and, And I think there's all als often been
Speaker 6:  essential stuff in the pro line and now it's right,
Speaker 6:  it's the main camera is a little bit nicer on the pro, but that's
Speaker 6:  fair. There's a telephoto camera on the pro That's cool. I like telephoto.
Speaker 6:  But the, I think that's it, right? Like it has a, it has a cool new redesign.
Speaker 6:  You can't get this one in orange, right? No one is gonna know you have
Speaker 6:  a brand new iPhone, which
Speaker 1:  To be clear is not nothing like if we've learned one thing in
Speaker 1:  the last seven days, it's that iPhone aesthetics matter an awful
Speaker 1:  lot to people. And the, the addition of a new color
Speaker 1:  was a big deal. Like especially a loud new color that screams this is a
Speaker 1:  brand new iPhone that matters to people.
Speaker 6:  I do think there's something there, right? If you, if you look at this phone,
Speaker 6:  it looks the exact same as every iPhone has for
Speaker 6:  the past like six years, right? And, and so if you're upgrading
Speaker 6:  from an iPhone 11, you are not gonna be able to tell the difference. You're
Speaker 6:  gonna be like, I replaced my phone with the same phone. Right. Which maybe
Speaker 6:  feels like a bummer even if the change inside are enormous.
Speaker 1:  Was that the sage one by the way?
Speaker 6:  It is the sage one. The sage is, I love the sage.
Speaker 1:  It's a great one for, for people watching this on YouTube. I hate doing this.
Speaker 1:  Can you just hold it up? This is the one Alison said I'm, she's gonna take
Speaker 1:  in with, at the event outta the stage And I haven't actually seen
Speaker 6:  Second. Yeah, no, let me show you this. It's lovely.
Speaker 1:  How do you feel about the sage? Beautiful.
Speaker 6:  The sage is a fantastic color. It's really nice. It looks, it looks really,
Speaker 6:  really nice. It's one of the best iPhone colors in a long time.
Speaker 1:  It is really nice. It's very, it's like a quiet color, but really nice looking,
Speaker 1:  which I really appreciate. Like it
Speaker 6:  Doesn't, it's saturated enough. Yeah. It's not like, yeah, it's not, it's
Speaker 6:  not a whisper of
Speaker 1:  Things. Yeah. Finally Apple did colors instead of just like, I always think
Speaker 1:  of apple's color scheme as they just like put The iPhone down next to a can
Speaker 1:  of paint and then ship it to you. This one they actually, they painted the
Speaker 1:  things this time it's
Speaker 6:  Very exciting. No, it looks really good, thank God.
Speaker 1:  So having used, having used the 17 now, Jake, what's, what are
Speaker 1:  the downsides? What do you not like about the 17?
Speaker 6:  What I,
Speaker 6:  I mean again, I'm just gonna keep complaining about notification management
Speaker 6:  on iOS, but like that's not No, nobody's here for that. Right? If if, if
Speaker 6:  you want an iPhone, you like it's still an iPhone, it's great. Yeah, no,
Speaker 6:  I truly, the the, the biggest
Speaker 6:  issues that have, that I had with The iPhone 16 have been mitigated. Right?
Speaker 6:  They were, they were the screen.
Speaker 6:  I don't think I have major pro, like I don't think there are major flaws.
Speaker 6:  I don't think there are major restrictions that, that
Speaker 6:  are only right? Like, I don't know, are there some ProRes features?
Speaker 6:  I can't get, I I couldn't even tell you. That's fine. Like I,
Speaker 6:  I I don't need to shoot in ProRes. That's fine.
Speaker 1:  Can I just say the, the fact that that question is really hard to answer
Speaker 1:  is so exciting and such a big deal for the base iPhone because it's like,
Speaker 1:  yeah, Alison, you And I have been going through this for years where it's
Speaker 1:  like, okay, I have, I have a, a list of things on each side And I
Speaker 1:  have to try and explain to you whether
Speaker 1:  the this tiny upgrade to the, the hardware and this new button and this tiny
Speaker 1:  new thing in the camera. All of that adds up to you should, you know, spend
Speaker 1:  a few hundred more dollars and get a new phone. I, we just don't have to
Speaker 1:  do that anymore. Right? Like the, and and that's the thing with so many of
Speaker 1:  these things, like v And I are gonna talk about the watches later, but I
Speaker 1:  think what happened with the watches was they were basically like the, the
Speaker 1:  base one is a great one and then for a little more money
Speaker 1:  you get the health stuff and it's like that, that is a completely
Speaker 1:  understandable decision, but there's nothing
Speaker 1:  missing from the base model. And it feels like The iPhone for the first time
Speaker 1:  in kind of, as long as I can remember, there's nothing missing on the base
Speaker 1:  iPhone.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It, it doesn't feel like you're putting up with something and
Speaker 5:  Apple's being like, well if you want that, you really gotta pay a
Speaker 5:  few extra a hundred dollars. Right. Jake, are you like a
Speaker 5:  promotion guy, 120 hertz? Can you see, you see the difference
Speaker 5:  and it bothers you kind of deal.
Speaker 6:  Yeah, absolutely. And I think like once you get used to that, it's, it's
Speaker 6:  very hard to go back. It's like even after a week with the standard
Speaker 6:  model coming from a one 20 herz display, everything felt so
Speaker 6:  like sluggish. My
Speaker 1:  IPhone 16 is sitting here and it's, it's hearing you and it's really upset
Speaker 1:  by all of this. It's, I just want you to know you've been hurting the feelings
Speaker 1:  of my still very new iPhone. I
Speaker 6:  I don't know how you're living with that thing. It's, I, I seriously, like
Speaker 6:  it's hurting my productivity, not having a screen that's on, like
Speaker 6:  it really is. I
Speaker 1:  Will say Allison, you And I talked about the always on display last week
Speaker 1:  and a couple of people reached out and were like, hey, one thing you should
Speaker 1:  try is turning off the wallpaper on the always on display.
Speaker 1:  And I went to turn off the wallpaper on my iPhone 16 and was
Speaker 1:  like, oh right. I don't even have an always on display. Like it's,
Speaker 5:  Oh no, it's
Speaker 1:  Been, I hated it so much. I bought a phone that doesn't support it without
Speaker 1:  even realizing.
Speaker 5:  Okay JI wanna, Jake, where do you stand on the wallpaper? Dimming on
Speaker 5:  the always on display.
Speaker 6:  I thought I was gonna hate it because I, I have not been using
Speaker 6:  that feature in the past and actually it's totally fine. Doesn't bother me
Speaker 6:  at all. Yes, yes.
Speaker 5:  Okay. One more. Yes, it's fine. Vote for totally fine. This
Speaker 1:  Is the worst you get are you guys are terrible. So on the pro
Speaker 1:  Allison, you, you've, you're not reviewing it, Todd Hazelton is reviewing
Speaker 1:  it and we'll we'll link to that in the show notes, but you've used it a bunch
Speaker 1:  along with it. How does it feel compared to kind
Speaker 1:  of these other funds? Like it is bigger and heavier. It is the more like
Speaker 1:  substantial device and actually it seems like more so this year because the
Speaker 1:  air is allowed to be the thin one. This one doesn't have to be like, how,
Speaker 1:  how does the pro feel just as a phone to use right now?
Speaker 5:  Yeah, it, it feels a little like a cheat kind of going
Speaker 5:  between the air and the pro is, is like not the situation most people
Speaker 5:  are gonna be in. So the, the pro really
Speaker 5:  did feel kind of just like dense and heavy
Speaker 5:  in a way. I, I don't think it would've really struck me
Speaker 5:  if I hadn't been using the air so much. The,
Speaker 5:  the switch to the more curved edges. I don't
Speaker 5:  particularly like, so the last,
Speaker 5:  the 16 pro had more straight sides.
Speaker 5:  I feel like that is nicer in my hand. I can grab another phone. I
Speaker 5:  don't feel like it's gonna go flying. Most people could put a case on their
Speaker 5:  phone. This does not bother them. Yeah, it bothers me a tiny bit,
Speaker 5:  but I'm, I'm still just appreciative of the
Speaker 5:  smaller pro being everything that the
Speaker 5:  bigger pro is. Like the prom max, you get the same
Speaker 5:  telephoto camera, you know, it's just a matter of battery life
Speaker 5:  really in screen size if that's a thing to you.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. The the little pro kind of remains my,
Speaker 5:  my little pet favorite of, of the bunch.
Speaker 1:  It is a very good phone. I think there, there are increasingly few people
Speaker 1:  I would recommend it to because it's like, if you want all the things that
Speaker 1:  the pro has, you probably also want more battery and more screen
Speaker 1:  on which to do those things. So I'm like, I'm not sure who the base
Speaker 1:  pro is for,
Speaker 1:  but I also am with you. And that like, there's something about that phone
Speaker 1:  that I just really love. It's like you are, you are the in-between phone
Speaker 1:  And I love you for that.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. I'm like, just please don't go anywhere. Don't get bigger.
Speaker 5:  Don't disappear
Speaker 1:  Next year. Apple, take that one and make it thin. No, and everything will
Speaker 1:  be fine.
Speaker 5:  Whoa. Mind blown.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. The iPhone Pro air And I will, I will love that phone
Speaker 1:  And I will come, come on the show And I will spend a month talking about
Speaker 1:  how stupid the name is. And that is, that is my promise to you. Allison,
Speaker 1:  question on the, the camera thing. 'cause Right, I think if, if we're looking
Speaker 1:  at it and we're saying the, the single most compelling and,
Speaker 1:  and in many ways only reason to go from base iPhone to
Speaker 1:  iPhone Pro is still about the cameras. You're,
Speaker 1:  you're the most professional photographer of the three of us.
Speaker 1:  How compelling is that case to you right now? This year
Speaker 5:  It's, you know, it does put you
Speaker 5:  in a, in a class of like you really care about image quality,
Speaker 5:  which is all, all three of us I think. So
Speaker 5:  on the base iPhone, the camera sensor in
Speaker 5:  the main camera is just a little smaller than
Speaker 5:  the one you get on the pros. You do not notice
Speaker 5:  anything about this in good lighting. Portrait mode's fine.
Speaker 5:  Where I see a difference and I'm, the air also has the
Speaker 5:  smaller sensor on the main, as the base
Speaker 5:  iPhone is in the two x portraits.
Speaker 5:  So if, if I've lost anybody, then that's fine just
Speaker 5:  by the base iPhone, if you know what I mean by the two
Speaker 5:  time portraits and you're screaming like, oh God, I can't give that up. Like
Speaker 5:  I, I take portrait mode photos constantly
Speaker 5:  take them of my kid the two time Zoom is just so nice for
Speaker 5:  that. So one X feels too wide. The four
Speaker 5:  x on the pros this year is actually very nice, but sometimes that's too
Speaker 5:  close anyway. But I can see the difference in low light,
Speaker 5:  you know, you're taking a small, a portion of a smaller sensor
Speaker 5:  and you lose detail that the pro hangs onto. So it's,
Speaker 5:  it's in the minutia. I don't think there's a, a
Speaker 5:  great case for, oh you really should spend extra on
Speaker 5:  the pro because two times portraits, but it's, it's there if you go
Speaker 5:  looking for it.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I think I I I find this all really
Speaker 1:  interesting like from an Apple strategy perspective, but from a, just like
Speaker 1:  I'm a person who wants a phone perspective, really exciting because in many
Speaker 1:  ways I think this decision of which iPhone to buy is kind of
Speaker 1:  easier than it's been in a long time. Where it's like, do you just want a
Speaker 1:  really good iPhone by the, by The iPhone 17 if you want the camera
Speaker 1:  by the pro, if you want the like aesthetics
Speaker 1:  by the air, like done and done right. And I think there're small trade offs
Speaker 1:  on each side, But that fact it, it is as clean
Speaker 1:  a delineation between the phones as I can remember, like in a long
Speaker 1:  time.
Speaker 5:  Yeah. It's very helpful to us. Like a huge Yeah. People who
Speaker 5:  recommend phones.
Speaker 1:  Travis, our producer just slacked me. The air is an orange though, and it
Speaker 1:  makes a reasonable point. Brad,
Speaker 6:  Do you think like it's, it's been so frustrating. I think I for the, the
Speaker 6:  typical buyer, right? The thing that says iPhone, right?
Speaker 6:  The plain old iPhone. It should, it should be the essential version of the
Speaker 6:  phone. And I, I truly feel like that has not been the case in recent years
Speaker 6:  and this year I it it is so clearly the case, right? Like
Speaker 6:  I I don't think you're missing anything major. I think you'll have a fantastic
Speaker 6:  phone for a while to go and, you know, I don't know what's coming next for
Speaker 6:  the pro, but it, it doesn't feel like there's any obvious thing at the moment
Speaker 6:  that I don't know. You have to be like, well that's too bad. Yeah. Right.
Speaker 6:  You don't get a vapor chamber cooling.
Speaker 1:  Oh no. Whatever will I do?
Speaker 1:  Yeah. I don't have a vapor chamber. I can't vape with it. Like what are we
Speaker 1:  even doing here If
Speaker 6:  They build a vape into the pro?
Speaker 1:  Oh no, that's i's changed.
Speaker 6:  That's terrible for America. But they'll sell a lot of phones.
Speaker 1:  Indeed. Alright, so before I let you guys go, we got a hotline question that
Speaker 1:  the three of us are gonna answer together and it is, it
Speaker 1:  caused me to think more than I thought it would. So here lemme just play
Speaker 1:  it and then let, we're gonna talk about it.
Speaker 7:  You know what, I feel like anybody who has an iPhone air is now
Speaker 7:  susceptible to losing their phone in the couch. It's gonna
Speaker 7:  be the most losable phone ever.
Speaker 1:  Okay, so here two questions. A Allison, true or false
Speaker 1:  is this, is this a very losable phone?
Speaker 5:  Oh, true. Yeah. I was on a, a plane
Speaker 5:  and had The iPhone air. I usually put it in my pocket and
Speaker 5:  it has happened that the phone will kind of fall out when I'm moving around.
Speaker 5:  And then, then you're in that situation where you're like, oh God, it's in
Speaker 5:  the seat somewhere. They say don't adjust your seat 'cause you're gonna start
Speaker 5:  a fire with the battery or something like that. I had almost a full panic
Speaker 5:  attack because I thought it had fallen out of my pocket and it,
Speaker 5:  it will just slip right in between the seats and then you gotta call it
Speaker 5:  flight attendant. Long story short, I just, I put it in my bag
Speaker 5:  And I forgot it was in my bag. But that's a long way of saying yes.
Speaker 5:  This feels like a phone that you will lose in the couch.
Speaker 1:  It is a, it is ausable phone even maybe not in the
Speaker 1:  ways that you think it's gonna be Ausable phone. Yes. Okay. And then
Speaker 1:  my other question is, does everyone else almost lose their phone
Speaker 1:  all the time? Because I almost lose my phone all the time.
Speaker 1:  Like, like yesterday I was sitting down in the car
Speaker 1:  phone just slipped outta my pocket without even noticing and fell
Speaker 1:  like in the side between the seat and the car door. Yes. And I
Speaker 1:  spent like half the afternoon being like, oh no, I've lost my phone. It's
Speaker 1:  gone forever. I have also lost my phone in couch cushions. I have also just
Speaker 1:  randomly left my phone places that it doesn't make sense to leave your phone.
Speaker 1:  Like is this like a specific medical condition that I have or
Speaker 1:  does everyone almost lose their phone all the time?
Speaker 5:  I, if I'm gonna lose it, it is in that exact situation in the
Speaker 5:  car. 'cause it will just go in between all the
Speaker 5:  weird inner workings of the seat and the console. And I will
Speaker 5:  spend a lot of time like fishing it out from the bottom of the car where
Speaker 5:  there's a lot of goldfish crumbs. Yep.
Speaker 5:  But I've trained myself, I think
Speaker 5:  to leave my phone in very specific places. So
Speaker 5:  if I go in the kitchen, there's like a place I put it down in the kitchen.
Speaker 5:  If I go in the TV room, I, and, and when I,
Speaker 5:  when I have that moment of, oh, I lost my phone. I don't remember where it
Speaker 5:  is, I go to one of those spots and it's usually there.
Speaker 5:  But I have had to like actively do that otherwise
Speaker 5:  I would lose my phone all the time.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I'm glad that's not just me, Jake is sitting here like, I've never
Speaker 1:  lost a phone in history.
Speaker 6:  I, I used to be like really, really good at this because I, I just always
Speaker 6:  just like put it straight back in my pocket when I was done with it. And
Speaker 6:  now phones got bigger and these like silicone cases are
Speaker 6:  really popular and as they get older they get kind of like funky. They like
Speaker 6:  don't slip into pockets very well. And so now I'm just, I'm just like, stick
Speaker 6:  it wherever. It's like, I don't know, it could be anywhere.
Speaker 6:  It's fine if it gets lost. It, it was meant to be
Speaker 1:  Hands down. The best feature of the Apple watch is the thing where it will
Speaker 1:  make my phone make noise That's good. So that I can find it, which I do
Speaker 1:  more often than I'm proud of. Alright, we need to take a break. Alison
Speaker 1:  and Jake, thank you both for doing this. Good luck
Speaker 1:  being just in the cross hairs of our commenters for
Speaker 1:  the foreseeable future. We gotta take a break, we'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  You really have like spent, how many hours have you spent at your
Speaker 1:  home in the last 10 days?
Speaker 9:  Not many. Yeah, maybe 36.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, that's, that's how, that's probably how many in the last 10 days.
Speaker 1:  That's good stuff. So you're, if if I have my schedule correct here,
Speaker 1:  you're currently traveling for MediConnect?
Speaker 9:  Yes, I am. Okay. What's happening at Meta Connect? You can read
Speaker 9:  the leaks at The Verge dot com but
Speaker 1:  I Yeah. Gosh, what could it be? Could it be Mark Zuckerberg has many glasses?
Speaker 9:  What could it possibly be?
Speaker 1:  Exactly. Alright, well we'll come back to that another time. I actually think
Speaker 1:  there's a chance Meta Connect is like sneaky fascinating this year, but
Speaker 1:  we'll come back to that another time. You are also deep in
Speaker 1:  the throes of oh, so many Apple reviews. So many,
Speaker 1:  And I, I wanna, I wanna talk about AirPods for like two seconds because
Speaker 1:  I think that is all that is required to more or less tell the story of AirPods
Speaker 1:  and Oh, you're wearing them. Okay. I am wearing them. So let's, let's start
Speaker 1:  with the wearing them because I would say that your feeling
Speaker 1:  and the general consensus on the AirPods PO three is that they are terrific.
Speaker 1:  They were, they're, we came outta the event being like, like this is the
Speaker 1:  most straightforwardly great upgrade. And it seems to have been pretty much
Speaker 1:  exactly that.
Speaker 9:  Basically Apple went and tripled down on a good thing and made
Speaker 9:  everything that you like about the AirPods better and then said, Hmm, what
Speaker 9:  do you not like about the AirPods? Let's see if we can fix that too. And
Speaker 9:  you know, the by and large, the largest, the most
Speaker 9:  common complaint that I've ever heard about AirPods from people who are tech
Speaker 9:  journalists, from people who are normal people from just anyone
Speaker 9:  is the fit, right? Because either you are blessed with ears that the
Speaker 9:  AirPods fit into, and that's true across the regular AirPods range or the
Speaker 9:  pro range, or you're, you're just not, you're just not blessed with the,
Speaker 9:  the, the ear canal for, for an AirPod and you know, you take the AirPods
Speaker 9:  Pro three out of the case at a first glance, eh, it just looks the same,
Speaker 9:  right? But then I happen to have my own personal pair of the AirPods Pro
Speaker 9:  two. You take that outta the case and you go like, oh, oh, oh oh.
Speaker 9:  The shape is definitely different. The AirPods Pro two are
Speaker 9:  flatter, these are more angled. So when you look at them side to side and
Speaker 9:  you, you compare them from every single angle and we have some comparison
Speaker 9:  photos in my review, you can just tell that they're much more angled and
Speaker 9:  designed to fit in better. One thing that you can do is you can kind of
Speaker 9:  twist to adjust the fit a little bit with these, and you could,
Speaker 9:  you could do that with the AirPods Pro two. But you know, if you twist
Speaker 9:  it just a little too far, it's gonna pop out this, you can actually feel
Speaker 9:  it, at least with my ear shape, you can feel it, get
Speaker 9:  more secure, the seal tightening and not in an uncomfortable way. So that's
Speaker 9:  a
Speaker 1:  Pretty normal thing for these kind of in ear things that you, you kind of,
Speaker 1:  they, they teach you to sort of put it in and turn it. Yeah. And that's actually
Speaker 1:  how you get that seal. But AirPods, my, my experience has never been, are,
Speaker 1:  are particularly suited to that. So it's good that they've leaned
Speaker 9:  Into that. No. So they've leaned into that. I went on a run with these and
Speaker 9:  during that run I went, eh, eh, trying to shake 'em outta my ear and
Speaker 9:  they didn't shake out. So, you know, that's a process actually. So, you know,
Speaker 9:  I really do think that if you've had trouble with fit before that you should
Speaker 9:  go to an Apple store or bug your friend who has them to see and
Speaker 9:  and try them out before you commit to buying them. Because every
Speaker 9:  ear shape is unique and I've, I've never had a major problem with
Speaker 9:  AirPods fit, so I'm not surprised that I also
Speaker 9:  don't have a problem here. But if you've had a problem in the past,
Speaker 9:  I would recommend trying trying them out before getting
Speaker 9:  your hopes up too high. I'm just saying as someone who
Speaker 9:  hasn't had that issue, they still fit me better. So like there,
Speaker 9:  it's like I even, I saw an improvement. So I think a lot of people
Speaker 9:  will see an improvement. That's
Speaker 1:  Good news. So it seems like, yeah, the, the, the existence of more
Speaker 1:  sizes of tips plus the little subtle design changes both feel like wins.
Speaker 1:  The thing that seems to be somewhat controversial is the actual material
Speaker 1:  of the things themselves. They're not, they're not foam, but
Speaker 1:  they're not, not foam. Like what, what are these things you're sticking in
Speaker 1:  your ears?
Speaker 9:  So I saw Dan Seifert right after the Apple event, and Dan is
Speaker 9:  is famously, if you know him, he has had problems with earbuds and so
Speaker 9:  he uses the real traditional foam tip and he's like, show me these
Speaker 9:  things and show me that foam tip. And I showed him the tip and he goes, that's
Speaker 9:  not a foam tip. And he's correct
Speaker 9:  and he's kind of correct. It's, it's not what you would think a traditional
Speaker 9:  foam tip is, you know, a foam tip. It's foam, it expands in your ear
Speaker 9:  and it gets disgusting if you sweat in them. So these
Speaker 9:  to the naked eye are gonna look exactly the same as the silicone tips that
Speaker 9:  you're used to from the regular AirPods Pro. The difference is, is in the
Speaker 9:  very like, and hopefully this doesn't mess up anything in the very
Speaker 9:  front part right here. That's where they've infused some foam.
Speaker 1:  I
Speaker 9:  See. And the reason why they, they've done that is that's the part that will
Speaker 9:  expand for the more secure fit. The rest of it is silicone so that when you
Speaker 9:  sweat, it doesn't get disgusting. Right. And so that
Speaker 9:  it's easier to clean. That's the the philosophy that I was told when
Speaker 9:  I was at Apple Park on the day of the event. And so, you know,
Speaker 9:  foam's there, just don't, don't think of it as like a traditional foam
Speaker 9:  tip.
Speaker 1:  Do you notice them, do they feel any different in your ears because of the
Speaker 1:  material change?
Speaker 9:  Absolutely not. Okay. Like they just feel like I, the, the fit feels more
Speaker 9:  secure. It could be that some of that is this foam infused tip,
Speaker 9:  but just looking at them I was like, this, this looks the same.
Speaker 9:  Like they, they won't fit. Like you can't interchange the tips between the
Speaker 9:  old ones and the new ones. Mm. So there is a difference there. It's just
Speaker 9:  like, I, I put them in my ears and, and they stay that
Speaker 1:  Interesting. I think the, the thing that I'm most curious about with these
Speaker 1:  is like, you, like, you know, you mentioned everybody's ears are different.
Speaker 1:  My thing is my ears start to get like
Speaker 1:  sore after wearing the sort of in-ear headphones for too long.
Speaker 1:  It's one of the reasons I've become a huge fan of the, the shocks over the,
Speaker 1:  the conduction
Speaker 9:  Stuff. Oh, I, you know, I love those too. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  I do. And there's just something about them that is like, because they're
Speaker 1:  not blocking that ear canal, there's just, there's some, it's some combination
Speaker 1:  of like the buildup of pressure that I feel in my head from having them blocked
Speaker 1:  along with just the physical toll of them pressing against my ear
Speaker 1:  canal. If I wear them like for hours and hours, like on a cross country
Speaker 1:  flight or something, I will come off and like feel physical pain as I take
Speaker 1:  them out. And I've seen mixed things on that front.
Speaker 1:  In this one. Some people are like, they block sound better,
Speaker 1:  but as a result they're actually, the seal is better, which means they're
Speaker 1:  going to hurt more.
Speaker 1:  But, so I think apple just like continues to poke at this. And this is another
Speaker 1:  reason I'm excited about the idea of there being five tip sizes is like,
Speaker 1:  what I normally do is just go to the smallest tip size And I will sacrifice
Speaker 1:  a little bit of the noise cancellation in order to not
Speaker 1:  have them hurt over time. So the idea that I can go even smaller here
Speaker 1:  actually seems potentially like it'll solve that problem for me.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. So here's what I can say from my testing. I wore them on two
Speaker 9:  cross country flights now for several hours at a time and they
Speaker 9:  were pretty comfortable for me. I did wear, I've worn these
Speaker 9:  an obscene amount over the last few days to test them. So
Speaker 9:  when I was wearing them for a really, really long time, like I wanna say
Speaker 9:  seven hours at a time, at one, at one point while I was writing my
Speaker 9:  review 'cause I was like, oh let me, lemme check this. Let me verify like
Speaker 9:  my notes and whatnot. I did have a little bit
Speaker 9:  of like itchiness on the inside, but that's just kind of similar to
Speaker 9:  any AirPods. But by and large I found them quite comfortable.
Speaker 9:  I didn't experience as much pressure buildup, although there were times
Speaker 9:  that I did and usually I would just take them out, have a little break, put
Speaker 9:  'em back in. So I think if that's something you're sensitive to, you're gonna
Speaker 9:  have to play around with it. I don't think it's gonna go away completely,
Speaker 9:  but it is improved.
Speaker 1:  Okay. I'm excited to try 'em. These, these were the one thing I like jumped
Speaker 1:  to buy immediately because I'm like, it's, it's been a while. I still have
Speaker 1:  the regular AirPods with the lightning port and it's like this, this feels
Speaker 1:  like the thing to upgrade for. So I'm excited about that. Mostly I wanna
Speaker 1:  talk about the watch 'cause I think the, the watch situation
Speaker 1:  seems much more complicated. And I would say what you found so far is that
Speaker 1:  our, our suspicions from last week have been confirmed, which is that the
Speaker 1:  watch SE three is the watch most people should buy.
Speaker 1:  Tell me why you landed there.
Speaker 9:  It's the star. It has the biggest upgrade from the last
Speaker 9:  generation to the next. So the difference between it and
Speaker 9:  a series watch is almost non-existent
Speaker 9:  depending on what are the things that you care about. And the big thing that
Speaker 9:  I was gonna say is the, was the major thing for the
Speaker 9:  series 11 watch was the improvement in battery. And that was quite modest
Speaker 9:  in my testing so far. Because
Speaker 1:  You were excited about that when we saw the announcements, the jump from
Speaker 1:  18 hours of rated battery life to 24 hours of rated battery life seems like.
Speaker 1:  And like you said last week, apple tends to underestimate those things. So
Speaker 1:  like a six hour jump, which is what like a 33% leap in battery life could
Speaker 1:  be a big deal. It's, it was a bummer to hear that it wasn't a big deal.
Speaker 9:  It's more like the 24 hour battery life estimate is now more accurate,
Speaker 9:  whereas, okay. Whereas the, like the 18 hour battery life estimate was I
Speaker 9:  think inaccurate. It was quite low. And now I think
Speaker 9:  24 hours is accurate, but still
Speaker 9:  a little low. Just not very low. So I was getting around,
Speaker 9:  I mean it's very hard to fully tell you what the battery life expectation
Speaker 9:  is gonna be on the amount of time I've had testing three
Speaker 9:  watches simultaneously on two wrists and you know, there's there
Speaker 9:  it's, it's easier And I'll have a much better idea once I get to just wear
Speaker 9:  one watch at a time for a longer period of a time instead of like switching
Speaker 9:  between watches and wearing two watches on same wrist, which means it's switching
Speaker 9:  between phones. So take what I say as nice, perfectly
Speaker 1:  Normal use case that
Speaker 9:  Everyone does all the time. Perfect use case that everyone does and is not
Speaker 9:  like my specific thing. So I'm gonna say to like
Speaker 9:  take this as my first crack at the battery testing, which
Speaker 9:  I, you know, I have my whole process down to a pet I account for these things
Speaker 9:  my first 24 48 hours with the Series 11.
Speaker 9:  I got maybe about 28 to 30 hours on a single charge. Okay.
Speaker 9:  Which is better. It's better than 24 hours, but is it
Speaker 9:  the 36 to 40 hours that I think people were hoping for? No, it's not.
Speaker 9:  Right. So if you're on a series nine, if you're on a series
Speaker 9:  10, what I think you're gonna find is that you don't have to worry quite
Speaker 9:  as much. If you go to bed with less than ideal battery life, you'll wake
Speaker 9:  up and you'll have like 3% left, that sort of thing. And you can hot
Speaker 9:  stick it on a charger. It goes zero to 80 in about 30 minutes. So,
Speaker 9:  you know, it's, it's even more true that if you just stick it on
Speaker 9:  a charger while you're getting it ready in the morning, you're good, you're
Speaker 9:  good to go. You don't really have to think about it as much. But you know
Speaker 9:  that I can already hear the Garmin users going like, well
Speaker 9:  I measure battery life not in hours but in weeks and months and this is ha
Speaker 1:  We're thrilled for you. We really are.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. And I, I love that for you guys. You guys are not gonna be impressed
Speaker 9:  by this battery life change. But you know, if you are coming from a series
Speaker 9:  five, a series six, And I am sure if you've had those watches, the
Speaker 9:  battery has decorated since in a long time and you jump to this,
Speaker 9:  you're gonna be pleased with the battery life that's available.
Speaker 9:  But is it exciting? Is it exciting for me having worn the,
Speaker 9:  the new iteration year after year? I'm like, oh it's, it's a little bit
Speaker 9:  better than the Series 10. Just
Speaker 1:  A lot. Well I think the, the thing I think is interesting about this is my,
Speaker 1:  my sense from talking to people over the years is that the idea
Speaker 1:  of upgrading your watch every year is essentially
Speaker 1:  non-existent. Like I, I know, I know a lot of people who are like, I get
Speaker 1:  every other phone because I like phones and want the new stuff or whatever.
Speaker 1:  I know people who get every phone because they're like, I like the new stuff.
Speaker 1:  I don't know anyone who is like I get every watch every year that's just
Speaker 1:  Parker. You wear your watch until it doesn't work anymore and then you get
Speaker 1:  a new watch. And so I think that makes this sort of iterative
Speaker 1:  upgrade cadence to me even more acceptable on the watch
Speaker 1:  than on some of these other devices.
Speaker 9:  Yeah. Because when you are, when it is time for you to upgrade all of these
Speaker 9:  small changes, they do add up to something big. But I really do
Speaker 9:  think that the SE three,
Speaker 9:  that's just on every single level, if you have an SE two
Speaker 9:  on every single level except bezels, this has been improved.
Speaker 9:  The bezels are still bezels, but if you've been on the se you don't know
Speaker 9:  what you're missing with non bezels. So it's, it's a really great
Speaker 9:  thing. And the only thing that's new that I think
Speaker 9:  the SC three is not getting is the hypertension notifications,
Speaker 9:  which I can't really talk about because it rolled out yesterday. And so I
Speaker 9:  am testing that in real time with everybody else who got the watch OS 26
Speaker 9:  update. Which to my point as to why the
Speaker 9:  Series 11 feels like it's the middle child of Apple Watches is
Speaker 9:  that everything that's new and cool that has come to this watch is not
Speaker 9:  exclusive to this watch. Right. Either the Ultra three has it or
Speaker 9:  the SE three has it or the Apple Watch Series nine
Speaker 9:  10 and ultra two also have it. So you're just kind of like,
Speaker 9:  eh, 'cause the SE three, it's got an always on display, it has
Speaker 9:  the pinchy pension, the flippy flip, so it has those gestures
Speaker 9:  and those were the two things that I really felt
Speaker 9:  were kind of deal breakers for me on an SE versus a series. Well they have
Speaker 9:  them.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. And to be clear, the thing where a bunch of old watches are also getting
Speaker 1:  all the new features, unbelievably good news. This is, this is great. Incredible,
Speaker 1:  incredible. It just means you probably most, most people with recent watches
Speaker 1:  probably don't need the new one. But wait, in terms of the new things on
Speaker 1:  the se I want you to rank four features for me in terms of how
Speaker 1:  big a deal they are.
Speaker 1:  The four features are fast charging, the always on
Speaker 1:  display, 5G and the battery life improvements.
Speaker 1:  I, I have a ranking in my head of how much I care about each of those things,
Speaker 1:  but I want you to rank them for me. So fast charging always on display, 5G
Speaker 1:  battery life
Speaker 9:  Always on display number one. Okay.
Speaker 9:  What were the other three? So always on display number one 5G
Speaker 9:  at the very bottom. Okay. And the other two were
Speaker 1:  Always on fast charging and battery life.
Speaker 9:  Fast charging is number two. And then battery life is
Speaker 9:  number three. Okay. Because the battery life is still 18 hours.
Speaker 9:  It's pretty, it's a pretty good 18 hours. I, I must say, so I was on a 13
Speaker 9:  hour flight. I started that flight with maybe about
Speaker 9:  87% battery And I got home and it was at 27.
Speaker 9:  So, or not 13 hour flight, but 'cause at the time change difference
Speaker 9:  from when I got onto the, to the, to the flight and, and
Speaker 9:  it was, it, it was, it it it went from 87 to
Speaker 9:  27. Sure. And I think that's pretty great. Stuck it on the charger for 10
Speaker 9:  minutes, went back up to 37.
Speaker 9:  You know, it's, it's, it's fine. You're gonna have to baby it a bit more.
Speaker 9:  What happens there is that it's, it's just doesn't have as
Speaker 9:  much capacity for, for the battery life. But because you have fast charging,
Speaker 9:  the sting is taken out because the last se didn't have fast charging. Usually
Speaker 9:  we have to sit there and wait for your watch to charge. Right. That took
Speaker 9:  a a while. The fast charging is not as fast as on the se
Speaker 9:  as on the Series 11. It's I think zero to 80
Speaker 9:  and 45 minutes as opposed to zero to 80 and 30. So you do have to
Speaker 9:  wait a bit longer. Yeah. But it's, it's not so bad
Speaker 9:  really, it it, it's just kind of like now that the fast charging is
Speaker 9:  there, you don't mind the lesser capacity quite as
Speaker 9:  much. Whereas if you don't have the capacity and you don't have fast
Speaker 9:  charging, you're just sitting there watching at that wa looking at that watch
Speaker 9:  and going faster.
Speaker 1:  Yes, a hundred percent. And it is, it is the thing there is, there is a amount
Speaker 1:  of time, And I think it's probably an hour where if my watch takes
Speaker 1:  more than an hour to charge, there's a strong chance I'm just gonna forget
Speaker 1:  about it. This literally happened to me yesterday. I I, my watch
Speaker 1:  was almost dead. I put it down to charge on my incredibly
Speaker 1:  slow charger that I've complained about on this show before,
Speaker 1:  just flatly forgot about it for 24 hours, just didn't put it on. And it's
Speaker 1:  like, that's, that's the thing that Apple can't have happened, right? Yeah.
Speaker 1:  It's like these, these things can't just like die in a drawer somewhere or
Speaker 1:  else it all falls apart. So I agree. I would, I would rank them the same
Speaker 1:  way. And I actually think seeing what you saw about the fast charging, which
Speaker 1:  is that it's not like, you know, blistering, but it is like
Speaker 1:  put it down while you're making coffee in the morning and it is going to
Speaker 1:  meaningfully charge enough to potentially get you through the rest of the
Speaker 1:  day. Like that's pretty exciting. That goes a long way for me.
Speaker 9:  It goes a, a huge way. So it's really a question of whether do you
Speaker 9:  want a bigger screen with smaller bezels and
Speaker 9:  the whole entire health suite of features or if you're like,
Speaker 9:  you can keep that, I'm gonna save
Speaker 9:  $150 and the bezels are, I'll just use one of
Speaker 9:  those black backgrounds so I don't notice them at all. Right? Like it, that's
Speaker 9:  sort of like what is the trade off there for you? And
Speaker 9:  The Vergecast listeners I suspect will be like, I will pay for the little
Speaker 9:  bit of Polish madam. Sure. But I think the
Speaker 9:  average person, the, the vast majority of people, people who have not been
Speaker 9:  totally sold by the smartwatch idea, they're gonna look at the
Speaker 9:  SE three and go like whatever, I'll save 120 to
Speaker 9:  150 depending on the size that you want. And my recommendation actually for
Speaker 9:  people who are bothered by bezels is to go up to the 44
Speaker 9:  millimeter size on the SE three because if you compare the active display
Speaker 9:  area, it's similar to the 42 millimeter series 11. So
Speaker 9:  if you think about it that way and you trick yourself into
Speaker 9:  using the black backgrounds a bit more, you're really not gonna
Speaker 9:  notice that stuff quite as much.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah. I've, I've come to think of it as like, I think looking at it
Speaker 1:  now, apple just got the naming scheme of the watch
Speaker 1:  wrong. That actually what it is is is 'cause the SE
Speaker 1:  typically, like when you think about The iPhone se it refers to something
Speaker 1:  less, right? Yeah. It is not the base model, it is a specific thing for a
Speaker 1:  specific group of people. And even the watch SE was that for a minute it
Speaker 1:  was a very much like Fisher-Price, my first smartwatch kind of smartwatch.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. It's not that anymore. So now I think about it as like the SE is the
Speaker 1:  watch, the Series is the pro and the Ultra is the Ultra and that like,
Speaker 1:  that frames it better for me and is like, this is the, the SE
Speaker 1:  is the mainstream watch in the way that The iPhone
Speaker 1:  17 is the mainstream iPhone. And then if you want it to do
Speaker 1:  more sort of nichey stuff, you scale up and if you want it to do more nichey
Speaker 1:  stuff, you scale up again. But like most people who just like
Speaker 1:  want a smartwatch and don't have further questions about how they're going
Speaker 1:  to use it, the SE is going to be enough, right?
Speaker 9:  Thees is gonna be more than enough because what are the health features really
Speaker 9:  at this point in time that you are gonna be missing out on? Because the
Speaker 9:  SE three, they added the risk temperature sensor, you are getting the vast
Speaker 9:  majority of the health features on there. So what you're, you're missing
Speaker 9:  is the EKGs, And I wanna be clear with the EKGs,
Speaker 9:  you're only missing then spot checks for AFib
Speaker 9:  detection because the irregular heart rhythm notifications, which I
Speaker 9:  call the passive AFib, like checking. So you'll
Speaker 9:  get a notification being like, hmm, we've detected some irregular heart rhythm
Speaker 9:  notification that's on the SE three now. So if you're worried about AFib
Speaker 9:  that you can get the passive notifications via the, the SE three.
Speaker 9:  So it's just the spot checking with the EKG blood
Speaker 9:  oxygen which was missing on all the watches sold in the US for the last 18
Speaker 9:  months until recently. So really I don't, I, I know there are
Speaker 9:  some people who have reached out to me being like, no, I really care about
Speaker 9:  that feature And I believe that is true for a certain subsect of
Speaker 9:  people, but for the vast majority of people you didn't know it was there
Speaker 9:  and you didn't miss it. And the hypertension notifications, which I cannot
Speaker 9:  responsibly talk about because I have only used it for one
Speaker 9:  night or like one day. But you know, I think that
Speaker 9:  could be a very useful screening tool. But at the same time,
Speaker 9:  if you are on the relatively younger side, if you're not really worried about
Speaker 9:  hypertension at this point in your life, again, it's very possible that
Speaker 9:  you will never, ever interact with that feature. Right. So
Speaker 9:  are you gonna miss it? I don't think so. If you're older, that might be a
Speaker 9:  thing that you want to keep a track of. If you have a history, a family
Speaker 9:  history of blood pressure, high blood pressure, that might be a thing that
Speaker 9:  is a little bit of peace of mind or, or maybe not peace of mind, a
Speaker 9:  health anxiety that you wanna sign up for sure. But sleep apnea
Speaker 9:  notifications, sleep score, which is the new thing, all
Speaker 9:  of that stuff is coming to the SE three. So really the three things that
Speaker 9:  I mentioned are the only health features as of this point in time
Speaker 9:  that you're gonna be missing out on. And you know, the SE doesn't get updated
Speaker 9:  every single year. It could be that for the Series 12, they're like, we did
Speaker 9:  it guys, we figured out non-invasive blood glucose monitoring. I will
Speaker 9:  eat my shoe if that happens in a year. But you know, they could say that
Speaker 9:  that's the thing and then you're like, ah, I've got an SE three, but
Speaker 9:  that's not a right now problem. And if you're thinking about upgrading right
Speaker 9:  now,
Speaker 9:  I just laid it out for you. So Yeah. Right.
Speaker 1:  And yeah, I would say there is very little evidence to suggest that there
Speaker 1:  is some gigantic groundbreaking thing coming next year. Yeah, this is, this
Speaker 1:  is a thing everybody says every year and it's like, just if you want the
Speaker 1:  thing now, just buy the thing now it's gonna be fine. Yeah, yeah. It's gonna
Speaker 1:  be fine. Alright, so before I let you go, I do just kind of wanna walk up
Speaker 1:  the line of watches here because you've, you've used them all. You, you
Speaker 1:  have a, I think a sense of like what is for who. And so if we start with
Speaker 1:  the, the SE three, which I think is like the watch for most
Speaker 1:  people it is, it is the one you should start by looking at
Speaker 1:  you, you mentioned the health features, what else is there to sell me
Speaker 1:  on the Series 11? It's $150 more expensive. It goes from
Speaker 1:  2 49 to 3 99. What am I getting that I'm paying
Speaker 1:  for bigger
Speaker 9:  Screen? So if like me, you have garbage eyeballs and
Speaker 9:  you would really appreciate the larger space
Speaker 9:  that's there. If you are someone who's really like, ah, I'm gonna
Speaker 9:  stay up all night tossing and turning about bezels, that's the
Speaker 9:  series 11 as well. It is slightly thinner, like one millimeter
Speaker 9:  thinner if you're the princess and the P mattress type,
Speaker 9:  maybe that'll be a thing that you notice if you are buying
Speaker 9:  this for your parents and for their health and you really wanna show that
Speaker 9:  you love your parents and that you want them to have the full suite of
Speaker 9:  health detection features and have that a future proof sort of thing. That's
Speaker 9:  that I think the Series 11 is gonna be a good choice for you.
Speaker 9:  That's about it. Oh, and if, if you really want,
Speaker 9:  when you're using the messaging feature, if you really want a little keyboard
Speaker 9:  that is not accommodated at all on the E three,
Speaker 9:  you're gonna need the Series 11 for that. I don't know anyone
Speaker 9:  who is super
Speaker 9:  invested in the key. I I mostly call this up because I had one person ask
Speaker 9:  me online is like, is the keyboard there? And I was like, I'll find out for
Speaker 9:  you one person. But no, the keyboard is not there on the SE three.
Speaker 9:  So if you really love that keyboard and typing via
Speaker 9:  a keyboard on your Apple watch, that is a reason to get the
Speaker 9:  Series 11.
Speaker 1:  And honestly if, if you are that person A, God bless, and
Speaker 1:  BI would like to know more about you, I will say
Speaker 1:  the, the tap backs, I've, the using a watch made me such a like
Speaker 1:  religious user of tap backs. It's perfect. It is the perfect messaging
Speaker 1:  feature for a smartwatch And I love it very much. Okay, so
Speaker 1:  then we jump to the Ultra, which you're, you're still testing and
Speaker 1:  still reviewing. Yes. The is is it as simple
Speaker 1:  a case there as it has been in recent years, which is it's bigger and it
Speaker 1:  is more outdoorsy.
Speaker 9:  Yep, that's, there you go. There's satellite connectivity now.
Speaker 9:  Yay.
Speaker 1:  Yeah, I mean that's something I will say in the, in the we, we talked about
Speaker 1:  this last week, right? That I think like ultra people are sort of self-selecting.
Speaker 1:  Like you, you either are one or you're not, either aesthetically or because
Speaker 1:  there's a feature, but I, we've, I I'm sure you have too, but I've heard
Speaker 1:  from some people who are like, you don't understand the satellite connectivity
Speaker 1:  thing is huge. Like, it, it it is huge. It makes this thing
Speaker 1:  compelling for a whole new kind of purpose for this niche of
Speaker 1:  people.
Speaker 9:  For that niche of people. Satellite con connectivity is big. Is it gonna
Speaker 9:  replace the garment in reach for like the really serious through hikers,
Speaker 9:  right? No, because the battery life is not, it's just not there
Speaker 9:  for that. But if you are on a weekend hike going off the
Speaker 9:  grid, it's there. It's, it's there and it's helpful for you and you
Speaker 9:  don't need an extra subscription to use it, which is big. So for like the
Speaker 9:  Weekend Warriors, I think this is a big,
Speaker 9:  it's a big upgrade that gives them a little more flexibility in what
Speaker 9:  gear they wanna carry. If they wanna be a little bit more minimalist, they
Speaker 9:  can be,
Speaker 9:  you know, having 5G cellular, I mean they touted it
Speaker 9:  as this thing, which is, don't get me wrong, if you have the 5G coverage,
Speaker 9:  that's great, but it's 5G MLTE on the all three watches
Speaker 9:  have it though. So it's not that different from the Series 11 to the
Speaker 9:  Ultra in terms of the coverage for the, for the cellular, the, the main difference
Speaker 9:  is that, you know, there's a different antenna for, for the two higher
Speaker 9:  end watches. So in the edge cases where
Speaker 9:  things are dropping out a little bit, it'll be a little bit better
Speaker 9:  because it has this redesigned antenna whereas it's just regular 5G
Speaker 9:  and LTE on the, the se the number of people who I think this will truly
Speaker 9:  affect this minuscule, right? Is it,
Speaker 9:  it's just like how often do you download stuff directly onto your watch versus
Speaker 9:  doing it at home where you have wifi and your phone connected to it? I
Speaker 9:  I think for most people the 5G is not gonna be
Speaker 9:  a game changer or a life changing unless you're the
Speaker 9:  heaviest of cellular users. Cool.
Speaker 9:  The Ultra is still the Ultra I compared my ultra two
Speaker 9:  to my ultra three. And again garbage
Speaker 9:  eyeballs, I was really truly like, I guess it's
Speaker 9:  minuscule smaller the bezels. Sure.
Speaker 9:  Like
Speaker 1:  Sure it's not gonna change your life. This is what you're saying.
Speaker 9:  It's no, yeah, it's mostly for people. If you don't have and Ultra yet, it's
Speaker 9:  slightly better. Yay. Sure.
Speaker 1:  Yeah. Yeah, I think so. I, I have a series eight that is
Speaker 1:  finally kind of starting to show and feel its age and
Speaker 1:  I'm, I'm like, I, I've been debating like am I ready to become and Ultra
Speaker 1:  person just for the sheer screen size alone? And I think the
Speaker 1:  answer's no. I think I'm, I think I'm going se this year, but I want cellular.
Speaker 1:  Like I'm, I am, as much as everyone on our team keeps trying to be like,
Speaker 1:  I'm gonna live a smartwatch only life and it's a total disaster.
Speaker 1:  I'm gonna live a smartwatch only life and it's gonna be sick, I can't wait.
Speaker 9:  I, I would just say get the 44 because you are a tech nerd. So I do think
Speaker 9:  if you were to go for the 40 and you saw those bezels, you would be like,
Speaker 9:  what is this?
Speaker 1:  40 feels small I think, let me look at mine. Mine is, I think
Speaker 1:  I have the 45 right now. So I think I would probably go 44.
Speaker 9:  Yeah, go 44. The bezel situation, just use the
Speaker 9:  dark watch faces. Trick yourself into not thinking
Speaker 9:  that's there because I have the 40 millimeter se and when I did see
Speaker 9:  the icons I was like, what is this smart watch for ants? I can't see
Speaker 9:  anything. Good lord. Especially because watch it West 26
Speaker 9:  improves the smart stack so that you have a tiny icon that pops up when
Speaker 9:  there's a relevant suggestion in the smart stack. So
Speaker 9:  the example I've been using is you open your camera on your phone and a
Speaker 9:  little camera icon's gonna pop up and then you pinchy pinch and then you
Speaker 9:  can open up the, the camera remote. 'cause it shows up in the, it's very
Speaker 9:  neat, it's very contextual. When that happened on the, on the 40
Speaker 9:  millimeter And I had just switched from and Ultra two to a SE
Speaker 9:  three, I was like, what is this icon? Oh, put it
Speaker 9:  right next to my eyeball. That's what it is like. But again,
Speaker 9:  terrible eyesight. If you have 2020 eyesight, you're probably fine.
Speaker 9:  So yeah, this is a me problem. Yeah,
Speaker 1:  Fair enough. All right, last question. Are you using the flow
Speaker 1:  watch face?
Speaker 9:  Yes, I'm, I am. In fact I like it. I think it's very
Speaker 9:  minimalist. I think it's pretty, I love pink and purple and it's now pink
Speaker 9:  and purple on my wrist. Liquid glass
Speaker 9:  is liquid ass on the phone in my opinion, but on the watch it's
Speaker 9:  fine. Like it's,
Speaker 1:  See I totally disagree. I think it is like, I think it is more
Speaker 1:  offensive on the watch than almost anywhere because it's like I'm,
Speaker 1:  my problem with the flow watch face, I'm looking at it right now is like,
Speaker 1:  it's, it's pretty and it's charming and it is like borderline
Speaker 1:  unreadable and it's like, what I actually want from my watch is just
Speaker 1:  to show me the time all the time and, and ironically when it's
Speaker 1:  off and you're just glancing at it from the side when it just has the black
Speaker 1:  background, it's very readable and, and nice and translucent in a cool way.
Speaker 1:  You turn it on, it, it breaks, I don't like it.
Speaker 9:  Here's my hack, David hit me. You can go edit that watch face and turn off
Speaker 9:  the background so that it's never on. And then you just have the nice always
Speaker 9:  off look
Speaker 1:  Completely. I mean this is, this is such, the story of liquid glass is like,
Speaker 1:  if you just turn off like most of its features, it's pretty great.
Speaker 1:  And look now I've made it incredibly boring, but way more readable.
Speaker 1:  Thanks a lot Apple. We're doing great here. Yeah, yeah. Everybody,
Speaker 9:  Everybody, you're, everybody's killing
Speaker 1:  It
Speaker 9:  All.
Speaker 1:  It's fine as always. Turn off most of the features, it'll be fine. The the
Speaker 1:  OS 26 story
Speaker 9:  I that and if you turn off most of the features, your battery life will
Speaker 9:  improve. So
Speaker 1:  Also true. That's a fair point. All right. You've, you've convinced me. All
Speaker 1:  right V you have smart glasses to go play with I'm sure.
Speaker 9:  So I have so many and just gonna, this is just gonna be me all day. Smart
Speaker 9:  glasses V.
Speaker 1:  All right, we gotta take a break anyway, V thank you. We'll be right back.
Speaker 1:  All right, we're back. Let's get to a question from The Vergecast hotline
Speaker 1:  as always. The number is 8 6 6 VERGE one one. The email is Vergecast at The
Speaker 1:  Verge dot com. We love hearing all of your questions. This one is about Apple
Speaker 1:  because that's what we're doing here this week, but it's about a thing Apple
Speaker 1:  hasn't talked all that much about recently, which is ai. It's from Nathan
Speaker 1:  here, it's,
Speaker 15:  Hey friends, this is Nathan. This is probably a,
Speaker 15:  not likely take, but with Apple and The iPhone
Speaker 15:  17 event, having AI like basically not
Speaker 15:  present at all. And I've been wondering this for a bit, like is there any
Speaker 15:  chance that Apple just doesn't believe in AI and
Speaker 15:  they're not failing at it, they're just not even really trying and they're
Speaker 15:  just waiting for it to burn out? I don't know. Seems unlikely
Speaker 15:  but, and maybe that's optimistic of me but yep, thanks.
Speaker 15:  Alright,
Speaker 1:  So Nathan, I think the simplest version of the answer to your question is
Speaker 1:  no, I don't think Apple has given up on the idea that AI is important
Speaker 1:  and cool and exciting and is just waiting for it to burn out. I sort of love
Speaker 1:  that theory. It's a really fun conspiracy theory that would actually like
Speaker 1:  retroactively make a lot of apple's moves here. Make sense? But
Speaker 1:  that is like Galaxy brand, even one level beyond what I'm capable of.
Speaker 1:  So I, I admire the take, but I don't think that's what's going on. But I
Speaker 1:  do wanna talk about kind of the, the framework I've developed for
Speaker 1:  listening to companies talk about AI because it's been really helpful for
Speaker 1:  me and it might be helpful for you too. So if you're a company in the world
Speaker 1:  right now, you have to talk about ai. You just do, especially if you're a
Speaker 1:  public company who once a quarter has to sit in front of investors and be
Speaker 1:  like, here is our plan for growth over time. That
Speaker 1:  story is just about AI right now. And if you don't talk about ai, somebody
Speaker 1:  will ask you about AI and if you don't have an answer about ai, they will
Speaker 1:  hammer your stock price. That's just a thing that happens. It is completely
Speaker 1:  divorced from the actual reality of whether AI is good or useful or valuable
Speaker 1:  or anybody wants it. That's just what's happening. So that is, that
Speaker 1:  is one side of the AI story And I think is important. You have to understand
Speaker 1:  how often these companies are talking to their investors
Speaker 1:  and how many of the things that they say are not about product, they're not
Speaker 1:  about thesis, about the future, they are about stock price.
Speaker 1:  And if you start looking at it that way, a lot of the tech industry gets
Speaker 1:  much bleecker and less fun. But I think it starts to make sense. So you,
Speaker 1:  you have, you have your story for investors, then I think you have your story
Speaker 1:  for users and the story for users for Apple
Speaker 1:  is actually really AI heavy and really
Speaker 1:  different from the way lots of other companies talk about ai. So
Speaker 1:  Apple's in an interesting place in that it's been doing a lot of really interesting,
Speaker 1:  like what it used to call machine learning things for a long time.
Speaker 1:  Apple is actually very clever about the ways that it uses
Speaker 1:  the on-device processing that your devices have to do things for you. Like
Speaker 1:  the the thing where you would pull down the notification shade
Speaker 1:  and start to search and right at the top it would give you
Speaker 1:  like four or eight suggested apps that it thinks you might wanna open.
Speaker 1:  That's contextual, right? It's dependent on what time of day and what you've
Speaker 1:  been doing recently and it's, it's a guess as to what it thinks you might
Speaker 1:  wanna be doing when you open your phone. That's ai. Like
Speaker 1:  they didn't call that AI because that wasn't the buzzword when this stuff
Speaker 1:  was coming out, but that's ai, Siri, all the stuff Siri has done
Speaker 1:  around your phone, good and bad is ai, like what the rest of the
Speaker 1:  industry is doing is this M ideas. We, we've been at this a long time
Speaker 1:  and so I think if you think about the way Apple has done clever
Speaker 1:  processing stuff in photos over time, the the thing where you could go and
Speaker 1:  search for a person and find your photos, like that's ai. This isn't like
Speaker 1:  novel groundbreaking stuff that Apple's doing, but it is, the stuff like
Speaker 1:  that is the technology. What's changed is that now everybody is obsessed
Speaker 1:  with this guy idea of like a God level chat bot that can do everything
Speaker 1:  for you. And we're all talking about age agentic. And so where Apple I think
Speaker 1:  has gone awry is by trying to catch
Speaker 1:  up on the buzzwords because everybody is obsessed with this one very
Speaker 1:  particular instantiation of ai, which is a a bot that I
Speaker 1:  ask a question and it goes and accomplishes things on my behalf. Everything
Speaker 1:  that I have seen and read and talked to people about suggests that that tech
Speaker 1:  doesn't work for anybody and there's not a ton of indication that it's going
Speaker 1:  to anytime soon. There are little bits of this agentic stuff that are starting
Speaker 1:  to work, but the idea that I'm just going to have like a magical
Speaker 1:  interface to the world that I just ask it to, I don't know,
Speaker 1:  fulfill all of my desires, I don't know, buy me groceries. It's like a thing
Speaker 1:  that all these companies want to be able to do And I just say like, Hey,
Speaker 1:  buy me groceries and it will go, it will figure out what I need. It will
Speaker 1:  figure out what it costs, it will figure out everything. It will meal plan
Speaker 1:  for me and it will, none of that works. I don't know. I don't know how to
Speaker 1:  be clear about that. None of that works and Apple is out over its
Speaker 1:  skis because it has to talk about that again because it has to make a case
Speaker 1:  to its investors that it is growing and is going to keep growing,
Speaker 1:  but none of it works. And so Apple is now in this tricky place where I think
Speaker 1:  what we've seen this year, And I think the thing that gives me hope
Speaker 1:  for what Apple is doing with AI is that a lot of the stuff at WW DC was
Speaker 1:  not like flashy AI first features where you're
Speaker 1:  interacting with the AI in order to do something. It's
Speaker 1:  just features like it's, it's just software. I think I, if you look around,
Speaker 1:  there are basically two kinds of ai. There's AI that is magical
Speaker 1:  God chatbots and there's AI that is software. And we're actually doing ourselves
Speaker 1:  a disservice by talking about them as the same thing because one side doesn't
Speaker 1:  work and might not, and also might be a total societal disaster. And the
Speaker 1:  other is actually going to meaningfully change the way that we interact with
Speaker 1:  our devices. And so Apple having these on device
Speaker 1:  models that it can use to help you do stuff
Speaker 1:  inside of your apps. We're seeing in iOS 26, a lot of devices are starting
Speaker 1:  to do this so that you can scan photos and pull text out of them. There's
Speaker 1:  this cool app called stuff that you can, you can write a to-do list on a
Speaker 1:  piece of paper, scan it and it'll pull it into the app as a
Speaker 1:  digital to-do list. That's ai. That's not magical Siri
Speaker 1:  chatbot, but it's ai. And so I think if, if Apple is
Speaker 1:  smart And I think Apple generally is smart, it's
Speaker 1:  going to do that kind of stuff more
Speaker 1:  going forward and to whatever extent it's gonna try to do magical god
Speaker 1:  chatbots, it seems like it's preparing to lean on companies like
Speaker 1:  OpenAI and Anthropic and even Google to do that. The idea that
Speaker 1:  Apple is going to internally build magical, beautiful, perfect Siri seems
Speaker 1:  unlikely. And I think that is where you're gonna see Apple start to pull
Speaker 1:  back because the idea of Apple intelligence being like the front and center
Speaker 1:  interface to your phone, I don't think was ever the right idea. I don't
Speaker 1:  think Apple knows how to do it. Apple is not doing it well so far And
Speaker 1:  I think you're gonna see it start to pull back on that stuff and start pushing
Speaker 1:  on the idea that actually what AI is is like an enabling infrastructure and
Speaker 1:  tool set to do really cool stuff inside of your devices. That is the version
Speaker 1:  of AI that I am much more excited about anyway. So I think that's cool.
Speaker 1:  And in the meantime, there is this messy thing where Apple is going to have
Speaker 1:  to keep telling everybody that it's inventing God inside of your iPhone so
Speaker 1:  that its stock price will go up. But if you just look at those different
Speaker 1:  things, pushing and pulling against each other, which side wins and
Speaker 1:  like who is drinking which Kool-Aid and huffing, which farts is like
Speaker 1:  the story in AI right now because there is, there is what you have to say
Speaker 1:  out loud. There is what is possible, there is what is useful and there is
Speaker 1:  what is interesting and those are not all the same thing right now. So that's,
Speaker 1:  that's my big take on just how I'm thinking about what Apple and all
Speaker 1:  of these other companies are up to are, are we building God or are we building
Speaker 1:  better software? I'm, I am deeply suspicious of one of those things and really,
Speaker 1:  really excited about the other And I think Apple is starting to lean toward
Speaker 1:  the side that makes me happy. Anyway, Nathan, I hope any of that makes any
Speaker 1:  sense. If you have theories about what Apple is up to with AI or if you've
Speaker 1:  seen cool ways in which it's actually giving developers tools or even
Speaker 1:  implementing some of this AI stuff itself, send them my way. All this new
Speaker 1:  software is packed with this stuff and I'm, I'm super curious to see how
Speaker 1:  people are using it in interesting ways. So hit me up. 8, 6 6 VERGE one,
Speaker 1:  one Vergecast at The Verge dot com. Thanks as always for calling it.
Speaker 1:  Alright, that is it for The Vergecast. Thank you to Jake and Allison and
Speaker 1:  VE for being here. And thank you as always for listening. If you wanna know
Speaker 1:  more about any of these gadgets, stuff we haven't covered in our reviews,
Speaker 1:  obviously you can read more stuff on the site, but send us questions if you
Speaker 1:  have questions about these or any of the gadgets that have come out this
Speaker 1:  year. We have some fun kind of gimmicky stuff we're gonna do with all of
Speaker 1:  these gadgets for the rest of the fall. But if you want to know anymore,
Speaker 1:  you can always call us on the hotline at 8 6 6 VERGE one one. You can email
Speaker 1:  Vergecast at The Verge dot com, send in all of your questions. We actually
Speaker 1:  have some fun stuff coming up. I think we're gonna probably do like a mega
Speaker 1:  hotline episode in the pretty near future. So keep all your questions coming
Speaker 1:  about all this stuff and anything else, I want to hear all of it.
Speaker 1:  The Vergecast is The Verge production and part of the Vox Media podcast network.
Speaker 1:  The show is produced by Travis Large Rock, Brandon Keefer and Eric Gomez.
Speaker 1:  We will be back on Friday to talk. I don't know, I have more hot takes that
Speaker 1:  I didn't get to